<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-22T18:20:39.004569+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiosl</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Oslo Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiosl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64db78f35b8f7a3fa27551ff_osl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3776960"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Oslo Airport (ENGM) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Greater Oslo Region with a yearly average of 30 million passengers.  It was opened 25 years ago, replacing Oslo's former main airport (Fornebu), deemed too small for the ever-growing demand for air travel in the region.  Sporting over 200 destinations (domestic and international), OSL is a hub for Norse Atlantic Airways, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe. The visitors' list includes most major european airlines, such as Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Swiss, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish, and WizzAir. Trondheim (2,092,000), Bergen (1,987,000), and Stavanger (1,603,000) are among the top three busiest destinations from Gardermoen, further reinforcing the strength of domestic operations in the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models, SAM animated jetways, PBR texturing on objects and ground, custom ground textures, ground traffic plugin, custom autogen around the airport, and performance-friendly optimization.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $24.04, requiring at least 2.72 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgbur</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Announces Uberaba Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgbur" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64db883044d339e25f2f93b4_sbur.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="498300"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently announced the development of Uberaba - Mário de Almeida Franco Airport (SBUR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Uberaba in Minas Gerais, Brazil, with a yearly average of 104,856 passengers. ‍ The airport was built in the 1930s, with its commercial debut in April 1934: a VASP flight on a Monospar ST4 from São Paulo, with a single stop in Ribeirão Preto. During its first decades of operation, it was only an airfield.  ‍ A passenger terminal was only built in 1950, and promotion to airport status only came in 1958 after it was donated from the city to the government (the now defunct Ministry of Aviation).  ‍ Infraero (a state-controlled airport administration company) took control in 1980, investing heavily in modernization and bringing it up to the expected standard of a commercial airport in Brazil: night lighting, a meteorological station, and an eventual terminal expansion many years later in 2008, doubling its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ It was recently purchased by Aena, granting them 30 years of administrative rights over the airport and the obligation of modernizing it within five years of taking control (by 2027, at the very least).  ‍ ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a detailed terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ There’s no release date or price information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgmaf</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Releases Uberaba Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgmaf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64dd0a1576ab009e67160439_1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="359609"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently released their rendition of Uberaba - Mário de Almeida Franco Airport (SBUR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Uberaba in Minas Gerais, Brazil, with a yearly average of 104,856 passengers.  Built in the early 1930s as an airfield, its commercial debut only happened in 1934 with a VASP flight on a Monospar ST4 from São Paulo with a single stop in Ribeirão Preto.  A passenger terminal was only built in 1950, and promotion to airport status only came in 1958 after it was donated from the city to the government (the now defunct Ministry of Aviation).  Infraero (a state-controlled airport administration company) took control in 1980, investing heavily in modernization and bringing it up to the expected standard of a commercial airport in Brazil: night lighting, a meteorological station, and an eventual terminal expansion many years later in 2008, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It was recently purchased by Aena, granting them 30 years of administrative rights over the airport and the obligation of modernizing it within five years of taking control (by 2027, at the very least).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a detailed terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  It’s available in their official shop for roughly $7.03. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflsof</id>
    <title>AflOSim Releases Sofia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflsof" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64dd11757ace5260f080195a_sof1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="984183"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AflOSim has recently released their rendition of Sofia Airport (LBSF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the capital city of Sofia in Bulgaria with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  The airport was built after a decree from Tsar Boris III in 1937 authorizing the construction on land within the village of Vrazhdebna. It was inaugurated two years later with its first passenger terminal.   After a brief period of military exclusivity during World War 2, it was returned to the city in 1947 with a new passenger terminal designed by Ivan Marangozov.   In the 1960s, said terminal was already at capacity, with extension work starting in 1968 to counter that issue. From a measly 600,000 passengers in the 60s, the airport was handling around 3 million passengers by the late 1970s.   With the numbers constantly growing, they started planning a new expansion in the 1990s, which comprehended the construction of Terminal 2. It was formally opened in 2006, after a 200 million euros investment from the European Investment Bank and the Kuwait Fund for Arab Economic Development.   Terminal 1 serves low-cost carriers such as WizzAir, easyJet, and European Air. Terminal 2 handles the “fancy” carriers with seven air bridges, 50,000 square meters of total area, 38 check-in desks, and a car park for 820 vehicles.  Aegean Airlines, Air Cairo, Air Serbia, Austrian Airlines, BH Air, British Airways, Bulgaria Air, Corendon Airlines, easyJet, EI AI, European Air Charter, flydubai, GullivAir, ITA Airways, Jet2.com, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Ryanair, Sky Express, SkyUp, Sun Express, Swiss International Air Lines, TAROM, TUI Airways, Turkish Airlines, Windrose Airlines, and WizzAir serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, moving jetways, animated people, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.27, requiring at least 621.71 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtelp</id>
    <title>Dominicdesignteam Announces El Paso International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtelp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64de84c4dfab9441e56a3016_elp1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="411758"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Dominicdesignteam has recently announced the development and imminent release of El Paso International Airport (KELP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of El Paso, Las Cruces, and Ciudad Juaréz, averaging 3.6 million passengers yearly. ‍ Standard Airlines built the airport in 1929 as Standard Airport for transcontinental mail service. It only became El Paso’s main airport in 1936 after Standard Airlines became a division of American Airlines. They decided to use Standard Airport as their de facto destination in El Paso. ‍ It was utilized by the US Army Air Force during World War 2 for training, hosting three different bombardment groups. ‍ It was expanded for the first time in 1971, tripling its terminal size with two new concourses built behind the old terminal, designed by Garland &amp; Hilles. ‍ Its terminal features a pier-satellite layout and 15 gates, divided between A1 and A4 and B1-B11, with A1 and A4 being exclusively used by American Airlines and American Eagle, B1 for Delta Air Lines, B3, B5, B6, and B7 for Southwest Airlines, B10 for Allegiant, B8 and B9 for United Airlines and United Express, B4 for Alaska, and B11 for Frontier. ‍ According to their announcement post on Facebook, the scenery should be released in the next few hours on SimMarket, featuring PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, custom jetways, custom animated objects, and more.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkul12</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Montréal International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkul12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64de94524d847232b32ceb34_yulnew1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1014051"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently updated their Montréal - Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport (CYUL) to version v1.1.0, adding general aviation parking, 3D animated people, general fixes, and more.  It’s the third update since its release in late July, with a strong focus on optimization, taxiway layout updates to match real-life, new apron textures, etc. The full changelog follows down below:  - Extensive optimization, - Updated taxiway layout (new taxiways), - Updated taxiway and apron textures, - Air Canada animated doors and hangar interior (use NAV light and hide/show yoke), - Additional handcrafting around the airport, - GA parking added, - Fixed barrier facing on the rear of the terminal, - 3D Animated people test placement, - General fixes.  They claim to be working on the next update (1.2.0), which will aim to improve the terrain and consequently eliminate bumps in a few areas, along with improvement on the surroundings as requested by users.  They finish the announcement with a hint at a potential new French scenery: “Air France is not a hint. Or is it?”.  ‍ The scenery is available on SimMarket for roughly $18.55, requiring at least 2.33 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddteia</id>
    <title>Dominicdesignteam Releases El Paso International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddteia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64df8218463b21b4ae64305f_elp1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="891926"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Dominicdesignteam has recently released their rendition of El Paso International Airport (KELP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of El Paso (Texas), Las Cruces (New Mexico), and Ciudad Juaréz (Mexico) with a yearly average of 3.6 million passengers.  It was built in 1929 by Standard Airlines as Standard Airport for transcontinental mail service, eventually becoming El Paso’s main airport in 1936 after Standard became a division of American Airlines, which liked Standard Airport better than the other El Paso Airport.  During World War 2, the US Army utilized El Paso Airport to train three different bombardment groups.  The first expansion happened in 1971, tripling the terminal size with two new concourses built behind the old terminal, designed by Garland &amp; Hilles.  Its terminal features a pier-satellite layout and 15 gates, divided between A1 and A4 and B1-B11, with A1 and A4 being exclusively used by American Airlines and American Eagle, B1 for Delta Air Lines, B3, B5, B6, and B7 for Southwest Airlines, B10 for Allegiant, B8 and B9 for United Airlines and United Express, B4 for Alaska, and B11 for Frontier.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, custom hand-crafted pavement, custom jetway, custom animated objects, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.99, requiring at least 781.63 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hybe</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Belgrade Nikola Tesla Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hybe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64dfc93a4f22c99d504634e5_bel.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="568896"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Belgrade Nikola Tesla Airport (LYBE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Serbian city of Belgrade with a yearly average of 5.6 million passengers. ‍ ‍ The airport was built from 1958 to 1962, when it was opened by President Josip Broz Tito, with a passenger terminal occupying 8,000 square meters, a 3,000-meter-long runway, and concrete aprons for sixteen airplanes. It used modern navigational equipment, which granted it the highest international classification according to the ICAO.  ‍ The Yugoslav wars brought stagnation and sanctions, which reduced passenger movement to a minimum, and most of the facilities were decaying and in dire need of repairs. ‍ International traffic only resumed in 2001, followed by a major reconstruction of terminal 2 and runway upgrades in 2005, bringing it up to CATIIIb standards. Its current name was given in 2006 after the famous Serbian-American inventor and scientist.  ‍ Expansion and modernization work started in 2012, reconstructing the A and C gate departure and transit areas, adding an extra 2,750 square meters of built space.   Currently, both terminals occupy a total area of 33,000 square meters, with 66 check-in counters and 27 gates (16 with jetways). Terminal 1 is the oldest of the two, recently renovated in 2017. Terminal 2, the largest, was built in 1979 and renovated twice (2006 and 2013), with capacity to deal with 5 million passengers yearly. ‍  The airport is a hub for Air Serbia and WizzAir, connecting Serbia to the world. The visitors’ list includes Aegean Airlines, Air Cairo, Air Montenegro, AnadoluJet, Arkia, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings, flydubai, Hainan Airlines, Jazeera Airways, KLM, Lot Polish Airways, Lufthansa, Luxair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Nouvelair, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Swiss, TAROM, and Turkish Airlines. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom VDGS, hand-made ground textures, dynamic airport lighting, highly detailed models, an official GSX profile, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $20.64, requiring at least 9.16 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thr172</id>
    <title>Thranda Announces Cessna 172M for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thr172" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e12958b34225ee9e6bbbd5_172-1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="74749"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda has recently announced the development and imminent release of a Cessna 172M for X-Plane 12, part of their Dynamic Generation Series of aircraft, with a strong focus on realism and customizability.  The 172M is a variant of Cessna’s long-lasting 172 family of aircraft, introduced in 1955 and still under production to this day, with 44,000 units built in total, making it the most popular aircraft in the world. Said variant dates back to 1973, featuring a drooped wing leading edge as its main design difference compared to the previous variants, and the 1974 model had a baggage compartment expansion. Every model year brought a subtle change, with the lettering changing every four years on average (the M variant was manufactured from 1973 to 1976). For example, the L variant from 1971-1972 had changes on the main gear, a dorsal fin extension, and a propeller diameter reduction.   The last generation of 172Ms from 1976 marked the end of airspeed registration in miles per hour, switching to knots per the new standard. It was also the last generation to sport the Lycoming O-320-E2D with 150 horsepower, as the 172N had the “infamous” O-320-H2AD with 160 horsepower.   Thranda’s rendition features extremely high-resolution textures (1700 pixels per meter) in 8K, a fully configurable 3D instrument panel, VR compatibility, interchangeable yoke styles, over 50 instruments to choose from, liberty to move instruments to any location on the panel, four panel presets, 3D lighting, a dynamic livery editor, full PBR control for livery creators, adjustable wear and tear, windshield ice and rain effects, individual functional circuit breakers, and more.  The complete feature list can be found here on their X-Plane.Org Store placeholder (as the product isn’t out at the time of writing). The add-on will be available for $29.95 (25% off) and will require 1.4 GB of hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpstr</id>
    <title>RDPresets Announces Stuttgart Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpstr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e13f7004a0acb031b81b24_str1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="427641"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced the development and imminent release of Stuttgart Airport (EDDS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Stuttgart in Germany with a yearly average of 7 million passengers. ‍ Built in 1939 to replace Böblingen Airport, it was taken over by the American forces right after the war. It was partially returned in 1948: runway and facilities were shared with the US Army during the Cold War. ‍ The original terminal was replaced in 2004 with four terminals capable of handling up to 12 million passengers annually.  ‍ Eurowings and Turkish Airlines use Terminal 1; Terminal 2 is used by Lufthansa and Star Alliance partners; Terminal 3 is used by TUIfly and KLM, and Terminal 4 is a separate building for other airlines, set to be rebuilt and expanded in the future. ‍ It’s a hub for Condor, Eurowings, and TUI fly Deutschland, sporting a substantial list of destinations. ‍ The scenery, set to release on Monday, will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, a terminal interior, 3d people, and more.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eglc12</id>
    <title>Orbx releases London City Airport (EGLC) for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eglc12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e1b11e3e306d20a65ad58e_Screenshot%202023-08-20%20at%201.22.18%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="379183"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has released their rendition of London City Airport (EGLC) for X-Plane 12. The company announced on its social media accounts that those who purchased the airport for X-Plane 11 will be able to upgrade to the new version for $9.99.  London City Airport is located in the Royal Docks in the borough of Newham, approximately 6 miles east of London. The airport, which features a single runway, has strict noise abatement procedures due to its proximity to the city. Because of these procedures, the list of aircraft able to operate in and out of EGLC is quite short and features mainly turboprops and regional jets.  Those interested in the new version of EGLC from Orbx can expect to find several new features from the previous version including updated terminal and building models, updated satellite imagery for the airport and surrounding area, and animated vegetation. The new version of the scenery also features custom PBR textures, a detailed interior for the ATC tower, and integration with default roads, railways, and autogen and is available on the Orbx website for $29.99AUD. ‍ Be sure to keep an eye on Threshold to stay up to date in the world of flight simulation!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skwrks</id>
    <title>Skunkworks Updater for X-Plane Goes Standalone </title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skwrks" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e2799a63d2210846070633_SkunkCraftsUpdaterv3.0.go_005.thumb.jpg.225758de8b30ba545f3b3ad23cf824eb.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="80576"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The popular aircraft updater for X-Plane, has recently been released as a standalone client. This client was developed alongside Aerobask, who have had a strong relationship with Skunkworks since its initial inception.  ‍ The new standalone client has all the same features of the current plugin version, although users can now update their X-Plane aircraft without the need to launch the program. Existing users can use the new standalone client without uninstalling the existing plugin. However, developers are recommending that users choose one version over the other.  The new standalone client can be downloaded for free from the X-Plane Forums, both Mac and Windows versions are available. X-Crafts have also written a user guide for the new updater, that guide can be found here.  ‍ As always, stay tuned to Threshold for the latest Flight Sim News ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbde3</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Idaho’s Deadly 3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbde3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e284bf443afee27e4cd5ad_ded1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="561791"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of Idaho’s Deadly 3 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a pack with three challenging airstrips and a bonus makeshift helicopter area with a STOL landing zone.  ‍ The “Deadly 3” are three challenging airstrips scattered around Idaho with tricky approaches, uphill slopes, birds, wildlife, and drones!   ‍ Dewey Moore, the first of the airstrips, is located on the north side of Big Creek, 19 miles west of the junction of Big Creek and the Middle Fork of the Salmon River, with a 700 ft long gravel runway at 4,494 feet above sea level. It’s recommended for highly experienced mountain pilots only (in real life). ‍ Simonds is a very difficult airstrip located on Monumental Creek, close to where it joins up with Big Creek. It’s often used for guided hunting trips and doesn’t have any infrastructure, meaning pilots should bring their own tie-downs and camping equipment. It has a 900 ft long gravel runway, and pilots are instructed to watch for traffic from the nearby Monumental Ranch private airstrip. ‍ Vines Airstrip is located on the south side of Big Creek Canyon, two miles west of Cabin Creek Airstrip, close to where Big Creek joins into the Middle Fork of the Salmon River. It’s a 1,100 ft gravel strip at 4,110 feet above sea level, and pilots are instructed to land on runway 27 and take off from runway 9. Real-life recommendations include instructions on short field operations, and pilots are generally advised to follow Big Creek to avoid trees on final approach and watch their airspeed very carefully as a 10 percent increase in approach speed means a 21% increase in landing distance.  ‍  The three strips are a short flight away from 85U Soldier Bar and McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL), both developed by Milo Taylor, the author of Idaho’s Deadly 3. His new creation features substantial terraforming work, custom animations, custom vegetation, and much more. The complete feature list for the package follows down below:  ‍ There is no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zls152</id>
    <title>ZL Simulation Releases Cessna 152 Freeware for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zls152" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e28c1e555ee9fc45747f4d_152.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1293898"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ZL Simulation has recently released a freeware Cessna 152 for X-Plane 11 and 12, featuring a realistic flight model and physics, PBR textures, a 3D cockpit, and much more.  ‍ The Cessna 152 is one of the most popular trainer aircraft in the world, with over 7,500 built during its eight years of production (1977-1985). It was a modernization of the Cessna 150 design with an improved engine, greater useful load, noise level reduction, and better compatibility with 100LL fuel. They were powered by a Lycoming O-235-L2C engine producing 110 horsepower at 2,550 RPM, with a range of 416 nautical miles, a 14,700ft service ceiling, and 123 miles per hour of cruise speed. ‍ Production ended when Cessna decided to end production of all of their light aircraft, with a successor being developed in the form of the unsuccessful 162 Skycatcher (2007-2013). ‍ According to the developer, the project has been worked on for over three years, featuring a realistic flight model, PBR texturing, a 3D cockpit, custom FMOD sounds, ten liveries, a paintkit, performance-friendly optimization, windshield rain effects on X-Plane 12, a built-in Garmin GNS 430 GPS, and custom coded systems using XTLua. ‍ It’s free on X-Plane.Org, and the source code is open-sourced on GitHub.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpsta</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Stuttgart Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpsta" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e3b2140c83b990822b06c4_str1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="208592"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced the development and imminent release of Stuttgart Airport (EDDS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Stuttgart in Germany with a yearly average of 7 million passengers.  Built in 1939 to replace Böblingen Airport, it was taken over by the American forces right after the war. It was partially returned in 1948: runway and facilities were shared with the US Army during the Cold War. ‍ The original terminal was replaced in 2004 with four terminals capable of handling up to 12 million passengers annually. ‍ Eurowings and Turkish Airlines use Terminal 1; Terminal 2 is used by Lufthansa and Star Alliance partners; Terminal 3 is used by TUIfly and KLM, and Terminal 4 is a separate building for other airlines, set to be rebuilt and expanded in the future. ‍ It’s a hub for Condor, Eurowings, and TUI fly Deutschland, sporting a substantial list of destinations. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with animated jetways, custom models, PBR texturing, a custom interior with 3D passengers, more than a thousand clutter objects around the apron and surroundings, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, accurate night lighting, custom taxiway signage, ground traffic, and more. ‍ It’s available on their website for roughly $22.87, requiring at least 1.02 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shdlgw</id>
    <title>SHADESCENE Releases Langkawi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shdlgw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e3b62db27874f94dfe72e8_lkw1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1200571"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SHADESCENE has recently released their rendition of Langkawi International Airport (WMKL), serving Langkawi and Peris in Malaysia with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  It was built by the Japanese Army in 1945 as an airfield, only becoming a passenger airport in the late 1980s after a huge effort by the government to develop Langkawi as a major tourist destination.  It saw its first upgrade in 1991, bringing it up to international standards in terms of infrastructure.  The airport was expanded in 2018 to accommodate up to 4 million passengers annually.   AirAsia (Johor Bahru, Kuala Lumpur–International, Penang, Singapore), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Kuala Lumpur–International), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Penang), Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur–International), MYAirline  (Kuala Lumpur–International), and Scoot (Singapore) serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, moderate terminal interior details, custom night lighting, hand-crafted ground markings and textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.03, requiring at least 242.91 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
