<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-08-31T18:31:33.819376+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wsszhe</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studio Releases Zhengzhou Xinzheng International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wsszhe"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68afc088aa630c478e9fb00a_zheng1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. WF Scenery Studio has recently released their rendition of Zhengzhou Xinzheng International Airport (ZHCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Zhengzhou, China, with a yearly average of 25.3 million passengers. Zhengzhou International was built in the early 1990s to replace the city’s former main airport. Its suboptimal location made expansion impossible, and city residents constantly complained about noise. The new project was much larger, with a 45,900-square-meter terminal and a 3,400-meter-long runway. It opened in late 1997, and the old airport was demolished soon after. Nearly a decade after its opening, the airport was expanded for the first time, with the main terminal becoming twice as big with 128,000 square meters of built area. A new expansion project—a new terminal, a second runway, and a ground traffic center—was approved in 2013. Construction started shortly after approval, and completion was achieved in 2015. The airport’s cargo traffic increased substantially after opening a Foxconn branch in Zhengzhou (the company that manufactures the iPhone for Apple). Between 2010—when it launched—and 2017, the yearly cargo volume went from 85,798 to 502,714 metric tons, with a record growth of 34% a year. Since late 2017, it has been the busiest airport in central China, surpassing Wuhan and Changsha in the process. It’s a hub for Cargolux and China Southern Airlines, a focus city for Shenzhen Airlines, and an operating base for Lucky Air. 9 Air, Air Cambodia, Air China, Air Macau, Batik Air Malaysia, China Eastern Airlines, Donghai Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Korean Air, Nok Air, Shandong Airlines, Sichuan Airlines, Spring Airlines, Thai Lion Air, West Air, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, PBR textures, custom clutter, and more. It’s available on SimMarket (2020/2024)for roughly $23.20, requiring at least 2.82 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ascsou</id>
    <title>Aeroscape Releases Southampton Airport for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ascsou"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b0c8ca94ec6d43dbfaebd2_11_72091832-7c27-4b40-b50f-ae2675d60387%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. New to the iniBuilds Store, Aeroscape has recently released Southampton Airport (EGHI), for XP12. The scenery features a highly detailed rendition of one of southern England’s busiest regional airports, with bespoke modelling, accurate ground details, and optimised performance, for Laminar’s newest sim. Southampton Airport, well known for its rather short runway, lies in Hampshire, four miles northeast of the city centre. The Airport has a long history, stretching back to its role as Eastleigh Airfield in the early 1900s. It became a hub of British aviation history when the prototype Supermarine Spitfire first flew there in 1936. Today, the airport is an important regional gateway, with connections across the UK and Europe. Aeroscape’s scenery includes custom-made textures for runways, aprons, and taxiways, alongside a fully recreated landside environment, with accurate vegetation, road layouts, parking barriers, and signage. Dynamic night lighting has been implemented throughout, with bespoke taxi signs and custom-modelled ground service equipment, scattered across the apron. The main terminal has also been modelled internally, with lighting and detailed objects, designed to reflect its real-world counterpart. You can view the full feature list below: ‍ FULL FEATURES LIST Southampton handled nearly two million passengers in 2016, though traffic fell dramatically after the collapse of Flybe in 2020. Since then, carriers including easyJet, Aer Lingus, KLM, and Blue Islands have restored connectivity, with routes to major destinations such as Amsterdam, Dublin, and Belfast. Aeroscape Southampton for XP12 is priced at $10.77 USD, and is available exclusively through the iniBuilds Store. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lca101</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lca101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b0cd0a91ade4a715bbecbd_FlightSimulator2024_2hpFwJrwRL_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a brief update this week, iniBuilds has released version 1.0.1 of their Larnaca International Airport (LCLK), for MSFS 2024. The update addresses a number of minor issues, including a fix for models that were not rendering SSAO correctly. In addition, the jetway previously serving Gate 47 has now been reassigned to Gate 48A. You can read the changelog below: Changelog v1.0.1 Larnaca International Airport, Glafcos Clerides, (LCLK), is Cyprus’ largest airport, located 2.5 miles southwest of Larnaca. Handling over 8.6 million passengers in 2024, it serves as the country’s primary international gateway, connecting Europe, the Middle East, and beyond. iniBuilds Larnaca version 1.0.1 is available now through the iniManager. For new customers, the product is available via the iniBuilds Store, for $13.47 USD, excluding taxes. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfrj14</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates RJ Professional, including MSFS 2024 Support, and New Variant</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfrj14"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b0d93504f10abe94b08df4_rj-professional-msfs_64_ss_l_250828094625.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has released version 1.4 of its RJ Professional for MSFS 2020 and 2024, adding native MSFS 2024 support, performance enhancements, and a new aircraft variant. The headline feature is the RJ100 QT (Quiet Trader), a semi-fictional freighter variant, with four liveries: DHL, FedEx, TNT, and a prototype scheme. While the real aircraft never left the drawing board, Just Flight has now brought it to life in MSFS. Version 1.4 introduces full support for MSFS 2024, custom cabin textures for each passenger livery, and new model LODs, to improve performance. In addition, the GNLU-910A FMS now supports SimBrief flight plan imports, while refinements have been made to cockpit logic, crew callout timing, and autopilot behaviour. Passenger operators also benefit from this update, with custom cabin textures now included, for every default RJ70, RJ85, and RJ100 livery. Elsewhere, the aircraft recieves additional LODs for performance improvements, in both sims. Following this is a complement of various fixes, including corrections to cockpit animations, hydraulic systems, and gear logic. The issue of EFB flickering in MSFS 2024 has also been addressed. Cabin crew callouts now follow more realistic procedures, while the altimeter and autopilot behaviour have been refined. GSX integration has also been expanded, allowing ground power and air connections via the jetway. To comply with the latest MSFS 2024 SDK, the navdata folder has been moved externally, with Navigraph Hub updated, to support the change. Documentation has been streamlined, and all manuals, operations, EFB, and GNLU-910A have been revised. A refreshed paint kit is also included, now covering the new freighter variant. You can read the full changelog here. Existing owners who purchased directly from Just Flight can download Version 1.4 now, via their account page, with third-party stores to follow soon. New customers can pick up the RJ Professional at 25% off until the end of August, through the Just Flight store. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2astar0911</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2astar0911"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, implementing circuit breakers and many fixes and improvements. Update v0.9.11 brings circuit breakers to A2A’s newest airplane, along with new additions and improvements to further refine the simulation. The complete changelog follows below: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsrt24</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Real Taxiways for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsrt24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b1d88f6a9d1247718ea115_real-taxiways-usa-class-b-c-d-and-non-towered-airports-msfs-2024_5_ss_l_250819085522.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has recently released new editions of its Real Taxiways add-on, now available for MSFS 2024. Building on the earlier MSFS 2020 version, this release brings refined visuals, layout corrections, performance improvements, and native support for MSFS 2024. Black Square offers the product in several, separately sold editions, one for Europe, one covering the United States, and an edition specifically for military airfields. A discounted bundle package is also available. This release features various new sign models, with revised textures, improved night-time lighting, and LOD optimisation, that keep them readable from farther away without pop-in. Installation is now simpler, with no separate texture setup required, while several airports have received layout adjustments and smaller signage fixes. Black Square notes that performance impact remains negligible, and airports can be excluded from the installation to avoid conflicts with freeware, payware, or World Update scenery. Marketplace and Xbox versions are planned for a later date. The following editions of the product are available: Across all packages, airports have received updated layouts, thousands of revised taxiway signs, and improved consistency with ICAO standards and regional naming conventions. In total, tens of thousands of signs have been reworked, aiming to provide a more accurate and readable navigation experience in MSFS 2024. Pricing is set at $39.99 USD for the Europe and USA editions, $44.99 USD for the bundle, and $19.99 USD for the military package. Existing MSFS 2020 customers are eligible for discounts on the new editions, with details distributed via email. Black Square’s Real Taxiways, as well as the full feature lists and changelogs, can be found on the Just Flight Store. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksrhu</id>
    <title>MK Studios Provides Update on Rome and Helsinki for MSFS, Targeting Fall Release</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksrhu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b1e174318c5444a5dc3557_540514511_1197192542429031_5833321835656931320_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently issued a brief update on its upcoming projects, confirming the progress of Helsinki Vantaa (EFHK) and Rome Fiumicino (LIRF) for MSFS. The developer explained that the holiday period, along with the release of Sim Update 3 and work on various scenery updates, had slowed progress in recent weeks. According to MK Studios, the main cause of the delay was a lack of reference material for both airports, which has now been resolved. With the necessary resources in place, the team stated that development is continuing at pace, following what it described as a quieter stretch during the summer months. Alongside the announcement, MK-Studios shared three new preview images, showing progress on the upcoming sceneries. More previews will follow in the coming weeks, as work on the two airports advances. Both EFHK and LIRF represent large international hubs in Europe, and are considered major projects for the studio. With the schedule change, the releases are now expected in fall 2025, though no specific dates have been confirmed. We’ll keep you updated on their progress. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fpfcx</id>
    <title>Flight Panels Releases Stream Deck Profiles for MSFS 2024 Citation X</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fpfcx"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b1f08679b604e91043dee4_SimMarket%20-%20FlightFX%20Cessna%20Citation%20X%20-%20Page%2001.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flight Panels has released its latest Stream Deck profiles for Microsoft Flight Simulator, designed for the recently launched FlightFX Cessna Citation X. The package introduces a comprehensive set of controls, intended to replicate the look and functionality of the aircraft’s cockpit. The Citation X profile features over 435 pre-programmed, custom-designed buttons, arranged across 19 pages, offering coverage of almost all aircraft systems. These include autopilot, navigation, communications, hydraulics, electrical, audio, lighting, ground services, and cabin systems. Flight Panels says the profiles are fully synchronised with in-sim functions. Support is provided for both 15-key and 32-key layouts, making the profiles compatible with the Stream Deck MK.2, Stream Deck XL, and Stream Deck Mobile on iOS and Android. In addition, Flight Panels has released dedicated autopilot profiles for the Citation X and the FSLabs A321 Neo, designed specifically for the Stream Deck +, to take advantage of its touchscreen, rotary dials, and tactile buttons. Here's a list with some of the main features: Key Features You can view the full roster of images and info on the official product page. The FlightFX Cessna Citation X Stream Deck Profile is available now for $27.00 USD, sales tax included, through the Flight Panels store. Discounts are available when purchasing the profile alongside other products, such as the Citation X Autopilot Profile or Profile Switcher. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/isdfw3</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Updates Dallas Fort Worth International for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/isdfw3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b1fa935b7857a190b6654d_imaginesim_KDFW_MSFS2020_07.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Imaginesim has released a new update for its Dallas Fort Worth scenery for MSFS 2024, aimed at addressing issues introduced following the SU3 update.  According to the developer, the most significant change resolves missing ground textures in the western terminal area. Alongside this fix, a number of smaller tweaks and refinements have been made to improve overall usability and visual accuracy. Existing customers can access the update through the Imaginesim Operations Center. Dallas Fort Worth International Airport is the second busiest airport in the world by passenger numbers and a central hub for American Airlines. Covering an area larger than Manhattan, DFW handles more than 88 million passengers annually, serving 265 destinations across 37 countries. The airport also supports extensive long-haul services, including a 17-hour nonstop Qantas flight to Melbourne, Australia, as well as nearly 200 daily domestic flights. DFW is also a global cargo hub. Imaginesim’s Dallas Fort Worth scenery is available for both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, in separate editions, via the Imaginesim’s website, priced at $33.75 USD each. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atms24</id>
    <title>REX Simulations Releases Atmos CORE for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atms24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b22135b840111e25eedc32_atmos-core-hero.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. REX Simulations has released Atmos CORE, a new atmospheric and weather engine, designed for MSFS 2024. Atmos CORE operates within the simulator engine, providing extra control over how weather, lighting, and atmospheric effects are depicted within the sim. The tool integrates with Asobo’s Live Weather and external engines, such as ActiveSky. You are able to adjust a wide range of variables in real time, including temperature, pressure, wind layers, and cloud formations, as well as more advanced properties, such as Rayleigh scattering, particulate simulation, and ambient lighting. A built-in preset management system allows for saving, sharing, and automatic loading of customised presets. The developer emphasises that Atmos CORE is non-destructive, leaving simulator files untouched and reverting to default states when disabled. REX also notes upcoming integration with its Weather CORE product, and future support dynamic atmospheric adjustments, in real time. Here are some of the key features of the product: Key Features‍ Atmos CORE is available through the REX Store, for $14.50 excluding sales tax, as well as Simmarket, Contrail, Orbx, Just Flight, Aerosoft, and Flightsim.to. Customers who purchased the original REX Atmos for MSFS 2020 are eligible for a 50% discount, provided the new version is bought from the same vendor. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/340dev</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares Previews of A340-300 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/340dev"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b215a34f9ea1e9581a2fc0_FlightSimulator2024_4Hu5ukHv2T.png.930f3ff717475b9025e29cc5a1f0e83b.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A couple weeks after announcing the project, iniBuilds has finally released the first development update. This time, the focus of the update has been placed on the art section of the development. In contrast from the A350, where the airframe looks relatively new and clean, the A340 has been modelled to the likes of an 20-24 year old aircraft, with a lot of attention given to the small details that emphasize the aircraft’s age, such as hydraulic staining, grease accumulation, panel wear, worn markings, chipped paint, faded text on placards and labels, as well as differences in materials on the aircraft that can be seen after years and years of service and maintenance. Moving on with the update, the next part covers the infamous engines - or shall I say the 4 additional APUs. One of the more interesting features of the engines is the use of the FS24 ‘shader’ effect for the engine spinners, making the transitions between different thrust settings look much smoother. The only issue with this effect however, is that the fan is turning the opposite way, due to the current simulator limitations. As with all iniBuilds products, the A340 will also feature openable engine cowlings. ‍ In the performance part of the update, the developers have mentioned that instead of using the traditional 4K/8K liveries, the A340 will feature decal-based liveries, that look better even when using the lower graphical settings and will use less resources. Another advantage of the FS24 is the use of the improved SimObjects system, that has let the developers fine-tune the LOD models, so that the little details can be rendered without the cost of the higher resource usage. In addition to this, a significant number of airline-specific options will be included, with some of them being the SATCOM antenna, ice detection probes, brake fans, etc. As mentioned previously, a lot of attention has been directed on wear and tear on the exterior. The more you fly the aircraft, the more weathering will be seen on the fuselage, for example, speed tape on various parts of the airframe, dents, paint flaking, residue and streaks, as well as tire and brake pin wear.  Another area of development that has been showcased were the animations, more specifically, the wingflex. With the wingspan of 60.3 meters, and with two CFM56 engine on the each wing, you can definitely expect a lot of flex. Included in the update was the video showcasing the current state of the wing animations. Aside from the wings, the gear retraction and compression upon touchdown has also been tuned to act like their real-life counterpart. For all the eyecandy lovers out there, iniBuilds has also covered the visual effects: from the wing vapors, engine condensation, over-wing vortices and wingtip trails, to the the heat blur behind the engines and the cold-start smoke. The development update has also mentioned that the A340 will include a lot of interactive hatches with which you can fiddle around during the walkaround mode in FS24: External Power, Engine Cowling, Potable Water, Waste Water, Cargo Door opening, Cargo Control Panel and many more.  The most exciting part of the update, at least in my humble opinion, is the inclusion of the EIS1 configuration. Something that has been heavily underrepresented in the flight simulation, will be an option in the A340. While the main focus is on the newer EIS2, the CRT screen configuration will be featured eventually. Lastly, the development has also addressed the cabin. Like with the A350, the A340’s cabin has been modelled based on the cabin of a german carrier too. Once again, thanks to the FS24 systems, the cabin has been modelled in a way that even the users with computers with lower-end specifications will be able to run it with comfortable performance.  Another interesting part of the update, this time regarding the cabin, is the preighter configuration. Instead of converting the entire aircraft into the cargo configuration (which takes a lot of time and money), airliners realised that they could just remove the seats from the cabin, and have more space for cargo transport. This configuration was especially popular during the COVID pandemic, as the airlines had no passenger service, while the amount of freight to be moved was only rising. In the iniBuilds rendition of the preighter configuration, you can walk around the cabin and open containers carrying food, medical supplies, parcels, car parts, flowers, live animals and more. Currently, no release date, nor the price of the upcoming iniBuilds A340 has been announced, but as always Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfdevf</id>
    <title>Just Flight Shares Extensive Development Update on F70/F100 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfdevf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b21dd2219be524d34ad206_Logo290825_NY-VwHlYRy.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. With the release of Just Flight’s Fokker 70 and 100 drawing ever closer, the developer has issued what it says will likely be the final text-based update before pre-release coverage begins. The latest report highlights progress across cockpit systems, cabin features, and the remaining technical hurdles before release. Recent weeks have seen major avionics fall into place, including the Traffic Collision Avoidance System (TCAS) and weather radar. The TCAS now produces traffic and resolution advisories, under the correct conditions, displaying intruder aircraft on the navigation display with colour-coded symbols and trend indicators. The weather radar, meanwhile, renders precipitation returns directly, on the EFIS display, graded by intensity, from green to red. Alongside these core systems, smaller quality-of-life features are also appearing. An interactive speed flipchart sits beside the captain’s display, automatically calculating take-off and landing speeds, or allowing manual reference by weight. Interactive paper checklists make a return, being mounted on the yoke’s chart holder, and illuminated by a built-in light, for night operations. Customisation has been a particular focus. Each default livery is equipped with accurate airline-specific configurations, drawn from research of real-world operators, including lighting options and units of measurement. Additional features, such as IRS alignment times, pilot callouts, and sun visor visibility, can be managed through the EFB. The Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) itself has been modelled with a new black design, available in both wall- and window-mounted variants. As in Just Flight’s other airliners, the EFB houses payload controls, fuel management, checklists, and configuration tools. Beyond the cockpit, the developers have continued to expand cabin functionality. Calls between crew stations are now fully modelled, complete with audible tones and call lights. Cabin lighting systems have been fine-tuned across all variants, controlled from the galley, while the digital music player has returned, with new support for passenger announcements. These can be triggered manually or set to run automatically, through an “Auto Cabin Crew” option. While much has been completed, attention remains on the interconnected Automatic Flight Control and Augmentation System (AFCAS), Autothrottle System (ATS), and Flight Management System (FMS). Just Flight describes these as some of the most complex features it has attempted, currently handled by a full-time developer, focused entirely on these systems. Other work continues on the custom sound set, which now includes cabin announcements and pilot callouts. As with other aspects of the aircraft, the development team is in regular consultation with real-world Fokker pilots, to verify behaviour in areas not covered by the official manuals. Just Flight expects this to be the final written entry before video previews and pre-release coverage take over, finally bringing demonstrations of the highly anticipated aircraft in action. You can read the full development update from Just Flight on their website. We'll keep you updated leading up to release. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/azrbaku</id>
    <title>Azrsim Releases Baku Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/azrbaku"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b265efc02418b6fa2fafd8_baku1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Azrsim has recently released their rendition of Heydar Aliyev International Airport (UBBB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Baku, Azerbaijan, and has a yearly average of 7.5 million passengers. The airport opened in 1933, and the first scheduled route started a few years later, taking 15 passengers to Moscow. In the late 1930s, two new routes were added, including Rostov and Grozny, to the destination roster. A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1964, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and attracting new operators and routes. In late 1990, Baku gained its international status while opening up for flights outside of the Soviet Union, which was already in the process of dissolution after the massive crisis that spiraled post-Chernobyl and Gorbachev's own measures to "lift" the invisible shielding dome. In 1997, a new passenger terminal, Terminal 2, was presented. In 1998, a new runway was opened to make operations even smoother for airlines and passengers.  Terminal 2 was inaugurated only 2 years after its official presentation, and President Heydar Aliyev was among the attendees. In mid-2004, a new domestic terminal was inaugurated, quickly becoming one of the country's most important domestic hubs. ‍ A new passenger terminal project was announced in 2011, and it opened in 2014, three years later.  Later that same year, Baku Airport earned its first 4-star ranking on Skytrax, which it repeated in 2016. In 2018, it earned a 5-star rating in the regional airport category, according to Skytrax. In 2023, it was also the first airport in the world to completely switch to cloud technologies, which helped it earn the Best Airport in Central Asia and CIS award in 2024, which it had also won five times in a row before. It's a hub for Azerbaijan Airlines, Azal Avia Cargo, Silk Way West Airlines, ASG Business Aviation, and Silk Way Airlines. Aegean Airlines, Aeroflot, Air Arabia, Air Astana, Air Cairo, Air Montenegro, AJet, arkia, Belavia, Centrum Air, China Southern Airlines, Etihad Airways, Flyadeal, Flynas, Gulf Air, Iran Air, Iraq Airways, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Pakistan International Airlines, Qatar Airways, Red Wings Airlines, S7 Airlines, SCAT Airlines, Turkish Airlines, Ural Airlines, Uzbekistan Airways, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed terminal buildings, high-resolution ground textures, dynamic night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $24.32, requiring at least 12.26 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/757aug</id>
    <title>Bluebird Simulations Shares More Progress on 757 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/757aug"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b335a1b3bbfef5ad0b8006_539685627_1083311053930975_7858960782618143749_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Bluebird Simulations has today issued an update on its Boeing 757 for MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, setting out what has moved forward, what remains, and how the team will proceed. Furthermore, Bluebird is planning two more video previews before release, with the first due for Q4 of this year, focused on system depth. The headline item is the pneumatic system, which Bluebird says has reached a new milestone and has been a major time sink in recent months. Alongside that, LNAV and VNAV are reported to be about 70% complete. Additional systems, including doors, oxygen system, and landing gear logic, have progressed in parallel. The 757 currently features 153 working circuit breakers, with Bluebird targeting more than 200 by release. The upcoming Q4 video will walk through a broader set of systems, pneumatics, the FMS, landing gear, ice and rain protection, oxygen, and doors, to show how they tie together in day-to-day use. A final pre-release video is planned to concentrate on remaining areas, with the EFB still flagged as the largest single item to be wrapped up. Bluebird has begun more extensive testing in MSFS 2024, and the latest screenshots have been taken there. The team describes the 2024 build as work-in-progress to offer a “compatible” version, at or shortly after release. A fully native MSFS 2024 edition is intended to follow later. Development on MSFS 2020 continues in tandem, which should help maintain feature parity, while the 2024 path matures. Internal testing has focused on stabilising core systems, before handing the aircraft off to external testers. With the pneumatic work now in place, Bluebird says it is approaching the first stage of beta in the coming weeks. Some items typically reserved for later testing, such as door logic, oxygen, and landing gear behaviour, have already been advanced to reduce risk, as the 757 heads towards broader evaluation. Bluebird reiterated that the Boeing 757 will cost $80 USD. The purchase will include both the 757-200 and 757-300, with Rolls-Royce and Pratt &amp; Whitney engine options, for both simulators. For 2024, a “compatible” version will be released first, while a native version is planned for “much later”. For those interested, the full development update can be found on Bluebird's Facebook page. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dgqsr</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Salerno Costa d’Amalfi for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dgqsr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b33f91d4534b6e5fd13cd1_113_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDG has released Salerno Costa d’Amalfi (LIRI) for MSFS 2020 and 2024, introducing a rather compact coastal airport in a stunning part of Italy. The package already arrives with an initial maintenance update applied (v1.1), which aims to address early issues. Set just short of 25 miles south-east of Naples, Salerno sits between sea and foothills, which shapes both the approaches and the kind of flying it invites. The real-world runway has been extended to around 1,600 metres, and the scenery reflects that updated layout, opening the door to everything from general aviation to smaller airliners. Arrivals over the shoreline are framed by rising terrain, while departures quickly put Mount Vesuvius, the Amalfi Coast, and the Bay of Naples within easy reach. On the ground, FSDG’s rendition features interior modelling, revised ground layouts, and optimised performance. The team has also modelled the surrounding greenhouse belts, which sit close to the traffic pattern, with their glass roofs being notorious for kicking back reflections onto the arriving traffic, in real life. Salerno Costa d’Amalfi is available now from FSDG and partner stores, priced at roughly $15,18 USD, including taxes. Marketplace release is planned for next week. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ccx136</id>
    <title>FlightFX Updates Cessna 750 Citation X for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ccx136"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b3592eaf1bb7da32c83742_screenshot_2025-05-20_223415%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Five weeks after the aircraft’s initial release, FlightFX has issued version 1.3.6 of its C750 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing the Citation X's first big update. The update introduces a wide-ranging set of refinements across the aircraft’s visuals, handling, and systems, alongside improvements to its integrated V.A.M.S. 2.0 interface.  Key changes include the addition of a VR collision mesh and a new co-pilot camera view. Exterior lighting has been overhauled, with corrected intensities, positions and rotations, as well as LED-style strobe and beacon lights, for winglet-equipped airframes. Improvements were also made to the cabin lighting LODs. Graphical fixes have addressed texture gaps and lighting misalignments, while sound changes were made to engine start volume, wind noise and exterior exhaust tones. The FADEC logic now better handles low-altitude cruise thrust, and high-altitude fuel flow discrepancies have been adjusted. Furthermore, ground handling has been retuned, with a focus on tiller sensitivity and yaw behaviour, plus a new option to separate rudder and tiller inputs. Thrust reverser logic has been significantly revised, with faster bucket deployment, smoother N1 ramping, and more consistent autothrottle transitions. Avionics fixes range from functional autopilot disengagement to SimBrief import errors and VSD indicators. Support for 8.33 kHz spacing has been added, alongside improvements to crossbleed logic, TOD behaviour and flight plan sequencing. The Virtual Aircraft Management System (V.A.M.S.) has seen some targeted fixes as well, including chock logic, tablet stability in third-party views, and toggle settings for tiller control. A redundant OpenStreetMap link has also been removed for clarity. For the full changelog, use this link to visit FlightFX’s Discord server. FlightFX has also updated the accompanying instruction manual, available for free on Google Drive.  The FlightFX Cessna Citation X is available exclusively on the in-sim Marketplace, for $29.99. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
