<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-02T18:23:02.906747+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bawrcs</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases Cirrus SR-22 Sound Set for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bawrcs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6384d7e6c7b43ad6ce2ddc42_boris.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1922471"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Known for their work on the freeware FlyByWire A32NX, and the Cirrus Sound Set for X-Plane, Boris Audio Works has released their Cirrus SR-22 sound set for Microsoft Flight Simulator, after 9 months of development and 50 hours of high fidelity recordings from a real airplane with an industry-standard microphone. It’s only compatible with the Deluxe Edition of MSFS, which has the SR-22 among the extra aircraft lineup.   The feature list follows down below: -Interior and exterior engine sounds, -Avionics and ventilation fans, -Levers, buttons, and switches, -Flaps, -Ground roll, -Wind and cabin air vent whistle sounds, -Differences of sound when on ground vs. in air, -and much more.  It’s available on the Threshold Store for $15.00, and on SimMarket for roughly $15.56, requiring at least 12 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/trtafm</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Trieste Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/trtafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6384ed25f9f58a6766e0c279_trop1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1008795"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released their rendition of Trieste Airport, also known as Aeroporto Friuli-Venezia Giulia (LIPQ), for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With nearly 800.000 passengers a year, TRS serves the city of Trieste in Italy and its surroundings, with a catchment area nearing 5 million people due to the proximity to the border with Slovenia, Austria, and Croatia.   It’s frequently visited by Ryanair with 8 destinations (Bari, Cagliari, Catania, London Stansted, Malta, Naples, Palermo, and Valencia), with three more to come shortly (Barcelona, Charleroi,  and Dublin). Lufthansa also flies to Trieste from Frankfurt and ITA Airways from Rome.   The founding of Trieste Airport is unknown, but the first mention of it dates back to November 1935, when it housed a wing of the Royal Italian Air Force. Commercial operations took off in December 1961.   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with native MSFS night lighting, animated jetways, seamless integration with the default Bing imagery, usage of SDK materials and native gITF models, and PBR textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.12, requiring at least 770 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrpafm</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Patch 1.29.30.0 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrpafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6385351cbb8ea76ae93ffbb1_aib2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="724870"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently made patch 1.29.30.0 available on the normal branch of Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing several crashes, an issue with the Guimbal Cabri G2, and a potential crash when requesting missing or malformed waypoint, VOR or NDB, along with a major update to the iniBuilds A310-300, including improvements to the EFB and overall performance, texture fixes, revamped audio (including AI), mitigation of FMS crashes, and the Top of Descent now triggers when it should.  The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ General Bug Fixes ‍ Airbus A310-300 ‍ Known Issue Accessing the secondary flight plan without a primary flight plan entered may cause the aircraft to lock-up. Textures EFB/IFE ‍ Sounds ‍ FMC/Systems ‍ ‍ Tooltips ‍ ATC ‍ SDK Microsoft Flight Simulator is available on the Microsoft Store and on Steam, starting from $69.99, requiring at least 150 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baarst</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Seattle-Tacoma for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baarst" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638647698be4d403721765a1_sea1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1770240"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the World and AmSim teamed up to build a rendition of Seattle-Tacoma International Airport (KSEA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, released earlier today. Sea-Tac is the busiest airport in the Pacific Northwest, with over 50 million passengers per year (before the pandemic), serving both Seattle and Tacoma, situated almost equidistantly between both (23 km away from Downtown Seattle and 29 km away from Downtown Tacoma).    It’s the hub for Alaska and Delta, with a huge domestic network covering both the west and east of the United States, along with several international routes with either Delta or the several other airlines that visit Seattle everyday, such as Air Canada, American Airlines, British Airways, Japan Airlines, Turkish Airlines, and Virgin Atlantic. It totals up to 91 domestic and 28 international destinations!  The scenery features animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures and dirt, surrounding buildings, night lighting, and parallax windows.   It’s available on Orbx Direct for $22.75, requiring at least 2.01 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdpale</id>
    <title>Tailstrike Designs Prague Airport Landing in Early December for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdpale" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63864d94ee4a3b1216f75c8a_prg01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="538436"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Tailstrike Designs made an announcement on their Discord with a release date and further information on the upcoming Václav Havel Airport Prague (LKPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which should be landing on the 5th of December. With 85 years of history and a yearly average of 15 million passengers, PRG is the main gateway to the country, home to Czech Airlines and Smartwings.   Aside from CSA and TVS, it’s also a base for Eurowings Europe and Ryanair, with a significant route network both intra-european and transcontinentally. It’s regularly visited by Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Emirates, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and many other. Amsterdam, Paris and Moscow are among the three busiest destinations in terms of passenger volume.  The scenery will include Aerosoft VDGS, highly detailed models with photoreal textures, custom runway, taxiway, apron, and stands layout, modeled terminal interiors, accurate taxiway signage, custom airport service road traffic, accurate terrain slope, high resolution aerial imagery, custom jetways per pier, and stands with accurate parking codes.   There’s a trailer for the product which is still private, but should be made available on the 5th. There’s no information regarding pricing and install size yet.  Shout out to Tang0 on Discord for the scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/frbafm</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Bremen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/frbafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638666fb2b78abe3bb1830f5_bremen1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2318490"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Sim Development Group has just released their rendition of Bremen Airport (EDDW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city and state of Bremen in Northern Germany with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. The route network is mostly intra-european, served by airlines such as Corendon, Eurowings, KLM, Lufthansa, Ryanair, SundAir, Turkish, and WizzAir.   The airport was built in the early 1900s, when a local aerospace club ran a couple experimental flights at the site that would then become Bremen Airport. It was then transformed into a military airport during WW1, with a reopening in 1920, when KLM had a scheduled flight to Amsterdam. In the 1930s, it was repurposed as military airfield, serving as a training base for the Luftwaffe, housing a squadron of Focke-Wulf Fw 200 bombers between late-1939 and mid-1940. It was heavily bombarded and partially destroyed, repaired in 1945, when the US Army took over and repurposed it as an airbase, only to be handed back in 1949.  The scenery features an accurate representation of Bremen Airport, with fully customized vehicles and facilities, realistic light environment and interior modeling, seasonal changes, reflective textures, compatible with GSX and Landmarks of Germany, including a custom GSX profile and a user manual.  It’s available on FSDG’s Store for roughly $23.35.  Shout out to Tang0 for the scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/frsvjg</id>
    <title>FlightFX Releases SF50 Vision Jet G2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/frsvjg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6386a9c61abb3d289023c24b_cirrus1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2537729"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has just released their SF50 Vision Jet G2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engine very light jet manufactured by Cirrus Aircraft. With a ceiling of 31000 feet, 311 knots of cruise speed, 1275 nautical miles of range, and a modern glass cockpit, it’s the private jet of choice for many people around the globe, with 350 built as of June 2022.  The SF50 features a custom G3000 (based on the Working Title G3000), three different seating configurations following real-life specifications (executive, family, and complete), custom integrated checklists, dynamic aircraft registration, high-quality texturing with performance in mind, visual icing effects, a comprehensive package of custom sounds, and more. The full feature list follows down below: ‍ Details • Model tested by real world Vision Jet pilots. ‍ • A reworked and optimized navigation suite based off of the Working Title G3000 (included in package). ‍ • Custom V.A.M.S. (Virtual Aircraft Management System) that controls all aspects of aircraft status. ‍ • Bose Active Noise Reduction system that can be activated right from the V.A.M.S. ‍ • Three different seating configurations that match its real-life counter part (Executive, Family and Complete). ‍ • Custom-built Initialization Screen. ‍ • Custom G3000 integrated checklists. ‍ • Dynamic aircraft registration appears on placard, Primary Flight Display, aircraft storage cover, and chocks. ‍ • Radio frequency IDs built into the PFD. ‍ • Engine and Aircraft performance pages. ‍ • Accurate interior/exterior lighting design, including the iconic courtesy lights setup. ‍ • Accurate two-step start procedure synonymous to the Vision Jet. ‍ • Revamped fuel reporting system to mimic the real-life aircraft. ‍ • Selectable ground power unit with custom audio. ‍ • Interactive luggage and loading system with prepopulated weights and trip selections. ‍ • Custom emergency gear deployment system. ‍ • Integrated CAS messages and audio warnings. ‍ Model Details ‍ • Painstakingly optimized for performance ‍ • A multitude of custom sounds recorded on site with professional recording equipment including ‍ GPU Rain Wind and cabin noises Drag noises Mechanicals Annunciators and warnings Doors Ground roll Buttons, switches and knobs • Extremely high quality texturing without killing frame rates ‍ • Supports MSFS visual icing effects and includes enhanced animated de-ice boots. ‍ • Includes three liveries derived from actual Vision Jet paint schemes. ‍ • Detailed interior and exterior textures for ultimate realism. ‍ • Intuitive cockpit camera views for quick cycling through instruments. ‍ It’s available on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $24.99, requiring at least 4.21 GB of free disk space to install. Pricing may vary per country due to regional pricing practices.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrana</id>
    <title>Sierrasim Simulation Releases Antonio Nariño Airport for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrana" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63876d7514c0205a7d922c71_pasto1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1853382"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Sierrasim Simulation has just released their rendition of Antonio Nariño Airport (SKPS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, located in Chachagüí (Colombia) and serving the city of Pasto (popularly known as Pasto Airport). With its table top runway built on a plateau and an elevation of 5,951 feet with only 2,312 meters of runway length, one of the trickiest approaches in Colombia. It is often rendered useless during certain days because of crosswinds that make takeoff and arrivals an impossible - and unsafe - task, especially in August.   The visitor's list includes Avianca and Latam Colombia, with routes to Bogotá and Cali, EasyFly to Cali, and Viva Air Colombia to Cartagena and Medellín. The overall figure amounts to 330,000 passengers yearly (as of 2019).   The scenery features textures and models based on aerial imagery, photo-realistic PBR textures for buildings and vehicles, orthophoto, sloped runway, performance-focused optimization, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:  It’s available on SimMarket for $11.39, requiring at least 774 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arbafm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Bratislava Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arbafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63877645b09f12d126dd36fb_brat1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="268524"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has just released their rendition of Bratislava Airport (LZIB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport of Slovakia, with a yearly average of 2.2 million passengers. Its slovak name (Letisko M. R. Štefánika) is after general Milan Rastislav Štefánik, victim of an airplane accident in 1919.   Due to its proximity to Vienna International Airport (LOWW), it’s often considered a cheaper alternative by LCCs. It’s the hub for AirExplore and an important city for Ryanair, Smartwings, and Wizzair. Traffic gets busier during the summer, when seasonal charters take people to coastal cities like Brač and Antalya.   The scenery features aerial imagery covering the airport surroundings, optimized 3D objects, detailed passenger terminal interior, animated passengers inside the airport and in the vicinity, true-to-life logistic parks and delivery centers, and more. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍  It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for $16.99, requiring at least 5 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oamvou</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Major Volanta Update</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oamvou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6388b90d207f340d2482fed9_vo2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="958100"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently made a forum post teasing some of the features of the upcoming Volanta 1.4 update, which includes a mobile app, a new - and updated - flight schedule source, and a stream overlay. There is no information regarding a release date yet, but it is said to be coming soon. The mobile app will allow premium users to track their flights remotely with statistics, route map, and the possibility to remotely pause the flight (P3D, X-Plane and FSX only). It acts as an extension of the Desktop application, and easening tasks such as taxiing, thanks to taxiway labels and gate information, specially for users with just one monitor.  It’s going to be available on the App Store and Google Play once 1.4 is out.   The new flight schedule source is FlightAware, increasing the quality and quantity of the data available, with reliability on the flight number, aircraft type, etc.  The stream overlay will provide a dynamically updated and customizable overlay for streamers, with information such as callsign, departure, arrival, ETA, ground speed and vertical speed.   The Discord Rich Presence is also getting a revamp, with more information shown, such as simulator in use, aircraft type, and a button that takes you straight to the flight on Volanta’s website. ‍  The built-in roster system, introduced on Volanta 1.2, has been improved, allowing users to schedule flights outside the real-world scheduling system, making it possible to plan out your entire daily schedule or maybe that long sought after world tour. They conclude the announcement with the information that there is more to come, currently being worked on.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssrji</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Juneau International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssrji" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6388ea7ba249e65c71d473c8_pajn1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1159915"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Northern Sky Studio has recently released their rendition of Juneau International Airport (PAJN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving a city with no direct road access to the outside world, making it extremely important for the townsfolk to get around. It’s a regional hub for all air travel, ranging from tiny carriers to big players such as Alaska Airlines. According to 2020 statistics, the yearly average is around 300,000 passengers. Alaska Airlines comprehends 87% of the yearly traffic figures, transporting people to six destinations (Anchorage, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Seattle-Tacoma, Sitka, and Yakutat). The other 13% are shared between minor regional airlines such as Alaska Seaplanes and Harris Air. The scenery features a detailed replica of the airport, with custom surroundings, PBR materials, shading and occlusion on all buildings, high-resolution textures, native gITF models, and custom ortophoto for the airport and surrounding areas. It’s available on SimMarket and OrbxDirect for roughly $17.95 and $18.11, respectively. At least 5.47 GB of free disk space is required to install the product.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdlmps</id>
    <title>TFDi Design Launches MD-11 Pre-Sale</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdlmps" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6388eef3cb3c453cdfc5029b_tfdi3.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="984334"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TFDi Design has recently announced the launch of a Collector’s Edition of their MD-11, with a limited run of 1000 copies priced at $80 each, granting early access to the aircraft once the beta is out, an extended range variant, and a special certificate for all the early customers. The complete feature list of the limited edition follows down below:  The developers plan to release the aircraft to the public in September 2023, with early supporters able to fly it earlier and provide direct feedback to the developers. They have also made a statement on the pricing plan for the product, with the base edition coming at $70 (passenger or freighter), $10 extra to have both variants, and $5 for the extended simulation package. The Collector’s Edition includes everything for $5 less.  The pre-order is available on their website for $80. There’s no information on system requirements as of now. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrcivf</id>
    <title>LuchoDev Releases Chacalluta International V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrcivf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6389011d96601a72c16e2352_arica1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="716909"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LuchoDev has just released the second version of their Chacalluta International Airport (SCAR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Arica in Chile. It’s visited by over 200,000 passengers yearly (according to Cointer), served by JetSmart, LATAM Chile, and Sky Airline, all domestically.  The scenery aims to represent the airport as it’s going to look after the current remodeling finishes, featuring an accurate representation of the upcoming terminal, a fire station, the control tower, and the DGAC sector buildings. Version 2 improves the terminal redesign while adding new areas, building upgrades on the DGAC sector, custom jetways, improved runway lights, PBR textures, more buildings, and several bug fixes.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.53, requiring at least 323 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gsrvim</id>
    <title>Gaya Simulations Releases Vienna International v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gsrvim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a286685446b76caa9111e_vie1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2043471"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Gaya Simulations has recently released the second version of their Vienna International Airport (LOWW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, overhauling the airport based on customer feedback, and adding custom ground service equipment.   VIE is the largest and busiest Austrian airport, with over 30 million passengers in 2019. It’s home to Austrian Airlines, with 48% of the annual figures (as of 2021), with many intra-european and intercontinental routes. Ryanair and WizzAir take another significant chunk, with 18% and 8%, respectively, and a wide network of intra-european routes to minor and major airports.   The updated scenery features the aforementioned overhaul, custom GSE, new true-to-life jetways, improved object placement across the airport, fixed AFCAD for AI traffic, fixed taxiway lights, static AI removal, better optimization, and more. The complete changelog/feature list follows down below:  • New true-to-life jetways models for all terminals with all new billboards and advertising. • New Gaya GSE: beautiful and fully custom Vienna-specific ground service equipment. • Overhauled object placement throughout the airport, improving visuals and accuracy. • Fixed AI traffic (FSLTL). • Fixed AFCAD for AI traffic. • Fixed taxiway lights, including the addition of orange and blue lights in the W area. • Static AI removed. • Fixed TIN/Imagery bug from World Update 6. • Added Solar Farm south of RWY11/29 • Added LODs to all objects. • Optimized normal map sizes for Xbox compatibility. • Fixed missing parking positions and improved spawn positions. • Fixed vegetation to fit new satellite imagery. • Fixed some terraforming issues. • Many quality of life fixes, such as fence placement, jetblast fences, taxi signs, etc. • Supporting an on release community-made GSX profile  The V2 upgrade is a free update to previous owners on Orbx Direct, with the Marketplace and Xbox version to release soon. It’s available on Orbx for $15.14 (48 hour v2 sale. Original price is roughly $21.65). At least 4.82 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fstefm</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Teases Embraer 175 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fstefm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a30c5c78b99b09e1b8d42_aviationlads01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1117508"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG has just released a teaser video in partnership with AviationLads teasing their upcoming Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a regional jet used by many airlines around the globe. There is no information other than external shots showcasing different liveries, model details, and sounds.   The video producer, AviationLads, made a post on Facebook indicating more content down the line (further showcasing the product), which is still in development.   The Embraer 175 is one of the four variants of the Embraer E-Jets, seating from 78 to 88 passengers in different class configurations, and with a range of 3334 kilometers on the standard variant (1800 nautical miles). It’s operated by 12 airlines around the World, with SkyWest being the largest operator (193 aircraft). Republic Airways is the second with 163, and Envoy Air takes the third place with 98.   There’s no information regarding pricing, release date, or system depth yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for further updates on the E175 and more! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drabim</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Austin-Bergstrom International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drabim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a3703e1c2984fff723fe0_kaus1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1582742"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam has just released their rendition of Austin-Bergstrom International (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Greater Austin metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16 million passengers. Built on what remained of what once used to be the Bergstrom Air Force Base, it is now the third busiest airport in Texas, with over 76 destinations (domestic and international) and approximately 510 arrivals and departures on a typical weekday as of 2018.  It is an important airport for Southwest Airlines, which takes 34% of the market share as of 2021, followed by American Airlines and Delta, with 22% and 13%, respectively. Destination-wise, Los Angeles is the most popular, with 543000 passengers. Dallas and Atlanta are second and third, with 530000 and 513000, respectively.   The scenery features PBR textures, dynamic lighting, true-to-life ground markings, custom hand-crafted pavement with imperfections and dirt, custom jetways, custom animated objects, passengers, and airport buses.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.85, requiring at least 870 MB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
