<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-06-23T18:23:52.861876+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdtur</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases Turweston Aerodrome for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdtur"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667499afab799ba0188b15c6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Burning Blue Design has recently released its newest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This time, it’s Turweston Aerodrome (EGBT). This aerodrome is situated in Turweston, Buckinghamshire, and serves as both a business park and the headquarters of the Light Aircraft Association (LAA). Turweston Aerodrome opened in 1942 as RAF Turweston. Over the years, it served as a training base for various squadrons within the Royal Air Force Bomber Command. After the end of World War II, the aerodrome was used for agricultural purposes before becoming a hub for general aviation. Today, the aerodrome is home to several entities including flight schools. It is also closely located to the racing track Silverstone, making it a convenient hub for events at the race track. Turweston Aerodrome boasts numerous features, including custom 3D objects, PBR textures, a hangar interior, animated hangar doors, a working fuel truck, a dynamic fountain, dynamic spectators and vehicles, custom terraforming, night lighting, and more. Turweston Aerodrome is now available on Burning Blue Design for roughly $16.39. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsct1</id>
    <title>Moza Teases Flight Sim Controls</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsct1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66751a5df0f6e0677a7c03ed_FB_IMG_1718950050245.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Sim racing hardware powerhouse Moza Racing is expected to announce their entry into the world of flight simulation. The UK based company are mainly known for their wheel bases and pedal sets teased the announcement on their facebook page saying “something revolutionary is coming soon. A game-changer is taking flight at the FlightSimExpo(sic). Stay tuned for more!” Accompanying the post is a picture that looks to depict a flight stick and base, a throttle system, and rudder pedals. ‍ Threshold’s own Drew Webb will be in attendance to bring you further updates on this story!Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for the flight simulation news that matters to you!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/330621</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes New A330 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/330621"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675cfa9c0ad8f263b81ce83_aerosoftmeme1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently published a new development update on their upcoming Airbus A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with a brief status update on how the ordeal is progressing on models, systems, sounds, etc. ‍ Before even getting into how the project is progressing, they explained their change of direction from an initial seemingly straightforward port of their Prepar3d version, which eventually evolved into something that aimed to fully take advantage of the new platform, along with more engine options and the like. ‍ The 3D model is complete on all engine variants, and the general systems are also nearly ready, with only the Neo RRs still being at 80%. On the other hand, the autopilot is still at 30% on every variant and sounds still need work.  ‍ There are no significant changes to their schedule. They plan to release a Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version with a free upgrade to 2024 later.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p4232i</id>
    <title>Parallel42 Releases A320 Immersion Pack</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p4232i"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675d57e32c0d8d674d99f80_k2gKOp67iLg-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 (//42) has just released A320 Immersion package for MSFS. This addon is the first addon from the Immersion series for MSFS, after 16 packs for various aircraft for FSX and P3Dv2-5. The Immersion packs aim to upgrade already existing simulator effects and add new effects to improve the user experience. The A320 Immersion is an All-in-One A320 visual effect package that is compatible with the most used renditions of the A320 family: Fenix, FlyByWire, IniBuilds and LatinVFR A320 series. This package will include 17 effects that are designed to enhance the overall experience, some of those effects are wing vortices and condensation, skid marks, engine condensation, contrails, St. Elmo’s fire, APU and engine heat blur, hot brakes smoke, rain on wheels, and many more. For the immersion package to work, SimFX is required. As of the publishing of the article, this add-on is available for purchase only at the Parallel 42 store for $15.00 and is expected to be available on OrbxDirect, PC and Xbox Marketplace, and Contrail Store. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozab9</id>
    <title>MOZA Unveils Flight Simulation Gear at FSExpo 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozab9"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675d8e84e14f9d2c66a201e_Screenshot%202024-06-21%20164559.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. MOZA, known for their state-of-the-art direct-drive steering wheels, has recently entered the flight sim world by announcing a flight stick, force-feedback base, throttle, and rudder, aiming to bring flight simulation to a new dimension. The AB9 Base will feature 9 Nm high torque dual servo motors, providing strong and direct force feedback, enhanced by a force feedback algorithm that aims to accurately replicate the feel of a real airplane, configurable via their own Cockpit Control Software. Its complete feature list follows below: The MH16 Joystick aims to replicate the controls of real fighter jets. Its aluminum alloy construction warrants sturdiness and reliability, and it has detachable modular components for maximum customizability. It also has 27 entirely customizable input signals and is universally compatible with third-party bases. The MTP Throttle Panel and MTLP Landing and Takeoff Panel aim to replicate fighter aircraft controls with extended throttle travel, customizable detents, and thirty-five physical switches. They feature infinitely adjustable resistance, real-time airspeed feedback via a vibration module, and high-precision angle sensors.  The MRP Rudder Pedals are adaptable to various aircraft types, from fighter jets to helicopters, offering maximum flexibility.  Pricing information has yet to be made available, but Threshold will keep you posted! Please refer to their website for further info. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkbb75</id>
    <title>MK Studios Previews Bluebird 757</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkbb75"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675dfbcd65102094d5917e6_448548242_875730297908592_2952996330623077927_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer MK Studios has shared some preview images of the upcoming BlueBird 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The post comes ahead of BlueBird’s presentation at Flight Sim Expo where they’re expected to show the aircraft in more detail.  The post has a selection of screenshots featuring the 757 wearing the iconic Iceland Air Hekla Aurora livery with the aircraft on the ground at MK Studio’s rendition of Keflavik Airport (BIKF). Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for all your breaking flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcodrd</id>
    <title>X-Codr Releases Denver Intl' Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcodrd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675dc95f87ff38000a3faff_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. X-Codr has recently released their rendition of Denver International Airport for MSFS. This airport, also known as DIA, serves the Denver metropolitan area and Front Range Urban corridor. With over 75,000,000 passenger operations and more than 660,000 aircraft operations per year, DIA is the third busiest airport in the USA and the sixth busiest in the world. After 6 years of construction, DIA was finally open for public use in 1996 and replaced the older Denver Stapleton Airport. The first flight to land at the new airport was United 1474 from Colorado Springs, while the first flight to depart was United 1062, to Kansas City. Originally, the airport had 5 runways: 7/25, 8/26, 16L/34R, 17L/35R, and 17R/35L, and all of them were of the same length: 12,0000ft. This changed in 2003 when 16R/34L was built to accommodate fully loaded A380s and B747s in hot and high conditions. With its length of 16,000ft, only 6 other runways in the world are longer. DIA consists of a single terminal named The Jeppesen Terminal and consists of three concourses: Concourse A - used by Delta Air Lines, Frontier, JetBlue and United Airlines, Concourse B - used by United Airlines and Concourse C - primarily used by Southwest Airlines, as well as American Airlines and regional airlines. More than 30 airlines fly to over 100 destinations across 4 continents from Denver, as well as 7 cargo airlines to 34 destinations, mostly in the USA. X-Codr’s rendition of Denver International Airport features Highly detailed models and high-resolution textures, Custom models for all airport buildings, modelled terminal interiors, custom jetways textures, high-quality ground textures, blended orthoimagery, custom animated runway guard and wig-wag lights, accurate airport data, ​up-to-date airport layout, and performance optimisation. ‍ This scenery is available for purchase on OrbxDirect for roughly $22.15 and will require at least 8.50GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flightsim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flaming-cliffs-2024-update-announced</id>
    <title>Flaming Cliffs 2024 Update Announced</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flaming-cliffs-2024-update-announced"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675e7885a530c356d73ec35_FC4_Eshop_cover_700x1000.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has recently previewed an update to the Flaming Cliffs franchise.  Flaming Cliffs is a pack of less-detailed aircraft made for players who prefer a straightforward experience, without complex systems. Some of the well-known FC aircraft are MiG-29, A-10A, and Su-27. The FC2024 update will include three planes: F-5E, F-86F and MiG-15bis.  F-5E is an exceptionally capable aircraft for air combat and unguided ground strikes. Equipped with “Sidewinders” and cannons for dogfights, the F-5E also has a BVR (beyond visual range) radar. F-86F was one of the best fighter jets during the Korean War.  Armed with 50-calibre machine guns for dogfighting and early infrared-guided air-to-air missiles. Aside from Air-to-Air, F-86F can also be equipped with unguided bombs and rockets for air-to-ground attacks. MiG-15bis was also one of the most revolutionary fighters, also one of the best fighters in the Korean War. It was unrivalled and would outmatch every aircraft in a dogfight until the F-86F Sabre came. Small and light plane, but a tough fighter. Its armament included two 23mm guns and a 37mm cannon. Existing Flaming Cliffs 3 owners can upgrade to the new update for $9.99 until the end of July when the upgrade fee will increase to $14.99. F-5E, F-86F and MiG-15bis can also be individually purchased for $14.99 each.  The exact release date is unknown, however, we know for a fact that it will come with the new DCS update. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news! ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbfsep</id>
    <title>Bluebird Simulations Shows off 757 and More </title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbfsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675f026ae53391c81d96d3e_image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Sim Expo 2024 opened with a huge announcement from the team at Bluebird Simulations who are behind the long-anticipated 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The presentation opened with a preview video showing off the aircraft both on the ground and in flight. Shervin from the Bluebird team then moved into a slideshow detailing both the 757 and 767, we’ve summarized the slides below Goal:  ‍ Focus: ‍ 767 Update: Following the 757 and 767 updates, Shervin proceeded to surprise the audience with a surprise announcement of an upcoming 787. The 787 has reportedly been in production since November of 2023. There’s currently no release date planned for the 787 but we will stay updated on these developments</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fscfse</id>
    <title>FliteSim.com Reveals New Products at FSExpo 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fscfse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675fe0699f26947dba0028c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FliteSim.com recently unveiled several new products during its presentation at this year's FSExpo in Las Vegas. After sharing fun facts about their current Force Feedback Yokes and Flight Consoles, they announced a total of four new projects. The first product to be unveiled is a G1000 Console. The new console will feature authentic buttons and knobs and has been developed from an FTD Level 5 Device. It is scheduled to be available in Q4 2024. After the G1000 Console was announced, the team proceeded to announce a new Boeing-style 737-800NG Yoke Handle. This new yoke, designed to pair with their current CLS-60/120 Yoke, will be a premium offering and will be available in Q4 2024. Furthermore, a new Force Feedback Stick Base has been unveiled. It will feature a dual motor with 15 Nm of peak force and will be available in Q4 2024 alongside the other announced products. Finally, to complete the new product lineup, the team is introducing Force Feedback Rudder Pedals. These pedals will be equipped with a single motor, providing a peak force of over 250 N. They are expected to be available in Q4 2024. To summarize, FliteSim.com announced at FSExpo 2024 that they will be releasing four new products in Q4 2024. These new products include a G1000 Console, a Boeing-Style 737-800NG Yoke Handle, a Force Feedback Stick Base, and a Force Feedback Rudder. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkskef</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Keflavik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkskef"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6676fdd9d54da70643bee8d7_FlightSimulator2024-06-1913-38-36_4472x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just released their rendition of Keflavik International Airport for MSFS. Serving the Greater Reykjavik Area, Keflavik International Airport has more than 7,500,000 passenger operations and more than 75,000 aircraft movements yearly. Built by the United States Military during WWII, the airport served as a replacement for British airfields in the northern part of Iceland. It consisted of two separate runways built 4km apart. After the war, the Meeks Field was renamed to Naval Air Station Keflavik, and in 1951, the US military returned to the airport. After the military air base in Keflavik was reestablished, passengers had to pass several military checkpoints before boarding the aircraft until 1987, when the separate civilian terminal was built. Two 10,000ft (3,000m) long runways are 200ft (60m) wide, which is enough to accommodate AN-225 and even a NASA Space Shuttle. This airport is also an important alternative in case of emergency during trans-Atlantic flights. Despite the low population of Iceland, it is a popular destination among travellers from both Europe and North America. Keflavik International Airport is a hub of two airlines: Icelandair - the flag carrier of Iceland, and PLAY - a low-cost airline. It also serves 25 airlines that fly to more than 80 destinations in the USA and Europe, as well as more than 35 seasonal destinations, mostly in Europe. Aside from passenger airlines, Icelandair Cargo flies to Boston, Liege and Los Angeles from Keflavik. MK Studios rendition of the airport features a detailed rendition of Keflavik Airport (BIKF) and Reykjavik Airport (BIRK), the up-to-date layout of the airport, custom jetways and vehicle models, modelled terminal interior, custom runway and taxiway lights and custom taxiway markings. This scenery is available for purchase on the IniBuilds store for roughly $18.98, but for the first 7 days after release, there will be a 5% discount ($18.08). It will also require at least 1.93GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcexan</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Provides Update on Management, Charlie Pedals</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcexan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667735d349b77bf0627bd420_IMG_6781.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a press release provided to Threshold, Nicki Repenning of Honeycomb Aeronautical provides an update on the progress of the Charlie Rudder Pedals, management of Honeycomb, and RMA units for those who have returned their products.  Starting off with the replacement units, Mr. Repenning says that over the past few months, he’s “been trying to find a solution to replace approximately 110 faulty units that were sent out to customers and have been returned,” but has run into issues due to his former business partner, Mike Steup of Snakebyte-group, not replacing customer’s faulty units. As an alternative, Repenning says that he has been able to obtain replacement products that he will start shipping out to customers July 15th, and he plans to have them all shipped by the end of July. As for the Charlie pedal pre-orders, both Mr. Reppening and his former business partner at Snakebyte have started production of the pedals at different factories. According to Snakebyte, they will start shipping to customers on June 24th, but customers are still waiting for confirmation on the shipping. If that does not pan out, Reppening says, pre-order customers will get an email with an “alternative solution.” Furthermore, Mr. Reppening addresses questions about the future of management at Honeycomb. Reppening explains, “After months of trying to find a new partner to buy out my former partner’s interest in Honeycomb, I realized that it wasn’t a task I was able to handle by myself,” and he has “engaged capable business and legal advisors who are helping me move forward.” He continues to say that both Snakebyte and Honeycomb are working towards a “ solution that doesn’t require litigation and they [Repenning’s advisors] have done an excellent job,” and that he believes that “we [Honeycomb] are in the home stretch and will come to an agreement soon on the terms by which I will regain ownership and management of the full Honeycomb business.” Reppening adds that he hopes to make an announcement on that situation soon, but is cautious and is “not counting my chickens yet.”Additionally, Mr. Reppening says that he is at FSExpo 2024 in Vegas, and he is open to questions, but he will be “doing an AMA in the coming weeks, so everyone else will have the chance to do the same.” Reppening reports that they “have the first production units ready to ship but will also bring ten units to FS Expo which I will personally hand deliver at the show.” As for the second run of production, that will “be ready at the end of July and will be made available for purchase once the factory has confirmed the shipping date to us.” Finally, Mr. Reppenning thanks the community for “the incredible support that I and my team have received,” and he says that they “have also read the comments from people who have been critical and have taken that to heart.” He ends off with a message to the community, saying that “The only thing we can do right now is to look ahead, learn from the past and stay optimistic about the future,” and that if customers have any question for him, they can email him at: AskNicki@HoneycombSim.com. As for his former business partner at Snakebyte-group, they have not followed up on any questions in a request for comment sent by Threshold.Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kpnsv2</id>
    <title>FSDesigns Releases Pensacola International Airport V2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kpnsv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6677d6cf3c8a793c880facc1_pns1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FS Designs recently released an upgraded rendition of Pensacola International Airport (KPNS) for X-Plane 12. It is the second-busiest airport in North Florida, with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. Pensacola got its first passenger terminal in 1935, with commercial service to begin two years later with Atlantic and Gulf Airlines, although very short-lived due to financial issues. National Airlines took over in 1938 with flights to Mobile and Jacksonville. World War 2 saw the airport become a US Navy training facility, granting it a new control tower and runway.  The terminal was expanded 12 years ago at $35 million, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and modernizing the infrastructure. There are talks of a new concourse and parking expansion to come shortly. American Airlines, American Express, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Silver Airways, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. Delta tops the market share chart with 26.04%, followed by Southwest and PSA Airlines with 21.63% and 10.87%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ortho imagery, high-quality 3D modeling, animated hangars, reworked textures, PBR texturing, custom 4K ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, up-to-date layout, and wear and tear effects using the latest technology. It’s available on their store for $14.99, requiring at least 1.61 GB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners are eligible for a 50% discount. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimclt</id>
    <title>Nimbus Releases Charlotte Douglas International for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimclt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6677dda02107f43bc3fc4397_clt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus recently released their rendition of Charlotte Douglas International Airport (KCLT) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves Charlotte, North Carolina, and has a yearly average of 53.4 million passengers, making it the sixth busiest in the country. It opened 85 years ago as Charlotte Municipal Airport, funded by Works Progress Administration funding. It was the largest WPA project at the time, featuring a terminal, three runways, a hangar, and a beacon tower. ‍ The USAF took control of the airport shortly after due to World War 2, establishing an Air Force Base. Over 5 million USD were invested between 1941 (when the takeover happened) and 1946 when it was handed back to the city. A 6,500 square meter terminal was built in 1954 to accommodate the ever-increasing passenger numbers. It had two floors, with passenger operations confined to the ground floor.  ‍ Major renovation work started in the late 1960s to keep up with the harsh demands of the jet age and become a major player in domestic traffic. This led to its eventual consolidation as a hub after the airline deregulation of 1978.  A new 30,200 square meter terminal was built by Piedmont Airlines in 1979 and inaugurated three years later.  ‍ In 1990, a 7,400-square-meter international concourse was built, followed by an expansion of the central terminal building.  A regional concourse was built in the early 2000s, adding a 32-gate concourse (Concourse E). ‍ Expansion work followed in 2015 with “CLT 2015”, a 2.5 billion USD investment to modernize and accommodate the envisioned passenger figures for the following decade and beyond.  The airport currently has 115 gates on five concourses, all connected to the central terminal building. It’s a hub for American Airlines and is also served by Air Canada Express, Contour Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Lufthansa, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and Volaris. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 3D interiors, PBR textures, dynamic lighting, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ It’s available on the X-Plane.org Store for roughly $26.95, requiring at least 2.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spkspg</id>
    <title>SPINOZA Releases Albert Whitted Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spkspg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66784bc34acbc624d331cc3d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SPINOZA has recently released their version of Albert Whitted Airport (KSPG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located in and serves the city of St. Petersburg, Florida, which is renowned as the birthplace of the first scheduled commercial airline flight. Situated in the Tampa Bay area, the airport features a total of two runways. Construction of Albert Whitted Airport began in 1928, and the airport officially opened in 1929. In 1934, National Airline initiated service to the airport, but this ceased after World War II when the airline shifted operations to St. Pete-Clearwater International Airport. Upon its opening in 1929, the Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company stationed one of its airships at Albert Whitted Airport, marking it as one of the first airports to serve as a base for their blimps. Over the years, a Coast Guard Air Station was also established at the airport. Today, the airport remains a popular choice for general aviation in the area. The recently released scenery package provides Microsoft Flight Simulator users with a variety of features for the Florida-located airport. The newly released Albert Whitted Airport is now available on SimMarket for approximately $18.34 and requires 487.25 MB of storage space. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pfeyka</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Releases Kaunas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pfeyka"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66785abedc30d84b47cba670_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Propair Flight recently released its version of Kaunas Airport (EYKA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the Lithuanian city of Kaunas, it is the second busiest civilian airport in the country after Vilnius Airport, catering to approximately 1.3 million passengers annually. Kaunas Airport opened for flights in 1988. Flights were transferred from the former S. Darius and S. Girėnas Airport to the new Kaunas Airport. It wasn't until 1991 that the airport became an international airport. This happened after Lithuania acquired its independence. Throughout the years, the airport has seen a variety of airlines flying to different destinations, along with improvements to the airport and its infrastructure. Today, the airport is a hub for Ryanair, but also serves airlines such as Wizz Air, Corendon Europe, Freebird Airlines, and SkyUp. These airlines offer flights to destinations such as London, Madrid, and Milan, and the airport handles around 1.3 million passengers yearly. The newly released Kaunas Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator comes with numerous features, providing users with plenty of content to explore. The add-on requires 1.88 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $14.76. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
