<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-08-12T18:28:10.493158+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carpvp</id>
    <title>CloudSurf Asia Releases Puerto Princesa International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carpvp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66adfb7c4f131c862f06e6ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CloudSurf Asia has recently released its version of Puerto Princesa International Airport (RPVP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the province of Palawan, Philippines, the airport serves the area of Puerto Princesa. The airport welcomes just over 1.1 million passengers annually. Built by American prisoners of war during the Second World War, the airport was under construction from 1942 to 1944. After completion, the airport was used by Japanese transport aircraft alongside a former grass airstrip located near today's NCCC Mall Palawan. After the liberation of Palawan in 1945, various units from the US Army Air Forces were stationed at the airport. It wasn't until 1947 that Puerto Princesa opened and started with air travel. Since then, the airport has seen a variety of airlines and aircraft, and has also undergone several expansions and improvements due to the increasing demand for air transportation. Today, the airport is an operating base for Air Juan and serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific, Philippine Airlines, and Philippines Air Asia, with nearly 9000 aircraft movements and around 1.1 million passengers yearly. The newly released Puerto Princesa International Airport for MSFS includes a variety of features such as up-to-date airport data, a fully modeled terminal with an interior, full custom objects around the airport, custom ground markings, full PBR textures, and more.  The add-on requires a total of 0.99 GB of storage space and is now available on Orbx, SimMarket, and iniBuilds for approximately $15.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dfkjac</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Releases Jackson Hole Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dfkjac"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66aff06032dddac583208ad5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Dreamflight has just released its version of Jackson Hole Airport (KJAC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the valley of Jackson Hole, located in the U.S. state of Wyoming, and welcomes just under 1 million passengers annually. The airport was constructed in the 1930s after it was determined that the chosen location would be the best place for an airport in Teton County. In 1943, the airport was designated as a national monument and in 1950 it was incorporated into the Grand Teton National Park. In 1959, the runway was extended to a length of 6,300 feet, which remains the same today. That year, Frontier Airlines became the first airline to operate at the airport. Between 2009 and 2014, the airport's terminal was completely rebuilt and received the American Institute of Architects Honor Award in 2014. Additional improvements were initiated in 2021 and 2022. Currently, the airport serves a variety of airlines such as Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, United Airlines, and more, which collectively facilitate the annual arrival of around 1 million passengers. The newly released Jackson Hole Airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator includes a range of features, such as an accurate representation of the airport, high-quality textures, detailed models, fully detailed interior, custom ground polynomials, realistic night lighting, PBR textures, GSX profile, and more. The entire scenery package requires 1.79 GB of storage space and can be purchased on Contrail for approximately $16.38. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/if73mmp</id>
    <title>iFly Provides More Previews of 737 MAX8 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/if73mmp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66afee6d904d4ddddea5ee05_453720661_906550331515825_3897020728462941253_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In their most recent post on the Flight One Software Facebook page, iFly provides more previews for their highly anticipated rendition of the Boeing 737 MAX8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  Following up on a preview video of the passenger cabin of the iFly 737 MAX, these photos share close-ups of various parts of the cockpit, such as the overhead, pedestal, and cockpit entryway. iFly states that these screenshots were taken during “[...] a departure from KDEN to KSFO at dusk.” Also showcased are shots of the cockpit lighting, large screens, and EFB, among others.  No release date has been announced yet by iFly, but Threshold will keep you informed whenever they do, so stay tuned for that and for more high quality news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksoah</id>
    <title>MK Studios Announces Naha Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksoah"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66aff1bc7ca272c5cc63e54f_naha1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently announced the development and imminent release of Naha Airport (ROAH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Okinawa Prefecture with a yearly average of 21.5 million passengers. The Imperial Japanese Army built the airport in 1933 as Oroku Aerodrome. The United States took it over in 1945, and it was renamed Naha Airport. Scheduled service started two years later with Pan American World Airways and Northwest Orient.  ‍ Refurbishment work began in the early 1950s, bringing the structure up to the standards of the time. ‍ In the early 1980s, the US military transferred control of the airport to the Japanese forces, which then developed the airport. The first major upgrade happened in the 1990s, with a main passenger terminal expansion.  ‍ Further development started in 2008 when the government agreed to expand the domestic terminal and construct a new parallel runway. The expansion required a new international terminal, which opened in 2014, and the construction of the new parallel runway started around that same year. The new international terminal was expanded again in 2016, gaining another 3000 square meters.  ‍ The new runway started operation in 2020 after nearly six years of construction. ‍ It’s a hub for Japan Transocean Air and Ryukyu Air Commuter and a focus city for All Nippon Airways, Japan Airlines, and Peach. Air China, Asiana Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, EVA Air, HK Express, Hong Kong Airlines, Jeju Air, Jetstar Asia, Juneyao Air, Korean Air, Spring Airlines, Starlux Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan also serve it. ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed terminal, various POIs, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom vehicle models, custom runway profile and elevation data, a high-quality terminal interior, custom taxiway labels, and more. There’s no information on pricing yet, but the scenery is set to release sometime next week.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukeghq</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Cornwall Airport Newquay for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukeghq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b0ef7456e31ac2b9724a47_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has just released its latest airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Cornwall Airport Newquay (EGHQ). Located in England, the airport serves the areas of Newquay and Cornwall. Annually, the airport welcomes just over 400,000 passengers. The airport opened in 1933 as a civilian airfield. When the Second World War broke out, the airport was renamed RAF Trebelzue, and it was used to support other bases in the Cornwall area. In 1943, the airfield was renamed RAF St Mawgan and was handed over to the USAAF. After being put under maintenance in 1947, the airport reopened in 1951 as a Coastal Command base. Since then, various aircraft squadrons have operated at the airport, but those operations have since ceased. From 2006, a series of changes and upgrades gradually transformed the airport into a fully civilian airport. In 2008, the airport was officially separated from RAF St Mawgan and rebranded as Cornwall Airport Newquay. Today, the airport serves various airlines such as easyJet, Loganair, and Ryanair, and it is also a hub for the airline Eastern Airways. These airlines, along with others, contribute to the airport's annual 400,000 passengers and just over 19,000 aircraft movements. The scenery offers a range of features, including detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, night effects, airport vehicles, vegetation, PBR materials, static aircraft, and more. The newly released Cornwall Airport Newquay is now available on SimMarket for approximately $16.46. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo111</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Updates San Francisco International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b155ffa00dd012a7b10e3f_sfo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ Flightbeam Studios has recently updated their newly released rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding the all-new high-speed taxiway Tango, new vehicles, and more. Their best-selling product to date has seen its first major update, bringing a series of improvements and additions, which include the new high-speed taxiway Tango, new rescue vehicles, improved runway textures and decals, improved tire markings, new flora, and tire marks on the runway, which were absent on 1.0 due to a blunder (it got swept underneath another layer). The complete changelog follows below: They have also teased what will be in the next update (1.2): custom taxiway lighting, with custom lights (LODded, directional, colored properly, and dynamically lit).  The airport is available on their shop for $19.99, requiring at least 2.57 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b727ms</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Releases Boeing 727-200F for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b727ms"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b1fa8571f28db988ba1a32_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio has just released its highly anticipated Boeing 727-200F add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The iconic three-engined cargo aircraft is now available for users to add to its fleet. The original variant of the Boeing 727 was launched in 1958. This new aircraft was developed after the Boeing 707 to meet the demand for short-haul flights. Initially designed as a passenger aircraft, a cargo version was introduced in 1981. The Boeing 727-200F was equipped with Pratt &amp; Whitney engines and had a windowless cabin with a freight door on the front main deck. Since the introduction of the cargo variant, the aircraft has played a significant role for various airlines in cargo operations worldwide. FlightSim Studio's rendition of the 727-200F includes a range of features. The aircraft features a detailed exterior with PBR textures, custom animations, 3D lighting, winglets, and custom liveries. The interior is also highly detailed, with a complete cockpit, custom night lighting, cargo cabin, animated cargo doors, and various cockpit interactions. The package comes with an Electronic Flight Bag, offering users a variety of options and tools. The flight dynamics have been designed by a real pilot to ensure the highest level of realism. There are a total of four navigation options available. Additionally, the aircraft includes comprehensive documentation to assist you in getting started. The newly released Boeing 727-200F requires 5 GB of storage space and is available at Aerosoft for about $42. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rttrec</id>
    <title>Rafael Tango Tango Releases Recife International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rttrec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b3d6bc466846538d5b95d9_rec1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rafael Tango Tango has recently released their rendition of Recife/Guararapes—Gilberto Freyre International Airport (SBRF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Recife in Pernambuco, Brazil, with a yearly average of 9 million passengers. It was built during World War 2 to replace an airfield at the same location. In the years following the conflict, it became a strategic technical and refueling stop on routes from South America to Europe. A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1958, and its two runways at the time were extended to accommodate larger aircraft. In the late 1970s, an agreement was reached with Infraero (a state-owned airport operator) to develop the airport further, which led to a renovation in 1982 and expansion work in the 1990s. A new passenger terminal, including a new shopping mall and a new concourse, was built in 2004, increasing its passenger handling capabilities from 1.5 million a year to 9 million. In late 2009, the government invested 8 million BRL into upgrading the terminal for the 2014 World Cup, adding eight more jetways and modernizing the infrastructure. It’s a hub for Azul Linhas Aéreas and is served by Gol Linhas Aéreas, LATAM Brasil, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, a custom 3D-modeled passenger terminal, custom jetways, custom autogen for the city, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $6.55, requiring at least 263.59 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vixivt</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Releases Vitória Airport &amp; City for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vixivt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a92332e38316851644db86_background07.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently released their rendition of Vitória —Eurico de Aguiar Salles International Airport (SBVT) and its surroundings for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Vitória in Espírito Santo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 3.2 million passengers. Originally built in the 1930s, it would not receive its first passenger terminal and paved runway until a decade later. Heavy renovation work, including a new passenger terminal and runway, was carried out in 2005. Although scheduled to be completed in 2007, several scandals led to a "temporary" halt for nearly a decade. Construction work only resumed in 2015 and concluded three years later, in 2018, sixteen years after the original planning.  A few years before the resumption of the expansion works, the airport's operator, Infraero, deemed it the country's worst airport. ‍Operated by Zurich Airports AG since 2019, the new airport finally meets international standards and swiftly leaves its dark past behind. Azul (Belo Horizonte, Campinas, Recife), Gol (Brasília, Porto Seguro, Rio de Janeiro, Salvador, São Paulo), Latam (Brasília, Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo), and Voepass (Porto Seguro) serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a highly detailed terminal, city POIs, custom ground clutter, custom ambient sounds, custom terraforming, and more. It's available in the MSFS Marketplace for roughly $8.99 (on sale for $6.49).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksoki</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Naha Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksoki"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b50b06bde4b5d5c16321ff_roah1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios recently released their rendition of Naha Airport (ROAH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Okinawa Prefecture and has a yearly average of 21. 5 million passengers. The Imperial Japanese Army built the airport in 1933 as Oroku Aerodrome. The United States took it over in 1945 and renamed it Naha Airport. Scheduled service started two years later with Pan American World Airways and Northwest Orient.  Refurbishment work began in the early 1950s, bringing the structure up to the standards of the time. In the early 1980s, the US military transferred control of the airport to Japanese forces, which then developed it. The first major upgrade happened in the 1990s, with a main passenger terminal expansion.  Further development started in 2008 when the government agreed to expand the domestic terminal and construct a new parallel runway. The expansion required a new international terminal, which opened in 2014, and the construction of the new parallel runway started around that same year. The new international terminal was expanded again in 2016, gaining another 3000 square meters.  The new runway started operation in 2020 after nearly six years of construction. It’s a hub for Japan Transocean Air and Ryukyu Air Commuter and a focus city for All Nippon Airways, Japan Airlines, and Peach. Air China, Asiana Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, EVA Air, HK Express, Hong Kong Airlines, Jeju Air, Jetstar Asia, Juneyao Air, Korean Air, Spring Airlines, Starlux Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed terminal, various POIs, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom vehicle models, custom runway profile and elevation data, a high-quality terminal interior, custom taxiway labels, and more. It’s available on Contrail and OrbxDirect for roughly $17.50, requiring at least 2.39 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777737</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b513e7ef7b99bf0023a0d0_77f.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published a new development update concerning their upcoming Boeing 77F, further updates for their 737 lineup, the 77W's arrival in the Marketplace, and more.  Their newly released 777-300ER will be available in the MSFS Marketplace later today, albeit without any purchasable livery packs, which are scheduled to come later today or next week. The 737 Lineup will soon receive another update, which will be pushed for their testers soon and bring extra WASM freeze fixes inherited from the 777 development stream. It's supposed to be made public around the third week of August. ‍ With their upcoming 77F going into testing, they anticipate moving the new features into the 737 lineup for testing (new navdata, etc). As mentioned in a previous development update, those will be rolled out gradually. ‍ Upon completion of the backporting, their 737 will leave the "early adopter" phase, and the pricing will be adjusted accordingly. As of yesterday, PMDG turned 27 years old, and they will run a three-day celebratory sale through Friday, Saturday, and Sunday, with 27% off on any of their products (except for the 777-300ER).  Robert finishes the development update with information on their 77F, which is being prepared for beta testing. "We packed this new airplane full of features to bring you a feature-rich simulation experience for one of the world's most capable freight haulers!" he added, followed by hinting at a new project that "you don't know anything about" hidden somewhere in the update. The PMDG product lineup for MSFS is available at PMDG.com, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdghe</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Marsa Alam International Airport</title>
    <updated>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdghe"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b662d3e4e675a224c75689_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released its version of Marsa Alam International Airport (HEMA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located 34 nautical miles from the Egyptian town of Marsa Alam, the airport plays an important role in welcoming tourists from Europe. Annually, the airport serves just over 1.5 million passengers. The airport opened on October 16, 2003, initially named Marsa Mubarak Airport. Construction began in March 1999 and was completed four years later. It was built to serve the south of the Red Sea and its coastal region, with an initial capacity of 600 passengers per hour. In 2011, it was renamed Marsa Alam International Airport, a name it retains today. The airport now serves a variety of airlines and destinations, including Air Cairo, Neos, Smartwings, and more, offering flights to destinations such as Cairo, Rome, and Warsaw. The new version of Marsa Alam International Airport includes updated features like an accurate rendition of the airport, updated ground layout, dynamic lighting, reflective textures, and more. The new scenery is now available from FSDG for approximately $16.37. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a162</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a162"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b6a667d03737a221cfd962_comanche.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently issued a micro-update to their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding an accurate weight option for users wishing to fly with animal companions.  ‍ Update 1.6.2 also fixes the to/from flags in GPS OBS mode, a small area of protruding mesh when the stabilator tips are fitted, and updates the tail number font logic for their new livery pack (available in the Marketplace). The complete changelog follows below: The Accu-Sim Comanche 250 is available in their store for $49.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kolaud</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates DCS Kola Map</title>
    <updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kolaud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b74a3d1764368d8b095c2c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Orbx has recently released a new update for its DCS add-on, Kola Map. The update includes a variety of new features and several improvements. It adds three new airfields and reduces the total size of the installed map by about 12 GB. The new update introduces three new airfields: Kirkenes (ENKR), Kallax (ESPA), and Vidsel (ESPE). Additionally, cities, towns, and infrastructure have been added around the new airfields. In addition to the new features, several fixes and updates have been implemented. Some noteworthy fixes include adjustments and revisions to the ILS at Bodo airfield (ENBO), improved ground imagery at new airfields, and a reduction of the installed map size by approximately 12 GB. The updated add-on is presently available on Orbx for $55.91 during early access and will increase to $69.99 upon full release. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/adta3v</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Posts First "Discover the Aerosoft A330" Video</title>
    <updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/adta3v"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b76fd99e2499b6330c941e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has released a new video showcasing its upcoming Airbus A330 CEO and NEO products. This video is the first in a series called "Discover the Aerosoft A330". In this video, the team focuses on the 3D model of the aircraft. The video previewed the exterior of various upcoming aircraft variants. According to the video, the different variants being made are the A330-302 (GE), A330-323 (PW), A330-343 (RR), and the A330-941 (NEO). There was also a quick glimpse inside the cockpit. The video created by AviationLads does not provide any information about a release date or potential price. However, we will keep you updated as more information becomes available.‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hase</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Aspen/Pitkin County Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hase"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ba15f1130f595c749b78c3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has just released its version of Aspen/Pitkin County Airport (KASE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The US airport serves the city of Aspen, Colorado and has an annual average of just over 625.000 passengers. In 1946, a private gravel airstrip was opened at the current location of the airport. The airstrip was open to the public. In 1956, the pavement of the runway began, and it has been expanded a total of four times since, with the latest expansion occurring in 2011. The airport is served by the following airlines: American Eagle, Delta Connection, and United Express. These three airlines offer flights to various destinations, including Chicago, Los Angeles, and San Francisco. The scenery includes various features such as an accurate representation of the airport, hand-made ground textures, dynamic airport lighting, highly detailed models, and more. Aspen/Pitkin County Airport is now available on Orbx for $7.91 and takes up around 1.77 GB of space on disk. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
