<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-03-15T18:29:12.554096+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nv2024</id>
    <title>Navigraph Launches Community Survey 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nv2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cb46b8f96abf8d6d17e6cc_survey2024.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has just launched the seventh edition of their FlightSim Community Survey. The Survey asks various questions about preferred platforms, add-ons, use cases, preferences, etc. It provides great insight into the modern flight sim demographic, thus making it easier for the industry to understand what the simmers really want. Unusually, the Survey was delayed until early 2025 so Navigraph could more comprehensively and accurately capture the community's sentiment due to the large number of major releases near the end of last year. Averaging more than 20,000 respondents since the 2020 edition, the Survey has become the go-to reference for hardware metrics, given it differs massively compared to mainstream reference data such as the Steam Hardware Survey, which takes their entire user base into account. Focusing exclusively on flight simmers, it provides a more accurate image of the most popular hardware among virtual pilots.  It also sheds light on the most popular flight sim platform, intent (whether simulating just for fun or training for a pilot's license), simulation proficiency, and how many of us are real-life pilots.  The Survey will run for ten days starting today (March 7), and the results will be published shortly after. It is entirely GDPR compliant and fully anonymous, with no personally identifiable data being collected and no redirects.  Click here to participate in the world's most comprehensive flight simulation survey! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhr024</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases London Heathrow Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhr024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cb4ee60b8603e71fc9b1f5_innit1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently released the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 Edition of their London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) rendition, which features a complete rebuild designed for maximum detail and performance. London Heathrow is the eighth-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprising international travel and the remaining 6% strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom landside, custom night lighting, a walkable terminal 5A interior, high-quality terminals, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, and more. It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $28.30, and owners of the 2020 version can upgrade for $12.90.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350102</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350102"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bf1797199e80fda0eaa13a_fitty1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing further WASM stability, bug fixes, and two new features. Marked by a controversial launch—with a creator even asking for a refund—update v1.0.2 aims to get their ultimate airliner experience back on track with enhanced WASM stability, a substantial amount of bug fixes, and two new features: the A350 MORA (Minimum Off-Route Altitude) implementation and the Secondary Navigation Display, which provides backup navigation should the primary flight management system be unavailable or degraded. They have also made a note on the many community mods that supposedly improve the A350’s flight model: “Comments and updates from the community regarding flight model cfgs are mostly irrelevant, or a placebo effect, as they have little to no effect on how the aircraft performs in sim. We have tuned the plane to fly as closely to real life with the support of our technical working group and A350 pilots team”, concluded iniBuilds, while also addressing one of the mod files and their direct impact – or lack thereof – on the flight model: Mod File Feature List: ‍ Major Flight Stability Increases (aircraft should feel much heavier on the controls, will be improved on) iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Corrected Reference Speeds (Overspeed Limits increased, set to real values) Overspeed and Cruise Mach iniBuilds: Fixed in v1.01    Reduced Thrust Multiplier (lower overall thrust output). iniBuilds: Only effects total thrust. Reducing it as indicated will have a negative/unrealistic impact on SRS   Increased Ground Friction (initial roll requires thrust increase) iniBuilds: Unrealistic modification as this was tuned as per IRL references and pilot feedback.    Reduced Elevator Trim Speed (slightly) iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Slower Spoiler-on Deploy timing (mostly in-flight, the spoilers seem unaffected) iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.  Can be adjusted slightly in cfg’s but this is not realistic.    Custom Flight Dynamics Overhaul. iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Improved Flare and Rotation Behavior (looking into this). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Slower Spoiler Deployment (looking into this, may not be needed after V1.0.1). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Improved Fuel Flow Scalar (looking into this). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Improved Climb-Lift Ratios. iniBuilds: Unrealistic modification as this was tuned as per IRL references and pilot feedback.   Brake Changes (higher priority, looking into this also). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.  ‍ The complete changelog for the update is available here.  The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cpl143</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes Launch Details for ChasePlane</title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cpl143"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cf2f51feebfd0936b69459_chaseplane2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently published another blog post providing further details on their upcoming physics-based camera add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, including its full price, release date, and new pre-release content. For the unaware, ChasePlane is a highly versatile physics-based camera system that allows you to quickly create and share custom views for any airplane. It gives you seamless control over views, be it from within the flight deck, cabin, wing, or even landing gear bay, if you so fancy. ‍ The user feedback on their many pre-launch videos allowed Parallel 42 to take extra time to fine-tune the experience, polish features, and refine the onboarding process for newcomers.  ‍ As far as platform compatibility goes, ChasePlane will debut on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 first, but a 2024 version is in the works. Eventually, it will be made available for free for all ChasePlane 2020 owners for a limited time period after release. ‍ The add-on will be available to Club 42 members on Friday (14/03) at 11:42 CST for $30 (including cloud backups and community). The limited rollout will allow the developers to stress test the community features and backup infrastructure, ensuring everything works well enough before opening the floodgates. ‍ If you are wondering what “Club 42” is and how to become a member, it is Parallel 42’s way of giving something back to its supporters, providing them with early access to products, permanent discounts, exclusive sales, and personalized recommendations. Click here for further information. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simwee</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Weeze Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simwee"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cf36e162e29a7edc64ebe1_weeze1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimPixel has recently released their rendition of Weeze Airport (EDLV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Kreis Kleve (Germany) and Nijmegen (Netherlands) with a yearly average of a million passengers. It was built on top of a preexisting military facility (RAF Laarbruch) and started operating as a civilian airport in 2003. The airport’s name was supposed to be after the city of Düsseldorf, but it was ruled out due to the distance (83 km) and the fact Düsseldorf already had two international airports in close proximity (Düsseldorf Airport and Cologne-Bonn). The name idea was eventually ruled out by the court in 2016 due to the huge potential to mislead passengers. Ryanair still refers to it as Düsseldorf-Weeze, though. It’s an operating base for Ryanair, and Sky Express serves it seasonally. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, custom 3d models, dynamic night lighting, detailed interiors, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.02, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmsnuu</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Nuuk Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmsnuu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cf3dc1a1b70d124f258a84_nuuk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently released their rendition of Nuuk Airport (BGGH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Nuuk, Greenland, and has a yearly average of 69,324 passengers. The airport was built in 1979 when the government decided to create a network of STOL-capable domestic airports. It originally featured a 950-meter-long asphalt runway located 86 meters above sea level. The terminal and apron were built on a leveled platform on an undulating slope under a mountain.  After many years of expansion proposals, the administration decided to expand the runway to 2,200 meters, build a new terminal to accommodate the expected passenger traffic figures, and expand the apron and service buildings. Construction started in 2019 and reached partial completion in 2022. The new terminal was only inaugurated two years later, in 2024. The scenery accurately depicts the airport, including its new terminal, the 2,200-meter-long runway, handcrafted terrain elevation, detailed 3D terminal with a custom interior, animated objects, custom ground service equipment, up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.82, requiring at least 747.95 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/m24mar</id>
    <title>Microsoft Rolls Out Marketplace for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/m24mar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d07d293d738725a21c989f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Not long after the release of Sim Update 1, the team at Microsoft has launched the in-sim Marketplace for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This Marketplace has been highly anticipated by the community and is now accessible within the simulator. Many items from the Marketplace in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 have been ported to the new simulator. These items should be available in the library and need to be activated. However, content created by Microsoft and Asobo is automatically activated. The Marketplace offers a variety of options. Ported content from the 2020 version to 2024 is marked with a small logo indicating that it is ported. Content upgraded to the 2024 version may have a new price or be available as a free upgrade, and it is also indicated with a logo showing that it has been upgraded. Users can purchase content using Simverse Coins, which is an in-sim currency that can be bought either in the Marketplace or at select retailers. Currently, the Marketplace does not support rentals or gifting, but these features are expected to be introduced with Sim Update 2 in April. Additionally, there are a few known issues with the Marketplace. For the full release notes and details on these issues, please check the official release announcement. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfxix</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XIX for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfxix"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d081b40d6ccf1f34811fdc_xix1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft recently released a new World Update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which enhances half the landmass of South America with detailed coverage of Brazil, Guyana, Suriname, and French Guiana.  They partnered with Bing Maps, Maxar, and Vexcel to craft the update, which features sights ranging from vast dune fields to bustling metropolises. Fusing several types of recent geospatial data, including aerial photographs, satellite imagery, DEM (digital elevation model) data, and DTM (digital terrain model), they managed to concoct a very realistic rendition in real-time. It captures 75 Points of Interest in total, including Fort Diamant in French Guiana, Monte Roraima in Guyana and Brazil, and Brazil’s Christ the Redeemer statue in Rio de Janeiro. It also includes four TIN cities, all in Brazil: Brasilia, Ouro Preto, Rio de Janeiro, and Sao Paulo.  Gaya Simulations – one of their partners – crafted seven airports: Foz do Iguaçu International Airport (SBFI), Fernando de Noronha Airport (SBFN), Santos Dumont (SBRJ), and Santarem - Maestro Wilson Fonseca International Airport (SBSN); Guyana’s Kaieteur International Airport (SYKA), Suriname’s Zorg en Hoop Airport (SMZO), and French Guiana’s Saint-Laurent-du-Maroni Airport (SOOM). The update also includes three discovery flights, three landing challenges, and three bush trips.  New MSFS 2024-only content will be added on March 17th, including a helicopter landing challenge at Mirante Dona Marta (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil), a rally race through Rio in an F/A-18, and a low-altitude challenge in an L-39 through the Serra do Corvo Branco, a rugged mountain range in southern Brazil. The update is free for all Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 owners. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/halzhu</id>
    <title>HALUA6683 Releases Zhuhai Jinwan Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/halzhu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d08af596da9f2a04b8a36a_zhu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. HALUA6683 recently released their updated rendition of Zhuhai Jinwan Airport (ZGSD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves Zhuhai, Guangdong, China, and has a yearly average of 11.4 million passengers. Construction work started in December 1992, and it opened three years later in 1995. It went on to host China’s first International Aviation and Aerospace Exhibition in 1996, which it still does to this date. The airport was expanded in 2017 to accommodate the predicted passenger figures, gaining an expanded eastern corridor, two new floors on the terminal, and a western VIP lounge, totaling over 122,000 square meters of area. It’s a focus city for China Southern Airlines and served by Air China, Air Guilin, Chengdu Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China United Airlines, Donghai Airlines, Juneyao Air, Loong Air, Lucky Air, Shandong Airlines, Shanghai Airlines, Shenzhen Airlines, Sichuan Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tianjin Airlines, West Air, and Xiamen Air. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed replica of the terminals, custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, custom objects, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.22, requiring at least 304.37 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asoemb</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator and Embraer Announce Partnership</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asoemb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d0a325e2695cc0b421150b_embraer.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In conjunction with their newly released World Update XIX: Brazil, Suriname, Guyana, and French Guiana, the Microsoft Flight Simulator team is happy to announce a strategic partnership with Embraer, one of the largest aircraft manufacturers in the world. ‍ "We are thrilled to announce our partnership with Embraer, one of the global aerospace industry leaders," said Jorg Neumann, Microsoft Flight Simulator's lead developer. "Embraer's latest generation fleet and their innovation-driven focus make them a perfect partner for Microsoft Flight Simulator, and our objective is to bring many Embraer aircraft over to the simulator as part of our Expert Series. We are happy to announce that we are starting this collaboration with the widely popular Embraer Praetor 600, which will be released in MSFS sometime this year", he added. ‍ "We are thrilled to share the Praetor 600 with the Microsoft Flight Simulator community.  The most innovative executive jet from the Super Midsize category and the most technologically advanced in the world", said Embraer's Marketing Director, Felipe Alfaia, to which he added, "It's a pleasure to see our industry-leading jet landing on the most popular consumer flight simulator of the world near the end of 2025".  ‍ The Praetor 600 is a super-midsize jet with the biggest range in the world so far, being able to fly from London to New York or Sao Paulo to Miami. Aside from the superb range, it also brings full fly-by-wire, a highly advanced avionics suite, and an insane degree of connectivity, making it one of the most technologically advanced airplanes in its class. Its interior fully uses the cabin's dimensions, ensuring no space is wasted with six foldable seats, custom tiles, and a vacuum-operated lavatory system. ‍ Furthermore, the Praetor 600 also brings a turbulence reduction system, a highly silent cabin, a large cargo capacity for baggage, and a comprehensively sized wardrobe in the rear bathroom. ‍ There is no further information regarding pricing or features, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozale</id>
    <title>Moza Teases Launch Event for Flight Sim and Sim Racing Products </title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozale"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d0ab27e4875ca5bdeec471_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Moza has recently announced the launch of their next-generation lineup of products for both flight simulation and sim racing, scheduled for March 18th at 9 AM EDT. They emphasized that this is an event you won't want to miss. Originally known for their sim racing equipment, Moza has expanded into the flight simulation hardware market. They now offer a variety of products, including a force feedback base, which our very own Magnus had the chance to review last year. The announcement included an image that appears to depict an airliner alongside what looks like a Formula-style car. Moza has described this launch as a groundbreaking moment, and we are eager to see what they have in store. We will keep you updated as soon as we have more information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/meri25</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Announces Brand; Product Announcement</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/meri25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d1913052f024653fd52772_meridian%20banner.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The world of flight simulation hardware welcomes a significant new player today - Meridian GMT. At the helm is Nicki Repenning, a name long familiar to the simulation community through his former role as founder and public face of Honeycomb Aeronautical. While Repenning’s earlier work helped establish some of the most widely adopted peripherals in the sector, Meridian GMT is attempting a distinct break from the past - a clean-slate approach grounded in new principles, or rather, on their terms. Repenning played a central role in bringing to life the Honeycomb Alpha Flight Controls, Bravo Throttle Quadrant, and Charlie Rudder Pedals - devices that saw widespread acclaim for their feature set and accessibility. However, Honeycomb’s legacy is not without complications. Despite its disruptive design, price point, and popularity, the Bravo Throttle faced recurring quality concerns, such as cable issues and mechanical wear, which were highlighted in long-term user experiences. Furthermore, the very protracted delivery timeline for the Charlie Rudder Pedals and the outright conflict between Repenning and his former business partner Mike Steup from Snakebyte Group, a German product development company, over the ownership and direction of Honeycomb, left a permanent mark on the brand’s reputation. That conflict was central to the community's growing distrust towards Repenning and the Honeycomb name. These challenges were not unnoticed. Community discourse and critical media coverage, including our own reporting at Threshold, explored the implications of Honeycomb’s faltering transparency and logistical setbacks. Our piece "Into the Hive: Updates on Honeycomb's Journey", we provided a deep dive into the frustrations voiced by customers and the broader lessons for hardware developers in the flight sim industry. It should be noted that while Honeycomb eventually fulfilled the Charlie pre-orders, the extended wait, poor support, and surrounding controversy left the brand tainted in the eyes of many. Today, however, marks a turning point. Meridian GMT positions itself not as a continuation of Honeycomb but as a new venture with its own values, structure, and trajectory. While Repenning’s experience is undeniable, Meridian is shaped by a conscious intent to move beyond prior missteps. A more modular design philosophy, increased repairability, a tighter internal team, and strategic outsourcing of non-core competencies reflect this new direction. The company’s first product presentation will take place this coming weekend. Repenning will take the stage at FSWeekend and reveal three hardware products that aim to set new standards across their respective categories. Until then, the full product lineup remains under wraps. As stated in Meridian GMT’s official press release today on their website. "Meridian GMT is more than just a brand; it's a commitment to the flight simulation community", said Repenning. “Our core values - innovation, precision, durability, and affordability - are at the heart of everything we do. Our mission is to deliver hardware that not only exceeds the expectations of the community but also makes products for the casual flight simmer, embarking on their first solo flight, and bring immersion and fun to their experience too". The brand’s identity is also symbolically constructed. Meridian says the logo reflects its mission: three diamonds representing Community, Industry Partnerships, and Innovation, set within a golden hexagon signifying Legacy. The inverted Y in the logo nods to aviation roots, with a subtle aircraft silhouette formed by the space between the diamonds. While the past casts a long shadow, Meridian GMT is determined to navigate new horizons - without relying on nostalgia or name recognition to carry its message.  Instead, they hope to enter the market with clear eyes, tempered expectations, and a commitment to better serve the simulation community. The brand’s story begins here—and what follows will be watched with interest. </summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350103</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350103"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d1d3360d1288fc525c3463_v103NowAvailSocials.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently rolled out a new update to their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, aiming to mitigate WASM crash issues and aid overall stability. Update 1.0.3 focuses on making the product more stable and less vulnerable to WASM crashes that have plagued the product since its release, sparking a lot of controversy around many online flight sim communities. They have discovered that the update rates between third-party services and the A350’s systems sometimes don’t align, inducing issues, and specific data exchanges may cause unexpected increases in memory usage, leading to potential crashes.  To further illustrate what has been going on with their A350, iniBuilds decided to provide an in-depth explanation of how the WASM system works and why it may, at times, stop working: it needs memory to run the avionics, custom systems, and other third-party add-ons, which isn’t random access memory, but its very own virtual memory running separately inside the simulator, which is allocated according to the demand, and allocation issues may happen, leading to a WASM crash (that either entirely kills the simulator or freezes the airplane’s system). They have switched their method of handling that by going from manually managing memory to smart pointers, which helps prevent memory leaks and automatically handles freeing up memory when it’s no longer needed. Furthermore, they have taken steps to avoid using unnecessary copy constructors, which lead to high memory usage and performance issues.  iniBuilds has also implemented a delay to third-party data requests. Previously, they requested data at 30 fps, which overwhelmed the WASM environment. Now, it only polls it once every second, reducing the memory and processing overhead. The expected benefits of the above measures are fewer crashes due to bad memory management, more efficient memory use in the WASM environment, and better performance and smoothness.  The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/midx12</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Chicago Midway International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/midx12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d1dc724732690bcb80c4de_chi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Drzewiecki Design recently released their rendition of Chicago Midway International Airport (KMDW) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Chicago Metropolitan Area and has a yearly average of 22 million passengers. Established in 1927, Midway was Chicago’s main airport until the advent of O’Hare International in 1944. This did not stop it from being one of the busiest airports in the nation.  It is an operating base for Frontier Airlines and Southwest Airlines. Allegiant Air, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Porter Airlines, and Volaris also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-quality 3D models, PBR materials, custom animated jetways, VDGS, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.64, requiring at least 1.73 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f28two</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases F28 Professional V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f28two"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324880615470b16ee888a_fuk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently released the Fokker F28 Professional Version 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This version brings many significant upgrades over the first version, such as a new flight management system (UNS-1), new cockpit equipment, boarding/refueling simulation, and more. The Fokker F28 Fellowship is a twin-engined regional jet developed in the late 60s. Its first flight was in 1967 and its introduction happened in 1969, with 241 units built after a 20-year run (production ended in 1987). Multiple variants were developed, with the F28-1000 seating up to 70 passengers, the F28-2000 housing 79 people, and the later revision, the F28-4000, featuring quieter engines (Rolls-Royce Spey 555-15H), a redesigned cockpit and modified wings, and increased seating (up to 85 passengers). It was then superseded by the Fokker 70 and 100.  As of 2019, there are no current operators of the F28 around, with Fly-SAX being the last to operate it commercially. Garuda Indonesia was the largest former operator, with 62 of them. Other Major operators include the Ansett Group (13), AirQuarius Aviation (4), and Biman Bangladesh Airlines (4). The Ansett Group was also responsible for the longest nonstop F28 route in the world, between Perth and Kununurra, roughly 2300 km apart.  Version two of the F28 ensures compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It adds many new features to the product, further enriching its realism, such as the new UNS-1 flight management system, new cockpit equipment, boarding and refueling simulation, and more. Please refer to this page for further information on all the features included.  It’s available in their store for $50.39 (a promotional price to celebrate the new update). V1 owners are entitled to a free upgrade. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atekos</id>
    <title>Atelic Releases Kos International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atekos"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d4a1380e553fb3265e9e27_kos1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Atelic has recently released their rendition of Kos International Airport (LGKO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Kos Island, Greece, and has a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers. It opened in early 1964, and the first expansion work was carried out within a decade, bringing the runway to 2,400m and thus enabling it to accommodate larger jet aircraft. The ever-increasing passenger traffic figures led to the construction of a new passenger terminal in 1980, which underwent renovation and expansion seventeen years later. Upon winning the airport’s concession in late 2015, Fraport was heavily committed to improving the infrastructure through heavy maintenance and upgrades and ensuring it was within the safety regulations. It’s a focus airport for Aegean Airlines and seasonally served by Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air Serbia, Austrian Airways, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, Discover Airlines, easyJet, Enter Air, Eurowings, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Smartwings, Swiss, Transavia, TUI (multiple), and Wizz Air. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality PBR textures, realistic night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, detailed terminal and tower interiors, realistic terrain profile, custom vegetation, custom roads, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.32, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
