<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-04-04T18:27:51.831377+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfsvc</id>
    <title>Xometry Announces Victorville for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfsvc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6237d8428ff7b368140cb918_KVCV_Preview_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1857976"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Xometry is expanding into the MSFS2020 environment, as they've previewed their Victorville rendition in the new simulator. The upgraded scenery will be their first for the sim, and it surely won't be the last. Conveniently, VCV was their first airport in X-Plane 11, and it appears that Xometry is continuing that theme.  Victorville is a local legend among AvGeeks and aviation nerds in the Pacific Southwest. Famous for its vast graveyard containing hundreds of stored airline relics, the played a significant role in keeping aircraft during the COVID-19 pandemic. Fleets such as the Aero California DC-9s, Delta MD-80, MD90, and FedEx DC-10s have found their permanent home in the lower desert.  Unfortunately, the Xometry team hasn't provided an MSFS-specific feature list, so we'll give you their X-Plane 11 features: We'll keep you updated when Xometry posts additional information regarding the upcoming scenery. Join their Discord server to interact with the community if you're a prospective Victorville owner.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfto28</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews PA-38 Tomahawk for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfto28" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623936c6c13d9480f5204fe1_Pic_6_pHU32rEUR.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="501533"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has previewed their upcoming rendition of the Piper PA-38 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This update brings a new look into the aircraft, along with a detailed feature list to add to what users can expect upon release. At a first glance, the modeling on the aircraft is up to the expectations and correlates to the previous aircraft released, and upcoming. All aspects of the aircraft both exterior and exterior, are modeled accurately to resemble real-world aircraft. A total of 16 liveries will be provided on release and features liveries from many different countries. Users will also be provided a paintkit for the aircraft to create their own liveries and tailor to their own taste. Looking at the feature list provided by Just Flight, PBR texturing has been used alongside real-time reflections and realism. Full support of MSFS's icing effect has also been featured. Ground services and equipment such as chocks, fuel trucks, tie-downs, etc. are all included with the aircraft. A full 3D cockpit has been included with a full EFB will be provided to add accessibility to the user. IFR avionics will be included as well. The aircraft will be VR compatible upon release. All sounds are recorded from a real-world PA-38, alongside utilizing MSFS audio capabilities. If you are interested in the full feature list, you can view it over on Just Flight's Website. As of today, no release date or pricing has been announced. If you are interested in other products by Just Flight, you can view their full catalog over on their website. Threshold will keep you updated on further developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md1132</id>
    <title>Rotate Announces MD-11 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md1132" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623a3a9bc89d94f6d67c586b_md111.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="953620"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer Rotate has announced the release date of their upcoming McDonnell Douglas MD-11 for X-Plane 11 via X-Plane.org's YouTube channel. The hyped trijet will release on March 24th. This release marks the first-ever high-quality heavy trijet in X-Plane 11. Since the project was initially announced in May of 2017, nearly five years have passed while the community has eagerly awaited its release. As mentioned before, MD-11 is the first quality heavy trijet that the X-Plane 11 community has ever seen. Complimenting this fact is the lack of high-caliber heavy trijets in any sim, as the CaptainSim L1011 TriStar exists as the last notable 3-engined model. Preceding the CaptainSim L1011, the PMDG MD-11 and JustFlight DC-10 were developed originally for 32bit platforms such as FSX.  Rotate has distributed some preview copies to streamers for usage in anticipation of the release. Q8Pilot is currently active on the YouTube platform, showcasing the aircraft in its full glory. Check out his channel to learn more about the upcoming release. Last but not least is the pricing of the MD-11; unfortunately, neither Rotate nor X-Plane.org have provided a specific figure as to how much the plane will cost, though it was mentioned in the comments of the release trailer that pilots could expect the trijet to be in the 80-90USD range.  ‍ a special thank you to "Hampus Murling" on Discord for providing these screenshots of the MD-11!</summary>
    <published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdpsdf</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases KSDF v2 for XP11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdpsdf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623b552ad86ea5291a61aa38_X-Plane_W1h0nNAr3n.png.bafa8dc283c7e8025a3d3beba14187bd.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="915872"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has returned, this time updating their visual rendition for Louisville Muhammad Ali International for X-Plane. This update brings the scenery version to version 2 and involves the team's updated style and detail to the well-known cargo airport. Louisville International is the hub for the mainline cargo carrier, UPS. With a square footage of 5.2 million square feet and a perimeter of 7.2 miles, the UPS Worldport sees about 2 million packages a day, averaging 416,000 packages an hour. and 125 aircraft cargo stands, which makes it one of the more popular cargo airports in the world. KSDF also features a passenger terminal which in 2019, serviced about 4.2 million passengers from carriers such as Delta, Southwest, American, and many other carriers. ‍ No feature list has been provided by ZDP, however at a eye glance, detailed ground textures and 3D buildings are all provided in this package. From the included screenshots, the airport seems to be WorldTraffic 3 compatible, alongside a possible SAM Jetway extension for movable jetways. Alongside this, detailed airport ground equipment on both the cargo and passenger side of the airport, are all modeled. You can find this scenery package by Zero Dollar Payware over at the Threshold Forums, free to download. If you are interested in other packages by Zero Dollar Payware, you can find their catalog over on the Threshold Forums as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aseddn</id>
    <title>Aerosoft/Captain 7 Releases Airport Nuremberg for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aseddn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623c1261468601aab3ca01cf_aerosoft-airport-nuremberg%20(27).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="374740"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, Aerosoft/Captain 7 released its rendition of Airport Nuremberg (EDDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery, crafted with highly detailed models, high quality textures, and custom aerial images, brings an immersive experience for pilots who are flying into Bavaria. The airport, developed by Captain 7, 29Palms, and LimeSim, is accurately recreated based on the latest layout of the airport. It will feature “highly detailed buildings with internal modeling”, sloped runways, custom signage, animated jetways, realistic night lighting, and custom orthoimagery. For the full list of features, checkout Aerosoft’s store. Airport Nuremberg (EDDN), located 5km from the center of the city, is the second largest international airport in Bavaria and the 10th busiest airport in Germany. The airport, serving more than two dozen lines, connects some 4 million passengers to business and leisure destinations across Europe each year. Currently, the airport can be purchased on Aerosoft’s webstore for €16.76 or $18.40 USD, excluding any sale tax that may incur. To successfully install the product, users must have an active Aerosoft account and download the scenery via Aerosoft One.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ro11xp</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-11 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ro11xp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623cb8b379009ea6d4fcbeb5_X-Plane_1803_2227.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1893033"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Following the announcement of the release date on Tuesday, Rotate has delivered upon their promise and has launched their MD-11 for X-Plane. The MD-11 has been Rotate's active development project since its announcement in May 2017, almost 5 years ago. The aircraft accurately depicts its real life counterpart, currently only simulating the General Electric (GE) engine option in the freighter variant. Rotate has been sharing teasers and system previews of the widebody tri-jet frequently since it first announced the aircraft aircraft, mainly focussing on individual system areas during these updates. Nearing the end of the development process, the aircraft subsequently entered beta testing in late October of 2021. Following this long test period, the developer shared the aircraft with media outlets and streamers over the past weeks ahead of today's release.  Rotate has shared an extensive feature list on the product page, although the full thing is too long to share on this article, highlights of this include over 200 custom failures, and accurate simulation of all critical aircraft systems. Rotate has also announced today, prompting lots of backlash that the aircraft will see the passenger variant as an extra purchase. Seeing as the aircraft also does not ship with the Pratt and Whitney engines, and has lots of small bugs degrading the experience, the community is seemingly disappointed. You can purchase the highly awaited Rotate MD-11 for X-Plane 11 now from the X-Plane.org Store for $83.95.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/414rel</id>
    <title>Flysimware Releases C414 for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/414rel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623edd7a8687e4e14065546d_flysimware-cessna-414aw-chancellor-msfs2020.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="287973"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aircraft developer Flysimware has released their version of the Cessna 414 Chancellor for the new simulator. The team took great detail into account with this aircraft, as their tech pilot owns one of these birds in real life. Flysimware has teased their Chancellor for an extended period but has finally decided to post the plane on their website for purchase.  The Cessna C414 Chancellor is a pressurized, twin-engine aircraft developed by a famous company. Containing two TSIO-520-J engines, the plane outputs nearly 310hp. It can obtain about 1700 feet per minute during the climb, with a ceiling of 30,000 feet with a range of 1,528 miles. Flysimware's C414"AW" signifies an upgraded -A Variant with winglets and offers the "RAM IV" conversion, providing more power for the pilot.   Flysimware's C414 Features: The C414 delivers with four liveries. Flysimware points out that the product is still "a beta version." Aspiring C414 pilots can obtain the aircraft on the Flysimware store for $39.99. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mscaip</id>
    <title>Macco Simulations Announces Cancun Airport For Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mscaip" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623ff68dc52c4dc9df929702_Screen%20Shot%202022-03-27%20at%201.29.37%20AM-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1737790"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Macco Simulations announced their latest product - Cancun International Airport (MMUN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport, equipped with detailed models, 8 layers of ground texturing, and custom ground objects, will serve as an ideal vacation destination for pilots all year round. According to the developers, Cancun will mark the team’s first attempt to recreate an airport outside of the United Kingdom. They have spend more than 10 months working on this project, with almost half of it dedicated to “ sorting out the [region’s] atrocious [default] satellite imagery”. They also revealed that a full version of the scenery will be available on release, instead of beta versions like their previous airports. The finished product will include custom static vehicles, PBR/4k textures, "fully optimized LODs for best performance on PC and XBOX", and fully custom jetways. For the full list of features, checkout the developer's website.  Cancun Airport, located on the Caribbean coast, is the main airport serving the popular holiday destination of Cancun. It's visited by various major airlines such as KLM, Lufthansa, Delta, and American, seeing some 22 million passengers per year. From the airport, passengers can board flights to destinations such as Orlando, Los Angeles, and London. Currently, Macco Simulations has teased that Cancun Airport will be released early next month, though the specific date and pricing were not provided. Threshold will keep you updated on this front.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xovict</id>
    <title>Xometry Publishes Victorville for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xovict" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62413e0476f54667010716c0_ezgif-5-1899149dc2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="566185"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The team over at Xometry Design is back bringing Victorville Logistics Airport to Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release brings the developers both attention to detail, and quality work to the Southern California Logistics Airport. The Victorville Airport is known for a variety of subjects, most recently being used as a aircraft storage and an aircraft retirement area. At its inception, the US Federal Government was trying to situate the area after the closure of George Air Force Base, once coming to a conclusion, the airport was convereted to a Logistics Airport in 1992. Since then, the airfield has been used for cargo and airline logistics and storage. In 2020, as a result with of the COVID-19 Pandemic, many airlines both housed in the US and outside the US, use this airfield for aircraft storage due to lesser demand on routes. Xometry has provided a detailed feature log upon release of this package. Starting off, detailed buildings and ground textures have been modelled with PBR textures. Xometry has provided both a pre COVID and current renditions fo the airport. Disassembled aircraft parts can be found across the airfield, with including over 150 custom placed aircraft over the airport grounds. If you are interested in the full feature list, you can check out the products webpage. If you are interested in this scenery package and picking it up for yourself, you can purchase it over on the iniBuilds Store and sells for $17.00 USD. If you are interested in any other products by Xometry, you can check out their extensive catalog on the iniBuilds Store as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/srv14</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Ships Out Trailer for RV-14</title>
    <updated>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/srv14" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62369b5c06dd18d4cb15a7b0_rv141.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1216362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios have taken to the AviationLads YouTube Channel to release their trailer for their upcoming RV-14 aircraft rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release will bring another general aviation aircraft to the simulator's ever expanding GA catalog. Diving in, the trailer starts of a showcase of the 3D cockpit which features and an all glass cockpit, with an included Garmin Suite is shown in the cockpit. Later on in the video it is stated that the aircraft is compatible with PMS GTN750 Premium and GTNXI. Before that, exterior modeling is showed off in all views and angles. All external features have been modeled, including exhaust pipes, and other miniscule features to resemble the real world counterpart. Returning to the cockpit, all features to resemble the real world aircraft has been modeled with all buttons and switches presumably working as designed and operable. Furthermore, there is a small cargo area that has been modeled with including modeled bags for an extra feature. Another added feature is an included retractable sunshade on the aircraft canopy, to help block out that pesky sun. As of now, the release of the aircraft has been postponed and a further date has not been mentioned. The product will be available on the SimWorks Studios Website once released and will sell for €14.99. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/yssyxp</id>
    <title>TaiModels Releases Sydney Kingsford Smith International Airport for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/yssyxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6243ecebb11a4b283982ddf1_Cessna_172SP_G1000-2022-03-247.44.57PM_thumb_c0324458-01fb-4a78-8254-451752e5fb6b%20copy.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="698548"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, scenery developer TaiModels released Sydney Kingsford Smith International Airport (YSSY) for X-Plane 11. The airport, created using 4k textures, custom SAM jetways, and custom ground mesh, will serve as the gateway for pilots looking to visit one of Australia's most well known metropolises. According to the developers, Sydney Airport has been recreated to mirror its real life counterpart. Some notable features of the scenery include high detailed models, interior models for terminal 1 and 2, custom animated objects, PBR textures, and optimizations for best performances. For a complete list of features, check out the product’s store page. Sydney Airport, located only 5 miles away from Sydney’s central districts, is the main international airport that serves the region. One of the busiest airports in Australia, YSSY serves as a hub for international travel, connecting the country to almost every continent in the world. In 2018 alone, the airport handled some 45 million passengers and was nominated by Skytrax as the world’s 20th best airport. Currently, TaiModels’s Sydney Airport can be purchased on iniBuilds’s webstore for £20.99 GBP/$27.50 USD, excluding any sales tax that may occur. The product is supported all three operating systems and the developers recommend the users to have at least 1.86GB of free disk free for successful installation.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/conc331</id>
    <title>DCDesigns Releases Concorde for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/conc331" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62467a4cbbf30f709871b8fd_concorde-microsoft-flight-simulator_2_ss_l_220330095555.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="130917"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aircraft developer DCDesigns has released their rendition of the Aerospatiale Concorde for MSFS2020. The product is accompanied by MSFS native materials, a realistic flight model, and a complete operations manual. While it's unlikely that you don't know much about the Concorde, here's a bit of a history lesson anyway. The Aerospatiale/BAC Concorde is a French-British afterburning turbojet supersonic airliner that operated at a cruising speed of Mach 2.02. Considered a technological marvel, it contains the title of the most successful supersonic aircraft, beating its only "viable" competitor, the Tupolev Tu-144. It initially garnered interest from many airlines, such as Pan Am and Trans World Airlines, but production delays and hesitance regarding the airframes viability as a profitable mechanism led to mass cancellations of orders, leaving only British Airways and Air France to operate the aircraft. The Concorde is still the only "successful" supersonic airliner to date, even though the airframe's last flight took place in 2003. Today, most Concordes are presented at notable museums such as the Intrepid and Boeing museums, existing as figures of an incredible legacy of the past.  Rewinding to the DCDesigns rendition of the Concorde, it's imperative to mention that the developer designed the aircraft intending to simplify the plane so that it is accessible to all users without requiring "intense" studying to fly. Therefore, it's important to keep expectations humble as it doesn't compete with the likes of the FSLabs Concorde, for example.  DCDesigns' Concorde Features: You can obtain the DCDesigns Concorde for MSFS2020 through the JustFlight store for $39.99. In addition, aspiring pilots can check out the release trailer beforehand to get a glimpse of the aircraft in action. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gsxp11</id>
    <title>Stairport Releases GroundService for XP11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gsxp11" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624705641a92f3a612f7b5dd_sam-groundservice-xp%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="138515"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. One of the most anticipated airport environment add-on's has been released. Stairport, in collaboration with MisterX, have released GroundService plugin for X-Plane 11. Being the second plugin of its kind, many XP11 users have looked forward to this product developed by the well known developers. The plugin enhances the various aspects of airport life that has often been neglected in X-Plane 11 for quite some time. While other development teams have included basic ground services in their plugins, this release brings the whole world of ground services to light. With cleaning trucks, to passenger stairs for smaller airports, this plugin provides it all, with high accessibility for users through the SAM3 plugin. With a multitude of features, this plugin provides it all. First, the product does come with a aircraft compatibility list, and a 10 minute demo has been provided to give users a chance to take a dip in the water before purchasing. All aspects of ground services have been included in the package with items such as GPU, cleaning trucks, loaders, and animated passenger stairs being included. X-Plane 12 compatibility is currently under development for the plugin to be ready at the launch of XP12. This plugin by Stairport is available for purchase on the Aerosoft Store with a selling price of $34.99. If you are interested in other products developed by Stairport and MisterX, you can check out their product pages over on Aerosoft Store for Stairport, and the X-Plane.org Store for MisterX</summary>
    <published>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hema20</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Releases Marsa Alam Airport for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hema20" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6247f90c9d29b720c66edf19_hema1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="541258"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds affiliate Chudoba Design has released its rendition of Marsa Alam (HEMA) airport for MSFS2020. The Egyptian airport is faithfully recreated, feature-rich, and moderately priced to add to its offerings.  Marsa Alam International Airport is an international airport, mainly serving as a vacation destination for European leisure travelers. The airport features traffic from many notable airlines, such as easyJet, Edelweiss, Lufthansa, Smartwings, and TUI fly. It served over 1 million passengers back in 2012 and contains a singular, 9800 foot, or 3,000-meter runway. Marsa Alam for MSFS is presented with the following features:  You can purchase HEMA airport for MSFS on the iniBuilds store for 6.99GBP/8.30EUR/9.19USD. The download will consume 158MB of space on your hard drive and 364MB after installation. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ch65up</id>
    <title>Hot Start Pushes Out Challenger 650 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ch65up" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/61c7db088f6818366ca10a5a_01.jpg.dad1a93442e931e0ffc7e416570e9972.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1298071"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The development team behind the renowned Challenger 650 aircraft is back bringing a small bug fix and improvement update for the small business jet. This includes a variety of fixes and minor improvements to make the aircraft more like its real-world counterpart and bring more accessibility to the user. Whilst this update is quite small. It comes packed with a variety of features. Starting off, additions such as click spots for wing inspections for preflight and adding a variety of system support such as OCEAN CLX, ATS LOG, and DEP CLX, but also features a brief update to xPilot SELCAL datarefs. Moving forward, an assortment of improvements have also been made. Datarefs for the "walking mode" and libfail have been enhanced, alongside an enhancement to overnight icing accumulation that follows real-world METAR data. Support for the online network POSCON has been added as well. The large parts of this update contain bug fixes. A multitude of these features are mainly system improvements and bug fixes, along with a variety of FMC and Flightplan system improvements have been made as well.  You can find the full content list of the update by visiting the X-Pilot Forums, and if you are interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can find it over on the X-Aviation Store.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fscytz</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Billy Bishop Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fscytz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624a5a4acb6eec317ae69588_293023_17.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="887872"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The team over at FSimStudios has released their visual rendition of Toronto's Billy Bishop Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release has brought an all-new look to the small regional Canadian airport. Before Toronto Pearson International Airport was constructed, Billy Bishop Airport served as Toronto's main airport. Being built in 1939, the airport served as the main hub for all air traffic. A decade later, the Canadian Government proposed an expansion to the small airport to increase passenger traffic to the area. Later on, with the airport receiving a regional jet ban in 1983, passenger air travel slightly declined. Now in the 21st Century, the airport was approved to receive the Airbus A220 for a limited time. For this release, the team has included a feature list of what is included in the scenery package. Starting off, the package has the current 2022 layout airport and more than 20 accurate handmade models of downtown Toronto have been included. Many helipads for Toronto's hospitals have been included for our rotorcraft friends to fly to. Static Q400s are an option for users to include in their scenery as well. The full feature list is listed below: This scenery is able to be purchased over on the simMarket Store and sells for €13.99. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
