<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-11-02T18:31:18.058842+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/osrlhx</id>
    <title>Origami Studios Releases London Heathrow for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/osrlhx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634fff2d77435c1046dfffd5_london1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1456939"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Origami Studios has worked hard to get this project released in the last two days after announcing its development for X-Plane 12. London Heathrow (EGLL) is the busiest airport in the United Kingdom and within the top 10 in the world! Founded in 1946 and originally known as London Airport, it was renamed London Heathrow in 1966. It used to have six runways, placed in a Star-Of-David pattern. As Heathrow became bigger and bigger over the years, it was decided there was no longer a need for the 3 of Heathrow’s four diagonal runways, culminating on their closure by the 1970’s, leaving one runway intact (05/23), eventually decommissioned in 2003 for an extension of an existing terminal. It’s the hub for British Airways and Virgin Atlantic, and they cater for many other airlines that fly in and out daily from different countries. It has four passenger terminals which can see over 78 million passengers a year, according to data shown in 2017, heading to and from 185 countries around the world. Fun fact, did you know that aircraft had to be moved from the Terminal 4 remote stands when runway 23 was in use? Origami Studios have brought out a massive asset to X-Plane 12. Including custom buildings, a highly detailed rendition of Terminal 5, landmarks and moving jetways. ‍ Key Features: Want to fly to the busiest UK airport in X-Plane 12? Head over to the iniBuilds Store to purchase Origami’s London Heathrow Airport for £21.99 GBP. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hrdf</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Destin-Fort Walton Beach Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hrdf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635001f6ac01b2f46c087c67_fwb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1062607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Destin-Fort Walton Beach Airport (KVPS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an airport within Eglin Air Force Base and serving the cities of Destin and Fort Walton Beach in Florida. It’s exclusively commercial, known for being a focus city to Allegiant Air, and often visited by American, Delta, and Southwest, with Sun Country to begin seasonal operations to Minneapolis/St. Paul in April 2023. With nearly 2 million passengers between 2021-2022, it’s among the busiest airports in the state.  Formerly known as Okaloosa Regional Airport, it was renamed Northwest Florida Regional Airport in September 2008 and then given its current name in February 2015.  ‍ The scenery features a fully modeled terminal exterior, PBR materials on buildings and ground, apron clutter, and animated humans.  ‍ It’s available on FlightSim.to for $8.99 and requires at least 2.4 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gaftam</id>
    <title>Gaffer Simulations Releases FAOR O.R. Tambo International For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gaftam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63508df31d6a19bf2b6b5c39_305916_74_MSFS.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1687964"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Gaffer Simulations has released their highly anticipated O.R. Tambo International scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, South Africa’s biggest international airport located in Johannesburg that first opened in 1952. The airport, serves as the primary international gateway for South Africa and is home to several notable African carriers including Airlink, CemAir, FlySafair, LIFT Airline &amp; South African Airways. The airport encompasses around 4000 acres of land in Kempton Park, Gauteng, situated about 12 miles from the city of Johannesburg. The airport has two runways parallel to each other adjacent to the airport’s terminal buildings, and provides direct connections to over 75 destinations which are served by a multitude of aircraft from general aviation, cargo and commercial aircraft. originally served under the name Jan Smuts International Airport, it was renamed in 2005 after former African National Congress member Oliver Reginald Tambo. The airport has received  numerous upgrades and expansion projects, the most notable being the major developments which took place in preparation for the 2010 FIFA World Cup. For Gaffer Simulations rendition of O.R Tambo International, the scenery comes with a standard set of features that we can expect from most airport sceneries on Microsoft Flight Simulator, in which the recreation is built with high-definition PBR textures and models that accurately represent the airport in its current form. The complete feature list follows down below: Gaffer Simulations’ O.R. Tambo International airport for MSFS is available for purchase on the SimMarket store for €21.60, requiring over 6 GB of free disk space to install.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbifx</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Brisbane International for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbifx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6353062ab8d72cd9aefcb5c5_ybbn3.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1692460"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has just released their first product for X-Plane 12, a  rendition of Brisbane International (YBBN), the primary international airport in Queensland, visited by 20 million passengers yearly. It’s a hub for Alliance Airlines, Jetstar, Qantas, Toll Aviation, and Virgin Australia, totalizing around 50 domestic destinations. International-wise, it’s visited by the likes of Air Canada, Air New Zealand, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, Emirates, Singapore Airlines, and many others, amounting to 29 international destinations. The scenery was developed by their in-house experts using the latest techniques, which include PBR texturing, custom SAM jetways (including T-Style), and VDGS integration, along with the inclusion of runway 01L/19R that opened in mid-2020. It’s said to be their most detailed scenery yet for X-Plane. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for $18.41, requiring at least 2.11 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prlrgm</id>
    <title>PILOT’S Releases Lynchburg Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prlrgm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635373200837b57d55a83a96_lynch3.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1865944"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PILOT’S has just released their rendition of Lynchburg Regional Airport (KLYH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use airport in Campbell County, Virginia. Mainly a General Aviation airport, it sees commercial operations through American Eagle, with daily flights to Charlotte in North Carolina.  It was formerly known as Preston Glenn Airport, after Lt. Preston Glenn, a WW1 hero from Lynchburg.   The scenery features an accurate and up-to-date representation of the airport in 2022, with high-quality scenery objects and textures, and a convincingly reproduced - and rather unique - single jetway. The feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for roughly $14.50 (depending on region), requiring at least 6.79 GB of free disk space to install. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vslf19</id>
    <title>VSKYLABS Releases F-19 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vslf19" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635452fc8bbb51cf21b6c9ed_vskylabs-f19-v1.0-ea-024.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="680926"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The all-new rendition of the F-19 Stealth fighter has been released for X-Plane 12. This release adds to the ever-increasing and vast library of military aircraft a part of the new next-generation simulator. With the ever-increasing aircraft network being moved to the new simulator, the F-19 Stealth Fighter Project is no different. Attempting to recreate the 80s aircraft to the best of their abilities, VSKYLABS has not only replicated the exterior model but also developed the systems and the interior. The developers have provided an extensive feature list. Starting off, they have replicated the flight model of the actual aircraft with XP12’s flight dynamics upgrade. Along with FMOD sounds being included, the aircraft has been developed to be compatible with VR and optimized for 2D usage. For the full feature list, you can view it on the product page. If you are interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can purchase it on VSKYLABS Website. Though the developer has stated that it is not an official release, the project is under constant maintenance.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drxmsf</id>
    <title>DarkSpace Releases xEnviro 2020 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drxmsf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6354924af966741e8259c926_2xE20.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="373812"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DarkSpace has just released xEnviro 2020, a brand new weather engine aiming to improve the weather depiction in Microsoft Flight Simulator, built upon their ten years of experience developing xEnviro for X-Plane. With a shared core code based on two decades of atmospheric studies and a sophisticated mathematical model, it aims to bring professional class weather simulation to everyone. On the announcement thread, they have also stated their long-term plans for the product, which will initially feature the engine itself and historical weather* (first weather add-on to feature historical weather), but with a - potential - addition of true-scale clouds that are already available on their version for X-Plane. They also mention that MSFS depicts weather differently due to how the clouds are scaled (twice as big), meaning some very specific METARs can’t be faithfully reproduced as of yet (the announcement features an example). The complete feature list follows down below: Features It’s available on the Threshold Store for $42, and xEnviro (X-Plane) owners get a $20 discount.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! *Historical Weather from 16.10.2022 and beyond</summary>
    <published>2022-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrsma</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Scandinavian Mountains Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrsma" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635756991d55c663d2b5b173_esks1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1867043"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyline Simulations has just released their rendition of Scandinavian Mountains Airport (ESKS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, among the most modern airports and the first in the world with a remote control tower. Opened in December 2019, the traffic figures are not yet impressive, with 14,157 passengers in 2020 and 16,236 in 2022 (until July).  Unlike most airports, it only gets commercial traffic during the winter, when it gets visited by airlines such as Luxair, Scandinavian, Transavia (by December 2022), and TUI fly Nordic.  The scenery features an updated taxiway layout, ultra-high definition textures, PBR, custom 3D vegetation, animated people and luggage, and night lighting. The complete list follows down below: ‍ It’s available on Flightsim.to for $18.80 and requires at least 1.22 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brtafm</id>
    <title>BMA Releases Trieste Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brtafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6357f5fedfbed16383d175fc_trieste1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2060714"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addons has just released their rendition of Trieste Airport (LIPQ) and five POIs (Memorial of Redipuglia, Fortress of Monfalcone, Castle of Duino, Basilica of Aquileia, and the Cerje Peace Monument) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in north-eastern Italy, it serves the region of Friuli-Venezia Giulia and adjacencies (Austria, Slovenia, and Croatia), with a yearly average of 800.000 passengers.  It’s visited by airlines such as Air Serbia, ITA Airways, Lufthansa, Ryanair, and Volotea (seasonally), with RYR offering the most destinations (nine). The scenery features updated taxiways and ground markings, an accurate representation of the passenger terminal, and the aforementioned POIs.  It’s available on FlightSim.to for $18.40 and requires at least 121.06MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrnau</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases New A320 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrnau" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6358191032e01e7ba85063f3_fenix1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3158078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently updated their A320 add-on to v1.0.5.139, addressing a significant list of issues, including flare law tweaks, flap behavior, sound fixes, and the return of contrails. There is an in-depth forum post regarding their findings on the landing behavior, including comparisons with real-world data and footage, which can be a worthwhile read for A320 aficionados. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ [SYSTEM] ‍ - Adjusted custom low speed friction model ‍ - Adjusted G/S mini logic ‍ - Fixed beacon/strobe desync ‍ - Fixed flap 2 to flap 3 excessive nose-down ballooning in manual flight and autoflight. ‍ - Adjusted tuning for G/S hold for better tracking of G/S in autopilot modes ‍ - Autoland told to stop mucking about and do the job properly, should flare a little more aggressively now. ‍ - Fixed issue with loss of ILS signal in the FMS autotuner. This causes lack of yaw control during ROLLOUT, leading to grassy excursions. Please note, it's possible this issue still exists in specific sceneries that do not have their guidance beams set up properly. ‍ - ISA fixed. ‍ - Small tweaks to FLARE mode behaviour. ‍ - Introduction of LIGHTER/HEAVIER sidestick option in CONTROL CONFIG, default changed to "lighter" for desktop hardware.  ‍ - Changed amount of force needed to disconnect autopilot with stick pressure. Now a user needs to apply roughly 60% of travel before the AP will disconnect. This is the best way we can emulate a "control lock" which requires a fair amount of force to disconnect. ‍ - Disabled brake temperature simulation for GSX pushbacks. ‍ - Reduced sensitivity of yaw when nose wheel is in contact with the ground, leading to significantly smoother yaw control during crosswind landings and at high speeds. ‍ - Minor refinements to initial VNAV descent angle calculations.  ‍ - Fixed issue where the flat deceleration segment for 250kts was missing when a "at or above" altitude constraint was present. ‍ [FM] ‍ - Slight bump to flap full lift, aircraft should feel more responsive in flap full configurations, ergo FLARE feels slightly more energetic now as opposed to throwing elevator up into a bowl of porridge. All in, this should be more consistent, simply put. The prior the lack of lift was causing inertia issues. Please be aware of this on your next approach, some refamiliarization might be required. ‍ - Made a small adjustment to lateral friction values ‍ - Made a small adjustment to ground spoiler effectiveness ‍ [ART&amp;SOUND] ‍ - All exterior lights now volumetric ‍ - Added back missing antennas ‍ - #bringbackcontrails ‍ - Volume bug resolved preventing some sounds from playing at their intended volume ‍ - Fixed nose gear retraction sounds ‍ - Brighter cockpit ‍ - Sound fixes and improvements (flaps/slats/fuel-pumps/AEVC/packs) The update is available on their website for registered customers.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inima2</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases iniManager v2</title>
    <updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inima2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635957f6b8b3a10570ebe370_IMG_2641-min.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1824321"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Known developer iniBuilds recently announced and released the v2 version of their in house software iniManager. Featuring many new additions and optimizations for users to enjoy. The iniManager is a software that eases the installation and update process for aircraft and scenery renditions. All while supporting products for both X-Plane 11 and Microsoft Flight Simulator. Recently it was announced that v2 of the software was in the works and it has now been released to the public. The update comes packed full with new features. The software now supports X-Plane 12 and P3D with products coming soon. An all new “World View” has been added to display installed scenery packages across the globe, alongside viewing packages available for purchase on the iniBuilds Store. iniManager also now has an in-app purchasing option for those that want an all-in-one access. The software can now install liveries for MSFS aircraft, which will install directly in the Community Folder. Finally a support page for pilots has been added to give more accessibility to SimBrief. It can display your OFP, METAR’s and more, all in one place. Version 2 is now available to download for free on iniBuilds Website. If you would like to view the full press release from iniBuilds you can view it on the iniBuilds Forum</summary>
    <published>2022-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xrfsau</id>
    <title>X-Codr Releases Free Sedona Airport Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xrfsau" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635b10388b567383cf03bc9f_sedonacover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="305730"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr has updated their Sedona Airport (KSEZ) scenery, ensuring compatibility with X-Plane 12 and adding many new features, such as improved textures, animated 3D grass and people, and hand-sculpted 3D rock formations for the surrounding valley.  The revamp also includes the addition of detailed 3D interiors and optimization work to ensure the scenery runs well on a wide range of hardware. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ Ultra detailed rendition of KSEZ - Sedona Living Airport Custom surroundings It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $21.95, requiring at least 3GB of free disk space to install.  Current owners of the X-Plane 11 version get the update for free. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrgub</id>
    <title>AKD Studios Releases GLF550 Ultimate Business Jet for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2022-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrgub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635c247613876cd9b791345d_akd1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="81802"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After two years and a half of development, AKD Studios has finally released their GLF550 for X-Plane 11 and 12, a business jet introduced in 2004 and primarily used by the USAF, US Navy, Israeli Air Force, and Netjets. With a capacity for 14-19 passengers and a range of 12.500 km, it is the private aircraft of choice for many governments and armies around the globe.  The add-on features many custom systems, including pressurization, oxygen, air conditioning, hydraulics, fuel, APU, and auto flight suite, along with an EFB that brings ground service controls, performance calculator, refueling and load manager, avitab integration, checklists, and aircraft options. The detailed cockpit features tridimensional switches and 4K PBR textures all over. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ ‍ Aircraft Systems:   Custom MFD’s:   DU 1:   •1/6 Top:    •1/6 Bottom:   2/3:   DU 2:    1/6 Top:    1/6 Bottom    2/3:    DU 3:  1/6 Top:   1/6 Bottom: •2/3:    DU 4: 1/6 Top:  1/6 Bottom:    2/3:   Electronic Flight Bag(EFB): Detailed modeling and textures: Other: It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $31.95 and it requires at least 1 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/trfbnx</id>
    <title>TearWearDesigns Releases Freeware Buffalo Niagara for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/trfbnx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635d50105474bb42a368a006_buf1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1112849"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TearWearDesigns has released their rendition of Buffalo Niagara International (KBUF) for X-Plane 12, free of charge. The airport serves the city of Buffalo, NY, and part of Ontario, Canada. Averaging 5 million passengers every year, it’s the third busiest in the state, with over 100 flights a day from airlines such as American, Delta, Frontier, JetBlue, Southwest, and United. The scenery features tridimensional grass, custom markings, dirt and wear around the airport, hand-placed night lighting, true-to-life parking lots, orthoimagery (ZL19), and a custom terminal, tower, and hangars.  It’s available for free on X-Plane.Org, with a download size of 560 MB.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inixp12</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Free A300V2 Compatibility Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inixp12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635e12ec8fb6acc2d668856b_A300-v2-Store_14.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="179896"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, developer iniBuilds has announced their plans of bringing their existing aircrafts to X-Plane 12, focusing exclusively on their much-popular A300. According to the developers, the A300V2 will soon receive an update that makes the plane compatible with X-Plane 12. All existing owners of the aircraft will be able to update free of charge. In addition, a significant reduction in price for the entire family is planned, though the developer didn’t offer any details regarding this planned price change. However, the developers have decided to not provide a release date for the compatibility update, though they hinted that it is expected to come in early 2023. Though the date seems far in the future, the developers reasoned that their current focus is to improve and polish the A300.  Currently, the A300V2 is on sale and can be purchased on iniBuilds webstore for £34.99 GBP, or $40.5 USD. Threshold will keep you updated on future iniBuild news.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/adpfkm</id>
    <title>Aero Dynamics Previews Freeware KC-10/DC-10 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/adpfkm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63604ca24006b960ce3f1ba3_dc-10-4.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1972447"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Aero Dynamics team has published a new quarterly drop on their Discord server, showcasing the current state of their freeware KC-10/DC-10 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with extensive focus on their 3D scanned cockpit. It is said to feature swappable instruments to provide both the OG experience and a modern flight suite, along with an EFB that will allow users to customize the cockpit settings, handle ground services, checklists, Navigraph and SimBrief integration, and OSM maps.   Regarding displays and systems, they have managed to integrate the fuel gauges into the aircraft, with upgrades to the font accuracy coming in the near future. Further progress with the electrical system has made viable work on a more advanced fuel system and the APU, with pneumatic and hydraulic systems to follow. They have also showcased two new models, the DC-10-30F (freighter) and the 10 Tanker. The 10F is their first DC-10 variant, featuring nine liveries, including FedEx (old and new), Aeroflot, and United. The latter is a tanker, capable of dropping fire retardant with the press of a button! ‍ Credits to AllNaturalBlue for the news scoop.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2022-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
