<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-06-05T18:20:58.273960+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfstre</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Treviso Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfstre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646cc05d156077ddade9ba58_liph1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3157607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Treviso Airport (LIPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Treviso in Italy and the neighboring towns of Venice and Padua, with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  Built in the 1930s to meet the needs of the Treviso Air Club and inaugurated by Benito Mussolini himself, the airport only got its first passenger terminal nearly twenty years later, in 1953, the same year when Treviso got its first international flights (to London and Vienna, operated by BAE and Austrian, respectively).   For a long time until the opening of Tessera (Venice Airport), Treviso was also the airport of choice for passengers visiting Venice.   In 2007, the airport got a new terminal named after Antonio Canova, a famous local sculptor. It expanded its passenger handling capabilities and became Venice's de facto secondary airport, fully embraced by low-cost carriers like Ryanair.   It's served by Ryanair (Alicante, Amman–Queen Alia, Beauvais, Berlin, Billund, Bucharest–Otopeni, Budapest, Charleroi, Cork, Crotone, Eindhoven, Fez, Hahn, Kraków, Málaga, Malta, Marrakesh, Palma de Mallorca, Porto, Poznań, Prague, Riga, Seville, Sibiu, Sofia, Tallinn, Tel Aviv, Tenerife–South, Thessaloniki, Trapani, Valencia, Vilnius, Warsaw–Modlin) and Wizz Air (Bucharest–Otopeni, Cluj-Napoca, Iași, Skopje, Suceava, Timișoara, Tirana), with a significant route network encompassing most of Europe and some of Africa.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom buildings, custom ground textures, a true-to-life taxiway layout, custom ground clutter, and custom airport vehicles.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $16.23, requiring at least 161.53 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lispal</id>
    <title>Lisium Design Releases Palanga International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lispal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646ccff56449cc129fa917f4_pal1-min%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3179474"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Lisium Design has recently released their rendition of Palanga International Airport (EYPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the town of Palanga in Lithuania with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was built during the post-WW2 period, aiming to replace the former Palanga Airport that sat 7 km east of the new one. It was originally a military airport, controlled by the Soviet Union’s Air Force. The civil airport conversion only came to be nearly twenty years later, in 1963.  ‍ Between 1994 and 1997, the airport underwent substantial renovation work, with a revamped passenger terminal, featuring ICAO-compliant passenger services and luggage handling, a full control center renovation, followed by a runway resurfacing. ‍ With Lithuania joining the European Union in 2004, the passenger figures skyrocketed, a 60% difference compared to the previous year. With extra passengers came the necessity to expand once again, improvement of which happened in 2007, increasing the terminal area by two thousand square meters to comply with the Schengen border crossing regimen. Later that year, the runway was extended to the current 2,280 meters. ‍ It’s served by airBaltic (Riga), Norwegian Air Shuttle (Oslo), Ryanair (Dublin, London-Stansted), and Scandinavian Airlines (Copenhagen, Oslo). ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, PBR, parallax interiors, custom night lighting, a true-to-life ground layout, animated models, GSX and AREX compatibility, and high quality models of the airport and its surrounding buildings. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.23, requiring at least 1.20 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aermar</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Marseille Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aermar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646f6bb808891fdf3f64be1d_mar1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="106505"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of Marseille Provence Airport (LFML) for X-Plane 12, the sixth busiest airport in France with a yearly average of 9,390,491 passengers.  The airport started operations in 1922, on a 230-ha site 2 kilometers from Marignane, with a seaplane station and a 200-meter pier. It was one of France's main points of operation for flying boats, hosting Aeropóstale, Air Union, and even Pan American World Airways, although briefly.   The passenger terminal was rebuilt in 1961, designed by architect Fernand Pouillon (exterior)  and Maxime Old (interior), increasing its passenger handling capabilities. Thirty years later, in 1992, they expanded the terminal even further with the construction of Hall B.  In 2006, they opened a new terminal (MP2) aimed at budget airlines such as Ryanair, one of Marseille's most popular carriers. It's their biggest base in France, with 60 routes and more than 240 weekly departures.  The airport is served by many airlines, including Air France, Aer Lingus, Air Transat, Austrian, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, KLM, Lufthansa, SWISS, Tap, Turkish, Volotea, and Vueling. It offered 132 regular destinations in 2013.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality 3D objects, native weather effects, high-resolution orthophoto, realistic ground textures, accurate dynamic night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, SAM integration, custom animated jetways, and more.  It's available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $22.47, requiring at least 3 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Poptart for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thrbn2</id>
    <title>Thranda Design Announces BN2A Islander for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thrbn2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646f74f63cb67dfca6839407_thr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="189943"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Design has recently announced the next member of their Dynamic Generation Series lineup: the Britten-Norman BN-2 Islander, a British light utility aircraft and regional airliner in production since 1965.  The BN2 took off for the first time in June 1965, initially powered by Rolls-Royce Continental IO-360B, and then later replaced by a set of Lycoming O-540-Es. The first production unit flew for the first time two years later, the year when it got its US certification.  Thranda’s version replicates the BN-2A Islander, which came out in 1969 with aerodynamic and flight equipment improvements, including lower-drag engine cowlings, a bigger rear baggage area, and slightly more powerful engines.  One of its key features is its ability to operate from unprepared airstrips, including grass and gravel runways. It is a popular choice for remote and inaccessible locations where traditional runways may be limited or absent. Its STOL capabilities allow it to take off and land in challenging conditions, such as short runways and rough terrain, making it ideal for island hopping, humanitarian missions, surveillance, and aerial survey work.  It has a seating capacity for up to nine passengers, although it can be easily reconfigured for cargo transportation. Its large cabin provides ample space for passengers or cargo, and the aircraft can be equipped with various interior layouts to suit specific requirements. The cabin can also be modified to accommodate medical equipment for air ambulance operations or fitted with specialized equipment for surveillance and reconnaissance missions.  Powered by two piston engines, usually the Lycoming O-540 or the Textron Lycoming TIO-540, the BN2A Islander has a cruising speed of around 140 knots (160 mph or 260 km/h) and a range of approximately 800 nautical miles (920 miles or 1,480 kilometers). Its fuel efficiency and relatively low operating costs have contributed to its popularity among operators worldwide.  The little airplane has been utilized in various applications, including regional airline operations, charter services, military missions, border patrol, fisheries protection, search and rescue operations, aerial surveying, and environmental monitoring. Its reliability and robustness have made it well-suited for operations in harsh environments and demanding conditions.  As of October 2019, 800 islanders were still flying out of the 1,280 built.  ‍ There’s no information regarding features, pricing, or the release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. Shout out to Luke for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsscal</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Calgary International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsscal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6470073bbd70cc6cc674035d_cyyc1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="124730"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently released their rendition of Calgary International Airport (CYYC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Canada with a yearly average of 14,452,000 passengers.  The airport was built in the late 30s, with a hangar financed by Trans-Canada Airlines and three runways funded by the Department of Transportation. It was initially named McCall Airfield after a Calgarian WW1 hero.  WW2 had Calgary International be repurposed as a fuel and maintenance stop for war aircraft and, later, housing a military flight training school. In the meantime, they continued to get regular passenger flights.  The end of World War 2 saw Calgary getting infrastructure improvements, including additional hangars, a fourth runway, and a passenger terminal, a repurposed hangar.   It turned out the repurposed hangars were not enough for the traffic boom of the 50s, leading to the construction of a new passenger terminal in 1956, designed by then architecture student Ken Bond. It was one of the most modern terminals in Canada back in the day.  Twenty years later, the once brand-new terminal could no longer handle the new passenger volume, forcing the city to spend $130 million on a 600,000 square feet terminal, which exists to this day.  More recently, in 2016, Calgary International got a new terminal, costing 1.6 billion dollars, covering 186,000 square meters of land and adding 24 new aircraft gates and a super modern passenger screening system with sustainability in mind.  It’s a hub for WestJet, flying to multiple destinations in the Americas and Europe. Air Canada and Flair are two other prominent operators with a significant destination list.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, fully detailed terminal interiors, realistic night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and more.  It’s available on Contrail  and FSimStudios' Store for roughly $21.44, requiring at least 7.12 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Tang0 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdhou</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Releases Houston Intercontinental Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdhou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647030a10cb90011f36c86f5_kiah1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="289678"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDreamTeam has recently released their rendition of George Bush Intercontinental Airport (KIAH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 12th busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 41 million passengers.  Inaugurated in 1969, it quickly became Houston’s busiest airport, getting all the scheduled passenger traffic that once flew into William P. Hobby, which remained open but just for general aviation traffic. It wasn’t until 1971 with Southwest Airlines that William P. Hobby Airport would also offer commercial scheduled services again.  The airport has five terminals, 161 gates, and support for jumbo jets such as the A380 and the 747 (terminal D).  It’s a hub for United Airlines, offering multiple global destinations, truly an intercontinental operation. United Express, their regional branch, also provides a significant domestic route network. Spirit Airlines and American Airlines also serve Houston with many domestic destinations.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a realistic airport definition file, a customized GSX Pro integration, full dynamic lights, PBR texturing, Parallax shaders, the new terminal c modeled from scratch with full interiors, and more.  It’s available on FSDT’s website for roughly $9.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtphl</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Philadelphia International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtphl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6473c98f39779002f0090742_phila1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="619208"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam has recently released their rendition of Philadelphia International Airport (KPHL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 21st busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 19.6 million passengers. ‍ Built as a training field in 1925, PHL got its first terminal building only 15 years later, in 1940, when they got their fair share of passenger traffic that once used to fly into Camden Central Airport instead because Philadelphia lacked the infrastructure. ‍ The military personnel demands of World War 2 converted it into a First Air Force training field, organizing and preparing various fighter and air bomber groups throughout the war. It was handed back to the city as soon as the war was over. It was also when the airport was granted its international status. ‍ In the 1950s, the airport got a new  terminal and underwent heavy expansion work, lasting up until 1970, when the entire structure was modernized. Two new terminals were built in the same decade, starting with Terminal D in 1973, and Terminal E in 1977.  ‍ American Airlines holds the majority of the market share with 63.75%, offering a considerable amount of destinations, domestic and international. Frontier is second with 11.02%, followed by Spirit, Delta, and Southwest, with 6.59%, 6%, and 4.51%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, hand-crafted pavement textures, custom jetway, custom object animation, and AI airline parking codes.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.99, requiring at least 704.85 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxikal</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Kalamata International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxikal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6474a687fa73925d4e31dc4f_kal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2647351"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has recently released their rendition of Kalamata International Airport (LGKL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the second most populous city of the Peloponnese Peninsula, Kalamata (Greece).   It was opened in 1959 as a military airfield, primarily serving as a base for the Hellenic Air Force. After nearly a decade of charter traffic, it converted into a dual-use facility in the 90s. A new passenger terminal was built in 1991.  The 2000s saw continuous work to upgrade and expand the airport, keeping up with the ever-rising passenger numbers, although on a seasonal basis.   It’s visited by multiple airlines during the summer, including the Greek carrier Aegean Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Condor, easyJet, Edelweiss, Eurowings, Jet2.com, Lufthansa, Neos, Olympic Air, Ryanair, Smartwings, Swiss, Transavia, and Volotea.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with up-to-date ground markings, detailed models with PBR texturing, a basic interior on both terminals, custom taxiway signs, 3D passengers, and custom vegetation.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.02, requiring at least 1.40 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inix12</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases A300 &amp; Beluga ST Open Beta for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inix12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647559958fd4882944d76e3f_beluga1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2633471"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniBuilds has recently made their A300-600R(F) and Beluga ST compatible with X-Plane 12 under an open beta program, allowing anyone with a copy of both products to experience their classic Airbuses on the new platform.   The A300 and Beluga, previously available on X-Plane 11 only, bring accurate flight dynamics, failures, a custom FMS, an extensively tuned flight model, PBR texturing, high-resolution cockpit displays, an electronic flight bag, interactive loading, and more. The X-Plane 12 open beta brings the following changes: ‍ It’s available for roughly $12.36 (temporarily) on the iniBuilds Store, requiring at least 3.5 GB of free disk space (each) to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wsslia</id>
    <title>WorldSky Studios Releases Lombok International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wsslia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64761dbb084f780d20984453_lombok1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="676163"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WorldSky Studios has recently released their rendition of Lombok International Airport (WADL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Lombok in Indonesia with a yearly average of 4 million passengers.  Opened in 2011 to replace Selaparang Airport, the only airport serving the island, Lombok International allowed the island to receive widebody traffic, which used to be nearly impossible with the former airport and its 2,100m long runway. Lombok’s runway is 1,200 meters longer, accommodating airplanes such as the Boeing 777 and the Airbus A330.  With a total area of 551.8 hectares, it is the second largest airport in the country after Soekarno-Hatta International, serving the metropolitan area of Jakarta.  There are expansion plans in mind for the near future (by 2028), increasing the terminal area to 28,750 square meters and adding 700 meters of runway length, along with an apron extension (from the current 63,294 square meters to 74,514).  It’s served by Batik Air, Citilink, Garuda Indonesia, Indonesia AirAsia, Lion Air, Scoot, Super Air Jet, and WingsAir.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, custom ground textures, PBR texturing, custom aerial imagery, a terminal interior, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.75, requiring at least 735 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/setcdi</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Cataratas del Iguazú Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/setcdi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647640b21df3a0f53f0f2302_igua1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1565828"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulacíon Extrema has recently released their rendition of Cataratas del Iguazú International Airport (SARI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Puerto Iguazú in Argentina with a yearly average of 1,000,000 passengers.  Inaugurated in 1943 as “Puerto Iguazú Airport,” it originally featured a small terminal with a short runway catering to the transportation needs of the local population and businesses in the region.   With the popularity growth of the Iguazu Falls, a nearby landmark, the passenger figures have risen considerably, which led to many infrastructure improvements and expansions.  In 1996, they inaugurated a brand new passenger terminal, increasing the airport’s capacity by a significant amount and allowing it to handle more traffic.  It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Córdoba, Rosario, Salta, San Salvador de Jujuy, Tucumán), Flybondi (Buenos Aires-Aeroparque), and JetSmart Argentina (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Buenos Aires–Ezeiza).   The scenery shows how the airport will look after completing the new improvement plan. It has high-quality custom jetways, custom ground textures, and a fully detailed control tower with its interior.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.93, requiring at least 633.45 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simesq</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Esquel Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simesq" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6476536a407647937a27e3af_esquel1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1155072"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Esquel Airport (SAVE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Esquel in Argentine Patagonia with a yearly average of 40,000 passengers.  Dating back to the early 20s, when the Argentine military recognized the strategic importance of establishing airfields in remote areas of the country, leading to the construction of a landing strip in Esquel in 1928.  With the increased air travel demand in the 1950s, the landing strip was finally expanded, along with the construction of a terminal building and its subsequent inauguration as a civilian airport.  Many upgrades followed throughout the next decades, culminating in its international status in 2001, opening up opportunities for tourism and business. It quickly became the gateway to Argentinian Patagonia.  To this day, it’s still an important economic driver for the city and its region, taking people to stunning national parks like the Los Alerces National Park.  It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas with a flight to Buenos Aires - Aeroparque.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport after the construction work is finished, with high-quality PBR texturing, custom jetways, custom ground textures, and a fully modeled terminal interior.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.86, requiring at least 614 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t2gorl</id>
    <title>Taxi2Gate Releases Orlando International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t2gorl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647749b784a7d531f0620a1f_mco1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3708726"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taxi2Gate has recently released their second scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator: a rendition of Orlando International Airport (KMCO), the busiest airport in Florida and seventh in the United States with a yearly average of 50 million passengers.  Orlando International started its life as Orlando Army Air Field #2 in 1942, an auxiliary field to the Orlando Army Air Base, now known as Orlando Executive Airport. Although very briefly, it was used for aircraft testing right after the war.   The Korean War saw its return as a strategic air command facility, housing B-47 Stratojets and KC-97 Stratofreighters. Then, during the Cuban Missile Crisis in 1962, it became a temporary FOB for fighter bombers and reconnaissance aircraft flying over Cuba.   Between 1974 and 1975, control of the airport was given to the FAA, where it finally became a civil-only airport. Previously, it was a joint civil-military airport, which was back then a model for other civil joint-military airports in operation (some are still operating today). After that agreement, in 1961, many airlines shifted their operation from the old Herndon Airport to Orlando International.   The opening of the Magic Kingdom at Walt Disney World in 1971 transformed Orlando into a major tourist destination, attracting traffic from all over, be it nationwide, South America, Asia, and Europe.   In 1978, they started constructing the current Landside terminal and two airside on the west side of the terminal, which reached completion in 1981. The original international concourse opened in 1984, and Airside 4 was finished in 1990 with a new International concourse. Arside 2, completing the North Terminal complex, reached its completion in 2000.  The airport has 93 gates, divided between three terminals: A, B, and C, with two airside each on A and B.   It’s a hub for Silver Airways and a focus city for Avelo Airlines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, and Spirit. Southwest leads the passenger market share with 23.54% of the yearly figures, followed by Spirit, Delta, and Frontier with 15.85%, 14.05%, and 13.06%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom photoscenery, a detailed custom mesh, full-detail buildings, numerous static objects, fencing, an up-to-date AFCAD, dynamic night lighting, PBR texturing, and more. The developers recommend turning off photogrammetry to avoid terraforming issues on bridges.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $25.77, requiring at least 2.35 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thbn2a</id>
    <title>Thranda Design Releases BN-2A Islander for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thbn2a" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646f7513212245607aea3254_thr5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="84531"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Design has recently added a new airplane to their Dynamic Generation Series lineup: the Britten-Norman BN-2A Islander, a British light utility aircraft released in 1969. ‍  The BN-2A is an evolution of the Britten-Norman BN2, which took off for the first time in 1965. With aerodynamic and flight equipment improvements, along with a slightly more powerful engine, the BN-2A turned good into better. The engines and its robust construction allow the aircraft to operate from unprepared airstrips, making it a popular choice for remote and inaccessible locations where traditional runways may be limited or absent. It soon became the airplane of choice for humanitarian missions, surveillance, aerial survey, and commercial island hops.  Seating up to nine passengers and featuring an easy way to reconfigure for cargo transportation, medical evacuation, or any task at hand, the BN-2A is versatile.  Powered by two piston engines, the Lycoming 0-540 or the Textron Lycoming TIO-540, it cruises at 140 knots, with a total range of 800 nautical miles. The combination of fuel efficiency and low operating costs has made it popular worldwide. As of late 2019, 800 islanders were still flying out of the 1,280 built.  The add-on features a fully configurable 3D instrument panel, full VR compatibility, over 50 instruments to choose from, 3D lighting, a dynamic livery editor, 8K high-resolution PBR textures, individual functional circuit breakers, detailed and accurate flight dynamics, an advanced FMOD-based sound system, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:  Special features: Feature-rich elegant fly-out menu with the following features: Flight dynamics and systems: Advanced FMOD-based sound system:  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $34.95, requiring at least 2.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Poptart for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nibn2b</id>
    <title>Nimbus Studio Updates BN-2B Islander for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nibn2b" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647a02737eb61e12abb9a49a_islander1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="150668"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Studio has recently updated their Britten-Norman BN-2B Islander, adding compatibility with X-Plane 12.    The Britten-Norman BN-2 was developed in 1963, with its creators aiming to create a reliable, cheap, and fuel-efficient aircraft. They wanted a plane that would sacrifice cruise speed or range for a higher payload, lifting more weight than the competition ever could. With 1,280 built and over 700 in use, it’s easy to say they have succeeded.  The BN-2B Islander is an improved version of the BN-2 with better soundproofing, increased takeoff, and landing weight, and minor improvements, making it more suitable for passenger transport.   The BN-2 family is known for its versatility, with an easily configurable interior that can carry passengers (up to nine), cargo, or even work as a medevac airplane. On top of all that, it’s also STOL capable, allowing it to operate anywhere in the world. It’s a British jack-of-all-trades.  The add-on features X-Plane 12 compatibility, a highly detailed 3D model, 4K textures, PBR texturing, a custom sound system, accurate handling and flight characteristics, real performance based on performance charts, and VR compatibility.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $34.95, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Highbrow for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simkho</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Khon Kaen International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simkho" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647b9946d155a5032ada4284_vtuk1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1131756"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Khon Kaen International Airport (VTUK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Mueang Khon Kaen in Thailand with a yearly average of 1,568,000 passengers.  Built by the Japanese Army during World War 2, the then airfield featured a 1,300-meter-long runway with no navigational aids, which was eventually expanded when the war ended, and the airport was converted into a civilian facility.   In 1962, the Civil Aviation Authority of Thailand revamped the airport's infrastructure for the first time, building parking lots, hangars, garages, and basic buildings to handle passenger traffic. A year later, Thai Airways started flying to Khon Kaen with a DC-3 from Bangkok to Ubon Ratchathani, carrying passengers, cargo, and mail.   A new passenger terminal was approved in 2017, expanding the airport's size to 45,500 square meters. The construction work started a year later. The finished project should raise the passenger handling capabilities to 5.5 million passengers a year and support wide-body aircraft like the Airbus A330 and the Boeing 777.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D terminal and its interior, an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, custom jetways, and custom night lighting.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $18.07, requiring at least 344.83 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
