<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-11-30T18:27:04.194427+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/trmufx</id>
    <title>Toliss Releases Major Update for A340-600</title>
    <updated>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/trmufx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637d19ca14369c697e5feb80_706093809_A340-600-2021-11-0321_19_14.png.1d10b954a4a6df9706959c35682af4ec.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1104000"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Toliss have been hard at work to release their newest update on the A340-600 that most people have been waiting for. We can now see a completion of their EFB, CPDLC has been introduced and now has native support for Mac M1 users. Version 1.2 of the Toliss A340 contains lots of new features to enhance the user’s experience when flying in the sim such as being able to communicate to Air Traffic Controllers via the Hoppie Network and also to calculate accurate performance data for takeoff and landing using their newly updated EFB. On the EFB, you will see an interactive checklist that you can customize to your liking by changing the XML files. You will also see that you can obtain a METAR through the EFB for any user-selectable airport. A new feature that Toliss has worked on is the compatibility for Mac users by adding M1 chip support to allow for better performance when using the aircraft. ‍ A full changelog for Version 1.2 can be seen below: Major new features: - EFB TO performance calculator for detailed TO performance calculation considering Anti Ice, Packs, etc. - EFB LDG performance calculator including METAR retrieval (X-plane 11 and X-plane 12 built-in weather) for user-selectable airport - EFB interactive checklist page with user-customizable checklists via xml files. - CPDLC integration based on the Hoppie network - Native M1 support on Mac OS.   Minor new features: - Added icing model to our custom engine model - Added option to always use the simbrief wind data for wind requests (independent of x-plane WX setting) - Texture improvements - Added pilot models in external view   Bug fixes: - Fixed chocks logic for start with engines running - Improved anti-ice operation in XP12 - Selecting an RNP value of 0.3NM or less with an RNAV approach will make it an RNP-AR approach - Improved glide slope capture behaviour - Improvements to Direct To function with abeam points - Fixed decals on rear doors - Fixed kink in passenger window frame on left side of mid fuselage If you are looking to fly the Toliss A340 for X-Plane then why not head to the X-Plane.org Store to make the purchase for $67.49. This product is currently on sale for $67.49 which is 25% off, please be aware when this sale ends the price will go back to $89.99.   Keep your eyes peeled for further news made by Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrbufm</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Beta Update 1.29.30.0 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrbufm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637d741cf1312cb102f80d38_airbus1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="545674"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has released another beta update (1.29.30.0) to Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing issues with the iniBuilds A310-300 and the Software Development Kit. Most notably, the SimBrief integration (flight plan import) is back, sound improvements were made (including the GPWS), the mitigation of some FMS crashes, top of descent no longer triggering too early, and texture fixes in the cockpit (trim wheel and yoke).  The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ Textures: ‍ ‍ EFB/IFE: ‍ ‍ Sounds: ‍ ‍ FMC/Systems: ‍ ‍ SDK  ‍ Please refer to this guide for instructions on how to join the public beta to install the aforementioned update. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrsafm</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Sevilla Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrsafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637f811e667b8007173ffbb0_sevilla1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2093802"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just released their rendition of Sevilla Airport (LEZL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport in Western Andalusia (Spain), averaging 6 million passengers per year before the pandemic. Mainly served by Vueling and Ryanair, it’s also visited by Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Iberia, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, and many others, forming a significant network of domestic and intra-european routes.  ‍ The scenery features high-fidelity 3D modeling, detailed apron and surrounding areas, hand-corrected orthoimagery, custom DEM mesh, PBR texturing, current ground layout, realistic night lighting, and optimized for good performance.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for approximately $16.95, requiring at least 2.05GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddrmdm</id>
    <title>Digital Design Releases Moscow Domodedovo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddrmdm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6380aa6abfcba73f6cae286c_domo1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="493718"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Digital Design has recently released their rendition of Moscow Domodedovo Airport (UUDD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest of the four major airports in Moscow, and the eighth in Europe, with an average of 30 million passengers per year. It’s the hub for Red Wings, S7, Smartavia, and Ural Airlines, covering the domestic market with a significant route network. It doesn’t get much international action because of recent political events.   The scenery features highly detailed airport objects, fully modeled terminal interiors, high-resolution textures, customized ground textures for realistic winter looks, animated airport vehicles, custom jetways, animated people in the terminals, and custom aerial imagery.  It’s available on SimMarket for $20.82, requiring at least 2.9 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jrofms</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Oslo Gardermoen for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jrofms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63829cb4b222def75e3b76c4_oslo1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="708886"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. JustSim has just released their rendition of Oslo Gardermoen (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Oslo in Norway and boasting a network of 26 domestic and 158 international destinations, amounting to an average of 28 million passengers a year. It’s the busiest airport in the country.  It is a hub for Flyr, Norse Atlantic, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe, responsible for the busiest domestic routes, with almost 8 million passengers a year heading to Trondheim, Bergen, Stavanger, or Tromso.   The scenery features an accurate representation of Gardermoen as it currently stands, with an updated ground layout, custom jetways, a deicing area, and landside objects.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $24.37, requiring at least 3.35 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrmxup</id>
    <title>Leonardo Releases Maddog X Update</title>
    <updated>2022-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrmxup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6383f26163dc0a6168eee986_leo1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2051648"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Leonardo Software House has recently released an update to their Maddog for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing feature parity with the P3D version by adding ACARS, CPDLC, integration with SimBrief and GSX Pro, and several bug fixes. The changelog follows down below: ‍ ******1.1b123 - 27/11/2022****** MSFS2020 edition ‍ &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;[NEW] - GSX Pro integration; - Simbrief integration for automatic download of latest OFP from EFB; ‍ &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;[FIXED] SYSTEMS - fixed issue with autoland align mode; - fixed issue that caused FMS in descent to slow down to 250kt below FL100 even if restriction was cancelled; - fixed issue in Load Manager where in some cases routes created with the LM where not availables as coroute in the FMS; - fixed issue with cockpit flood light; - fixed issue in fms not loading approaches in certain airports; - cabin pax light now dimmed also when seat belt switch on, reduced lights when dimmed (when off ground); - improved holdings; - added all missing ACARS pages; - added weather clients for METAR/ATIS (VATSIM/IVAO) and CPDLC; - added printing of ACARS message to physical printer or Pushover app; - OFP selection in EFB is now from a sorted list of files; EFFECTS - fixed issue with effects with latest MSFS version; - reworked contrails effect; 3D MODEL - fixed hole in the upper left vc window border; - fixed issue with missing reflections in instruments glass; DOCUMENTATION - updated User Manual, Quick Guide and EFB Manual; OTHER - added tray application MDClient to overcome limitation of the sandboxed environment; - removed routes folder from the aircraft folder, the common routes folder under Maddog X Files it is now used; - moved PM calls and attendant voices to the 'VOICES' slider in MSFS; - improved first-load MSFS compile time. As previously stated, the integration took a while because they had to develop a “bridge” to interact with the sandboxed environment of Microsoft Flight Simulator, allowing it to communicate with external applications. According to their statement, the “breakout” will also pave the way for future expansions and a return to normal development pace.  The Maddog is available on SimMarket for roughly $77.81, requiring at least 298 MB of free disk space to install.  Credits to Saffa-Jake on Discord for the scoop, and the images are courtesy of thoar. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orltim</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Lamezia Terme International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orltim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6384d182003dfe5a8a21703b_lica1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1936494"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Lamezia Terme International Airport (LICA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the principal airport of Calabria, with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. Regularly visited by ITA, Ryanair, Edelweiss, easyJet, and WizzAir, the traffic peaks during the summer, where other airlines also fly down to Calabria, such as Air Transat, Austrian, Condor, Eurowings, Finnair, Smartwings and Transavia.   The airport opened in June 1976, with the first modernization and expansion happening in 1982. Recently, the runway was extended from the original 2,414 meters to 3,017 meters. In 2008, Engco won a competition to design a new passenger terminal, aiming to expand the limited capacity of the old one, which grew unable to handle such volume. The idea was to build the new one while progressively demolishing the old terminal, keeping both functioning simultaneously until the progress was finally complete. Due to lack of funding, the plans never came to fruition.   The scenery features a detailed representation of the entire airport area, with an up-to-date layout (as of October 2022) featuring the new extended apron and the runway extension, custom static aircraft (an AB 412 and a Canadair CL-415 that operate at the airport), projected mesh groundpoly, custom GSE and clutter, an animated radar, and custom taxi signs and approach lighting.   It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $16.49, requiring at least 2.79 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bawrcs</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases Cirrus SR-22 Sound Set for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bawrcs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6384d7e6c7b43ad6ce2ddc42_boris.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1922471"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Known for their work on the freeware FlyByWire A32NX, and the Cirrus Sound Set for X-Plane, Boris Audio Works has released their Cirrus SR-22 sound set for Microsoft Flight Simulator, after 9 months of development and 50 hours of high fidelity recordings from a real airplane with an industry-standard microphone. It’s only compatible with the Deluxe Edition of MSFS, which has the SR-22 among the extra aircraft lineup.   The feature list follows down below: -Interior and exterior engine sounds, -Avionics and ventilation fans, -Levers, buttons, and switches, -Flaps, -Ground roll, -Wind and cabin air vent whistle sounds, -Differences of sound when on ground vs. in air, -and much more.  It’s available on the Threshold Store for $15.00, and on SimMarket for roughly $15.56, requiring at least 12 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/trtafm</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Trieste Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/trtafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6384ed25f9f58a6766e0c279_trop1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1008795"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released their rendition of Trieste Airport, also known as Aeroporto Friuli-Venezia Giulia (LIPQ), for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With nearly 800.000 passengers a year, TRS serves the city of Trieste in Italy and its surroundings, with a catchment area nearing 5 million people due to the proximity to the border with Slovenia, Austria, and Croatia.   It’s frequently visited by Ryanair with 8 destinations (Bari, Cagliari, Catania, London Stansted, Malta, Naples, Palermo, and Valencia), with three more to come shortly (Barcelona, Charleroi,  and Dublin). Lufthansa also flies to Trieste from Frankfurt and ITA Airways from Rome.   The founding of Trieste Airport is unknown, but the first mention of it dates back to November 1935, when it housed a wing of the Royal Italian Air Force. Commercial operations took off in December 1961.   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with native MSFS night lighting, animated jetways, seamless integration with the default Bing imagery, usage of SDK materials and native gITF models, and PBR textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.12, requiring at least 770 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrpafm</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Patch 1.29.30.0 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrpafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6385351cbb8ea76ae93ffbb1_aib2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="724870"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently made patch 1.29.30.0 available on the normal branch of Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing several crashes, an issue with the Guimbal Cabri G2, and a potential crash when requesting missing or malformed waypoint, VOR or NDB, along with a major update to the iniBuilds A310-300, including improvements to the EFB and overall performance, texture fixes, revamped audio (including AI), mitigation of FMS crashes, and the Top of Descent now triggers when it should.  The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ General Bug Fixes ‍ Airbus A310-300 ‍ Known Issue Accessing the secondary flight plan without a primary flight plan entered may cause the aircraft to lock-up. Textures EFB/IFE ‍ Sounds ‍ FMC/Systems ‍ ‍ Tooltips ‍ ATC ‍ SDK Microsoft Flight Simulator is available on the Microsoft Store and on Steam, starting from $69.99, requiring at least 150 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baarst</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Seattle-Tacoma for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baarst" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638647698be4d403721765a1_sea1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1770240"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the World and AmSim teamed up to build a rendition of Seattle-Tacoma International Airport (KSEA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, released earlier today. Sea-Tac is the busiest airport in the Pacific Northwest, with over 50 million passengers per year (before the pandemic), serving both Seattle and Tacoma, situated almost equidistantly between both (23 km away from Downtown Seattle and 29 km away from Downtown Tacoma).    It’s the hub for Alaska and Delta, with a huge domestic network covering both the west and east of the United States, along with several international routes with either Delta or the several other airlines that visit Seattle everyday, such as Air Canada, American Airlines, British Airways, Japan Airlines, Turkish Airlines, and Virgin Atlantic. It totals up to 91 domestic and 28 international destinations!  The scenery features animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures and dirt, surrounding buildings, night lighting, and parallax windows.   It’s available on Orbx Direct for $22.75, requiring at least 2.01 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdpale</id>
    <title>Tailstrike Designs Prague Airport Landing in Early December for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdpale" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63864d94ee4a3b1216f75c8a_prg01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="538436"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Tailstrike Designs made an announcement on their Discord with a release date and further information on the upcoming Václav Havel Airport Prague (LKPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which should be landing on the 5th of December. With 85 years of history and a yearly average of 15 million passengers, PRG is the main gateway to the country, home to Czech Airlines and Smartwings.   Aside from CSA and TVS, it’s also a base for Eurowings Europe and Ryanair, with a significant route network both intra-european and transcontinentally. It’s regularly visited by Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Emirates, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and many other. Amsterdam, Paris and Moscow are among the three busiest destinations in terms of passenger volume.  The scenery will include Aerosoft VDGS, highly detailed models with photoreal textures, custom runway, taxiway, apron, and stands layout, modeled terminal interiors, accurate taxiway signage, custom airport service road traffic, accurate terrain slope, high resolution aerial imagery, custom jetways per pier, and stands with accurate parking codes.   There’s a trailer for the product which is still private, but should be made available on the 5th. There’s no information regarding pricing and install size yet.  Shout out to Tang0 on Discord for the scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/frbafm</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Bremen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/frbafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638666fb2b78abe3bb1830f5_bremen1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2318490"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Sim Development Group has just released their rendition of Bremen Airport (EDDW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city and state of Bremen in Northern Germany with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. The route network is mostly intra-european, served by airlines such as Corendon, Eurowings, KLM, Lufthansa, Ryanair, SundAir, Turkish, and WizzAir.   The airport was built in the early 1900s, when a local aerospace club ran a couple experimental flights at the site that would then become Bremen Airport. It was then transformed into a military airport during WW1, with a reopening in 1920, when KLM had a scheduled flight to Amsterdam. In the 1930s, it was repurposed as military airfield, serving as a training base for the Luftwaffe, housing a squadron of Focke-Wulf Fw 200 bombers between late-1939 and mid-1940. It was heavily bombarded and partially destroyed, repaired in 1945, when the US Army took over and repurposed it as an airbase, only to be handed back in 1949.  The scenery features an accurate representation of Bremen Airport, with fully customized vehicles and facilities, realistic light environment and interior modeling, seasonal changes, reflective textures, compatible with GSX and Landmarks of Germany, including a custom GSX profile and a user manual.  It’s available on FSDG’s Store for roughly $23.35.  Shout out to Tang0 for the scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/frsvjg</id>
    <title>FlightFX Releases SF50 Vision Jet G2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/frsvjg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6386a9c61abb3d289023c24b_cirrus1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2537729"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has just released their SF50 Vision Jet G2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engine very light jet manufactured by Cirrus Aircraft. With a ceiling of 31000 feet, 311 knots of cruise speed, 1275 nautical miles of range, and a modern glass cockpit, it’s the private jet of choice for many people around the globe, with 350 built as of June 2022.  The SF50 features a custom G3000 (based on the Working Title G3000), three different seating configurations following real-life specifications (executive, family, and complete), custom integrated checklists, dynamic aircraft registration, high-quality texturing with performance in mind, visual icing effects, a comprehensive package of custom sounds, and more. The full feature list follows down below: ‍ Details • Model tested by real world Vision Jet pilots. ‍ • A reworked and optimized navigation suite based off of the Working Title G3000 (included in package). ‍ • Custom V.A.M.S. (Virtual Aircraft Management System) that controls all aspects of aircraft status. ‍ • Bose Active Noise Reduction system that can be activated right from the V.A.M.S. ‍ • Three different seating configurations that match its real-life counter part (Executive, Family and Complete). ‍ • Custom-built Initialization Screen. ‍ • Custom G3000 integrated checklists. ‍ • Dynamic aircraft registration appears on placard, Primary Flight Display, aircraft storage cover, and chocks. ‍ • Radio frequency IDs built into the PFD. ‍ • Engine and Aircraft performance pages. ‍ • Accurate interior/exterior lighting design, including the iconic courtesy lights setup. ‍ • Accurate two-step start procedure synonymous to the Vision Jet. ‍ • Revamped fuel reporting system to mimic the real-life aircraft. ‍ • Selectable ground power unit with custom audio. ‍ • Interactive luggage and loading system with prepopulated weights and trip selections. ‍ • Custom emergency gear deployment system. ‍ • Integrated CAS messages and audio warnings. ‍ Model Details ‍ • Painstakingly optimized for performance ‍ • A multitude of custom sounds recorded on site with professional recording equipment including ‍ GPU Rain Wind and cabin noises Drag noises Mechanicals Annunciators and warnings Doors Ground roll Buttons, switches and knobs • Extremely high quality texturing without killing frame rates ‍ • Supports MSFS visual icing effects and includes enhanced animated de-ice boots. ‍ • Includes three liveries derived from actual Vision Jet paint schemes. ‍ • Detailed interior and exterior textures for ultimate realism. ‍ • Intuitive cockpit camera views for quick cycling through instruments. ‍ It’s available on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $24.99, requiring at least 4.21 GB of free disk space to install. Pricing may vary per country due to regional pricing practices.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrana</id>
    <title>Sierrasim Simulation Releases Antonio Nariño Airport for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrana" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63876d7514c0205a7d922c71_pasto1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1853382"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Sierrasim Simulation has just released their rendition of Antonio Nariño Airport (SKPS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, located in Chachagüí (Colombia) and serving the city of Pasto (popularly known as Pasto Airport). With its table top runway built on a plateau and an elevation of 5,951 feet with only 2,312 meters of runway length, one of the trickiest approaches in Colombia. It is often rendered useless during certain days because of crosswinds that make takeoff and arrivals an impossible - and unsafe - task, especially in August.   The visitor's list includes Avianca and Latam Colombia, with routes to Bogotá and Cali, EasyFly to Cali, and Viva Air Colombia to Cartagena and Medellín. The overall figure amounts to 330,000 passengers yearly (as of 2019).   The scenery features textures and models based on aerial imagery, photo-realistic PBR textures for buildings and vehicles, orthophoto, sloped runway, performance-focused optimization, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:  It’s available on SimMarket for $11.39, requiring at least 774 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arbafm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Bratislava Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arbafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63877645b09f12d126dd36fb_brat1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="268524"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has just released their rendition of Bratislava Airport (LZIB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport of Slovakia, with a yearly average of 2.2 million passengers. Its slovak name (Letisko M. R. Štefánika) is after general Milan Rastislav Štefánik, victim of an airplane accident in 1919.   Due to its proximity to Vienna International Airport (LOWW), it’s often considered a cheaper alternative by LCCs. It’s the hub for AirExplore and an important city for Ryanair, Smartwings, and Wizzair. Traffic gets busier during the summer, when seasonal charters take people to coastal cities like Brač and Antalya.   The scenery features aerial imagery covering the airport surroundings, optimized 3D objects, detailed passenger terminal interior, animated passengers inside the airport and in the vicinity, true-to-life logistic parks and delivery centers, and more. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍  It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for $16.99, requiring at least 5 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
