<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-06-22T18:24:01.922195+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftkric</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Richmond International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftkric"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6672af70aae102505ed0d456_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere recently released its rendition of Richmond International Airport (KRIC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the Greater Richmond Region, it is situated approximately 7 miles from downtown Richmond and accommodates over 4.75 million passengers annually. The airport underwent several name changes before becoming Richmond International Airport. In 1927, it was dedicated as Richard Evelyn Byrd Flying Field and then renamed Richard E. Byrd Airport in 1950. It wasn't until 1984 that it became known as Richmond International Airport. Over the years, the airport has undergone various upgrades and expansions and has seen an increase in passenger traffic and aircraft movements. Today, airlines such as Breeze Airways, Southwest Airlines, and Spirit Airlines offer flights to destinations all over the United States. The newly released Richmond International Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator comes with numerous features, including highly detailed buildings, PBR texturing, a partially modeled internal terminal, custom animated jetways, improved lighting, and more. The add-on requires 693.80 MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $16.09. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tf24we</id>
    <title>Threshold at FSExpo 2024: What to Expect</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tf24we"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66742d6a006bf686a9ebd7c1_threshold_at_FSExpoV2.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Time has just flown away, and FlightSimExpo 2024 starts tomorrow! North America’s largest flight simulation event drew over 3,000 attendees last year, and is expected to draw even more at this year’s event in Las Vegas! With such a large concentration of flight simulation enthusiasts and developers in one place, there are bound to be many exciting announcements and updates during the event, and the Threshold team will keep you up to date with coverage from around the event, live from Las Vegas!  The freshest news will be on our social media pages, and we’ll be posting live updates there from the #FSExpoFriday announcements, as well as a live stream on our YouTube channel. We’re also interviewing some pretty big names at the event, so keep an eye out for those! Don’t want to miss out on the news but can’t watch it live? Don’t worry, because at the end of each day we will have roundup articles putting all the day’s news in one place! If you’re attending the event in person, come stop by the Media Partner Lounge and say hi! We hope you’re as excited for the event as we are to cover it, so stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news, reviews, and more!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcrepa</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Charlie Rudder Pedals Enter Production, Ship In August</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcrepa"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66744690048554085c9e1285_HC_Pedals_02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. After many months of uncertainty, and with questions still swirling about the status of the company as a whole, Honeycomb Aeronautical’s highly anticipated Charlie Rudder Pedals have gone into production today and will finally ship to customers starting in August, according to a statement from Aerosoft. Early this year, Honeycomb fell into hot water as many months of radio silence led to a statement by the company’s CEO, Nicki Repenning, admitting that they were struggling financially, and that his former business partner and CEO of Snakebyte-group, Mike Steup, hid this information from him and stole pre-order money set aside for the Charlie Rudder Pedal production had “gone elsewhere.” Snakebyte and Mr. Steup denies these allegations. Threshold interviewed Mr. Repenning as a culmination of a weeks-long initial investigation, which you can read here.  According to Aerosoft, production of the pedals has started today and they have been able to “test the pre-production models extensively,” and they are “impressed by the quality of the materials and the realistic feel of the pedals.” Aerosoft plans to start deliveries on August 29th. As a compensation for the long waiting time, all customers who have pre-ordered the Charlie Pedals via the Aerosoft Shop or have already pre-ordered them will receive an Aerosoft Shop voucher worth 30€ ($32.17USD). Aerosoft also says that those who are attending this weekend’s FlightSimExpo in Las Vegas can try out the Charlie Pedals at their booth. As a special promotion for the UEFA European Championship, New customers can get a Honeycomb Alpha Yoke at a discounted price of 199.99€ ($214.43USD), for as long as the German national team is in the tournament. The Charlie Pedals can now be pre-ordered on the Aerosoft Shop for 369.99€ ($396.70USD).  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ininbo</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Nairobi Jomo Kenyatta Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ininbo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66748aedb0f1674b8548971a_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has released its long-awaited rendition of Jomo Kenyatta Airport (HKJK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Nairobian airport serves the capital of Kenya, with nearly 2.000.000 passengers operations yearly.  After facing many challenges during the 4-year construction, Embakasi Airport was opened for use in 1958. Equipped with a 3.048 meters long (10.000 feet) paved runway, it is suitable for use throughout the entire year, and all its weather conditions. Four years later, in 1972, a major expansion of the airport began, including the construction of a new international and domestic terminal, a dedicated cargo terminal, new taxiways and aprons, police and fire stations, as well as car parks. In 1978, after the expansion was finished, the airport was renamed in honor of President Jomo Kenyatta. The airport receives service from more than 40 airlines to over 70 destinations on 4 continents. Aside from passenger service, Jomo Kenyatta Airport is also one of the biggest cargo hubs in Africa, serving 13 cargo airlines such as Emirates SkyCargo, Martinair, Lufthansa Cargo, Astral Aviation, Cargolux, and EgyptAir Cargo, to a total of 41 destinations IniBuilds’ rendition of Jomo Kenyatta International Airport features hand-made ground textures for roads, runways, taxiways, true-to-life airport landside representation (custom ground decals, vegetation, signposts, parking barriers, etc.), custom vehicles, dynamic night lighting, and GSX profile. This scenery is available for purchase on the iniBuilds store for roughly $19.00 and will require at least 5.31 GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msculv</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update 8: Las Vegas for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msculv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667490babe826b4c82953e52_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released its latest city update, City Update 8: Las Vegas, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new update includes this year's host city of FSExpo, also well known as Sin City. Users can now visit an enhanced Las Vegas and take in all its sights. Las Vegas has been significantly enhanced with eye-popping resolution through high-resolution aerial imagery, digital elevation model data, and high-fidelity TIN surface modeling, providing users with a highly accurate portrayal of the city to explore. The new city update is available for free on the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdtur</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases Turweston Aerodrome for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdtur"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667499afab799ba0188b15c6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Burning Blue Design has recently released its newest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This time, it’s Turweston Aerodrome (EGBT). This aerodrome is situated in Turweston, Buckinghamshire, and serves as both a business park and the headquarters of the Light Aircraft Association (LAA). Turweston Aerodrome opened in 1942 as RAF Turweston. Over the years, it served as a training base for various squadrons within the Royal Air Force Bomber Command. After the end of World War II, the aerodrome was used for agricultural purposes before becoming a hub for general aviation. Today, the aerodrome is home to several entities including flight schools. It is also closely located to the racing track Silverstone, making it a convenient hub for events at the race track. Turweston Aerodrome boasts numerous features, including custom 3D objects, PBR textures, a hangar interior, animated hangar doors, a working fuel truck, a dynamic fountain, dynamic spectators and vehicles, custom terraforming, night lighting, and more. Turweston Aerodrome is now available on Burning Blue Design for roughly $16.39. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsct1</id>
    <title>Moza Teases Flight Sim Controls</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsct1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66751a5df0f6e0677a7c03ed_FB_IMG_1718950050245.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Sim racing hardware powerhouse Moza Racing is expected to announce their entry into the world of flight simulation. The UK based company are mainly known for their wheel bases and pedal sets teased the announcement on their facebook page saying “something revolutionary is coming soon. A game-changer is taking flight at the FlightSimExpo(sic). Stay tuned for more!” Accompanying the post is a picture that looks to depict a flight stick and base, a throttle system, and rudder pedals. ‍ Threshold’s own Drew Webb will be in attendance to bring you further updates on this story!Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for the flight simulation news that matters to you!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/330621</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes New A330 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/330621"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675cfa9c0ad8f263b81ce83_aerosoftmeme1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently published a new development update on their upcoming Airbus A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with a brief status update on how the ordeal is progressing on models, systems, sounds, etc. ‍ Before even getting into how the project is progressing, they explained their change of direction from an initial seemingly straightforward port of their Prepar3d version, which eventually evolved into something that aimed to fully take advantage of the new platform, along with more engine options and the like. ‍ The 3D model is complete on all engine variants, and the general systems are also nearly ready, with only the Neo RRs still being at 80%. On the other hand, the autopilot is still at 30% on every variant and sounds still need work.  ‍ There are no significant changes to their schedule. They plan to release a Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version with a free upgrade to 2024 later.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p4232i</id>
    <title>Parallel42 Releases A320 Immersion Pack</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p4232i"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675d57e32c0d8d674d99f80_k2gKOp67iLg-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 (//42) has just released A320 Immersion package for MSFS. This addon is the first addon from the Immersion series for MSFS, after 16 packs for various aircraft for FSX and P3Dv2-5. The Immersion packs aim to upgrade already existing simulator effects and add new effects to improve the user experience. The A320 Immersion is an All-in-One A320 visual effect package that is compatible with the most used renditions of the A320 family: Fenix, FlyByWire, IniBuilds and LatinVFR A320 series. This package will include 17 effects that are designed to enhance the overall experience, some of those effects are wing vortices and condensation, skid marks, engine condensation, contrails, St. Elmo’s fire, APU and engine heat blur, hot brakes smoke, rain on wheels, and many more. For the immersion package to work, SimFX is required. As of the publishing of the article, this add-on is available for purchase only at the Parallel 42 store for $15.00 and is expected to be available on OrbxDirect, PC and Xbox Marketplace, and Contrail Store. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozab9</id>
    <title>MOZA Unveils Flight Simulation Gear at FSExpo 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozab9"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675d8e84e14f9d2c66a201e_Screenshot%202024-06-21%20164559.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. MOZA, known for their state-of-the-art direct-drive steering wheels, has recently entered the flight sim world by announcing a flight stick, force-feedback base, throttle, and rudder, aiming to bring flight simulation to a new dimension. The AB9 Base will feature 9 Nm high torque dual servo motors, providing strong and direct force feedback, enhanced by a force feedback algorithm that aims to accurately replicate the feel of a real airplane, configurable via their own Cockpit Control Software. Its complete feature list follows below: The MH16 Joystick aims to replicate the controls of real fighter jets. Its aluminum alloy construction warrants sturdiness and reliability, and it has detachable modular components for maximum customizability. It also has 27 entirely customizable input signals and is universally compatible with third-party bases. The MTP Throttle Panel and MTLP Landing and Takeoff Panel aim to replicate fighter aircraft controls with extended throttle travel, customizable detents, and thirty-five physical switches. They feature infinitely adjustable resistance, real-time airspeed feedback via a vibration module, and high-precision angle sensors.  The MRP Rudder Pedals are adaptable to various aircraft types, from fighter jets to helicopters, offering maximum flexibility.  Pricing information has yet to be made available, but Threshold will keep you posted! Please refer to their website for further info. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkbb75</id>
    <title>MK Studios Previews Bluebird 757</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkbb75"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675dfbcd65102094d5917e6_448548242_875730297908592_2952996330623077927_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer MK Studios has shared some preview images of the upcoming BlueBird 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The post comes ahead of BlueBird’s presentation at Flight Sim Expo where they’re expected to show the aircraft in more detail.  The post has a selection of screenshots featuring the 757 wearing the iconic Iceland Air Hekla Aurora livery with the aircraft on the ground at MK Studio’s rendition of Keflavik Airport (BIKF). Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for all your breaking flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcodrd</id>
    <title>X-Codr Releases Denver Intl' Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcodrd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675dc95f87ff38000a3faff_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. X-Codr has recently released their rendition of Denver International Airport for MSFS. This airport, also known as DIA, serves the Denver metropolitan area and Front Range Urban corridor. With over 75,000,000 passenger operations and more than 660,000 aircraft operations per year, DIA is the third busiest airport in the USA and the sixth busiest in the world. After 6 years of construction, DIA was finally open for public use in 1996 and replaced the older Denver Stapleton Airport. The first flight to land at the new airport was United 1474 from Colorado Springs, while the first flight to depart was United 1062, to Kansas City. Originally, the airport had 5 runways: 7/25, 8/26, 16L/34R, 17L/35R, and 17R/35L, and all of them were of the same length: 12,0000ft. This changed in 2003 when 16R/34L was built to accommodate fully loaded A380s and B747s in hot and high conditions. With its length of 16,000ft, only 6 other runways in the world are longer. DIA consists of a single terminal named The Jeppesen Terminal and consists of three concourses: Concourse A - used by Delta Air Lines, Frontier, JetBlue and United Airlines, Concourse B - used by United Airlines and Concourse C - primarily used by Southwest Airlines, as well as American Airlines and regional airlines. More than 30 airlines fly to over 100 destinations across 4 continents from Denver, as well as 7 cargo airlines to 34 destinations, mostly in the USA. X-Codr’s rendition of Denver International Airport features Highly detailed models and high-resolution textures, Custom models for all airport buildings, modelled terminal interiors, custom jetways textures, high-quality ground textures, blended orthoimagery, custom animated runway guard and wig-wag lights, accurate airport data, ​up-to-date airport layout, and performance optimisation. ‍ This scenery is available for purchase on OrbxDirect for roughly $22.15 and will require at least 8.50GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flightsim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flaming-cliffs-2024-update-announced</id>
    <title>Flaming Cliffs 2024 Update Announced</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flaming-cliffs-2024-update-announced"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675e7885a530c356d73ec35_FC4_Eshop_cover_700x1000.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has recently previewed an update to the Flaming Cliffs franchise.  Flaming Cliffs is a pack of less-detailed aircraft made for players who prefer a straightforward experience, without complex systems. Some of the well-known FC aircraft are MiG-29, A-10A, and Su-27. The FC2024 update will include three planes: F-5E, F-86F and MiG-15bis.  F-5E is an exceptionally capable aircraft for air combat and unguided ground strikes. Equipped with “Sidewinders” and cannons for dogfights, the F-5E also has a BVR (beyond visual range) radar. F-86F was one of the best fighter jets during the Korean War.  Armed with 50-calibre machine guns for dogfighting and early infrared-guided air-to-air missiles. Aside from Air-to-Air, F-86F can also be equipped with unguided bombs and rockets for air-to-ground attacks. MiG-15bis was also one of the most revolutionary fighters, also one of the best fighters in the Korean War. It was unrivalled and would outmatch every aircraft in a dogfight until the F-86F Sabre came. Small and light plane, but a tough fighter. Its armament included two 23mm guns and a 37mm cannon. Existing Flaming Cliffs 3 owners can upgrade to the new update for $9.99 until the end of July when the upgrade fee will increase to $14.99. F-5E, F-86F and MiG-15bis can also be individually purchased for $14.99 each.  The exact release date is unknown, however, we know for a fact that it will come with the new DCS update. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news! ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbfsep</id>
    <title>Bluebird Simulations Shows off 757 and More </title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbfsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675f026ae53391c81d96d3e_image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Sim Expo 2024 opened with a huge announcement from the team at Bluebird Simulations who are behind the long-anticipated 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The presentation opened with a preview video showing off the aircraft both on the ground and in flight. Shervin from the Bluebird team then moved into a slideshow detailing both the 757 and 767, we’ve summarized the slides below Goal:  ‍ Focus: ‍ 767 Update: Following the 757 and 767 updates, Shervin proceeded to surprise the audience with a surprise announcement of an upcoming 787. The 787 has reportedly been in production since November of 2023. There’s currently no release date planned for the 787 but we will stay updated on these developments</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fscfse</id>
    <title>FliteSim.com Reveals New Products at FSExpo 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fscfse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675fe0699f26947dba0028c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FliteSim.com recently unveiled several new products during its presentation at this year's FSExpo in Las Vegas. After sharing fun facts about their current Force Feedback Yokes and Flight Consoles, they announced a total of four new projects. The first product to be unveiled is a G1000 Console. The new console will feature authentic buttons and knobs and has been developed from an FTD Level 5 Device. It is scheduled to be available in Q4 2024. After the G1000 Console was announced, the team proceeded to announce a new Boeing-style 737-800NG Yoke Handle. This new yoke, designed to pair with their current CLS-60/120 Yoke, will be a premium offering and will be available in Q4 2024. Furthermore, a new Force Feedback Stick Base has been unveiled. It will feature a dual motor with 15 Nm of peak force and will be available in Q4 2024 alongside the other announced products. Finally, to complete the new product lineup, the team is introducing Force Feedback Rudder Pedals. These pedals will be equipped with a single motor, providing a peak force of over 250 N. They are expected to be available in Q4 2024. To summarize, FliteSim.com announced at FSExpo 2024 that they will be releasing four new products in Q4 2024. These new products include a G1000 Console, a Boeing-Style 737-800NG Yoke Handle, a Force Feedback Stick Base, and a Force Feedback Rudder. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkskef</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Keflavik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkskef"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6676fdd9d54da70643bee8d7_FlightSimulator2024-06-1913-38-36_4472x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just released their rendition of Keflavik International Airport for MSFS. Serving the Greater Reykjavik Area, Keflavik International Airport has more than 7,500,000 passenger operations and more than 75,000 aircraft movements yearly. Built by the United States Military during WWII, the airport served as a replacement for British airfields in the northern part of Iceland. It consisted of two separate runways built 4km apart. After the war, the Meeks Field was renamed to Naval Air Station Keflavik, and in 1951, the US military returned to the airport. After the military air base in Keflavik was reestablished, passengers had to pass several military checkpoints before boarding the aircraft until 1987, when the separate civilian terminal was built. Two 10,000ft (3,000m) long runways are 200ft (60m) wide, which is enough to accommodate AN-225 and even a NASA Space Shuttle. This airport is also an important alternative in case of emergency during trans-Atlantic flights. Despite the low population of Iceland, it is a popular destination among travellers from both Europe and North America. Keflavik International Airport is a hub of two airlines: Icelandair - the flag carrier of Iceland, and PLAY - a low-cost airline. It also serves 25 airlines that fly to more than 80 destinations in the USA and Europe, as well as more than 35 seasonal destinations, mostly in Europe. Aside from passenger airlines, Icelandair Cargo flies to Boston, Liege and Los Angeles from Keflavik. MK Studios rendition of the airport features a detailed rendition of Keflavik Airport (BIKF) and Reykjavik Airport (BIRK), the up-to-date layout of the airport, custom jetways and vehicle models, modelled terminal interior, custom runway and taxiway lights and custom taxiway markings. This scenery is available for purchase on the IniBuilds store for roughly $18.98, but for the first 7 days after release, there will be a 5% discount ($18.08). It will also require at least 1.93GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
