<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-11-23T18:21:59.952351+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/the-f-104-starfighter-by-colimata-for-x-plane-12</id>
    <title>The F-104 Starfighter by Colimata for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/the-f-104-starfighter-by-colimata-for-x-plane-12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6556510a7c2262aa3c78a587_20231103rocketmotor.jpeg.57c7ef75e90fe1b79ad57e11f5b9c72b.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="73137"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. A new F-104 Star Fighter is coming to X-Plane 12 Brought to you by Colimata! The Starfighter, developed by Lockheed, is a supersonic air superiority fighter designed to quickly claim control of enemy airspace. This required it to be super maneuverable and fast. The unique characteristics of its stubby wings, T-tail empennage, and dartish shape make it unmistakable from anything else. Later, it was developed into an all-role, multi-weather aircraft during the 60s, giving it more versatility. Over two thousand airframe variants were built, with the final retirement by the Italian Air Force in 2004, after serving for over fifteen air forces. The Starfighter was fast, designed with the GE J79 turbojet giving performance up to Mach 1.7, even increasing to Mach 2 for later variants. Max thrust produced 15,880 pounds in full burner and 10,000 at military power. The fuel system is supported by tip tanks, internal tanks, and pylons, totaling up to 12,260 lbs. Colimata shared previews of the upcoming aircraft via screenshots in this forum post. These images show off the loadmaster configuration interface, allowing you to load weapons from rockets to missiles and drop tanks to various hard points on the 104's airframe. The Star Fighter will have a custom radar supporting air-to-air and air-to-ground modes. These modes offer multiple levels of complexity based on the user's skill and avionics knowledge. C functions aid with targeting hostile aircraft and armaments. Citing Colimatas post, The package will include three variants, with each unique cockpits. These models range from the G variant, S, and the 21c with the most modern cockpit. Colimanta states that all variants will come with a "versatile" nav system that will work with X-Plane flight plans. Quoting Colimatas targeting system statement. ‍ Further posts covered updates of external modeling. Colimata emphasizes details of the 3d model, such as animated systems and livery textures amounting to 4k high-resolution textures. Minor important details like the thousands of rivets, panel details, and decals across the airframe are accurately reproduced based on the real-world counterpart.   ‍ ‍ As for liveries, several will ship with the package, according to Colimata; of course, The famous, polished livery will be included. Colimata will also provide paint kits for the community's creative means of creating the numerous liveries associated with the Star Fighter. Progress is moving along strongly by their indication via their x-plane.org post with the aircraft variants in beta under shakedown testing.  A prospective release date has been announced for the F-104 FXP during the beginning of December. More information via their postings on X-Plane.Org ‍ As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/venomz</id>
    <title>Venom Zero Productions has released the F-5 Tiger II for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/venomz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65565f320106266d2d7aad76_329291_19.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1294258"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Venom Zero Productions has released the F-5 Tiger II for Microsoft Flight Simulator via SIMMARKET! The F-5 is a light supersonic fighter designed by Northrop, with the F-5 II being the most updated version. It is known for its sleek, slippery aerodynamics and maneuverable characteristics. In an air superiority role, it is also capable of ground attack. The US Air Force uses a variant of the F-5, the T-38 Talon, based on the N-156 design. This aircraft gained notoriety for its agile performance and is still in active service and holder of the International Fighter Aircraft Competition. Many countries worldwide utilize F-5 variants within their air forces, for example, the Norwegian Air Force, Royal Netherlands Air Force, Mexican Air Force, and even the Kenyan Air Force, to name a few. Powered by two GE J85-GR-21 engines with afterburning, it can produce a maximum of 5,000lbs of thrust. These GE engines help the F-5 reach speeds of nearly Mach 1. Venom Zero Productions allows users to operate nine distinct liveries representing real-world operators, including the famous fictional MiG-28 from the original Top Gun movie. The detailed 3D cockpit features all the details you would expect, including detailed backlit gauges and the ability to switch to Gun Reticle and Asobo Hud is as an added ease-of-use feature. External armaments and equipment include a range of drop tanks and weapons. Venom Zero Productions focused on the details of animating various parts and control surfaces to complete the immersive experience as well. Aim-9 MK-82 and GBU-12 will be managed through the aircraft payload and fuel system. Avionics cover a basic autopilot system and a simulated radar scan; they note that this release is primarily for entertainment and not solely for a study-level combat simulation. The F-5 can be purchased via SIMMARKET and easily installed using the Siminstaller MSFS Auto-Install and Update App, found here. The price runs from approximately USD 14.12 and can be found on the product page here. Of course stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/n2023</id>
    <title>Navigraph Launches Community Survey 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/n2023" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6557b95f5d04da36719d8489_survey.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="150515"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has just launched the sixth edition of their FlightSim Community Survey, asking the community to answer questions ranging from their preferred flight simulation platform and add-ons to the hardware they use and why they simulate, providing a complete understanding of the modern flight sim demographic.   Averaging more than 20,000 respondents since the 2020 edition, the Survey has become the go-to reference for hardware metrics, given it differs massively compared to mainstream reference data such as the Steam Hardware Survey, which takes their entire user base into account. Focusing exclusively on flight simmers, it provides a more accurate image of the most popular hardware among virtual pilots.   It also sheds light on the most popular flight sim platform, intent (whether simulating just for fun or training for a pilot’s license), simulation proficiency, and how many of us are real-life pilots.   The Survey will run for ten days from today (November 17), and the results will be published on their website in December 2023. It is entirely GDPR compliant and fully anonymous, with no personally identifiable data being collected and no redirects.   Click here to participate in the world’s most comprehensive flight simulation survey! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwdpal</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Palmerston North Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwdpal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6557ca145131f75a6465ae03_palmy.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="557028"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios has recently released their rendition of Palmerston North Airport (NZPM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Palmerston North and the Central North Island (Manawatū-Whanganui) region with a yearly average of 652,000 passengers.  It was built in 1931 by the Milson Aerodrome Society, originally consisting of a grass runway made exclusively for private flights. Commercial operation started five years later with Union Airways. ‍ After a brief period of being utilized as a military facility during World War 2, it was embraced by National Airways Corporation for scheduled service, leading to the construction of a proper runway and a terminal building.   The 1990s brought a new terminal and taxiway, with Freedom Air launching regular international flights to Brisbane and Sydney right after the work was done.  Air New Zealand (Auckland, Christchurch) and Originair (Hamilton, Nelson, and Wellington) currently serve it.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail imagery, custom ground poly, a detailed terminal interior, PBR models, 4K textures, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $12.40, requiring at least 4.43 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spitfi</id>
    <title>Flight Replicas releases the Supermarine Spitfire for FS2020</title>
    <updated>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spitfi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6557fccc9be58c8d392f92ff_393304883_1035802050724534_5308484199314486767_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="132671"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Replicas has recently made their Spitfire available on the Marketplace store. The project was first announced in March 2022 and was submitted to the Marketplace on November 16th. Flight Replicas is a developer that has previously created several war legends for Prepar3D, such as the BF-109 and the B-24 Liberator, along with the Curtiss P40 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Their earliest project dates back to 2002, which was the Messerschmitt Me-262. The Spitfire is a legendary British fighter aircraft crucial in World War II. Flight Replicas has chosen to focus on the Mk.la/Mk.IIa variant of the airframe for this recreation. The Spitfire was designed by Reginald Mitchell in the early 1930s, with its first flight taking place in March 1936, powered by the Rolls Royce Merlin III engine. The Spitfire, an iconic aircraft, is renowned for its unmistakable design silhouette that features low-drag elliptical wings. It was equipped with new design and airframe construction techniques, such as its semi-monocoque construction and aluminum alloys, making it a highly efficient interceptor. The aircraft gained altitude rapidly, earning its well-known history as a hero of the Battle of Britain. Flight Replicas has created a model of the Spitfire based on actual factory drawings and schematics.   The model has full PBR textures, a fully modeled cockpit with custom sounds, and various animations for doors, canopies, and other operational functions. Accurate liveries based on the specific variants and models during the aircraft’s development period are included. This model depicts the conversion of use to 100 octane fuel, which increased performance over 87 octane. You can purchase the Flight Replicas Spitfire model on the Marketplace for $19.49. Flight Replicas has also published the manual for the aircraft on their website free of charge. Please visit their Facebook page or website to learn more about the Flight Replicas Spitfire. You can download the manual by following this link. As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42cri</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 releases Cheat River Island </title>
    <updated>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42cri" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655809809be58c8d393a8f13_12_86be9029-fc0e-4149-b187-63a2e3d646dd.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="73666"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 is recognized for creating innovative and sensational airstrip scenes and environments for Microsoft Flight Simulator has released a new scenery add on Cheat River Island. Cheat River Island, a small grass airstrip located within the Allegheny Mountains that hosts the Cheat River Fly-Ins. According to Parallel 42, "this isnt your ordinary airstrip." The scenic location is situated on a river island and offers a variety of immersive features and animations that bring the simulation to life. The turf airstrip adds to the challenge, testing your bush flying skills. Apart from flying, Parallel 42 offers much more with the //42 Campout Utility, which lets you camp out on the island airstrip and enjoy additional entertainment. Features include custom animations like animated ziplines, lawnmower event with custom sounds, various micro scenes located around the area. The scenery also includes over six miles of road designed for their recent Juice Goose all terrain vehicle. The package also includes a bonus airstrip within the vicinity. You can purchase the Cheat River Island Scene for your PC for $12.99 from their website/Orbx, and it will soon be available on the Flight Simulator Marketplace, including Xbox.‍ Check out the newly released trailer here on YouTube. To learn more about the Cheat River Island Scene, see the Parallel 42 website via this link. Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f14btc</id>
    <title>"ON MIGHTY WINGS" Heatblur and Indiafoxtecho releases new F14 trailer.</title>
    <updated>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f14btc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65591f44f4af37fcb6399193_I_b2abhiBwwhd%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="117419"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Heatblur Simulations/Indiafoxtecho, the team behind the exceptional recreation of the F-14 in DCS, has just released a new trailer for "ON MIGHTY WINGS," which features the highly anticipated F14 Tomcat for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The two developers have collaborated to provide the most accurate rendition of the F-14 Tomcat ever created for Flight Simulator, with over a decade of development and research resulting in a highly detailed flight model for the aircraft. The Tomcat features custom systems, photogrammetry, and laser scanning for interior and exterior modeling accuracy. The trailer showcases the Tomcat's aerodynamic effects, sounds, and flight model, putting it on the "final approach" for release. With no official release date announced yet, Indiafoxtecho has hinted that "it should be a question of weeks," indicating a possible release before the end of the year. To read more on the Tomcat development, check out Their Facebook pages here. Heatblur Simulations Indiafoxtecho  As usual, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd777</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd777" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6559367fbfec72de3e60b985_1250410_20231117211153_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1847404"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published a new development update with information on the next 737 Lineup update, marketplace intake, and the upcoming 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  The next update for the 737 lineup is already with their testing team for validation, including new features developed in the background and now ready, along with structural changes that aim to improve the tablet's stability within the MSFS environment.   PMDG has added data interoperability between the airplane and tablet, allowing users to see route changes reflected in the tablet's live map and providing increased situational awareness.  As it has been the norm since build 3.00.0080, the upcoming update will focus on the Universal Flight Tablet alone. The complete changelog follows below: 0012722: [EFB - General] Metars stop functioning between 0000z and 0100z (rmurdoch) 0012788: [EFB - General] PMDG map tiles names are fuzzy (rmurdoch) 0012777: [EFB - General] Fully convert to JSON for tablet-plane comms (rmurdoch) 0012782: [EFB - General] UFT 1.2 "New route loaded" message appears too often (rmurdoch) 0012475: [EFB - Simbrief] CO RTE field not showing CO RTE name (cbpowell) 0012783: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Arrival Airport Calls for Runway, not ICAO code. (cbpowell) 0012792: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Imported Flight plan times do not match Simbrief (cbpowell) 0012645: [EFB - General] Tablet map should pick up changes made on the FMS (rmurdoch) 0012692: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Landing Dispatch Data should be imported into Landing Enroute fields (cbpowell) 0012775: [EFB - General] Tablet namespace differentiation still not working correctly (rmurdoch) ‍ They plan to release the update for PMDG.com customers around the final week of November.   Build 3.00.0082 has been submitted to Microsoft for the intake process, and PMDG believes it should become available sometime next week (Microsoft's intake process is not an exact science).  The Xbox version of the aforementioned build will take longer, as PMDG found issues with some key functions and is working with Microsoft and Asobo to find a solution.  The upcoming 777 is still being worked on, with PMDG's focus on handling characteristics and system validation. They claim it hasn't been previewed yet because they have been packing details and features into the new product that will demand time to get to where they want and that the previewing process will begin once it's nearing entering testing. PMDG believes this extra attention to development will yield a shorter testing cycle.  The current PMDG lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator is available on their website, ranging from $34.99 to $69.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hc02v1</id>
    <title>VSKYLABS releases v1.1 of the Hungarocopter</title>
    <updated>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hc02v1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65593eab033a144645213e5e_403180543_1098231718245415_2795124046560015045_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="553183"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VSKYLABS announced the development of the HC-02 in early March of this year. The early access phase for the model has recently been completed. The HC-02 model was built using an actual HC-02 as a reference, with the team working steadily on the project. Real-world feedback was obtained from HC-02 pilots to create the most realistic flight model possible for the aircraft. The Hungarocopter, designed in Hungary, is an ultralight helicopter that uses the latest design technologies and construction methods. The HC-02 is powered by a Rotax 915, which can produce up to 141 Hp, allowing it to reach cruise speeds of 87 knots. With room for two people, the helicopter has a maximum range of 400km and an endurance of 2.5 hours. VSKYLABS has spent extensive time modeling the cockpit with detail and accuracy to give VR headset users a feeling of being inside the cockpit. VSKYLABS also brought all new first simulated systems to X-Plane, such as the Electric Rescue System. According to VSKYLABS, the ERS is a  The HC-02 offers several features, including Avitab compatibility and a custom FMOD sound pack. The V1.1 update improves flight dynamics, displays, interaction, and visual model. The FMOD sound pack is now updated with additional sounds as well. The Hungarocopter is compatible with X-Plane 11/12 and is available at X-Plane.org store for $19.47 and VSKYLABS.com for $18.85. These prices are still valid as of November 18th, 2023. As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates! </summary>
    <published>2023-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfldmi</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Don Mueang International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfldmi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655a81f88a7261e2a904a19b_vtbd.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="634522"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Don Mueang International Airport (VTBD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Bangkok Metropolitan Region with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.  Built in 1914 as a Royal Thai Air Force base, it’s considered one of the oldest international airports and Asia’s oldest operating airport, with its commercial operations starting in 1924, almost a century ago. ‍ It used to be Bangkok’s main airport until the inauguration of Suvarnabhumi Airport in 2006, which took most of the traffic. It has become a low-cost airline hub, becoming the largest of its kind since 2015. ‍ It has two terminals, with T1 being utilized for international flights and T2 for domestic. Terminal 3 has been abandoned for over a decade, but there are plans to rebuild it by 2029, with a total capacity of 10 million passengers yearly. ‍ It’s a hub for Nok Air and an operating base for Thai AirAsia and Thai Lion Air. The visitors’ list includes 9 Air, Air Macau, Bangkok Airways, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, China Express Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Firefly, Juneyao Air, Korean Air, Myanmar Airways International, Okay Airways, Qingdao Airlines, Sky Angkor Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tigerair Taiwan, T’way Air, and Vietnam Airlines. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom animated jetways, up-to-date ground layout, landside buildings, south cargo terminals, and more. Future updates will add more landmarks, terminal interiors, and an animated train. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.56, requiring at least 364.76 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/miltech-simulations-showcases-ch47-development-update</id>
    <title>Miltech Simulations Showcases CH47 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/miltech-simulations-showcases-ch47-development-update" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655b219d306128e1b169c5bd_384749766_320535503819592_1456714515925682622_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="250884"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Miltech Simulations has provided a development update for their Boeing CH-47D Chinook. The update, which was posted to their Facebook page, highlights their recent focus on finishing the 3D model and texturing and also includes some new screenshots of the interior texturing.  The CH-47D Chinook is a tandem-rotor transport helicopter first developed by Vertol in 1957 and later manufactured by Boeing. The CH-47D has a maximum take-off weight of 50,000 lbs and a range of 400 nautical miles. Production started on the CH-47 in 1962 and continues to this day.  ‍ Miltech also noted some features to be expected upon release of the CH-47 including a fully modeled interior and exterior, multiple cargo types from Humvees to fully animated paratroopers, and a “comprehensive yet practical rendition” of the Chinook’s systems. Miltech has been very upfront about some systems being “for display only” due to Microsoft Flight Simulator’s limitations. Miltech also promises that an EFB will be included at launch. Another feature that was noted in the update is the inclusion of a soundtrack that is based on recordings from a Chinook. The update included a look at possibilities post-release including an expansion pack that would add other variants of the Chinook including the more modern ‘F’ variant. Currently, there is no release date set however Miltech states that PC users will see the release first with Xbox following shortly after. The stated reason for the planned delay is due to Microsoft's marketplace verification. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim updates! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dfsc</id>
    <title>Dreamfoil Releases Schweizer S300CBi</title>
    <updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dfsc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655d9dd92fffacdad218fb00_S300CBi%20-%202020-05-16%2017.45.03.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2808132"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Dreamfoil Creations, known for their Embraer 110 and Bell 407 for X-Plane, have released their rendition of the Schweitzer S300. The new helicopter is available for X-Plane 12 and will bring users an in-depth experience with this retro helicopter. The Schweizer S300CBi is a light utility helicopter originally designed by Hughes Helicopters and later produced by Schweizer. The S300CBi is the fuel-injected version of the S300CB which helps alleviate carburetor icing. The S300 is commonly used for cost-effective training and agricultural purposes. Equipped with a 180hp Lycoming HO-360-C1A, the S300 boasts a maximum payload of 950 lbs (around 430kg) and a range of 195nm. The Dreamfoil S300CBi features a VR-compatible cockpit that includes a smart menu for easy navigation. Dreamfoil has also included full PBR textures, custom animations, enhanced night lighting, and removable doors. One feature that's not common on many products that users can expect is interchangeable exhaust options that change the engine sound. Another feature users can look forward to is the comprehensive external objects pack. This pack includes equipment for sling loads, and transport wheels that allow the helicopter to be moved without using the engine. Stay tuned to Threshold for all the flight simulation news that matters to you!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fp2012</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Studios releases the Tecnam P2012 Traveler</title>
    <updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fp2012" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655e157a602883d06dafd6ca_FSS-P2006-Beta-Photos-raphifrei-13-1-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="362828"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Sim Studios, known for their Embraer E-Jet release, has now developed the Traveler. The Tecnam Traveler is a dual-piston engine aircraft widely used by commuter airlines as feeders to their route systems. The Italian aircraft manufacturer unveiled the P2012 Traveller in April 2011. CapeAir was the largest buyer, seeking to replace its aging Cessna 402 fleet. The first flight of the Traveler took place in July 2016, entering service in February 2020. Two Lycoming TEO-540C1A six-cylinder engines power the aircraft and can seat nine passengers. It can cruise at an average speed of 170 knots and reach a maximum altitude of 19,500 feet. The aircraft is versatile and can be configured for many different missions, such as cargo, medivac, personal/corporate, and more. Flight Sim Studios has launched a detailed recreation of the Tecnam Traveler for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes PBR texturing to capture material and surface details from the exterior to the interior. The model consists of a set of liveries used in real-world applications. Several mission models include Airliner, Cargo, Combi Medieval Skydiving setups, and a special Mission Platform configuration. The model uses a customized version of the G1000 NXI by Working Title, with custom CAS messages, custom engine pages, the GMC225 autopilot system, and a working FMS keyboard. FADEC systems are also modeled for the two Lycoming engines. Ease of use features include an EFB tablet with aircraft config options, moving maps, panel state loading, FSS Mission hub, and more. Custom sounds cover the entire aircraft as well.  The aircraft's flight model, system workflows, and walkaround modes are tuned and influenced by actual Traveler pilots. Flight Sim Studios also provides a 40-minute video documentation of the real aircraft and procedures. The Tecnam P2012Traveler can be purchased via Contrail for $37.25. To find out more about Tecnam Traveler follow this link to FlightSimstudios website. As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rlfmld</id>
    <title>RDPresets releases FML Marseille for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rlfmld" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655e24849b5ce3565a417d0c_HEAD.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1479109"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets releases FML Marseille for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Aéroport Marseille-Provence is an international airport located within the territory of Marignane, about 14 miles northwest of Marseille. Marseille Provence Airport opened in October 1922, and its primary service was established for flying boats. Today, the airport has two runways (13L/31R @ 11,286 Feet and 13L/31L @7776 Feet); it’s also the fifth busiest airport in France, serving over 10 million passengers a year recorded in 2019. Marseille offers 124 direct flights to 33 countries across Europe, the Middle East, Africa, and more. Marseille is also the home for Airbus Helicopters as well. The airport has two terminals, with terminal two added in 2008. The airport serves over 30 airlines, from Air France, Delta, and Lufthansa to Ryanair, EasyJet, and more. RDPresets recreates the Marseille travel experience within Microsoft Flight Simulator by creating a detailed airport recreation in its current form. Details included custom 3D-modeled terminals with highly detailed and accurate interiors with accurate signage and placards.  ‍ The exterior model features animated jetways and thousands of objects amongst the airport grounds, providing the clutter you’d expect at a major international airport. Textures are fully featured with PBR adaptations and custom ground texturing that match the real-world asphalt at LFM Marseille. Custom ground traffic, night lighting, and custom-built taxiway signage are also included in the package.   The package is available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024 via SimMarket, Contrail, and the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace (coming soon) for € 19.99/ ~20.00 USD. Make sure to check out the official release trailer by AviationLads below. ‍ As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vcscal</id>
    <title>Velocity Studios Releases Calicut International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vcscal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655e744327f27cff31649ba2_cali.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="467142"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Velocity Studios has recently released their rendition of Calicut International Airport (VOCL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Karipur, Kondotty, and the Malappuram District in Kerala, India, with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  It was inaugurated in 1988 and heavily improved in the 1990s with the help of Gulf Malayalis, collecting funds for the airport’s development. They eventually made a society (Malabar International Airport Society) to raise funds to develop the airport further. ‍ It was granted its international status in 2006, which led to more infrastructural development. ‍ It’s a hub for Air India Express and is visited by Air Arabia, Air India, Etihad Airways, flydubai, Flynas, Gulf Air, IndiGo, Oman Air, Qatar Airways, Salam Air, and SpiceJet. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom ground markings, an up-to-date ground layout, and a basic terminal interior. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.38, requiring at least 248.24 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/redwing</id>
    <title>Redwings Simulations announces the upcoming release of the Hindenburg</title>
    <updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/redwing" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655e7b89910dcfc100a7c6a9_sun2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4170570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ Redwings Simulations announces the upcoming release of the Hindenburg via their Facebook page and Discord Channel. Redwings Simulations is known for bringing the Lockheed Super Connie to the Microsoft flight simulator. ‍ The Hindenburg was the largest airship ever designed and built by the German aircraft company Zeppelin. The German Zeppelin Airline Company operated it as a long-range passenger aircraft. The Hindenburg took its first flight on March 4, 1936; during that time, it was the largest aircraft ever built, coming in at nearly 800 feet long, three times the length of the Boeing 747. The LZ-129 carried 140,000 cubic meters of hydrogen. The LZ-129 was propelled through the air by ten Maybach engines, five mounted to the airframe as "engine cars." It could cruise at a maximum speed of 84 miles per hour and cruised at 78 miles per hour.  ‍ The Hindenburg could carry up to 50+ passengers comfortably with spacious amenities. Passengers could reside between two different decks, A and B deck. The accommodation included promenade areas, dining rooms, lounges, a reading/writing room, and 25 cabins available for passengers. The aircraft had a smoking room, a kitchen crew, officer's mess hall, a bar, restrooms, and a pursers' office on B deck. The Hindenburg could travel up to 8,700 miles at around 1,500 feet, flying over 1,000 passengers during its operational lifetime. The Hindenburg took on ocean liners as a new alternative to transatlantic ocean liner travel.  ‍ ‍ Meeting its demise on May 6, 1937, in a fiery crash on approach to the naval facility in Lakehurst, New Jersey. The accident claimed the lives of 36 of the 97 people aboard. To this day, the cause of the explosion is still unknown but is thought to be due to a leak and static discharge from the atmosphere. ‍ ‍Hindenburg relives in Microsoft Flight Simulator thanks to Red WING Simulations. Red WINGS accurately recreated the model in its former glory by covering all the details of the original through accurate modeling and texturing based on blueprint drawings of the actual Hindenburg. The model features functional cockpits and engine decks, modeled decks with crew and passenger areas, and maintenance corridors. PBR texturing is incorporated into texturing as well.  ‍ ‍The flight model in Redwings has been designed with airship particularities in mind , with new A.I. roles included. This simulator takes you back to the early days of aviation communication, where Morse code was used. The electrical systems are faithfully recreated in the simulation, allowing you to complete tasks manually or with the assistance of the A.I. ‍ The package will also include mooring mass such as the Empire State Building. Custom world maps for Hindenburg include weather details, drift headings displayed QDM/QDR ground stations, and more.  The flight model incorporates the effects of temperature, windspeeds, atmospheric pressures, ballast, gas volume, and other airship operational variables. The simulation also takes into account the need for repairs and routine maintenance. The package will also include additional liveries. The Hindenburg will be available soon for P.C. and XBOX. There is no official news of a release date yet, but RedWINGS indicates its release to be soon! To find out more, visit RedWINGS Facebook, website and Discord. Check out the launch trailer here on RedWINGS YouTube channel. As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
