<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-31T18:21:41.437169+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssmcd</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Previews E175’s MCDU for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssmcd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a63ac83eafb5b7ae8dc98b_crafts1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1606316"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG (in cooperation with X-Crafts) and AviationLads, have recently previewed the MCDU (Multi-Function Control and Display Unit) of the upcoming Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing a short route setup, performance initialization, and take-off data insertion. It’s the fourth and last preview video, with the next one being the official trailer and its eventual release under an early access program.  Yesterday, X-Crafts made a statement on their partnership with FlightSim Studio AG in order to bring the Embraer 175 to MSFS, where they clarified both are different products, developed by different teams and with distinct objectives, with the only commonality between both product lines being the 3D model, which is the same. They have also reinforced their commitment to bring the E-Jets to X-Plane 11/12 at one point in 2023.  The E175 is part of the Embraer E-Jets family, seating 78 to 88 passengers in different cabin configurations, with a range of 1800 nautical miles on the standard variant. There are 12 operators around the World, with SkyWest being the largest (193 aircraft).   There is no information regarding the release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cow206</id>
    <title>Cowan Simulation Releases Bell 206B3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cow206" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a642eecaf763b6416005a7_cow1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3532361"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cowan Simulation has recently released their rendition of the Bell 206B3 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a popular variant of the 206 family whose production ended in 2010 (later variants were to cease production in 2017). It is their first helicopter for MSFS, after releasing eight different models for X-Plane.  The Bell 206 had its first flight in 1962, after winning a competition held by the United States Navy to develop a Light Observation Helicopter. Their D-250 design went on to become the YHO-4, where it failed to win the contract bid, and Bell found themselves trying to market it as a civil aircraft (Model 206). The first attempt didn’t work well (terrible commercial success), but an eventual redesign aiming for a sleeker and aesthetic body made it a huge success. That one was launched as the Bell 206A JetRanger.   The first 206B JetRanger was introduced in 1971, with the 206B-3 coming in 1977 with a modified tail rotor, and improved engine. It got popular among TV channels for traffic and news reporting, armies, police departments, and private use.   The add-on features 4K PBR textures, realistic start up procedure, realistic flight dynamics, custom 3D instruments, virtual reality compatible, Wwise fully dynamic sound pack, detailed night lighting, and free future updates.   It’s available for purchase on CowanSim’s website for $32.99, requiring at least 2 GB of free disk space to install. Shout out to Henriks1 on Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ininan</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Nadi International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ininan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a64866724e8cdfd0eb8eec_nadi1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2708105"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has just released their rendition of Nadi International Airport (NFFN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport of Fiji and the main hub for Fiji Airways and Fiji Link. It averages 2.5 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic), handling 97% of the international traffic to the island, making it the gateway to Fiji.  It’s regularly visited by Air New Zealand with a direct flight to Auckland (and two seasonal hops to Christchurch and Wellington), Air Niugini with legs to Honiara and Port Moresby, AirCalin to Nouméa and Wallis Island, JetStar and Qantas with a hop to Sydney, and Virgin Australia with 3 aussie destinations: Brisbane, Melbourne, and Sydney. Fiji Airways, as the national carrier, offers a broader route network with flights to Adelaide, Apia-Faleolo, Auckland, Brisbane, Christchurch, Honiara, Honolulu, Los Angeles, Melbourne, Nuku’alofa, Port Vila, San Francisco, Singapore, Sydney, Tarawa, Vancouver, and Wellington.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Nadi International as it currently stands, with hand-made high-resolution ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation with custom decals, signposts, vegetation, parking barriers, and more; accurately modeled dynamic airport lighting (with its real positioning), accurate taxi signage, high-detail models of all airport buildings and objects, hand-placed vegetation, ground clutter, vehicles, and handling objects; accurate logos, real-world decals, and advertisements scattered throughout the airport; custom built jetways with PBR texturing, custom made tropical vegetation, terminals populated with people, Level of Detail optimization with performance in mind, and surrounding areas populated with churches, mosques, jetties, and boats.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for $12.03 (special Christmas Extravaganza sale price, expiring in 24 hours), requiring at least 5.37 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lowinc</id>
    <title>Low-End PC Studios Releases Inca Manco Cápac International v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lowinc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a65c47e100d7341a70d38a_inca1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="668943"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Low-End PC Studios has recently released their updated rendition of Inca Manco Cápac International Airport (SPJL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the highest airports in the World at 12,552 feet. It serves Juliaca, the Capital of San Roman Province in Southeastern Peru, the largest city in the region with 276,110 inhabitants. If being one of the highest commercial airports in South America was not enough, it also features one of the longest runways, with 4,200 meters of length.   It was named after Manco Cápac, the founder of the Inca Civilization in Cuzco.   It’s currently served by JetSmart Perú, LATAM Perú, and Sky Airline Peru, with scheduled flights to Lima and Cuzco (LATAM Perú only). Despite being an International airport, it doesn’t feature a single scheduled international flight.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D terminal and tower, PBR textures, and projected mesh for custom runway. The v2 update focused on correcting the windsock, adding two new city landmarks, a runway elevation profile, and runway texture improvements.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $6.58 (38% off), requiring at least 167 MB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffa350</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases A350 Beta Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffa350" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a6646d62ebc83521138d29_ff1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1143321"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor recently released a beta update (v1.7.01) for their A350 add-on, adding several improvements to the X-Plane 12 version, including a pitch behavior tuning for the new platform, lights and reflection compatibility, beacon light fix, and visual issues with some knobs.  The FlightFactor A350 XWB Advanced offers a high-quality rendition of the Airbus A350, with a high-resolution virtual cockpit, ground equipment, advanced systems simulation with SIDs and STARS, custom failures, Airbus electronic checklist system, fully customized ECAM monitoring system, full fly-by-wire simulation with realistic implementation of the normal laws, implementation of all Airbus autopilot modes (except for some non–precision approach modes), independent autopilots, custom 3D stereo engine sound system, and an interactive flight attendant helper, along with seven liveries. It’s available on X-Plane.Org Store for $45.47 (30% off), requiring at least 800 MB of free disk space to install.Images are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue, and special thanks to Poptart on Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd737</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd737" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a6d4c34c758f9f4b666bd5_boeing1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2415099"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently launched an update (3.00.0053) to their 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, focusing on increasing the quality and performance of the product. The highlights of the update include further work on the aircraft’s stability and prevention of eventual disturbances caused by the simulator’s exaggerated gusts, the addition of computationally derived stall angle of attack models for all wing configuration conditions on all of the three airplanes, reworked cabin collision models to allow native transition from cockpit to cabin, soundscape improvements (and expansion) in the cabin area, marked as a work in progress. The remainder of the changelog follows down below:  ‍ Regarding the 737-900, Robert Randazzo’s update announcement post mentions good progress on the testing, with a few areas they intend to clean up before the release.   The Universal Flight Tablet is partially working but not quite ready yet due to the fact they plan to build an universal framework that allows the EFB to work across their entire aircraft lineup, including stuff that is yet to come like the 777, the 737 MAX, and the 747. Such universality takes development time, but it’s said to be coming soon.   The DC-6 update is waiting on an Asobo update for MSFS that has to do with the avionics, and when that is out, PMDG will be able to roll out theirs with a greater range of GPS options, improved trim and flight characteristics, and extra stability for the autopilot when tracking a course or an approach.   They claim to have ‘quite a bit’ going on behind the scenes, which will be revealed once the 737-900 and the EFB are out to the public.  The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Images are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bartor</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Torino Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bartor" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a8dfc3795d9362780a2c07_torino1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="281402"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Torino Airport (LIMF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Turin (Northern Italy) and the Piedmont region. It is also known as Turin-Caselle Airport or Sandro Pertini Airport, named after a former Italian president.  The airport is a focus city for Ryanair, with 29 fixed destinations (and 11 seasonal legs). WizzAir is a close second with 9, both domestic and intra-European. The airport is also visited by flagship carriers such as Air France, British Airways, KLM, and Scandinavian Airlines (seasonally). The passenger figures sit at 4 million a year. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with a modeled terminal with its interior, custom jetways, custom ground textures and markings, night lighting, along with landside objects and clutter. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.95, requiring at least 115 MB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gf2112</id>
    <title>Global Forests Updated to Version 2.1 for XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gf2112" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a9b5b0d00104be72bc3eb0_FQlvahYU.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="269798"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The well-known package for X-plane that enhances forestry and tree sceneries that are automatically generated has recently received a new update which promises to provide users with an entirely new and improved experience.  In their latest 2.1 version update, all regions have been re-compiled to bring the latest and most accurate version possible. Along with this, the team behind Global Forests have added coverage for South American rejoins, Which were previously not included.  Along with the news of their latest update, the team behind Global Forests have revealed it will now be available exclusively through Orbx.  To read more about the announcement you can follow this link!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hche</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Cheongju International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hche" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63aba1b4aaed7110b371340f_cheo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="370215"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Cheongju International Airport (RKTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Cheongwon-Ku, Daejeon, and Sejong with an yearly average of 2 million passengers. It was built as a military airbase in 1978, with the international airport plan to begin construction in 1984 and its eventual conclusion in December 1996, opening in April 1997.  Back in the 80s, Cheongju was selected as a potential construction site for Korea’s main international airport, but Incheon ended up being the chosen one.  The airport was built to handle the current yearly traffic (2 million people) and 196 thousand airplane operations, along with a parking lot big enough for 770 cars. It also happens to house a fighter wing of the Korean Air Force, which means taking photographs of the apron, runways, and the military facilities is strictly prohibited. It’s served by nine airlines, with a selection of domestic routes and international legs to China, Japan, Taiwan, and Thailand. Aero K and Asiana fly from Cheongju to Jeju, Bamboo Airways operates a seasonal leg to Quy Nhon, Jeju Air flies to Guam, Jeju, Osaka-Kansai, and Taipei-Taoyuan, Jin Air and Korean Air fly to Jeju, Sky Angkor Airlines operates a seasonal hop to Siem Reap, T’way Air flies to Da Nang, and Yakutia Airlines operates two seasonal journeys to Khabarovsk and Vladivostok. The scenery features an accurate rendition of RKTU, with custom jetways, dynamic lighting, PBR materials, animated humans, and performance friendly optimization. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.75, requiring at least 2 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pkskrg</id>
    <title>PKSIM Releases José María Córdova International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pkskrg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63acefed3e3fcfaa593ad1c0_skrg1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2976933"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PKSIM has recently released their rendition of José María Córdova International Airport (SKRG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, located in Rionegro, 20 km away from Medellín, serving the entire Medellin Metropolitan Area with many destinations, both domestic and international. It is the second busiest airport in Colombia with 9 million passengers yearly.   It’s a hub for Avianca Colombia, Ultra Air, and Viva Air Colombia, with a destination list that encompasses Colombia, Mexico, the United States, and some of Europe. LATAM Colombia also features a list of domestic destinations from Rionegro. Among the international visitors, there’s Aeromexico with a hop to Mexico City, Air Europa with a long haul to Madrid, JetBlue to Fort Lauderdale, LATAM Perú to Lima, and Spirit Airlines with the Floridian trifecta (Fort Lauderdale, Miami, and Orlando).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of SKRG, with a detailed terminal model, custom jetways, custom ground textures, the Avianca maintenance facility, custom night lighting, realistic ground markings, and a detailed control tower interior.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.12, requiring at least 1.48 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simrep</id>
    <title>SimCoders Releases Reality Expansion Pack SR22 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simrep" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ad0c13a1f81e76eda2c07f_rep1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1009292"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimCoders has recently released an expansion pack for the default Cirrus SR22 included in X-Plane 12, improving the flight dynamics, adding an interactive walkaround system, a mass and balance tool, a custom piston engine simulation, and more.   The Cirrus SR22 is a single-engine aircraft launched in 2001, manufactured in Duluth, Minnesota. It’s an “upgraded” SR20 with a more powerful engine, larger wings, and improved fuel capacity. It’s one of the most successful general aviation airplanes of the past twenty years, topping the sale charts since 2003 with over 6149 units built in total (as of 2019). It’s also the most produced GA aircraft of the 21st century.  The Reality Expansion Pack SR22 improves the default SR22 with a substantial list of new features, including a custom flight model with realism in mind, an advanced walkaround system with the possibility to check lights, cockpit, control surfaces, engine cowls, pitot tubes, etc., a mass and balance tool with a variable center of gravity depending on the load, a complex damage system triggered by pilot actions and based on real world data, a simulation state saving so that every switch and lever stays where it was when you closed the simulator, an economy system fully compatible with FSEconomy, a custom piston engine simulation with many realistic features, a custom electrical and avionics system with realistic battery behavior, custom simulation of hypoxia with its common symptoms such as tunnel vision and hard breathing, and native VR support. The complete feature list follows down below:  ‍  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $19.99.  Shout out to Luke on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xprimu</id>
    <title>X-Rotors Seeks Developer for AW139 Primus Flight System</title>
    <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xprimu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ade715274c6fcf8909a727_X-Plane_Screenshot_2022.12.14_-_21.55.38.15.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1716467"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Rotors, a leading developer of Helicopters in X-Plane, is seeking a talented developer to join their team in creating a hi-res OpenGL-designed Primus flight system for the AW139 helicopter. The AW139 is a famous aircraft for various applications, including offshore oil and gas transportation, emergency medical services, and VIP/corporate transportation. The Primus flight system is a state-of-the-art avionics suite that provides pilots with a wide range of information and capabilities, including navigation, communication, and flight management. ‍ The successful candidate will have experience in developing flight simulation systems using OpenGL, as well as a strong understanding of avionics and aircraft systems. They will work closely with the X-Rotors team to design and implement the Primus flight system, ensuring that it meets the high standards of realism and functionality expected in a professional flight simulator. If you are a developer with the skills and experience needed to contribute to this exciting project, we encourage you to apply. This is a unique opportunity to be a part of a cutting-edge development team and make a real impact on the future of flight simulation. To apply, please contact X-Rotor on their website. ‍ We have previously reviewed the AW109 from X-Rotors on our YouTube channel. You can see the video here. ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pr7lup</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737 Lineup Update</title>
    <updated>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pr7lup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63af73d41471189c580845c3_737-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="913368"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their 737 Lineup to version 3.00.0056, reducing code execution latency, virtual cockpit model improvements to improve rendering efficiency, fixing the parking brake lever lock switch keybind, and improved data display on the in-game HUD.  Regarding the 737-900, they have pushed a new beta build to the testers for data collection. It’s still being “tidied up” with an eventual release getting closer, although they reinforced it won’t be before 2023, as work continues on a broad array of features.  The PMDG Universal Flight Tablet will be added to the -900 testing program by next week, putting them in a good position to begin rolling out the first functions for the EFB. They plan to release one function at a time to not overload the beta testing team, aiming for an eventual continual update process that should cover the entire fleet of existing and upcoming aircraft. They also stated the tablet will be updated separately from the aircraft update channel, meaning it might evolve independently and faster than the airplane updates.  The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Images are courtesy of Genista. Shout out to Geeky on the Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsmvir</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Viru Viru International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsmvir" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63af79106cce8065cb874015_viru1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="951180"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released their rendition of Viru Viru International (SLVR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Santa Cruz de la Sierra in Bolivia. It’s the largest airport in the country in terms of passenger density, handling traffic from the Americas and Europe.   It’s the hub for Boliviana de Aviacíon, founded in 2007 and currently the biggest airline in the country, offering flights to Buenos Aires, Cochabamba, La Paz, Lima, Madrid, Miami, Oruro, São Paulo, Sucre, Tarija, and Trinidad. The regional EcoJet, from Cochabamba, also offers a wide variety of domestic legs to Cobija, Guayaramerín, Riberalta, Sucre, Tarija, and Trinidad. As far as international visitors go, there’s Aerolíneas Argentinas with a sole leg to Buenos Aires, Avianca with a leg to Bogota, Copa (Panama City), Gol (São Paulo), Latam Chile (Santiago), and Latam Perú (Lima). Miami is the busiest international destination as of 2016 with 386,496 passengers, followed by São Paulo (372,773), and Buenos Aires (358,943).  The scenery features a detailed rendition of SLVR, with custom night lighting, native MSFS dynamic lighting, seamless integration with default MSFS scenery, PBR materials, and native gITF models.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.57, requiring at least 1.7 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/upship</id>
    <title>Major Update To Global AI Ship Traffic For MSFS Released</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/upship" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b031be180a5604b1d7d189_ai-boats-ships-ai-msfszip-70-screen-71.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1384359"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Henrik Nielsen, the creator of a popular freeware utility add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, has released a major update for the product. The update, which brings the add-on to version 3.0, significantly improves the realism of the virtual world in the flight simulator by adding a wide variety of ships, boats, and ferries with realistic 3D models and authentic routes. One of the key features of the update is the addition of more than 400 new ship models from around the globe, including cruise ships, fishing boats, container ships, oil and gas tankers, and ferries. This brings the total number of unique ship models to almost 900, with a total of over 1,800 ships including repaints. The update also expands the coverage of ship routes, increasing traffic density in different regions. In addition to the new ship models, the update includes more than 100 new ferry routes and the ability to witness real-world naval exercises featuring ships from various countries. These exercises, which include full-scale NATO landing exercises on the West Coast of the Jutland Peninsula in Denmark and similar exercises by the Brazilian and Chinese navies in their respective areas, add a level of realism and immersion to the virtual world. Other features and improvements in the update include light, smoke, and wake effects on all ship models, as well as dynamic sounds for each type of ship model. The update is compatible with the latest sim update and has a minimal impact on performance, depending on the density of ship models in a given region. The download size is approximately 2.2 GB, with an installation size of 5.6 GB. To learn more about the update and how to download and install it, visit the Global AI Ship Traffic MSFS GAIST Ultra V3 page at flightsim.to. </summary>
    <published>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simsol</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Announce Diamond DA20 For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simsol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b03bc7699a14463bc31c35_DA27.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4183387"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimSolutions, a leading aircraft design and development brand in the flight sim community, has announced its “return to Diamond” with the Diamond DA20-C1 Eclipse for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This marks the company's first foray into the new simulator and represents a significant milestone in its efforts to provide users with the most accurate and detailed aircraft models possible. According to the developer, the decision to create the DA20-C1 for MSFS was inspired by a personal passion for flying the aircraft. "Being the aircraft that I currently fly, I thought it was only fitting to remodel it with as much detail as I can to give an accurate model and operation of the DA20-C1”. "I am thrilled to have made the decision to create this aircraft for MSFS, but it will take some time." While the development of the DA20-C1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator is currently the group's top priority, it has not ruled out the possibility of releasing a version for X-Plane in the future. "An X-Plane version will likely come later," the development team said. SimSolutions expressed its gratitude to its supporters and wished them a Happy New Year. "We thank you so much for the support this year and are wishing you a very Happy New Year," To find out more, visit their Discord </summary>
    <published>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
