<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-03-11T18:25:55.146096+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfsv8</id>
    <title>Asobo Studio Released Sim Update VIII (v1.23.12.0) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfsv8" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621dd63b54a5a14f89e39168_JAPAN_Update_Shrine-1024x576.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="162837"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, Asobo Studio released Sim Update VIII (v1.23.12.0) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update brings a few new features and a large variety of improvements to simulator stability, weather, VR, developer SDK, and default aircrafts. Starting off with the new features, the developers announced that the Market Place will receive a brand new UI that brings “improved discoverability and a better navigation experience”. Additionally, an optional propeller simulation system with “hundreds of moving surfaces” is now available for the Cessna 152, Cessna 208 B Grand Caravan EX, and Beechcraft King Air 350i, improving the realism of propeller effects such as feathering and prop-drag. Finally, a new private match mode for Reno air Races can now be accessed via content manager and a new Spotlight Event has been added that features landing a Cessna Citation CJ4 at Reno Stead airport. In addition to the new features, Asobo Studio also introduced a long list of bug fixes and improvements that address almost every area of the simulator. The complete list can be viewed on MSFS’s website. Currently, Sim Update VIII is available to download for all users. As usual, the developers have reminded the community to temporarily move community packages to another folder if the new version brings “unexpected impact on the title’s performance and behavior”. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/waxp12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Addresses Wake Turbulence in X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/waxp12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621e3670cb15834234c64554_xp12wt01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="429571"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Phillip from Laminar Research addressed wake turbulence in the upcoming X-Plane 12 Flight Simulator. Involving both player aircraft and AI aircraft and its correlation with the simulator physics and aerodynamics.  AI Traffic After a brief introduction about wake turbulence, Phillip addresses the wake turbulence that is left by AI aircraft. All AI aircraft will leave the correct wake turbulence that corresponds to its aircraft, and is calculated properly with the vortex that is created by the wing of the aircraft. Same will apply for user aircraft. Phillip then goes on to say:  Online Traffic, 3rd Party Plugins, and Live Traffic Further on, Phillip addresses wake turbulence left by online network aircraft, live traffic, and other 3rd party plugins. With the correct data through an ADS-B exchange, X-Plane will calculate the best effects to aircraft weight, wing area, and wingspan through the data the plugin provides. Current XP11 traffic plugins are compatible with the wake turbulence and will be a base function in XP12.  That’s it for today’s update, but Threshold will be sure to keep you up to date with any further X-Plane 12 development updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md80be</id>
    <title>Leonardo Reveals New MSFS2020 Maddog Details</title>
    <updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md80be" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621f2a9f57462cd984e02f6a_06.thumb.jpg.5cb6893fdc5dd7a12d08f5ed7c1b07cf.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="109387"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stefano from Leonardo Software House has updated the community regarding the status of its upcoming McDonnell Douglas MD-80 for MSFS2020. The Long Beach-built airliner is officially in “advanced beta testing”, as the fixed Software Development Kit has allowed the team to progress on the project as anticipated. There’s no release date yet, as the foreseeable development is contingent on MSFS’s evolution.  LSH’s Release Plan Similar to their Prepar3D release map, Leonardo will most likely divide their Maddog packages by variant. The team will initially release the MD-82 with JT8D-217A engines, a 162Y configured cabin, and a Honeywell FMS to satisfy NAV, VNAV, and ACARS. Following the MD-82 will be an MD-83/88 expansion package, and then JT8D-217C/219 engines, the Canadian Marconi FMS and PMS, an EFB, as well as aging and servicing features.   Anticipated MSFS Features If you’re strapped for time, a few notable features of the release include: Below is the full feature list that’ll be included in the release version of the MD-80, the list is quite substantial, but not overwhelming.  Fly the Maddog X MSFS version 1.0 will include: - MD82 with -217A engines, PAX Cabin 162Y and Honeywell FMS for NAV/VNAV/ACARS; - Flight model and engines performances tested and matched against real aircraft performance tables; - All systems/avionics/tests etc, fully implemented as in the P3D version, including failures/INOPs feature, fully dimmable integral and flood lightning, working TCAS and EGPWS terrain mode; - New FMS Services page for controlling DOORS/STAIR, External power, fuel loading, etc.; - Fully integrated with MSFS ecosystem (jetway, catering, baggage loader, etc...); - Integration with PFPX/SimBrief via Load Manager and retrieval of OFP data via the ACARS system; - Livery manager, and aircraft settings configurable for different aircrafts; - Livery-based cockpit color (pink, blue or gray) and main panel variations (including placards and speed bugs); - Can be installed in the same machine with Fly the Maddog X for P3D; Configurable options from Load Manager:  - Panel state when starting simulation (Cold &amp; Dark, Ready at Gate, Ready for Takeoff...); - Weight &amp; Balance and route planner; - Load Manager units (Kg/mbar or Lbs/InHg); Aircraft options: - Cockpit units (Kg/mbar or Lbs/InHg); - PFD flight director style (cross bar or single cue), rising runway, ND wind arrow, groundspeed and aircraft map symbol, HDG UP or TRK UP option; - PFD wired to opposite NAV; - Armed altitude as FL and AutoArm altitude option; - Gear waring inhibit above 1500ft AGL; - Always play aural when autopilot disconnects; - Auto brake system; - Three VOR instrument versions: VOR/ADF/DME, VOR/ADF and VOR only; - Two altimeter versions: DUAL/SINGLE knob; - Optional TAS/SAT indicator; - Flat or Cone tail; Simulator options: - Enable failures; - Autopilot disconnect when flight controls moved; - Automatic update of aircraft weight and cg; - Automatic fuel loading; - Enable PM calls; - Sync CM1/CM2; - FSUIPC compatibility mode; - Maximum luminosity of all cockpit lights and instruments (flood, integral, LED, LCD and CRT); - Failures probability, separated for LIGHT, MEDIUM and DANGEROUS; - INOP systems according to MEL; Some Sidenotes Stefan informed the community that the Maddog will contain modifiable settings (including panel states) actively within the sim without requiring a flight restart. Another detail mentioned in the footnotes is the lack of weather radar functionality due to the SDK’s current state, but will be implemented, for free, as soon as the SDK will allow.  ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- As the war in Ukraine endures, Threshold is allocating all of the donation proceeds, including previous Threshold donations, towards the Ukrainian Crisis cause. 25% of all proceeds is set aside for Ukrainian X-Plane developers while the remaining is directly sent to UNICEF’s donation program for Ukrainian children. If you’re interested in contributing, please visit our donation page.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asmyko</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Updates Mykonos Airport Scenery </title>
    <updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asmyko" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621f2e00377af6e5088db6fa_lgmk-msfs_05.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="275243"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently released an update for their Mykonos airport scenery. The update is quite lengthy and substantial with numerous changes made to keep the airport's virtual rendition up to date with the real airport. Let's take a closer look and highlight some of the more interesting additions made.  Before we get into the particulars. Looking at the images above we can really begin to appreciate how far scenery development has come, with the developers putting effort into seamlessly blending the airport into an already realistic default scenery. The releases of yesteryears in flight simulation would frequently have contrasting colours between the scenery satellite imagery and the default textures. The majority of changes have been prompted by the recent changes Mykonos airport has undergone. The $28 million upgrade has essentially given the airport a “facelift” with a stunning new facade symbolizing the traditional Cycladic architecture. The project was set to open in 2021 and so it did, with no delay from Aerosoft who were relatively quick to follow suit and update their product. Here’s their full change list for you to check out: Reading through the list, it seems the team at Aerosoft has almost completely recreated the airport, with new lights, new textures, new modeling and enhanced mesh, with existing users being able to expect an almost brand new product. It is pleasing to see this focus on what essentially can be referred to as virtual modernisation, especially as an update and not as a whole new product. While not expected from developers, scenarios like these are appreciated. Check out their official post on the update, and should you wish to purchase the product, it can be found on the Aerosoft store.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dccord</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases Release Date for DC Design Concorde</title>
    <updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dccord" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62207602cb346868b9501678_274221808_3194114267576217_7149942691568301623_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="657894"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Recently, a new banner has quietly appeared on Just Flight’s website, announcing that the much anticipated Concorde for Microsoft Flight Simulator will be releasing sometime this month (March 2022). The aircraft, developed by DC Designs, is built ground up for the new simulator with customized handling models and accurate modeling/texturing, bringing users an enjoyable flying experience with the world’s only supersonic airliner. Over the past few months, DC Designs has released weekly updates on the development progress of the Concorde. The latest one, posted on February 25th, teases that work is currently being done on PBR textures and showcases the external and internal modeling of the aircraft. It is clear from both the text and the pictures that Concord is near completion. 	Announced in mid 2021, DC Design’s Concorde “is designed to be both an accessible and yet highly detailed rendition of this iconic aircraft”. To ensure a high degree of accuracy with its designs, the team has reconstructed the aircraft with hundreds of real life images of the Concord taken from museums and exhibits. Checkout Just Flight’s website for a complete list of the Concorde’s features. DCDesigns has priced the Concorde at £27.99 / $39.99 / €34.95. If there's any more news regarding the release, Threshold will keep you updated on this front. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/146332</id>
    <title>Just Flight Further Previews MSFS BAe 146</title>
    <updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/146332" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62207680bf135606de592e63_274787448_10161824804168499_4968259245970406681_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="533287"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has posted more previews of their upcoming BAe 146 for MSFS2020. The news comes in light of their subsequent aircraft developments, such as the newly announced 757, collaboration with DCDesigns, and In-House Fokker F28. The team mentions in their Facebook post that more news will be delivered in the imminent future and that "release time draws closer." The following screenshots showcase the aircraft partaking in a test flight from Southampton to Bournemouth.  For those who are unaware, the British Aerospace 146, also known as the BAe 146, is a short-haul regional airliner developed by British Aerospace. Containing four turbofan engines, as well as a T-tail, the "Jumbolino" garners its reputation from its quirky design features. Over 380 units were built from 1978-to 2001, primarily serving European operators such as CityJet and Swiss. The aircraft was delivered under the name "Avro RJ" after 1992, shipping with upgraded avionics and more powerful engines. In the current world, few Avro RJs remain, some serve middle eastern carriers, and some serve as "off the grid" transporters as the aircraft contains gravel landing abilities.  Just Flight did not share any additional information regarding the BAe 146's development, but keep an eye out shortly as the team admitted that there's a new development update around the corner.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xokefl</id>
    <title>Xometry Announces Keflavík International Airport For X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xokefl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6221d768abba3430b0bef817_ok.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="289560"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry has announced their latest project which takes us to the far North, a land that is often missed by flight simmers and overlooked by those who cross the pond. Keflavíkurflugvöllur or commonly referred to as Keflavík International Airport, is an airport many would have encountered but likely not visited. Typically overflown on routes between central europe and the west coast of the United States, this airport would likely feature as an alternative but hardly ever as a destination. Xometry could potentially have a reason to fly here.  The airport was initially established as a USAF base in 1942, later serving as a NATO air station, and as of 1987, becoming the gateway for passengers to the natural wonder that is Iceland. This airport is home to a few 757’s from IcelandAir, presenting us with the opportunity to operate the Flight Factor 757 outside of the USA. Handling almost 10 million passengers at its peak in 2018, it's anyone's guess as to why the flight simulation world has neglected to visit such an intriguing location. The project looks promising, with progress pictures that display an extreme level of attention to detail, which the team has claimed is their priority; mentioning “The airport has been recreated in high accuracy with much attention being put into making sure that we bring you the most up-to-date rendition of BIKF currently available for X-Plane 11/12.” It is important to note that the team is aware, and ready to ensure this scenery is off the bat ready to be compatible with X-Plane 12, especially as we fast approach its release.  Taking a look at their provided feature list below, we see all the usual features we expect from high quality payware scenery developers, however what is particularly interesting and not so common in X-Plane, is the modeled interior, a feature which is often overlooked but a neat detail when implemented. This inadvertently adds to the immersion and is certainly not expected but highly appreciated when done correctly. Check out their full feature list below: For more information stay tuned and we’ll bring you the latest when available. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12du</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Publishes March 4 X-Plane 12 Dev Update</title>
    <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12du" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622313d86cc398f518a65343_Cessna_172SP_seaplane_-_2022-03-04_15.38.53-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="459321"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. As X-Plane 12’s release date slowly encroaches upon our current simulators, it is almost time to say goodbye as we look to the future. One will know it's almost time to fork out and invest in the latest Flight Sim Software, when the time between announcements decreases, and with that our anticipation increases. In this article I want to give a brief breakdown on Laminar’s latest blog entry, detailing the latest progressions on the forthcoming simulator. Let's take a look. Confirming several speculations (and footage/software leaks as of late), X-Plane 12 currently resides within a closed private alpha group where our favorite third party developers have the opportunity to ensure their products are immediately compatible and without major bugs upon release. In the meantime, the team at X-Plane have provided in their announcement a table to give us a general overview on where the project currently stands and what still needs some work. As you will discover below, the announcement mainly addresses components mentioned under the “In Progress'' tab in their table. We will break down these items as we progress through the article. The first item mentioned is rendering low visibility. The team at X-Plane have been hard at work to ensure that the fog visually reacts like fog, with a real focus on how atmospheric conditions will impact its appearance. Sunny days will now illuminate the fog and anything less than sunny will have fog appear slightly darker, with nights obviously having the darkest tone. In addition to this, the team has mentioned that their focus remains on ensuring the simulator represents an accurate environment in which instrument training can be conducted. They are achieving this by using a modeled “monolith” surrounded by runway lights as a calibration target, pictured below: Next, the announcement shifts to water, something we typically tend to avoid an interaction with, unless you’re using a seaplane. Despite this, water has long been an oversight within X-Plane, with default textures looking underwhelming and dull. For version 12, water receives a major makeover in both function and form. In line with most modern titles nowadays, the water will be 3D, finally allowing users to see physical waves; the team has even gone as far as to work with Seaplane pilots during the Alpha phase, to pay particular attention on getting seaplane behavior correct. Lighting is the cornerstone of X-Plane 12’s visual rejuvenation, now utilising a photometric system and running entirely in HDR. The team has updated their methods in which they design night lighting and light sources, such as urban lights and street lights. Precise attention has been given to sources that will impact your flying experience, such as approach, runway, and PAPI lights, which they have done in accordance to FAA specs. Previously, users relied on FlyWithLua scripts to bring life to a number of environment aspects within X-Pane, particularly lighting. We hope to see the new default lighting exceeding that of third party addons.    Anti-Aliasing is next on the agenda. X-Plane in the past has made partial use of a deferred renderer, what we have now learnt from the recent update is that in order to implement the new weather effects and lighting, deferred rendering will have to be and is the exclusive mode at which the X-Plane graphics engine runs. With the deferred rendering, X-Plane 12 will now support MSAA or Multisample Anti-aliasing which it was not able to when X-Plane only partially utilised deferred rendering. This comes with the potential for improved performance as opposed to the use of SSAA which severely impacted Frame Rate. To further improve framerate the team will be implementing AMD’s FidelityFX Resolution, which allows for faster rendering and presents users the opportunity to scale up to 4K and retain their framerate. In terms of third party support, below are some short sweet points, that were mentioned in the announcement: As mentioned in their full official update, which you can find here, the team has indicated that the next step from the current phase will be early access beta, which will be accessible to everyone willing to participate. This can be done through either a demo or full purchase. For more information stay tuned, or check out their full announcement. We will bring you the latest when made available.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kiadxp</id>
    <title>Nimbus Studios Releases Washington Dulles for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kiadxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62231571156e94fb4de96e60_b738%20-%202022-03-02%2022.18.42.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="488904"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After much anticipation from the community, Nimbus Studios has recently released Washington Dulles International Airport (KIAD) for X-Plane 11. The scenery, featuring everything from fully modeled terminals and their interiors to custom HDR lightings and animated ground objects, presents users with an authentic experience when flying to the American capital. Based on the information provided, it can be seen that Nimbus has furnished KIAD with the latest technologies and the airport's most recent layout. A few notable features of the scenery include 4K PBR textures, custom night lighting, Dulles’s unique people movers, and ground traffic. A full list of features can be found on the product’s store page. Washington Dulles Airport, located in the state of Virginia around 40 miles outside of D.C, is one of the three major airports that services the capital. It has four runways and 139 gates. In 2019 alone, the airport saw some 24 million passengers and remains one of the region’s largest hubs for international flights. Currently, the scenery can be purchased on X-Plane.org for $29.99 USD, excluding any sales tax that may incur. Users who purchase the X-Plane 11 version will receive a free upgrade when X-Plane 12 is released. The developers recommend users to have at least 1.2GB of free space available on their hard drives in order to successfully install the products.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ts1112</id>
    <title>TorqueSim X-Plane 11 Updates Released; X-Plane 12 Preparations</title>
    <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ts1112" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6223275fbb74451768dd3078_sr22.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="78988"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Renowned aircraft developer TorqueSim has retaken to their forums to announce the release of their anticipated X-Plane 11 updates and further outline their X-Plane 12 ambitions. Their SR20 and SR22 received the most attention in this update.  The following updates consist of quality assurance improvements and preparations for X-Plane 12. It's imperative to mention, though, that there is no X-Plane 12 update just yet.  SR20/22 G1000 1.3.0 Release Notes: Bug Fixes: SR20/SR22 Entegra 1.1.0 Release Notes: All of the above "new" features found in the SR20/22 G1000, in addition to: Bug Fixes and Improvements Aspiring TorqueSim pilots can find the SR20/22 on the X-Aviation store. As we optimistically await X-Plane 12, Threshold will continue to report on all new things TorqueSim. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/37fenx</id>
    <title>Fenix Drops Another A320 Preview</title>
    <updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/37fenx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6225c44e92854cb1e04832ec_dattabletho-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1907053"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After entering beta in early February, the Fenix Simulations team has returned to keeping their lips tight. Aamir has since returned from the depths of silence to share a singular new screenshot of the upcoming A320 for MSFS. The screenshot showcases the functionality of the EFB, as well as shows the cockpit in a “turnaround” state. Aamir hasn't mentioned any additional details regarding the aircraft's progress in beta but did claim that an upcoming update will reveal "areas of the products as yet unseen/unheard!." For those who aren't familiar with the current functionality of the aircraft, you should gaze at Fenix's YouTube channel that exhibits the A320's components. The team also has a public Discord server where members can communicate with any inquiries or concerns.  Unfortunately, there isn't much more to share with this update, but Threshold will keep up to date with Fenix as more information is released shortly.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prevwe</id>
    <title>FlightBeam Studios Shares Wellington Airport Previews</title>
    <updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prevwe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6225c764e2560a5bd508b81f_eba5cc_48952dbfae60478ba673a688c58d84bbmv2-2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="290823"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Smooth seas don’t make skillful sailors, Wellington International Airport is testament to this. Located just outside of the world's windiest city, this airport has notoriously had pilots constantly on their toes and challenging their skills. Windy Welly has since its inception, had pilots and seatbelts alike tested everyday, with a relatively short runway not making things any easier. That said, you can’t beat Wellington on a good day! FlightBeam Studios have been hard at work to give us the opportunity to experience this airport first-hand, recently sharing a couple of preview images that evidently suggest that this project is indeed in its late phase of production. The textures are clear and complete with buildings looking true to reality. Unlike most sceneries, surroundings are particularly important here as your nose will almost never be straight down the centerline.  The precise attention to detail in the air bridge texturing in particular, demonstrates the teams capabilities, setting our expectations high as we hope this level of detail remains consistent throughout the scenery as a whole. We can confirm release is imminent as FlightBeam Studios have opened applications for Beta testers whom must meet the following prerequisites, as mentioned on their official application form:  For more information stay tuned. Do feel free to check out their original preview post. Should you be interested in beta testing and meet the above requirements, submit an application here.  </summary>
    <published>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aoda50</id>
    <title>Aerobask Drops DA50 Trailer</title>
    <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aoda50" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622832854e2a9c3365c72385_Screenshot%202022-03-08%20215126.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="113183"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Throughout the years, Aerobask has played a critical role in X-Plane’s 3rd Party Addons. Providing quality, detailed, and outstanding-looking aircraft for the simulator. Today, Aerobask and X-Plane.org have released a trailer for the upcoming DA50 aircraft, coming to XP11 and XP12. Being one of Aerobask’s more highly anticipated General Aviation aircraft, the trailer provides a good look into what will be included in the aircraft when it is released. At first glance, the exterior of the aircraft is modeled correctly to match its real-world counterpart. With all exterior lighting, and features such as the winglets, being modeled as well. The shots of the interior of the aircraft provide us with a look at the G1000 suite that comes with all Aerobask products alongside the standard cockpit of all Diamond aircraft. Interior lighting has been accurately placed, along with seats, air vents, and other miscellaneous aspects of the cockpit being modeled correctly as well. While no feature list has been provided as of yet, Aerobask’s reputation as a developer has reached all ends of the market, both freeware and payware. Users are looking forward to being able to test this product in X-Plane 12, which Aerobask has stated this product along with other products will be compatible with the next-generation simulator. ‍ No official date for release has been brought to light, but Threshold will be sure to keep you updated on any further developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctp22w</id>
    <title>VATSIM Cross The Pond Slots Now Open!</title>
    <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctp22w" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622862ff39bd5c2c4c9b55a0_Vatsim-color-tagline-white.png.97c5c207436092fc1acd7f853ce29e05%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="26539"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VATSIM's team has announced the opening of their slot system for pilots to express their interest in participating in the upcoming event. Those who aren't familiar with the new slot system should note that the new system doesn't allow you to book a specific slot initially, but rather "expressing interest" enters you into a lottery to win a slot.  ‍Cross The Pond is the largest and longest-running event on VATSIM. Its history dates back to almost 20 years ago, and the event takes place biannually in a transatlantic fashion between North America and Europe. The VATSIM team has adapted to the modern media landscape, so pilots can now monitor CTP updates by following the #CTP22W hashtag on Twitter rather than having to scour through the website. They've also created a Discord server for aspiring CTP pilots to communicate and receive news regarding the event.  Lastly, the team wants to thank the community for its dedicated volunteers for making the event possible. Pilots who desire to participate should check out their website to potentially win a spot for the event.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/39pmdg</id>
    <title>PMDG Posts New MSFS 737 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/39pmdg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622866b4e6406a0f5aaa500f_pmdg1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="993757"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has entered its fourth week of testing their upcoming 737-700 for MSFS. As reported in weeks past, the team is making better-than-anticipated progress on the aircraft. Hundreds of "taskings," also known as "bug reports," have been resolved since the beginning of the beta test.  Randazzo reports that the "number of knee-knockers we are hitting that are related to PMDG-platform interface issues is dropping rapidly, and the number of "this system/function is behaving incorrectly" reports is rising as a percentage of the whole." Systems-wise, the airplane is operating at an "expected level" in this development phase.  PMDG is simultaneously working on improving the visuals of the aircraft, such as adding more wear-and-tear to the cockpit and adding some more character to the textures. Randazzo noted some small yet crucial details of their texturing adventures, relating to aluminum being exposed on the backing plate for the right-most dimmer panel, left of the captain's FMS. Aesthetic fingerprints are also being incorporated onto the screens of the digital displays. Last but not least, PMDG will begin working on some other preview videos as some time is freeing up to allow them to do so. No additional information regarding the aircraft was shared, but keep up with Threshold to stay in touch with the latest and greatest from PMDG!</summary>
    <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfopti</id>
    <title>GotFriends Previews the EA7-Optica for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfopti" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622b783064130a5597768ae6_unnamed%20(3).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="155311"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After releasing a multitude of freeware projects, GotFriends have once again decided to venture into the world of payware, with the announcement of the EA7 Optica, their second payware aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This aircraft is a full remaster of the previous freeware version which released last year. The developer has made it clear, however, that this is built completely from the ground up and includes exciting features such as a KAP140 autopilot and full PMS50 (GTN750) support. Included are “several real world liveries the aircraft was most popular for,” an animated cat and dog sitting visibly in the cockpit, and the aforementioned KAP140 autopilot and GTN750 support. It should be noted, however, that currently the TDS GTN750 does not work with this aircraft. Upon its initial release, the aircraft is set to be exclusive to the Flightsim.to store, and will be coming to the MSFS Marketplace (and Xbox) within a month. Furthermore, the aircraft is set to cost $19.99, but will launch with a sale of 50% as a token of appreciation to the community. It was also stated that users should be looking forward to the aircraft releasing sometime next week. For further information make sure to check out the official teaser trailer, as well as the original announcement made on the Flightsim.to website</summary>
    <published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
