<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-03-25T18:27:06.858817+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shadxp</id>
    <title>Jemma Simulations Release CFM Shadow for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shadxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6232cdf318f88c2d674ef3dd_cover.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="559540"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Developer Jemma Simulations has released their rendition of the CFM Shadow ultralight kit aircraft. It is a two-seater powered by a two-stroke, two-cylinder Rotax engine for those unfamiliar with the airplane. The Shadow is the first aircraft produced by the developer. The aircraft is relatively basic by design, but the developer provided a feature list to give aspiring pilots an idea of what to expect with the aircraft.  Features:  Pilots can obtain the CFM Shadow for $15.95 on the X-Plane.org store. It'll consume approximately 250MB of space when downloaded. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pm7377</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Update on 737-700</title>
    <updated>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pm7377" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6209b16078b45f2be1a2d595_image_15297.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1049348"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, aircraft developer PMDG has published a new update on its much anticipated 737-700 project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, discussing the status of the aircraft’s testing, developmental progress, and upcoming plans. According to the developers, the testing of the aircraft continues smoothly, with some 70 issues reported by the testers and more than 120 solved by the development team. However, despite the 737 currently performing at a near satisfactory level, the developers expressed their frustration that MSFS currently lacks “tools that [they] would normally use to improve code stability and look for areas that require optimization”, preventing them from gaining vital insights on key areas needing improvements. In addition to updates on testing, the team also shined light on their current task of improving the details of some areas “to evaluate the impact different techniques may have on the performance of the simulator”. The developers are trying to gradually increase the level of details without sacrificing any performance, a process aided by their “increased confidence in Asobo's rendering engine”. The developer's progress is demonstrated by the completely rebuilt fire handles and light knobs pictured above. Finally, the developers revealed that a “full bore promotional process” will soon start, presenting the public with additional details on the aircraft and answering their questions. Currently, PMDG has not revealed the release date of the aircraft, claiming that its carefully designed workflow and testing procedure currently prevent it from determining a precise date. However, the developers teased that the 737 is “very close to that point” where a firm release date can be set and the embargo can be lifted for beta testers. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/esdchu</id>
    <title>Emerald Scenery Design Releases Chunilna Cabin Strip for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/esdchu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62360747e3980f4a6ad2158d_chunilna_cabin_strip_alaska_msfs_r17%20(1).jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="524472"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After originally releasing a plethora of sceneries for Prepar3D and various freeware sceneries for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Emerald Scenery Design have ventured into the world of payware for MSFS. Marking the developer’s first payware product for Asobo’s simulator, the developer has taken to the backcountry of Alaska, with the release of Chunilna Cabin Strip. Located 11km to the Northeast of Talkeetna Alaska, Chunilna Cabin Strip is an unregistered airfield with an incredibly short runway, with anything larger than a Piper Cub providing quite a struggle for pilots. Featuring environmentally dynamic features such as seasonal butterflies, morel mushrooms, rain puddles, VFX, and more, Emerald Scenery Design claims to have brought this scenery “to life in incredible detail.” Furthermore, the scenery uses its own custom library which includes custom vegetation, 3D trees, custom ground textures, and more. The full feature list is viewable below. Chunilna Cabin Strip is available for purchase from the developer’s store or store.flightsim.com for a price of $9.99 USD. Furthermore, the developer is hoping to release the airport on the MSFS marketplace and flightsim.to, but is currently awaiting approval. As well, they are considering a release on Xbox but nothing is certain. Lastly, make sure to check out the official trailer for the airport via the developer’s YouTube Channel. As well, for further information, one can join the developer’s discord.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pawdms</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studios Releases Seward Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pawdms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6236947a144f1324f2be5e88_PAWD.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1101401"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Northern Sky Studio, responsible for many payware Alaskan airports for MSFS and X-Plane 11, has added another product to its inventory. The developer has released its rendition of Seward Airport for MSFS2020. Seward is their ninth airport for the new sim.  Primarily a general aviation airport, Seward Airport is located in the Kenai Peninsula in Alaska. It was built during WWII under "Walseth Air Force Base" before its decommission and public usage. The airport is not currently served by any airline, but does see a fair share of private traffic. Northern Sky Studios version of Seward airport contains the following features:  Seward Airport can be yours for 13.87USD/10.57GBP/12.60EUR on simMarket. The download will utilize approximately 2.20GB of space. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdgtf</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Drops Fairoaks Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdgtf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623698857b5c7407d43f7ae1_fairoaks1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="405019"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Responsible for Martha's Vineyard, Farnborough, Popham airfield, and more, Burning Blue Design has released another project, Fairoaks Airport. The airport has seen faithful recreation in the new sim, including custom scenery objects and a working windsock. Unfortunately, the actual life airport has become the center of controversy. Its owner's desire to replace the airfield with housing development met with significant resistance. Though, the airport remains operational for now until further action is taken.  The MSFS version of "EGTF" contains the following features:  You may purchase Fairoaks airport for MSFS on the Burning Blue Design website for £12.95. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rv14msfs</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Announces RV-14 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rv14msfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62369b5c06dd18d4cb15a7b0_rv141.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1216362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Developer SimWorks Studios has announced that their RV-14 is scheduled for release on Monday, March 28th. Since releasing their Quest Kodiak for the sim, the team has remained active in the MSFS space.  SimWorks Studios also announced that their FSX and Prepar3D products would no longer be updated or supported and withdrawn from sale by April 1st. Their products will become available again as freeware in six months on the developer's website.  For those who aren't familiar with the Vans RV-14, the single-engine kit aircraft is one of Van's Aircraft's newest developments. Fitted with a Lycoming IO-390 four-stroke powerplant, the plane performs well, producing nearly 215hp and can cruise at 168 knots indicated airspeed. It also has a maximum range of 815nm.  SimWorks Studios RV-14 will be available for 14.99EUR on their website and 19.99EUR on third-party stores. Stay tuned with Threshold in anticipation of the aircrafts release!</summary>
    <published>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff7879</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Previews Boeing 787 EFIS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff7879" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62369fd5296f8a3a763d5601_7871.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="262578"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer FlightFactor has posted more previews of their upcoming Boeing 787 for X-Plane 11 on Twitter. The team has presented screenshots of the aircrafts Primary Flight Display (PFD), Navigation Display (ND), and Multifunction Display (MFD). Since first announcing their 787 for X-Plane, the community has built hype around its development. We've seen many reviews ranging from its cockpit to its rendered model to its systems. While we don't have any information regarding its release, the team is making significant strides in its development. One of their more recent development updates included some early in-sim cockpit previews.  FlightFactor has multiple aircraft projects at hand, from the 777v2 to the 787 and beyond. Be on the lookout for more of their updates in the coming months. Those who want to stay in the know with FlightFactor updates can join their Discord server here. If you're interested in previous 787 or 777v2 updates, peek at our other articles. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mi3119</id>
    <title>Milviz Posts MSFS Cessna C310 Tutorial Video </title>
    <updated>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mi3119" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6236a5d3296f8a08a244ada6_c3101.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="352009"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aircraft developer Milviz has posted a new tutorial video on their YouTube channel, in the form of a tutorial, in anticipation of their upcoming C310 release for MSFS. The aircraft has been previewed since the beginning of MSFS's days, and it appears that its release is now imminent.  ‍Complimenting their C310 efforts is their upcoming ATR for MSFS. We haven't received too much information on the coinciding project yet, except for a few screenshots showcasing its operation in the new sim. The C310 has seen its fair share of exposure, including other videos and screenshots, which can be seen on Milviz's Facebook here. Milviz's Tutorial video presents the aircraft in its current state, from cold and dark startup to shutdown. Take a look at it to understand the plane better before it releases.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukksna</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Announces John Wayne Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukksna" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6237c747f610daccfaf0a65c_Screenshot%20(140).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="789775"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. As their name suggests, UK2000 have previously exclusively developed sceneries located in the United Kingdom for various simulators. However, the developer is taking a different path with the announcement of John Wayne Airport (KSNA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This airport marks the first scenery by the developer located outside of the United Kingdom, as well as their first scenery located in America. Citing the reason for the switch as “part business and part getting bored with UK airports,” the developer has stated that their venture into the American scene brings a “leap forward in improved HD PBR materials and Level of Detail for UK2000.” According to the developer, KSNA is also set to include a plethora of accurately placed custom-made models created in an efficient way to limit file size, and line markings with “black-borders” typically seen in the United States have been included. As well, UK2000 has remodeled their general aviation library collection to include additional details with PBR materials. Furthermore, new models have been added, such as the C172, SR22, P-51, and B17 for the airport museum. Additionally, the airside terminal interior has been modelled, along with “21 unique animated Jetways with high PBR details.“ Unfortunately, no further information was provided, and no release date or pricing information is known. However, it was stated that release is due soon so Threshold will make sure to keep you updated on any developments that arise with this airport. In the meantime, make sure to check out the official trailer for KSNA via UK2000 Scenery’s YouTube Channel.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/206l3c</id>
    <title>CowanSim Releases Bell Helicopters 206L3 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/206l3c" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6237d4a7bb8a60b032ba7aea_206L3-2022-03-18-09.41.52.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="208203"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Last Friday, CowanSim released their rendition of the Bell 206. The helicopter delivers many features, including floats systems, dynamic weight options, and spotlights. This product is part of a developing lineage of helicopters in the X-Plane 11 space. Unfortunately, the helicopter space hasn't been well documented, but to preface this new product, the Bell 206 is a two-bladed helicopter manufactured by Bell Helicopter. The seven-seater LongRanger was eventually developed into twin-engine options, marketed as the TwinRanger. It can cruise at a maximum speed of 120 knots over 374 nm at 13,500 feet.  CowanSim has provided the following feature list for their 206L3: Prospective 206L3 can obtain the helicopter on the CowanSim website for $32.95. Once downloaded, the product will utilize approximately 1GB of space. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfsvc</id>
    <title>Xometry Announces Victorville for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfsvc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6237d8428ff7b368140cb918_KVCV_Preview_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1857976"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Xometry is expanding into the MSFS2020 environment, as they've previewed their Victorville rendition in the new simulator. The upgraded scenery will be their first for the sim, and it surely won't be the last. Conveniently, VCV was their first airport in X-Plane 11, and it appears that Xometry is continuing that theme.  Victorville is a local legend among AvGeeks and aviation nerds in the Pacific Southwest. Famous for its vast graveyard containing hundreds of stored airline relics, the played a significant role in keeping aircraft during the COVID-19 pandemic. Fleets such as the Aero California DC-9s, Delta MD-80, MD90, and FedEx DC-10s have found their permanent home in the lower desert.  Unfortunately, the Xometry team hasn't provided an MSFS-specific feature list, so we'll give you their X-Plane 11 features: We'll keep you updated when Xometry posts additional information regarding the upcoming scenery. Join their Discord server to interact with the community if you're a prospective Victorville owner.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfto28</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews PA-38 Tomahawk for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfto28" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623936c6c13d9480f5204fe1_Pic_6_pHU32rEUR.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="501533"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has previewed their upcoming rendition of the Piper PA-38 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This update brings a new look into the aircraft, along with a detailed feature list to add to what users can expect upon release. At a first glance, the modeling on the aircraft is up to the expectations and correlates to the previous aircraft released, and upcoming. All aspects of the aircraft both exterior and exterior, are modeled accurately to resemble real-world aircraft. A total of 16 liveries will be provided on release and features liveries from many different countries. Users will also be provided a paintkit for the aircraft to create their own liveries and tailor to their own taste. Looking at the feature list provided by Just Flight, PBR texturing has been used alongside real-time reflections and realism. Full support of MSFS's icing effect has also been featured. Ground services and equipment such as chocks, fuel trucks, tie-downs, etc. are all included with the aircraft. A full 3D cockpit has been included with a full EFB will be provided to add accessibility to the user. IFR avionics will be included as well. The aircraft will be VR compatible upon release. All sounds are recorded from a real-world PA-38, alongside utilizing MSFS audio capabilities. If you are interested in the full feature list, you can view it over on Just Flight's Website. As of today, no release date or pricing has been announced. If you are interested in other products by Just Flight, you can view their full catalog over on their website. Threshold will keep you updated on further developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md1132</id>
    <title>Rotate Announces MD-11 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md1132" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623a3a9bc89d94f6d67c586b_md111.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="953620"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer Rotate has announced the release date of their upcoming McDonnell Douglas MD-11 for X-Plane 11 via X-Plane.org's YouTube channel. The hyped trijet will release on March 24th. This release marks the first-ever high-quality heavy trijet in X-Plane 11. Since the project was initially announced in May of 2017, nearly five years have passed while the community has eagerly awaited its release. As mentioned before, MD-11 is the first quality heavy trijet that the X-Plane 11 community has ever seen. Complimenting this fact is the lack of high-caliber heavy trijets in any sim, as the CaptainSim L1011 TriStar exists as the last notable 3-engined model. Preceding the CaptainSim L1011, the PMDG MD-11 and JustFlight DC-10 were developed originally for 32bit platforms such as FSX.  Rotate has distributed some preview copies to streamers for usage in anticipation of the release. Q8Pilot is currently active on the YouTube platform, showcasing the aircraft in its full glory. Check out his channel to learn more about the upcoming release. Last but not least is the pricing of the MD-11; unfortunately, neither Rotate nor X-Plane.org have provided a specific figure as to how much the plane will cost, though it was mentioned in the comments of the release trailer that pilots could expect the trijet to be in the 80-90USD range.  ‍ a special thank you to "Hampus Murling" on Discord for providing these screenshots of the MD-11!</summary>
    <published>2022-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdpsdf</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases KSDF v2 for XP11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdpsdf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623b552ad86ea5291a61aa38_X-Plane_W1h0nNAr3n.png.bafa8dc283c7e8025a3d3beba14187bd.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="915872"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has returned, this time updating their visual rendition for Louisville Muhammad Ali International for X-Plane. This update brings the scenery version to version 2 and involves the team's updated style and detail to the well-known cargo airport. Louisville International is the hub for the mainline cargo carrier, UPS. With a square footage of 5.2 million square feet and a perimeter of 7.2 miles, the UPS Worldport sees about 2 million packages a day, averaging 416,000 packages an hour. and 125 aircraft cargo stands, which makes it one of the more popular cargo airports in the world. KSDF also features a passenger terminal which in 2019, serviced about 4.2 million passengers from carriers such as Delta, Southwest, American, and many other carriers. ‍ No feature list has been provided by ZDP, however at a eye glance, detailed ground textures and 3D buildings are all provided in this package. From the included screenshots, the airport seems to be WorldTraffic 3 compatible, alongside a possible SAM Jetway extension for movable jetways. Alongside this, detailed airport ground equipment on both the cargo and passenger side of the airport, are all modeled. You can find this scenery package by Zero Dollar Payware over at the Threshold Forums, free to download. If you are interested in other packages by Zero Dollar Payware, you can find their catalog over on the Threshold Forums as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aseddn</id>
    <title>Aerosoft/Captain 7 Releases Airport Nuremberg for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aseddn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623c1261468601aab3ca01cf_aerosoft-airport-nuremberg%20(27).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="374740"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, Aerosoft/Captain 7 released its rendition of Airport Nuremberg (EDDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery, crafted with highly detailed models, high quality textures, and custom aerial images, brings an immersive experience for pilots who are flying into Bavaria. The airport, developed by Captain 7, 29Palms, and LimeSim, is accurately recreated based on the latest layout of the airport. It will feature “highly detailed buildings with internal modeling”, sloped runways, custom signage, animated jetways, realistic night lighting, and custom orthoimagery. For the full list of features, checkout Aerosoft’s store. Airport Nuremberg (EDDN), located 5km from the center of the city, is the second largest international airport in Bavaria and the 10th busiest airport in Germany. The airport, serving more than two dozen lines, connects some 4 million passengers to business and leisure destinations across Europe each year. Currently, the airport can be purchased on Aerosoft’s webstore for €16.76 or $18.40 USD, excluding any sale tax that may incur. To successfully install the product, users must have an active Aerosoft account and download the scenery via Aerosoft One.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ro11xp</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-11 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ro11xp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/623cb8b379009ea6d4fcbeb5_X-Plane_1803_2227.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1893033"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Following the announcement of the release date on Tuesday, Rotate has delivered upon their promise and has launched their MD-11 for X-Plane. The MD-11 has been Rotate's active development project since its announcement in May 2017, almost 5 years ago. The aircraft accurately depicts its real life counterpart, currently only simulating the General Electric (GE) engine option in the freighter variant. Rotate has been sharing teasers and system previews of the widebody tri-jet frequently since it first announced the aircraft aircraft, mainly focussing on individual system areas during these updates. Nearing the end of the development process, the aircraft subsequently entered beta testing in late October of 2021. Following this long test period, the developer shared the aircraft with media outlets and streamers over the past weeks ahead of today's release.  Rotate has shared an extensive feature list on the product page, although the full thing is too long to share on this article, highlights of this include over 200 custom failures, and accurate simulation of all critical aircraft systems. Rotate has also announced today, prompting lots of backlash that the aircraft will see the passenger variant as an extra purchase. Seeing as the aircraft also does not ship with the Pratt and Whitney engines, and has lots of small bugs degrading the experience, the community is seemingly disappointed. You can purchase the highly awaited Rotate MD-11 for X-Plane 11 now from the X-Plane.org Store for $83.95.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
