<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-03-03T18:25:42.499333+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simacd</id>
    <title>Threshold Exclusive: Simmy Aircraft Launches First Aircraft Project - The DA42 With Exclusive Shots</title>
    <updated>2022-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simacd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621813644c0117c57681700a_2-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="340996"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Simmy Aircraft, a newcomer to the X-Plane community, is currently well underway in developing their maiden product, a DA42VI. Having worked and contributed to numerous projects including, LevelUp, Toliss, TFDi, X-Bureau and Magknight, it is evident the team themselves are anything but new. By participating in the production of some of our favorite aircraft, we can be hopeful to see similar qualities in their products. Their early work in progress images show an already stunning strong start, Simmy's has provided Threshold with a fresh set of new images to feature: The team have stated that their primary goal is to provide a product that can be utilized in a manner that aids training. It’s no secret the DA42 is widely used across the world as a modern twin engine training option, making this a great aircraft to have virtualized, especially considering so many students are actively training on it. With this in mind, the team have expressed that in conjunction to creating a visually immaculate model, the accuracy of flight behaviors and system depth, are at the forefront of their priorities.  Looking at the current team of two, it is interesting to note that both members are actively training. With one currently working on his Multi-engine commercial license on the DA42, and the other beginning their flight instructor training. This is a key point, given the fact that both developers know what students want and need from such a simulation, as they both approach this project from the perspective of a student. This in itself gives this team an upper hand, which we hope reflects in the end product.  With the aircraft aimed at the upcoming X-Plane 12 platform, this could very well be one of the simulators' very first native payware. Leading the way with a fresh new plane in a fresh new sim. For more information stay tuned, and we’ll be sure to bring you the latest when made available.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ksryxp</id>
    <title>VerticalSim Releases Syracuse for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ksryxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62186e8938a1935df7038b83_Cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="140798"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VerticalSim has released the visual rendition of Syracuse Airport (KSYR) for X-Plane 11 just 3 months after the initial release of Boise Airport for the same client. The developer’s scenery style has finally reached the Empire State. Syracuse Airport is locate near the city of Syracuse, New York. After land was purchased in 1928, a small airfield was constructed to service airmail carriers. After World War 2, the Army Air Corps leased the local bomber base near the small airfield, which then further transformed into the Clarence E. Hancock Airport in 1949. At the time of opening, the airport had four airlines basing routes in and out of the airfield, which included but are not limited to, American Airlines and Mohawk Airlines. Today, the airport receives both passenger and cargo operations. This visual rendition offers many qualities that VerticalSim has made standard in all of its releases. Right out of the box, 4K PBR textures and HDR night lighting have been included, alongside the airport's current layout as of 2022. SAM Jetway support and animated vehicle traffic have also been added to enhance the user’s experience. Lastly, taxi routes are available for AI Traffic addons. The full feature list has been provided upon release: If you are interested in purchasing this scenery, you can find it on VerticalSim’s Store Page for $19.99. For other visual scenery packages by VerticalSim, visit their website.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/recyyz</id>
    <title>RegDesigns Announces Toronto Pearson Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/recyyz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62194ddf74ffdb61a0d4d080_YYZ10%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="967588"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Toronto-based developer, RegDesigns have announced their rendition of Toronto Pearson International Airport (CYYZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. After being sought after by the community for quite a while now, the announcement of CYYZ comes with a plethora of excitement from the community. Unfortunately, not much information was provided, except the fact that the airport recently entered beta. Excitingly, however, a trailer is set to release later today via the developer’s YouTube Channel. Located in the Greater Toronto Area (Ontario, Canada), Toronto Pearson is an incredibly large airport within Canada, with 50.5 million visitors in 2019, the aerodrome sees a vast array of aircraft types frequently visiting, including the enormous Airbus A380. Furthermore, the airport marks the first major airport within Canada created by RegDesigns, with their previous creations including Waterloo (CYKF), Guelph (CNC4), and more.  Lastly, the airport is set to cost $19.99. However, no further information was given, and no potential release date is known. Nevertheless, make sure to check out the developer's YouTube Channel, to view the trailer which is releasing soon. Finally, to acquire additional information, make sure to check out the developer’s website, or join their discord server where a giveaway is being hosted as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lirfms</id>
    <title>MK-STUDIOS Releases Rome-Fiumicino For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lirfms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621ae48bb2da881966b3d78c_Cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="260149"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The development teams at MK-STUDIOS have released their visual rendition of Rome-Fiumicino International Airport (LIRF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release brings the developer’s quality and attention to detail to the Mediterranean airport. To some, this airport is also known as the Leonardo Da Vinci International Airport, opening its doors in 1961. With 2 runways operating upon opening, this airport was to help alleviate passenger traffic from the smaller Rome Ciampino Airport after the 1960 Rome Olympics. The airport later built a third runway when Alitalia Airlines built its main hub within the same decade. Today, the airport is ranked the 11th busiest airport in Europe, servicing 43.5 million passengers in 2019 (pre-pandemic), and services the new Italian carrier, ITA Airways as of late 2021. The feature list provided is short but simple, with the use of PBR textures alongside this rendition featuring the airport's current 2022 layout. Satellite imagery has been used on the airport grounds, including small simplified terminal interiors. The full feature list has been provided and below: - Rome Fiumicino Airport in very detailed rendition, - High definition PBR textures, - 2022 airport layout, - Satellite image for the airport area, - Simplified terminal interior.  To purchase the visual rendition of Leonardo da Vinci International Airport for €15.99, visit simMarket. For other scenery packages developed by MK-STUDIOS, visit their product page on simMarket.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kastms</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Astoria Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kastms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621aea579c2cc63da86a7a64_Cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2968597"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Skyline Simulations has released its newest product - Astoria Regional Airport (KAST) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Utilizing technologies such as PBR textures and FSEco-subsystem, the developers bring users an immersive experience of the unique regional airport on the coast of Oregon. According to Skyline Simulations, Astoria airport has been crafted to reflect the latest airport updates. Featuring HD/PBR ground decals, detailed 3D building models, custom static objects, landmarks, and an accurate city model based on realistic OSM data. A full list of features can be viewed on the developer’s store page. Located in Warrenton Astoria, Oregon, the airport serves both civilian traffic and the United States Coast Guard. Currently, KAST has no scheduled airline flights, though it is a popular general aviation destination for the locals. Flying to the region, users can “enjoy the night view with beautiful landmarks such as the Astoria Column, the Lighthouse, and the famous Astoria-Megler Bridge". Currently, Astoria Regional Airport (KAST) can be purchased on Skyline Simulation’s webstore or simMarket for $21.00 USD or EUR 19.00, excluding any potential sales tax.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctpwbd</id>
    <title>VATSIM Cross the Pond Westbound Airports Announced</title>
    <updated>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctpwbd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621c0b07bdead4684b8696af_7JRF7kO.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="26812"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After originally opening up voting earlier this month, the Virtual Air Traffic Simulation Network, better known as VATSIM, has revealed the airports set to be used for this year's Cross the Pond (CTP) Westbound event. This year, it will take place on April 2nd. For those unaware, Cross the Pond is an extremely popular event held annually on the network which allows users to fly across the Atlantic with full ATC coverage and realistic procedures. Not only does this event generate a lot of excitement within the community, but it typically sees an incredible amount of traffic, making it one of the busiest events on the network. Ranging from Munich Airport (EDDM) to Barbados (TBPB), the community has voted on a multitude of different departure and arrival aerodromes, which are viewable in the picture below. It should be noted, however, that users will need to book a CTP slot to ensure participation in this event without delays. However, users are able to take part in the event without booking a slot, but delays should be expected. For further information make sure to check out the VATSIM Cross the Pond website. As well, Threshold will make sure to keep you updated once the bookings for the event open.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdcyyz</id>
    <title>RegDesigns Releases Toronto Pearson Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdcyyz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621c1a3994f8cdea34ef58f3_YYZ1%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="733661"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After announcing the airport quite recently, RegDesigns have released their highly awaited rendition of Toronto Pearson Airport (CYYZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is set to be the first recreation of CYYZ within MSFS, and marks the first major airport created by the developer. Located in Ontario, Canada, Toronto Pearson is an incredibly large airport both by size and passenger amount, with the airport seeing 50.5 million passengers pass through its doors in 2019. Furthermore, the airport serves as a hub for some of Canada’s largest carriers, including Air Canada, WestJet, Sunwing Airlines, and more. The airport comes with a plethora of immersion-richening features to bring the airport to life, these include a custom and accurate interior, volumetric night lighting, custom jetways, and much more. The full feature list is viewable below. Feature List: • Accurate replica of Toronto Lester B. Pearson International Airport  • Accurate modelling from original images, personal experiences, aerial photography, and other   sources   • Custom animated jetways  • Accurate terminal interiors  • Custom animated objects  • Custom ground textures and markings  • Correct runway elevations (per CFS)  • Common roads around airfield modelled  • Nearby trenches and fields modelled  • Airport lighting (per the Canadian Flight Supplement)  • 3D Glass with Dynamic Rain  • Volumetric night lighting  • Emissive night textures  • Highly detailed airport environment  • Correct PAPI angles  • Hangar interiors  • LODs  • More (RegDesigns high standard of detail and fidelity) Canada’s biggest airport is available for purchase from a multitude of stores for various different prices. These include Contrail for $20.10 excluding VAT, and via the RegDesigns store for $18.95 plus a free copy of their Guelph Airpark scenery for MSFS. It was also stated that the airport would be coming to the MSFS Marketplace and simMarket in the coming weeks.  Finally, make sure to check out the official trailer for CYYZ which was originally previewed on Friday. As well, the developer has stated that they will be willing to take requests from people who work at the airport that would like something custom modelled. </summary>
    <published>2022-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crwxp1</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Posts Trailer Showcasing Upcoming West Virginia Airport for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crwxp1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621c809be24b25aeefb7331a_KCRW_Preview_22%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="578611"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniBuilds has posted a trailer showcasing Xometry Designs new project, West Virginia International Yeager Airport for X-Plane 11. The airport serves as the newest addition to Xometrys expanding range of products, which now include Victorville, Punta Delgada, Eagle County and West Virginia International Airport. Yeager Airport will take advantage of X-Plane 11s technology by featuring high resolution ground textures, PBR, SAM jetways alongside other luxuries.  Otherwise known as McLaughlin Air National Guard Base, West Virginia Yeager International airport is a dual-purpose airport, served both by the military and commercial airline operators. Carriers that currently provide flights to the airport include American Eagle, Delta Airlines, Delta Connection, Spirit Airlines and United Express. It’s also imperative to mention that the geography of the airport is unique, as it sits on a hilltop 300 feet (100 meters) above the lower Charleston metropolitan area providing for a cool approach. Reverting back to the X-Plane variant of the airport, iniBuilds provided this features list: Whilst iniBuilds hasn't provided a specific release date for the airport, they've detailed that the airport is “coming soon”. Once available for purchase, iniBuilds will publish Yeager Airport to their store for £15.49/€18.43/$20.77. Make sure to monitor Threshold in the forthcoming future in anticipation of the airports release.    </summary>
    <published>2022-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mdppms</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Studios Releases Puerto Plata Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mdppms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621d1b2e98c66a030b68479e_mdpp%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="473359"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Scenery developer Dreamflight Studios has released its rendition of Puerto Plata airport for MSFS2020. The news follows their recent release of McClellan Palomar airport for the new sim last month. Puerto Plata is a feature-rich airport, as it presents itself with full PBR and HD textures, sloped runways, as well as other commodities.  Gregorio Luperon International Airport, also known as Puerto Plata Airport, is one of the Dominican Republic's busiest airports. Its proximity to the coast makes it popular with leisure tourists, especially snowbirds who desire to escape the harsh winters of the Northern US, Canada, and northern Europe. Puerto Plata is served by a slew of airlines, most notably by Air Transat, American Airlines, Condor, Finnair, JetBlue, United in addition to other leisure airlines. Due to the nature of this region, the vast majority of this service is seasonal, only containing a few scheduled flights during the summer.  Dreamflight Studios rendition of Gregorio Luperon International Airport showcases the following features: Puerto Plata airport is available on simMarket for 12.99EUR/10.85GBP/14.55USD. The product is installed with the Contrail desktop app. Once downloaded, the airport will utilize approximately 500MB of space. Stay tuned with Threshold to keep current with future Dreamflight Studios news! </summary>
    <published>2022-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flyyyz</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Publishes Toronto Pearson for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flyyyz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621db201fb202563638518dc_cyyz5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="373391"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The renowned scenery developer, FlyTampa, has shipped out its rendition of Toronto Pearson International Airport (CYYZ), for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release brings more of the developer's high-quality development and accurate renditions to the major intercontinental airport.  Toronto has a small history that dates back to 1937 when the Canadian Government opted to build 2 airports, one of which currently resides on the Toronto Islands which is present-day Billy Bishop Toronto City Airport, and the other to be built in northwest Toronto, named the Malton Airport, and received its first passenger service in 1939. After WW2, the airport received international status in 1958 and was changed to Lester B. Pearson International Airport in 1984. FlyTampa has included a detailed feature list for this package. Starting off, an interior of the terminals has been provided alongside the latest layout of the airport as of 2022. PBR textures and Dynamic lighting are included as well. 3D terrain including both tunnels and bridges is accurately modeled to depict the current layout of the airport.  If you are interested in picking this scenery package for yourself, you can find it over on FlyTampa’s Website and it sells for $17.99. You can also find this airport for a variety of other simulators such as FSX and Prepar3D, over on their website as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfsv8</id>
    <title>Asobo Studio Released Sim Update VIII (v1.23.12.0) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfsv8" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621dd63b54a5a14f89e39168_JAPAN_Update_Shrine-1024x576.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="162837"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, Asobo Studio released Sim Update VIII (v1.23.12.0) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update brings a few new features and a large variety of improvements to simulator stability, weather, VR, developer SDK, and default aircrafts. Starting off with the new features, the developers announced that the Market Place will receive a brand new UI that brings “improved discoverability and a better navigation experience”. Additionally, an optional propeller simulation system with “hundreds of moving surfaces” is now available for the Cessna 152, Cessna 208 B Grand Caravan EX, and Beechcraft King Air 350i, improving the realism of propeller effects such as feathering and prop-drag. Finally, a new private match mode for Reno air Races can now be accessed via content manager and a new Spotlight Event has been added that features landing a Cessna Citation CJ4 at Reno Stead airport. In addition to the new features, Asobo Studio also introduced a long list of bug fixes and improvements that address almost every area of the simulator. The complete list can be viewed on MSFS’s website. Currently, Sim Update VIII is available to download for all users. As usual, the developers have reminded the community to temporarily move community packages to another folder if the new version brings “unexpected impact on the title’s performance and behavior”. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/waxp12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Addresses Wake Turbulence in X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/waxp12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621e3670cb15834234c64554_xp12wt01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="429571"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Phillip from Laminar Research addressed wake turbulence in the upcoming X-Plane 12 Flight Simulator. Involving both player aircraft and AI aircraft and its correlation with the simulator physics and aerodynamics.  AI Traffic After a brief introduction about wake turbulence, Phillip addresses the wake turbulence that is left by AI aircraft. All AI aircraft will leave the correct wake turbulence that corresponds to its aircraft, and is calculated properly with the vortex that is created by the wing of the aircraft. Same will apply for user aircraft. Phillip then goes on to say:  Online Traffic, 3rd Party Plugins, and Live Traffic Further on, Phillip addresses wake turbulence left by online network aircraft, live traffic, and other 3rd party plugins. With the correct data through an ADS-B exchange, X-Plane will calculate the best effects to aircraft weight, wing area, and wingspan through the data the plugin provides. Current XP11 traffic plugins are compatible with the wake turbulence and will be a base function in XP12.  That’s it for today’s update, but Threshold will be sure to keep you up to date with any further X-Plane 12 development updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md80be</id>
    <title>Leonardo Reveals New MSFS2020 Maddog Details</title>
    <updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md80be" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621f2a9f57462cd984e02f6a_06.thumb.jpg.5cb6893fdc5dd7a12d08f5ed7c1b07cf.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="109387"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stefano from Leonardo Software House has updated the community regarding the status of its upcoming McDonnell Douglas MD-80 for MSFS2020. The Long Beach-built airliner is officially in “advanced beta testing”, as the fixed Software Development Kit has allowed the team to progress on the project as anticipated. There’s no release date yet, as the foreseeable development is contingent on MSFS’s evolution.  LSH’s Release Plan Similar to their Prepar3D release map, Leonardo will most likely divide their Maddog packages by variant. The team will initially release the MD-82 with JT8D-217A engines, a 162Y configured cabin, and a Honeywell FMS to satisfy NAV, VNAV, and ACARS. Following the MD-82 will be an MD-83/88 expansion package, and then JT8D-217C/219 engines, the Canadian Marconi FMS and PMS, an EFB, as well as aging and servicing features.   Anticipated MSFS Features If you’re strapped for time, a few notable features of the release include: Below is the full feature list that’ll be included in the release version of the MD-80, the list is quite substantial, but not overwhelming.  Fly the Maddog X MSFS version 1.0 will include: - MD82 with -217A engines, PAX Cabin 162Y and Honeywell FMS for NAV/VNAV/ACARS; - Flight model and engines performances tested and matched against real aircraft performance tables; - All systems/avionics/tests etc, fully implemented as in the P3D version, including failures/INOPs feature, fully dimmable integral and flood lightning, working TCAS and EGPWS terrain mode; - New FMS Services page for controlling DOORS/STAIR, External power, fuel loading, etc.; - Fully integrated with MSFS ecosystem (jetway, catering, baggage loader, etc...); - Integration with PFPX/SimBrief via Load Manager and retrieval of OFP data via the ACARS system; - Livery manager, and aircraft settings configurable for different aircrafts; - Livery-based cockpit color (pink, blue or gray) and main panel variations (including placards and speed bugs); - Can be installed in the same machine with Fly the Maddog X for P3D; Configurable options from Load Manager:  - Panel state when starting simulation (Cold &amp; Dark, Ready at Gate, Ready for Takeoff...); - Weight &amp; Balance and route planner; - Load Manager units (Kg/mbar or Lbs/InHg); Aircraft options: - Cockpit units (Kg/mbar or Lbs/InHg); - PFD flight director style (cross bar or single cue), rising runway, ND wind arrow, groundspeed and aircraft map symbol, HDG UP or TRK UP option; - PFD wired to opposite NAV; - Armed altitude as FL and AutoArm altitude option; - Gear waring inhibit above 1500ft AGL; - Always play aural when autopilot disconnects; - Auto brake system; - Three VOR instrument versions: VOR/ADF/DME, VOR/ADF and VOR only; - Two altimeter versions: DUAL/SINGLE knob; - Optional TAS/SAT indicator; - Flat or Cone tail; Simulator options: - Enable failures; - Autopilot disconnect when flight controls moved; - Automatic update of aircraft weight and cg; - Automatic fuel loading; - Enable PM calls; - Sync CM1/CM2; - FSUIPC compatibility mode; - Maximum luminosity of all cockpit lights and instruments (flood, integral, LED, LCD and CRT); - Failures probability, separated for LIGHT, MEDIUM and DANGEROUS; - INOP systems according to MEL; Some Sidenotes Stefan informed the community that the Maddog will contain modifiable settings (including panel states) actively within the sim without requiring a flight restart. Another detail mentioned in the footnotes is the lack of weather radar functionality due to the SDK’s current state, but will be implemented, for free, as soon as the SDK will allow.  ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- As the war in Ukraine endures, Threshold is allocating all of the donation proceeds, including previous Threshold donations, towards the Ukrainian Crisis cause. 25% of all proceeds is set aside for Ukrainian X-Plane developers while the remaining is directly sent to UNICEF’s donation program for Ukrainian children. If you’re interested in contributing, please visit our donation page.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asmyko</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Updates Mykonos Airport Scenery </title>
    <updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asmyko" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621f2e00377af6e5088db6fa_lgmk-msfs_05.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="275243"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently released an update for their Mykonos airport scenery. The update is quite lengthy and substantial with numerous changes made to keep the airport's virtual rendition up to date with the real airport. Let's take a closer look and highlight some of the more interesting additions made.  Before we get into the particulars. Looking at the images above we can really begin to appreciate how far scenery development has come, with the developers putting effort into seamlessly blending the airport into an already realistic default scenery. The releases of yesteryears in flight simulation would frequently have contrasting colours between the scenery satellite imagery and the default textures. The majority of changes have been prompted by the recent changes Mykonos airport has undergone. The $28 million upgrade has essentially given the airport a “facelift” with a stunning new facade symbolizing the traditional Cycladic architecture. The project was set to open in 2021 and so it did, with no delay from Aerosoft who were relatively quick to follow suit and update their product. Here’s their full change list for you to check out: Reading through the list, it seems the team at Aerosoft has almost completely recreated the airport, with new lights, new textures, new modeling and enhanced mesh, with existing users being able to expect an almost brand new product. It is pleasing to see this focus on what essentially can be referred to as virtual modernisation, especially as an update and not as a whole new product. While not expected from developers, scenarios like these are appreciated. Check out their official post on the update, and should you wish to purchase the product, it can be found on the Aerosoft store.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dccord</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases Release Date for DC Design Concorde</title>
    <updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dccord" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62207602cb346868b9501678_274221808_3194114267576217_7149942691568301623_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="657894"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Recently, a new banner has quietly appeared on Just Flight’s website, announcing that the much anticipated Concorde for Microsoft Flight Simulator will be releasing sometime this month (March 2022). The aircraft, developed by DC Designs, is built ground up for the new simulator with customized handling models and accurate modeling/texturing, bringing users an enjoyable flying experience with the world’s only supersonic airliner. Over the past few months, DC Designs has released weekly updates on the development progress of the Concorde. The latest one, posted on February 25th, teases that work is currently being done on PBR textures and showcases the external and internal modeling of the aircraft. It is clear from both the text and the pictures that Concord is near completion. 	Announced in mid 2021, DC Design’s Concorde “is designed to be both an accessible and yet highly detailed rendition of this iconic aircraft”. To ensure a high degree of accuracy with its designs, the team has reconstructed the aircraft with hundreds of real life images of the Concord taken from museums and exhibits. Checkout Just Flight’s website for a complete list of the Concorde’s features. Currently, neither Just Flight or DC Designs has published an official announcement that specifies the release date and pricing for the Concorde. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/146332</id>
    <title>Just Flight Further Previews MSFS BAe 146</title>
    <updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/146332" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62207680bf135606de592e63_274787448_10161824804168499_4968259245970406681_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="533287"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has posted more previews of their upcoming BAe 146 for MSFS2020. The news comes in light of their subsequent aircraft developments, such as the newly announced 757, collaboration with DCDesigns, and In-House Fokker F28. The team mentions in their Facebook post that more news will be delivered in the imminent future and that "release time draws closer." The following screenshots showcase the aircraft partaking in a test flight from Southampton to Bournemouth.  For those who are unaware, the British Aerospace 146, also known as the BAe 146, is a short-haul regional airliner developed by British Aerospace. Containing four turbofan engines, as well as a T-tail, the "Jumbolino" garners its reputation from its quirky design features. Over 380 units were built from 1978-to 2001, primarily serving European operators such as CityJet and Swiss. The aircraft was delivered under the name "Avro RJ" after 1992, shipping with upgraded avionics and more powerful engines. In the current world, few Avro RJs remain, some serve middle eastern carriers, and some serve as "off the grid" transporters as the aircraft contains gravel landing abilities.  Just Flight did not share any additional information regarding the BAe 146's development, but keep an eye out shortly as the team admitted that there's a new development update around the corner.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
