<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-08-03T18:37:29.098324+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2htul</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Tulsa International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2htul"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68818185c24495951b939268_tulsa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Tulsa International Airport (KTUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Tulsa, Oklahoma, and has a yearly average of 3.2 million passengers. The airport opened nearly a hundred years ago, in 1928, as Tulsa Municipal Airport. Its initial infrastructure was rather rough, with a one-story wood and tar “terminal” and landing strips and taxiways made of mown grass. It was busy enough at the time to be the “busiest airport in the World,” handling nearly 10,000 passengers a month, somehow outpacing Croydon Airport in London, Berlin Tempelhof, and Paris Le Bourget. In the early 1930s, Frederick Kershner designed a new terminal with an elegant Art Deco design, no more wood and tar. That building soldiered on until the 1950s, when the administration realized it was no longer sufficient for the traffic figures, leading to the construction of a new terminal in 1958. The new – and much bigger – terminal opened in 1961, qualifying it to become an International airport two years later. It hosted the 130th Fighter Wing in 1940 during the early stages of World War 2. Within a year of that, the War Department determined that Tulsa would become the site of an Air Force Plant, operated by Douglas Aircraft Corporation to manufacture and assemble bombers from 1942 to 1945. A year after the war, American Airlines purchased two ex-Air Force hangars to start their maintenance facilities in Tulsa, where they had nonstop routes to Los Angeles and San Francisco. In the 1960s, McDonnell Douglas still used the Air Force Plant for aircraft maintenance. The lease ended in 1996, when Boeing acquired it for aerospace manufacturing. The passenger terminal was renovated in the 2010s, designed by Gensler and Benham Companies. The ceilings were raised, passenger waiting areas were improved, and the gates were redesigned. It’s a hub for Omni Air International and Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality terminal model and its respective interior, custom jetways, custom taxiway labels, custom ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket (2020 / 2024) for roughly $21.63, requiring at least 2.87 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksad2</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Adelaide Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksad2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883dabffe1f0d96eedca117_mk_ypad_21-scaled.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing Adelaide Airport to MSFS 2020 and 2024. This marks the developer’s first entry into the Australian continent, offering users the opportunity to explore one of Australia's perhaps lesser-known aviation hubs, with a high level of detail and accuracy. Adelaide Airport is located approximately 4 miles west of the city centre and serves as the primary gateway to South Australia. It accommodates domestic, international, and general aviation traffic, and operates flights to over 30 destinations across Oceania, Asia, and North America. The airport also functions as a hub for Virgin Australia, a focus city for Qantas, and a base for Jetstar. With over 8.7 million passengers recorded in the latest fiscal year, it ranks as the fifth-busiest airport in the country. The scenery package features a highly detailed rendition of the airport, including a fully modelled terminal interior, updated taxiways, custom terrain elevation and airport lighting, and animated ground vehicles. Enhancements for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 include newwalkable jetways. The scenery is also compatible with AI traffic, and includes custom aerial photogrammetry and infrastructure, based on extensive reference material. The new Safedock FleX docking system is also depicted, as well as animated traffic. Adelaide Airport for MSFS is currently available via Orbx for $28.99 AUD, excluding applicable sales tax. Wider availability through Contrail, iniBuilds, and SimMarket will follow at a later date. You can also buy Adelaide Airport as part of ORBX’s Adelaide Airport &amp; City Bundle, which includes the Orbx Adelaide City Pack, now available at a 15% discount. The full feature list follows below: ‍Key Features For all the latest in flight simulation scenery and more MK Studios updates, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwpncl</id>
    <title>RW Profiles Announces Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwpncl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883e3c1db9ba2bf21ac98f3_97701c_bac5e30604b747988423d17c3ed79561mv2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. RW Profiles has announced its upcoming release of Newcastle International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Set to launch later this month, the scenery aims to deliver a high-fidelity recreation of one of the United Kingdom’s key regional hubs. Newcastle International Airport served over five million passengers in 2024, connecting the Northeast of England to more than 80 destinations across Europe, the Middle East, and North America. It is home to over 15 airlines, including British Airways, Jet2, TUI and easyJet. Despite its short runway, the airport also sees regular service from Emirates 777s. The scenery comes with a comprehensive set of features, in order to replicate the airport to a high degree of accuracy. These include fully hand-crafted ground textures, a detailed terminal interior, and a complete representation of the landside area. Airport buildings, objects, and surrounding infrastructure are modelled in high detail, with the layout reflecting the airport’s current configuration. Additional features include accurate night lighting, hand-placed and custom runway and taxiway lighting, animated jetways in multiple configurations, and a fully modelled general aviation area, complete with static aircraft and an FBO interior. Custom ground clutter, GSE, and a bespoke GSX profile are also included. The package is further optimised for performance, using LODs and instancing. You will also have access to configuration options that can disable certain scenery elements, including the terminal interior. The current feature list follows below: Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020 and 2024 is scheduled to release on July 30, 2025. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to keep an eye on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrbh1</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Teases Birmingham Airport for MSFS, Targets Aug. 1 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrbh1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883ed371ae46b515563f918_523539154_18050624060547769_5117856982497558575_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pyreegue Dev Co. has announced a provisional release date of Aug. 1 for its highly anticipated Birmingham Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update, shared by Pyreegue in a social media post, confirms that we won’t have to wait much longer for its release. The airport will include a custom GSX profile, developed by Hinshee, and preview streams are planned for the coming week. The upcoming scenery will depict Birmingham Airport in high detail, covering the airside, terminal buildings, detailed interiors and more. Located approximately 7 miles east-southeast of Birmingham city centre, Birmingham Airport is a major UK aviation hub. It served over 12.9 million passengers in 2017 and offers flights to destinations across Europe, Africa, the Middle East, North America, the Caribbean, and the Indian subcontinent. It is currently an operating base for easyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Further details on features and pricing are expected to follow ahead of the targeted release. For all the latest on Pyreegue’s Birmingham Airport, and more flight simulation news, be sure to stay updated on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfftl</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Fly the Line – Short Haul Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfftl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883fd20616b2a467859d99e_videoframe_16378.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Just Flight has released Fly the Line – Short Haul Edition,  a standalone application designed to introduce structured, career-based progression to the flight simulation experience. Being compatible with all major platforms, including MSFS 2020, MSFS 2024, X-Plane 11, X-Plane 12, Prepar3D v4 through v6, and Flight Simulator X, the program offers a versatile and personalised short-haul airline experience. Fly the Line allows you to assume the role of a short-haul airline pilot, starting as a Junior First Officer and advancing toward the rank of Fleet Captain. Career progression is guided by performance across scheduled flights, with players earning cash, XP, and skill points to unlock new abilities, lifestyle improvements, and boost well-being, factors that influence job effectiveness. The application features three distinct game modes: Career Mode, where you build an airline career with generated routes and weekly schedules; Free Play Mode, which offers access to all features from the start, and Schedule Mode, focusing solely on realistic schedules and immersive flying, without the progression mechanics. You can create up to eight personalised pilot profiles and 16 aircraft profiles, each with its own schedules and data. Route generation is based on real-world airline data, and offers short- to medium-haul sectors, ranging from 30 minutes to around six hours. The software also includes dynamic diversions, sightseeing flights, side jobs, and a progression system that unlocks over 30 pilot skills. Lifestyle upgrades, such as home furnishings and sim pit setups, appear in a 3D-rendered home environment. Each flight is logged in a logbook, detailing performance metrics and feedback on landing quality, as well as other parameters. You can also create a custom airline, using any aircraft. Fly the Line is available from the Just Flight store for $39.99 USD. The program comes with an installer and includes built-in tutorials.  For the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simworks-studios-provides-update-on-airvan-pc-12-and-more</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Provides Update on Airvan, PC-12 and More, for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simworks-studios-provides-update-on-airvan-pc-12-and-more"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688409b1218da587bf89aa5d_523452896_1296718509122493_6898909485459796710_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimWorks Studios has recently issued a development update on social media, outlining progress across several ongoing projects, including the GA8 Airvan, PC-12, and FS2024 upgrades for the Kodiak series. Firstly, the developer stated that the MSFS 2020 version of the GA8 Airvan is nearing release, with the developer confirming that initial copies have already been distributed to ten users, ahead of launch. The MSFS 2024 variant is currently feature-complete; however, its release has been deferred by approximately one month to allow for additional testing following the rollout of Sim Update 3. Accompanying documentation, including the aircraft manual and a failures supplement for the SystemsPulse system, will be published next week, alongside the product page of the GA8. SimWorks Studios also stated that the Airvan will be released via the Microsoft Marketplace to begin with, with a direct store launch planned for a later date. The developer also shared updates on the Pilatus PC-12. The interior model rework has been completed, and is now entering the testing phase. In addition to improving FS2024 compatibility, the updated model features adapted Level of Detail (LOD) variants for better performance and reduced file size. The new cabin has seamless textures and enhanced customisability, allowing for more detailed liveries. Work on the PC-12 exterior model is expected to begin next week, with a teaser of the NG variant planned at a later date. SimWorks Studios is also working to enable hot-swapping between avionics configurations, the GNS, GTN and GTNXi, using the tablet system from the Airvan, which will be ported over to the PC-12. In closing, the developer noted continued progress on making both the Kodiak 100 and 900 compatible with MSFS 2024, with more news expected soon. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fenixbfupreview</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Teases Upcoming Major Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fenixbfupreview"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6886bd015bed0e2ee073dfd2_bfu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations recently published a 30-minute video showcasing some of the upcoming changes that will accompany the so-called Big Fenix Update, which is set to release on Tuesday or Wednesday. The changes include a complete rework of the landing behavior, using over 800,000 real-life landings from different A320 family aircraft, spanning their entire lineup (A319/A320/A321), the addition of the A319SL, a rare variant of the A319 only operated by a few airlines around the world, an entirely reworked cockpit for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version, making use of its new lighting engine, and an interactive walkaround mode (also 2024 only), among many other tweaks and fixes. Furthermore, their A320 lineup will feature a working weather radar – only missing the tilt feature due to a sim limitation –, LIDO charts support (2024), sound improvements, and become less reliant on the Prosim base. Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (complete bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxbfu</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases “Big Fenix Update” for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxbfu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6887a3b2db6f22ef4f786a4f_videoframe_356352%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations today released the long‑anticipated, aptly nicknamed “Big Fenix Update”, a sweeping overhaul of the entire A320 family, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. The update delivers full MSFS 2024 support, major flight-model enhancements, and a range of system, livery, art, and EFB improvements. The update introduces full FS2024‑native modular SimObject support and rendering updates, along with new engine models, as well as the new A319 Sharklet variant, with custom performance data. The flight deck has been remodelled and retextured for MSFS 2024, complete with reworked display rendering, new soundsets, and a revamped livery manager featuring dozens of new liveries. Landing dynamics and fly‑by‑wire responsiveness have been retuned, with ground law, elevator deflection, AoA protection and αMAX handling improved across all variants. Flex temp unlatching logic, OP CLB/DES behaviour, and Flight Director pitch response in normal flight have all been refined. Performance has also been improved through reduced CPU load and optimised display rendering. A new LOD-system has also been implemented for all models, bringing further optimization. Flight model enhancements focus on improved ground‑law behaviour, AoA protection, and refined handling characteristics across all variants. Autopilot pitch response, flex temp logic, and Open Climb/Descent behaviour have also been reworked. Furthermore, Wingflex has also seen further improvement. The update introduces full support for MSFS 2024’s walkaround mode, with interactive cargo doors, chocks, power panels, engine fanblades and refuelling controls. Automatic connection of stairs and door opening on spawn-in has been added. New configuration options in the EFB allow control over ADIRS type, ACP style and ISIS display preferences. The update also brings support for the MSFS weather-radar, which is now fully implemented, within simulator limitations. Furthermore, the update includes various visual upgrades such as new cabin lighting, a new native iridescent windshield material, microscratches and refined glass decals for MSFS 2024. New sounds have been added to doors, cooling fans and avionics contactors, amongst others. A completely new IAE engine sound set is also included, with windmilling effects.  Walkaround mode now supports inside‑outside sound transitions and even avatar walking noises, though collisions may still cause occasional jitter. A brand‑new native EFB chart app is featured, with LIDO support and an option to switch between simulator and Navigraph sources. Pilot Brief PDF viewing, custom refuelling rates, take‑off performance tools with ACT count, chart annotations and automatic switching of weight units when importing from SimBrief are included. The EFB also now works in walkaround-mode.  For a further deep dive into flight model and fly‑by‑wire behaviour, an unlisted video on Fenix’s official YouTube channel offers detailed insight into control input processing and control surface responses.  You can watch it here. The full changelog for the update follows below: Avionics and Systems Art and Sound EFB Flight and Engine Models For all the latest in flight simulation news, stay up to date on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fslneo310</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo &amp; neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fslneo310"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68540e8ed866ddc50457ee02_fslneo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs recently issued a new experimental update to their A321ceo and ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update focuses on increasing stability, improving visual performance, and improving the braking distance, among other things. Update v11.0.1.310 is a small interim update that brings further improvements to performance, improves stability by mitigating a problem with the TCAS that causes CTDs, and fixes a typographical error in the aircraft.cfg that would allow the plane to be used as AI traffic, hindering performance. They have also made further tweaks to the handling, fine-tuned the autobrake distance, and prevented the brakes from “grabbing” on touchdown under some specific circumstances. Furthermore, the update also extends compatibility with hardware such as overheads, pedestals, and more that can be used with Mobiflight. ‍ The complete changelog follows below: FMGC: BSCU: Systems Improvements: The developers have also announced they will improve the thrust and drag models for the LEAP engines. They will bring a more accurate thrust output across altitude and mach ranges and refined drag behavior to better reflect real-world figures in terms of overall performance and fuel burn. These improvements are based on deeper performance data analysis and internal validation work they have been doing for the past couple of weeks. The new changes are expected to roll out in an interim update next week. The A321ceo and neo are available in their store for $69.95 each. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2acomanche165</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2acomanche165"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665ba18298e4f651ac834e3a_comanche.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently rolled out an update to their Accu-Sim Piper Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, correcting “a few niggles that have crept in”. Update 1.6.5 swaps the Pilot and Co-Pilot, fixes broken 3rd party GPS units when additional liveries are selected, wind direction is reported in relation to the true north on the tablet, and the GTN 750 configuration was changed to prevent runaway trim situations. They had to hold back sending the previous update to other storefronts until this issue was fixed. With that out of the way, they have now submitted it to all third parties for intake. The add-on is available in their store for $37.49 (discounted price).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilca</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilca"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688a7a3e6e25861a4677a97b_videoframe_18336.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has announced its upcoming scenery release of Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024. The product aims to provide a comprehensive and performance-optimised recreation of Cyprus’s busiest airport, featuring an up-to-date recreation of the popular holiday destination. Located on the island’s southern coast, Larnaca Airport functions as a key gateway for both regional and international travel. The scenery features hand-made ground textures, dynamic lighting, a fully modelled terminal building, with interior detailing, and a complete set of custom buildings and airport signage. The layout represents the real-world operation as of 2025. Key features of the scenery include high-resolution textures in PBR, bespoke jetways, accurate foliage placement, and clutter models, to reflect the airport's current operational atmosphere. The package also comes with a custom GSX profile. The scenery uses Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s updated SDK and includes optimised LODs to ensure broad hardware compatibility. The product will be available for purchase soon through iniBuilds at £9.99, excluding sales tax. Be sure to stay updated on Threshold for all the latest in flight simulation! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwpnc1</id>
    <title>RW Profiles Releases Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwpnc1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688a81f555f9e6f2f1e79a82_videoframe_110467%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. RW Profiles has released its rendition of Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020 and 2024, following the developer’s announcement last week.  Located in the northeast of England, Newcastle International Airport handled over five million passengers in 2024, with connections to more than 80 destinations across Europe, North America, and the Middle East.  The package includes hand-crafted ground textures, a fully modelled terminal with interior, and an up-to-date airfield layout. Landside areas have also been recreated in high fidelity, alongside custom signage, static aircraft, accurate clutter and ground service equipment. Further features include animated jetways, a custom GSX profile, and dynamic lighting for runways, taxiways, and the apron. The general aviation area is fully modelled, with a detailed FBO interior. You can also customise performance through included configuration options that allow for disabling specific scenery elements, such as the terminal interior. The full feature list follows below: Newcastle International Airport is available now through RW Profiles, for £12.99, excluding sales tax. Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for all the latest in flight simulation! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a096</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a096"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688acadadc666ae7a637df33_gps600.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing multiple fixes, new GPS options, and more. Update v0.9.6 brings more fixes to their early access airplane, cross-fill support for multiple GPS layouts, a new dirt layer (dust), and more. The complete changelog follows below: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrebhx2024</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases Birmingham Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrebhx2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688cb3c6813a386cef7a159b_bhx1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently released their rendition of Birmingham Airport (EGBB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the West Midlands in the United Kingdom and has a yearly average of 12.8 million passengers, making it the seventh busiest in the Country. The idea for an airport in Birmingham was first conceived in 1928, and a committee was created shortly after to research possible locations to start building. After much deliberation, Elmdon was deemed the best of the bunch, but the project soon went back to the drawing board due to the Great Depression. It wasn’t until 1933 that works resumed, with a new committee formed to oversee its construction. Before taking any steps, though, the newly formed committee went on a research trip to multiple successful airports in Europe, such as Schiphol (Amsterdam), Berlin (Tempelhof), Paris (Orly), Brussels, and London.  By January 1935, they had finally approached a company—Norman and Dawbarn—to advise on the construction and help design the airport as lead architects. Groundwork started in 1936, after the government allowed the airport’s development. ‍ A year later, in 1937, Norman and Dawbarn were authorized to begin drawing the airport’s project, the undertaking of which took 6 months to reach completion. It was not until October 1937 that the construction of the airport’s buildings would start, costing around 360,000 pounds. Prime Minister Neville Chamberlain opened the airport in July 1939 as Elmdon Airport. The terminal featured a modern (for late 30s standards) art deco design with an integrated control tower and was the airport’s main terminal until 1984.  ‍ The airport was requisitioned by the Air Ministry to be used by both the Royal Air Force and the Royal Navy as RAF Elmdon during World War 2. The military “occupation” replaced the original grass runways with two hard runways, 753 meters in length and 1,271 meters in length, respectively.  It was used as a testbed for Avro Lancasters and Stirling bombers manufactured in northeast Worcestershire. These bombers were transported via land to Elmdon because their local airport didn’t have a long enough runway. ‍ On July 8, 1946, the airport, which was celebrating its 7th anniversary, was reopened for civilian use, albeit still government-controlled. ‍ Scheduled services started in 1949 with British European Airways, flying passengers to Paris. Over the years, the airline eventually expanded its network to Zürich, Düsseldorf, Palma, Amsterdam, and Barcelona. In the early 1960s, they built a new terminal to handle international traffic and extended the main runway to 2.2 km, allowing the airport to handle larger turboprop aircraft and jetliners. ‍ By the beginning of the 1970s, Birmingham Airport was already reaching a million passengers per year, significantly congesting their subpar terminal infrastructure. In the 1980s, BHX became home to the world’s first commercial maglev system, a train levitated by magnets. This system ran for nearly 10 years but eventually faced discontinuation due to unreliability. It was replaced by a cable-hauled system in 2003. ‍ In late 2007, the airport’s administration devised a development plan for Birmingham called “Towards 2030: Planning a Sustainable Future for Air Transport in the Midlands.” The plan included changes to the terminals, alterations to the airfield layout, and infrastructure improvements. Unexpectedly, environmentalists and locals complained, as they didn’t want the construction of a second parallel runway.  The original plan—now canceled—could have created up to 250,000 jobs in the area, made the airport handle up to 70 million passengers annually, and led to around 500,000 aircraft movements in total. ‍ In 2008, the shorter runway (06/24) was decommissioned due to its length and noise impact. Instead, it became a taxiway, allowing the expansion of the apron.  ‍ Construction work on the new 3-storey International Pier kicked off in June of that same year, taking a bit more than a year to complete. Now, Birmingham Airport was fully compatible with the Airbus A380, which visited the airport during its 70th birthday. It was the first commercial service of the A380 in the United Kingdom that was not bound to London Heathrow. ‍ In 2010, it was announced that they would merge Terminal 1 and 2 into a single building and change the name from Birmingham International Airport to Birmingham Airport. They figured this could help create a new corporate identity that would better reflect their current position in the market and attract more people to fly from it. Research showed that while 8 million people lived within an hour of the airport, only 40% of them used it.  ‍ A new control tower was built in 2011, ultimately replacing the original one built in 1939. The plans for extending the main runway, originally submitted in 2008, were approved a year later, but the work was only completed in 2014, two years after their original target, which was the 2012 London Olympics.  ‍ In late 2016, 100 million pounds were invested in building a new baggage handling system and two new car parks. ‍ It’s an operating base for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways, and served by Aer Lingus, Air France, Air India, Aurigny, Brussels Airlines, Corendon Airlines, Emirates, Eurowings, KLM, Loganair, Lufthansa, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, SunExpress, Swiss International Air Lines, Turkish Airlines, Vueling, and WizzAir. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout representing its finished status in 2026, 25,000 square meters of explorable interiors (2024-only), custom terraforming, animated people, a custom GSX profile, an animated monorail, and much more. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $22.78, requiring at least 3.42 GB of free hard disk space to install. You can read our product review here. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniegcc</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Manchester International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniegcc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688d737c2fd634e6fa1ecb48_manchesterr.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently announced their intent to develop a rendition of Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the third busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 23.3 million passengers. ‍ Construction work began in 1935, and the airport was partially operating by 1937 (the official conclusion happened a year later). KLM was the first airline to launch scheduled commercial flights to the newly opened airport in 1938. ‍ It was converted into an RAF base during WW2 and played an essential role in military aircraft production and parachutist training. ‍ The post-war period saw its return as a commercial airport, with rapid growth during the 50s and 60s, where it eventually managed to be Britain's second busiest airport after London Heathrow. ‍ The airport was heavily expanded in the 1980s and 90s to keep up with the exponential growth figures, eventually leading to the millionth passenger in a month mark in 1987. Plans for a new terminal were put in place, and Princess Diana opened it as Terminal A in 1989.  ‍ From 1997 to 2001, a second runway was built, leading to many protests from locals because natural habitats were disturbed and listed buildings had to be demolished, but they didn't have another option. ‍ New expansion work started in 2019 to keep up with the ever-growing passenger traffic figures. ‍ EasyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways have operating bases in Manchester. Many airlines from around the Globe serve it, including Air Canada, Air France, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad, Finnair, KLM, Kuwait Airways, Lufthansa, Qatar, Scandinavian Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish, Virgin Atlantic, and more. ‍ iniBuilds says they are heading back to the UK as British sceneries have been reaching new heights as of late, and they also want to be a part of it, delivering an accurate rendition of Manchester. ‍ Currently, they are looking for locals who happen to work at the airport to help them with data so they can craft an exquisite rendition of the airport. If you fit the bill, reach out to management@inibuilds.com. ‍ There's no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. Stay tuned! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini340</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Officially Announces Airbus A340 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini340"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688e2e8aa044ded0a0c14d6c_A340D-AIGUL.png.12c16eca56296cb3be00a21eaadc547e.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently provided an exciting update on aircraft development in their forum, announcing the official launch of the Airbus A340, which was teased earlier this summer. The A340 model in question is the A340-313 variant, powered by four CFM56-5C4 engines. IniBuilds says that the aircraft will feature a diverse selection of real-world liveries, custom cabins, a comprehensive failure system, and complete EFB (Electronic Flight Bag) integration. Additionally, IniBuilds is collaborating with Echo19 Audio to enhance the audio experience. Three variants will be included in one purchase: the passenger variant, the ACJ variant (luxury configuration), and the passenger-to-freighter converted variant. IniBuilds states that they intend to release it simultaneously on both PC and Xbox, while also confirming that the aircraft will be exclusive to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The development update primarily focused on A340, but we also received information that the A380 is very much still in active development and is making steady progress in the background.  ‍ Additionally, work is ongoing on the A350, which had its initial release earlier this year. iniBuilds is continuing to resolve bugs and making progress towards an Xbox release on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. ‍ For more details on the A340 and other iniBuilds news, check out their development update here. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
