<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-04-19T18:21:26.812349+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mscusg</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update 6: Southwest Germany for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mscusg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661ea6533eae9f93110a1948_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released its latest city update, City Update 6: Southwest Germany. The new update includes seven cities, which are Mannheim, Heidelberg, Karlsruhe, Stuttgart, Esslingen, Kehl, and the French city of Strasbourg. Additionally, the update includes the German Friedrichshafen Airport. The cities have been highly improved with the use of high-resolution aerial imagery and high-fidelity TIN surface modeling. These cities are some of the most vibrant and architecturally rich cities in Europe, offering plenty of opportunities for exploration and sightseeing. Furthermore, the update includes the handcrafted Friedrichshafen Airport (EDNY) by iniBuilds. The airport is a minor international airport, serving around 340,000 passengers annually. The new city update is available for free on the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwidnd</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Updates Dunedin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwidnd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661fb0b9b739f7411a22c761_dunedin1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios recently issued a major update to their rendition of Dunedin Airport (NZDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including improvements, bug fixes, further optimization, and more. Built in 1962 to replace a nearby airfield (Taieri Airfield) deemed not economically feasible to expand for the expected air travel demand, Dunedin was idealized for short-haul aircraft services. NZNAC was one of the first airlines to serve the airport with its fleet of Fokker Friendships and Vickers Viscounts.  The airport first underwent upgrades in the late 1960s and 1970s, with the inclusion of automatic sliding doors in 1969 and a toilet expansion in 1971. Three years later, it also got a new mezzanine floor and an aircraft viewing deck.  It was upgraded again in 1988 when the administration built airline lounges and airbridges to accommodate Ansett New Zealand's Boeing 737 operations (later replaced by BAe 146s). A runway extension followed soon after in 1993, bringing it to its current length of 1,900 meters. A new terminal building was inaugurated in October 2005, considerably increasing its passenger handling capabilities. It's served by Air New Zealand (Auckland, Christchurch, Wellington) and Jetstar (Auckland), averaging around 1 million passengers per year. Update 1.1 brings a vast list of changes to their rendition, including new hangars (entirely redone), a new ATC tower, LODs on terminal and hangars for extra performance, night lighting improvements, improved jetway docking, texture optimizations, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ ‍It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $7.67, requiring at least 4.05 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/osl184</id>
    <title>Aerosoft's Oslo Gardermoen Official Trailer Now Live</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/osl184"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661fba734e2df99324a4f5a4_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AviationLads has recently published the official trailer of Aerosoft's latest release, a rendition of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, developed by Jo Erlend Sund. It's the busiest airport in Norway, with a yearly average of 30 million passengers. ‍ It's the main airport serving Oslo. Located approximately 47 kilometers northeast of the city center, it opened in 1998 as a replacement for the outdated Fornebu Airport, which had been operating since 1939. It was built to modernize and expand Norway's airport infrastructure and improve accessibility to the capital city, quickly becoming the country's Main hub for domestic and international travel. The scenery is set to feature a highly accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom jetways, animated passengers, detailed terminal interiors, and much more. It's releasing tomorrow (18/04), and the pricing is yet to be revealed.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xommdt</id>
    <title>Xometry Releases Harrisburg Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xommdt"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661fdd08229542f1fee3bcce_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry has recently released its rendition of Harrisburg International Airport (KMDT) for X-Plane 12. Located in the state of Pennsylvania, it is the primary commercial airport for all the counties in South Central Pennsylvania. Being the third busiest airport in Pennsylvania, behind the airports of Philadelphia and Pittsburgh, it serves over 1.300.000 passengers yearly. Opened as Olmsted Field in 1918, it served the United States Air Force until 1969. The airport was renamed Harrisburg International Airport in 1973, along with the opening of a new terminal, designed by William Pereira. The first operators out of KMDT were Allegheny Airlines, Trans World Airlines, and Altair Airlines. Today, the airport serves more than 12 airlines giving the city of Harrisburg 16 destinations across the US. This scenery includes various features, such as detailed 4K buildings, high-resolution ground textures, accurately modeled land-side, custom mesh, custom SAM jetways, high-resolution ortho, custom night lighting, and more. The scenery is now available at the iniBuilds Store for approximately $19.19 and it takes up a total of 2.33GB of storage space. ‍ Stay tuned for more flight simulation news on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lldo31</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases Local Legend 15</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lldo31"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661fe4f122fbacca1f82cf63_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A new local legend has been released by the Microsoft Flight Simulator team. It's the Dornier Do 31, an interesting-looking VTOL experimental military aircraft made by West Germany in the late 1960s. The development of this distinctive aircraft was driven by German interest in Short Take-Off and Vertical Landing Aircraft (STOVL) aircraft. In addition to test flights, the aircraft was present at the Paris Air Show in 1969. A total of five world records were broken during its short service from 1967 to 1970). Most of those records were broken during the ferry flight to Paris. The plane was one of a kind since no one had ever tried to produce or design a similar aircraft. Unfortunately, due to the high operating costs, the Do 31 project was canceled in April 1970. Although the plane did not live for long, it was still an engineering masterpiece featuring a hybrid digital-analog supercomputer, the Do-960. The supercomputer collected all inputs from the pilot and converted them into thrust controls. Even after the project was abandoned, the computer was implemented all around the world, due to its amazing performance. With a service ceiling of 35.100 feet, a maximum speed of 393kt (730km/h, 452mph), and a range of 1800 km (1200 mi) the newly released plane comes with seven liveries: 1 Experimental, E3 Experimental, Olive Green, Green Camouflage, Marine Search &amp; Rescue, Xbox Aviators Club, and Aviators Club. The newly released plane is now available on the in-Sim Marketplace for $14.99 and takes up 7.66GB of disk space when installed. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/toliss</id>
    <title>ToLiss Reveals New Aircraft</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/toliss"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661fe9eb41ae95ceca417c9d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The X-Plane developer ToLiss, had recently announced that they were working on a new project. Although the project had been secret, the team has now shared which plane they are working on next. It was on Facebook that they disclosed that the new aircraft will be the A330. The Airbus A330 is one of the best-selling long-haul aircraft with over 1.600 built. This makes it the second most-produced wide-body aircraft after the B777. There are a multitude of variants of the plane, with the most popular ones being A330-300, A330-200, and A330-900neo. This will be ToLiss’ second wide-body addon and fifth Airbus addon. Being known for having great systems and modeling, ToLiss is often known as one of the best addon developers of X-Plane. Although we know that the new project is about the A330, the specific variant, release date, and features are still unknown. ‍ As always, Threshold will keep you updated on this project!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hfstas</id>
    <title>HiFi Previews Active Sky FS for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hfstas"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661fee9badd4be14e49699c6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. HiFi Simulation Technologies has just announced a long-awaited product for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Active Sky FS. Active Sky FS will come with tons of features ranging from direct MSFS integration to enhanced cloudscapes and the famous Active Sky Weather Engine. ASFS will feature two weather depiction modes, passive and preset weather. Passive weather depiction uses MSFS live weather data, allowing MSFS to take full control of weather depiction. At the same time, ASFS provides active air effects and other features, such as mapping, planning, voice features, condition reports, companion app, and more. Passive depiction is recommended for VFR flying, as it provides better cloud variation. When it comes to preset weather depiction mode, it contains weather condition controls for the best accuracy. It allows for full use of Active Sky weather data features, including real-time, historical, and custom weather options. This mode is recommended for those desiring realism in flight simulators. Active air effects will enhance the simulator with lots of different features, including clear air turbulence, broken and overcast cloud layer turbulence, internal MSFS turbulence compatibility, updrafts, downdrafts, microbursts, thunderstorm effect, gusts, wind variation, gust-related turbulence, and many more. Although ASFS's pricing is not yet determined, it is currently in beta testing and has gotten the status of releasing soon. Support for FS2024 is also planned without an additional fee unless there will be any major re-designs. The release date is currently unknown, but Threshold will keep you updated as always! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkslga</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases LaGuardia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkslga"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661ff9f36cc45f9f11d50d29_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released LaGuardia Airport (KLGA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which has been highly anticipated by the community. Located just 8 miles away from Midtown Manhattan, LaGuardia is the third busiest airport in New York. In 2023, the airport managed an impressive 369,393 aircraft operations and served just over 32,370,000 passengers, making it the twentieth busiest airport in the United States. LaGuardia Airport was opened in 1939 and has undergone multiple name changes over the years. It started as Glenn H. Curtiss Airport, then became North Beach Airport, and was later renamed New York Municipal Airport-LaGuardia Field after being redesigned by the city of New York. In 1953, the airport was finally named LaGuardia Airport after Fiorello La Guardia, the former New York mayor. Over the years, the airport has seen many upgrades and improvements. In 2024, it won the Airport Service Quality Award and now serves a wide range of destinations with multiple airlines, including Delta, American, JetBlue, and more. The recently released version of LaGuardia Airport features a highly accurate rendition of LaGuardia KLGA, detailed terminal interiors, VDGS, handcrafted 3D models, custom satellite imagery, elevation data, realistic lighting, and more. The add-on requires a total of 1.93GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for roughly $16.17. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asengm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Oslo Gardermoen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asengm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662118fe5d6720eb95459cca_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently launched its version of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Norwegian capital of Oslo and is situated in the county of Akershus, approximately 47 kilometers from the city. As the biggest and busiest airport in Norway, it welcomes around 30 million passengers annually. Oslo Gardermoen Airport was inaugurated in 1998 as a replacement for the old Oslo Fornebu Airport. The airport's location had been debated since the 1960s and five sites were proposed, with Hobøl initially being selected as the new main airport. However, the government was concerned that Hobøl was too centrally located concerning growth around Oslo, so Gardermoen was chosen instead. Construction of the new airport began, and since its opening, it has grown continuously while replacing Fornebu. Today, Oslo Airport has over 160 destinations, and many airlines fly to and from the airport. Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Widerøe, and Norse Atlantic Airways are the four airlines with their hubs in Oslo, while KLM, Air France, Qatar, Emirates, and many others provide a range of destinations. The airport is a hub for both commercial and cargo operations, handling over 240.000 aircraft movements every year. Jo Erlend Sund developed the newly launched version of Oslo Gardermoen Airport, which includes many features such as a highly precise rendition of the airport, detailed models, high-resolution textures, an up-to-date layout, accurate terrain and runway profiles, a dynamic airport environment, custom aerial image, custom lighting, and more. The add-on requires 5GB of storage space and is available on Aerosoft for approximately $22.36. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hfasfs</id>
    <title>HiFi Releases Active Sky FS for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hfasfs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66214b88e66c718a4155a31b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. HiFi has recently released Active Sky FS for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a highly anticipated product among flight simulation enthusiasts. This new add-on brings a variety of advanced weather features to MSFS, including the popular Active Sky Weather Engine, Enhanced Cloudscape, and Active Air Effects. Active Sky FS has direct integration with MSFS, which provides seamless integration for users. The add-on includes both passive and preset weather options. Passive mode uses MSFS live weather data, while preset weather uses Active Sky’s weather data, giving users the option to choose the mode that best suits their preferences. This feature-packed add-on offers many exciting features, such as direct MSFS integration, ASFS preset weather, ASFS passive weather, active air effects, historical weather, enhanced cloudscape, Active Sky weather engine, ground snow simulation, and much more. The add-on requires 1GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $24.52. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/muc220</id>
    <title>sim-wings Updates Munich International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/muc220"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66215fcb5b8a467dda458eac_mupdate1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. sim-wings recently updated its rendition of Munich International Airport (EDDM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing a wide list of bugs and making many enhancements, keeping the scenery up to date with its real-world counterpart. It serves Munich and Upper Bavaria with a yearly average of 47.9 million passengers.  It opened in 1992, replacing Munich-Riem Airport, which served Munich from 1939 to 1992. It was deemed hard to expand because of the growing number of inhabitants around its proximity, leading to the desire to move the airport to a completely different location. Construction work started in 1980 in the small village of Franzheim, whose 400 inhabitants were moved elsewhere. Operations began on 17 May 1992, with Riem closing the night before. ‍ It's one of Lufthansa's main hubs, with a comprehensive route network. Condor, Eurowings, Eurowings Discover, and TUIfly Deutschland also base themselves at the airport. ‍ Update 2.2.0 includes many corrected taxiway signs, removal of floating objects, Terminal 2 improvements (improved Lufthansa sign, for example), the addition of a meteorology station near RWY 26L, jetway connection tweaks, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ It's available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $24.99, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/josfra</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/josfra"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662242952fac797feee444c5_jofra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AviationLads has put together a trailer showcasing Aerosoft's upcoming rendition of Frankfurt Airport (EDDF), the busiest airport in Germany, with a yearly average of 59.9 million passengers as of 2023. Developed by Jo Erlend Sund and his team, their Frankfurt rendition was announced during FSExpo 2023. Aerosoft has been updating us ever since with development progress reports on their official landing page for the scenery.  While there's no official feature list, the trailer showcases great attention to detail, with custom ground clutter, custom jetways, accurate taxiway markings, landside buildings, custom dynamic lighting, and more. The pricing and release date are still to be revealed, but Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tornad</id>
    <title>Indiafoxtecho Releases Tornado for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tornad"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66225c75e9679a26c0de91b5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Indiafoxtecho has recently released its latest aircraft, the Tornado, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This plane is a long-range, supersonic fighter-bomber, which made its first flight in 1974. Since then, it has been operated by numerous operators and is still in use by many today. The Tornado is a military aircraft manufactured by Panavia Aircraft GmbH. Its maiden flight took place in West Germany in 1974, where it was first used by the German Air Force. In total, the German Air Force received 247 Tornadoes, while the German Navy received 112. The aircraft has been operated by several countries, including the Italian Air Force, Royal Air Force, and Royal Saudi Air Force. Despite being an older model, the Tornado remains popular among aviation enthusiasts and is still used by some air forces today. The aircraft has been recently released and comes with a detailed visual model, multiple liveries, a realistic flight model, a detailed system simulation, a realistic sound package, and many more features. The add-on requires 2.23GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $31.94. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftlppt</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Lisbon Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftlppt"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66227b3fd8a6a69bfcb53261_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released its version of Lisbon Airport (LPPT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the Portuguese capital of Lisbon, it is the 12th largest airport in Europe, serving over 33.6 million passengers yearly. Lisbon Airport opened on October 15th, 1942 during World War II, but remained neutral throughout the war. This allowed both German and British operators to fly to the airport. By 1946, major airlines like KLM, Iberia, and Pan Am started using the airport. In 1959, the airport underwent major upgrades to handle airliners like the classic Boeing 707. In 1983, there were more upgrades to buildings and facilities, and in 1991, the first air bridges were installed. Since then, the airport has been growing and attracting tons of airlines to operate there. Today, TAP Air Portugal, Azores Airlines, easyJet, and Ryanair have hubs there, and you can fly all over the world from New York to Dubai or Amsterdam. The newly released Lisbon Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator includes many features, such as highly detailed buildings, PBR texturing, real-world elevation data, runway slope, custom jetways, custom lighting, and more. The add-on requires 1.03GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $18.12. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbsgru</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations &amp; db Scenery Release Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbsgru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618c9dead3989329b5a7ebe_gdru1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations and db Scenery have recently released their rendition of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves São Paulo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 41.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in the country. The airport's planning started back in 1967, when the government first considered renovating the airport infrastructure in the country and ran some studies to figure out which step to take next, leading to a straightforward conclusion: Congonhas (São Paulo's main airport at the time) was not big enough to sustain the ever-growing demand, nor could it be easily expanded, which led to a plan B: transforming a former Air Force Base into a full-fledged international airport. After decades of planning, construction started in 1980, with three runways and four passenger terminals in mind at first, which turned into two runways and two terminals due to time and cost constraints. It was inaugurated five years later and quickly became the city's primary airport.  ‍ Four years after the inauguration, the runways were extended, and the passenger terminals were expanded, bringing the overall capacity from 7.5 million passengers a year to 8.5.  A third terminal, planned for 2001, was built a decade later, along with Terminal 4. The first phase (of Terminal 4's construction) had it holding up to 5.5 million passengers a year, and the second phase brought it to its intended capacity of 8 million passengers, making it so the airport could handle 28.5 million passengers in total. The terminals were renumbered in 2015, with Terminal 4 becoming Terminal 1, Terminals 1 and 2 becoming Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 retaining its numbering. ‍ It's a hub for Gol Transportes Aéreos and LATAM Brasil and served by Azul, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, an up-to-date taxiway layout, custom landside, custom terrain mesh, custom ambient sounds, dynamic lighting effects, detailed ground markings, and more. It's available in the MSFS Marketplace for $9. Refer to the product page for further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsigru</id>
    <title>Vref Simulations Updates Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsigru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6622b1cafd245fc3bbf93dc9_gru1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Vref Simulations has recently updated their rendition of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding a new custom jetway model, new landside buildings, texture improvements, and more. Update 1.5, the first since its official release earlier this month, adds a new custom jetway model on Terminal 2, minor bug fixing, texture improvements, satellite imagery tweaks, landside tweaks, and new buildings. The changelog follows below: Changelog V1.5 The scenery is available on SimMarket for roughly $9.07, requiring at least 573.59 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
