<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-09-17T18:19:32.228339+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflten</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Tenerife North Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflten" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8eb2de06c5ee3b1d19973_tenerife.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="267570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently released their rendition of Tenerife North-Ciudad de La Laguna Airport (GCXO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Santa Cruz de Tenerife in Tenerife - the largest and most populous island in the canaries = with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  After five years of fund gathering, the airport was built in the late 30s to improve a spot where flights were already happening regularly ten years prior with C.L.A.S.S.A. ‍ Commercial operations on the newly built airport started in 1941 with Iberia’s fleet of DH89A’s. Five years after its first proper commercial flight, the airport already had a couple of hangars, a passenger terminal, and a paved runway while also opening for domestic and international traffic—multiple runway expansions followed during the subsequent decades. ‍ The most significant runway expansion happened in 1964, when the runway was stretched to 3000 m to accommodate the DC-8, along with new navigation aids and an apron expansion. An ILS system was installed seven years later, in 1971.  ‍ That decade marked the inauguration of Tenerife South, which only came to be because Tenerife North often suffered with thick fog, the main contributor to the Tenerife tragedy of 1977 involving two Boeing 747s, still the deadliest accident in aviation history. ‍ A new terminal was inaugurated in 2002 with a four-story terminal building, 12 gates, and its international reopening after 24 years of domestic-only operations.  ‍ Air Europa, Binter Canarias, CanaryFly, Iberia, IberiaExpress, Plus Ultra Líneas Aéreas, Ryanair, and Vueling currently serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures and objects, animated jetways, animated custom vehicles, a modeled interior, realistic ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.38, requiring at least 1.99 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/codden</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Denver International Airport for X-Plane 11 and 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/codden" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8eef27f242211ccbf4c02_den1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1740086"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr Designs has recently released a major update to their rendition of Denver International Airport (KDEN) for X-Plane 11 and 12, delivering the culmination of two years of development time with a load of new features and improvements. ‍ Version 2.0 - free to owners of the previous version - brings a high-quality rendition of the airport as of 2023, with an up-to-date ground layout, realistic terminal interiors with multiple points of interest, animated escalators, animated people (with varying density according to the time of day), windows on buildings that mimic the optics of real glass, PBR texturing, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It uses their Living Scenery Technology plugin that warrants animated people, animated vehicles traveling at realistic speeds, animated electronic display boards on concourse B displaying time and temperature, variable AC fan blade speeds depending on temperature, and more. ‍  The complete list of features follows down below:  ‍ The scenery is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $29.95, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. As previously mentioned, owners of the previous version are entitled to a free upgrade. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2ac13</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2ac13" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64fb668b716c5dba1711f94f_cuman1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1159834"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 to version 1.3, including multiple bug fixes and two new features. ‍ The third update since its release brings the ability to switch off trim acceleration, an option to set metric air temperature and pressure units independently of each other and regional settings within the simulator, and a substantial changelog with seventeen fixes, which follows down below:  ‍ The add-on is available on their store for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lesdx2</id>
    <title>Leading Edge Simulations Releases DC-3 v2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lesdx2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64fb6ad1257527f71ebf8ae4_dc32.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="406637"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Leading Edge Simulations has recently released the v2 of their Douglas DC-3 for X-Plane 12, bringing two cockpit variants, custom-coded systems, and more. ‍ Their newly released DC-3 features an accurately modeled Douglas DC-3 with heavy use of PBR materials, ensuring great visual acuity. There are two cockpit options, ranging from the classic layout from the 1930s-1940s and a modern style with modern instrumentation and avionics.   ‍ The custom systems bring a deeply simulated electric system, two autopilot options, multiple navigation tools (VOR and ADF radios, GPS unit compatibility), a simulated hydraulic system, engines with fully simulated mixture control, a custom auto-feather mechanism, and realistic oil consumption figures depending on the engine’s health.  ‍ It also features an airframe system where every livery is individually persistent, with individual options, maintenance logs, and states, which can be controlled through a user interface. ‍ The developers also disclaim a list of things that will not be available right on release: the hydraulic system has correct indications, but X-Plane does not allow for deep interaction with it; the anti-ice systems are present yet not fully simulated; hardware support is said to be “basic” for the time being; the Sperry autopilot on the “Classic” variant doesn’t have heading mode, only the basic operations. ‍  It’s available on X-Aviation for $49.95 and is only compatible with X-Plane 12. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsasa</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Asahikawa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsasa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64fcf29998a948242f08db7d_asahi.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="552429"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Asahikawa Airport (RJEC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Asahikawa in Hokkaido, with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  ‍ After half a decade of planning, the airport was inaugurated in 1966, with scheduled service beginning that same year with Japan Domestic Airlines, flying a NAMC YS-11 to Tokyo Haneda via Okadama. It was primarily seasonal until 1970 when there was finally a year-round flight to Tokyo.  Nearly twenty years later, the airport was briefly closed for expansion work, with its sole runway being extended from 1,200 meters to 1,640 in February 1982 and then to 2,000 meters in November 1982, allowing the operation of larger jet aircraft like the DC-9, the MD-80, and the Airbus A300. ‍ In 2016, the administration made plans to build a new international terminal to the south of the old one, with 5,700 square meters of constructed area, targeting 500,000 international passengers yearly by 2030. It opened in November 2018. ‍ The airport is served by Air Do, All Nippon Airways (seasonally), Asiana Airlines, Japan Airlines, Tigerair Taiwan, and T’way Air. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom ground textures, AI traffic compatibility, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.38, requiring at least 31.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsvva</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Verona Villafranca Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsvva" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ff03f777f82a249650edbd_verona.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2889827"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Verona Villafranca Airport (LIPX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Italian city of Verona with a yearly average of 3.5 million passengers. ‍ Built as an air base in the early 1900s and heavily used during World War I, it opened to civil air traffic not long after the conflict with daily connections to Rome and multiple charter flight destinations in northern Europe. ‍ A passenger terminal was built in the late 1970s by the Province of Verona, the Commune of Verona, and the Local Chamber of Commerce. A managing society was formed shortly after, sharing the ownership between provincial governments from Veneto, Lombardy, Trentino, and Alto Adige. ‍ With healthy growth figures in the late 90s and early 2000s, the administration decided to expand the airport by constructing a new arrivals terminal, inaugurated in 2006. ‍ Aer Lingus, Air Albania, AirBaltic (seasonally), Air Dolomiti, Albawings, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings (seasonally), Finnair (seasonally), FlyOne, Jet2 (seasonally), Neos, Norwegian Air Shuttle (seasonally), Play (seasonally), Ryanair, Transavia (seasonally), TUI Airways, Volotea, and WizzAir serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, custom ground vehicles, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.06, requiring at least 374.60 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lepiap</id>
    <title>Low-End Pc Studios Releases Iquitos Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lepiap" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ff09637816a5dcf38a329e_iqutios.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1647987"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Low-End Pc Studios has recently released their rendition of Coronel FAP Francisco Secada Vignetta International Airport (SPQT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Peruvian city of Iquitos with a yearly average of 1 million passengers. ‍ It was built in the late 1920s as a gravel airstrip for military purposes, eventually evolving into a commercial airport over the following decades, along with several infrastructural upgrades and expansions.  ‍ Its current name was adopted in 1973 after a local Peruvian Air Force pilot who had fought in the war with Colombia between 1932 and 1933. ‍ The airport is of great importance to the city’s economy because it’s only accessible by air or river, meaning every urgent logistical operation has to go through the airport, which also justifies the relatively high passenger figures in comparison with the city’s population (1 million passengers yearly, and the city has less than half a million inhabitants). Said figures make it the fourth busiest airport in Peru. ‍ LATAM Peru, SAETA Peru, Sky Airline Peru, and Star Peru serve the airport year-round.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom ground mesh, PBR textures, terminal interior modeling, custom runway elevation profile, animated objects, and a performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.16, requiring at least 150.09 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pesbre</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Releases Brest-Bretagne Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pesbre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6500b1e1601eeb5bda949cba_brest.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="798902"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pilot Experience Sim has recently released their rendition of Brest-Bretagne Airport (LFRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the French city of Brest with a yearly average of 1.1 million passengers.  It was built by the US Navy during World War I, originally featuring two airship hangars. An airstrip was only constructed after the war, becoming “Brest Guipavas Airfield,” but it did not survive World War 2: it had to be rebuilt.  Rebuilding efforts only took place in the early 1950s, with the airport being reopened for commercial use in 1952, connecting Brest to Ouessant and Paris by the wings of Air Inter.   With the popularization of air travel and the consequent increase in passenger volume, the airport underwent a massive expansion project in 1986, followed by a runway extension six years later, transforming the airport into a diversion ground for transatlantic flights. By 1989, the airport was averaging 500,000 passengers a year for the first time.  In December 2007, they inaugurated a brand new terminal, with 22,000 square meters of total area, able to accommodate up to 1.8 million passengers a year, with two wide-body jetways and fourteen stands for medium and small aircraft. It’s shaped like a manta ray.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, PBR textures, a realistic terrain profile, custom jetways, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.00, requiring at least 1.93 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssapg</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Petersburg Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssapg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6501c667a6ce16776ca35f6f_papg.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1363994"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Northern Sky Studio has recently released their rendition of Petersburg James A. Johnson Airport (PAPG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Alaskan city of Petersburg with a yearly average of 13,042 passengers. ‍ It was built in 1947 as a seaplane base for the US Army, converted to a land airport five years later, and named after a local businessman and politician. ‍ It’s served by Alaska Airlines (Juneau, Wrangell) and Alaska Seaplanes (Juneau, Kake, Sitka, Wrangell), with Juneau being the busiest destination as of 2015-2016. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, PBR materials, high-resolution building textures, custom orthophoto for the airport and surroundings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.78, requiring at least 2.57 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csrmam</id>
    <title>Cloud Studio Releases Moraine Airpark for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csrmam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6501cea0c3f0a13909a141a9_moraine.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="544620"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cloud Studio has recently released their rendition of Moraine Airpark (I73) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use airport in Moraine, Ohio, with a yearly average of 26,000 aircraft operations.  ‍ It opened 116 years ago and is adjacent to the river where the Wright Brothers tested seaplanes in 1907. The seaplane base no longer exists, now part of the 155-acre area occupied by the airpark and its 1067-meter runway. ‍ From the 26,280 operations in 2022, 79% were general aviation, 20% air taxi, and 1% military. There are 111 aircraft based at the airport: 106 airplanes, three ultralights, one helicopter, and one glider. ‍ The scenery features a hand-made custom mesh, custom 3D models, hand-placed vegetation, custom ground poly, and a helipad. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.50, requiring at least 204.72 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ixp737</id>
    <title>IXEG 737 Classic Plus for X-Plane 12 Releasing on Friday</title>
    <updated>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ixp737" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6501d33507cdf5978723e7d4_ixeg.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="107969"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. IXEG has recently announced the imminent release of their 737 Classic Plus, adding full compatibility with X-Plane 12, new features, and “setting the stage for new improvements in the future.”  ‍ The Classic Plus version will bring engine bleed configuration improvements, code optimization, wingflex, a 3D cabin, moving cabin doors, cockpit &amp; cabin lighting up to the new standard, GUI enhancements, the ability to hide the yoke with the default key assignment, a FOV slider, cockpit windows with XP12 weather effects (rain and ice), improved external lighting, and tuned aerodynamics and engine performance. ‍ ‍ ‍ The upgrade will be free for customers who purchased the 737 Classic on or after February 7, 2022, and customers who bought it before that date will have to pay $14.95. The upgrade offer will last 60 days, counting from the release on Friday (September 15, 2023).  Refer to the announcement for further information on the matter. Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzmilf</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases Milford Sound Region for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzmilf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6501e23ca11f85e513f04b31_milf.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3013932"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NZA Simulations has recently released their rendition of the Milford Sound Region for Microsoft Flight Simulator, comprised of 8 airstrips: Milford Sound (NZMF), Martins Bay Aerodrome (NZMJ), Big Bay Beach Strip (NZQU), Cascade Lagoon Airstrip (NZ31), Hope River Aistrip (NZ32), Hollyford Track Airstrip (NZ34), Cascade Station Aistrip (NZ35), and Quintin Lodge Airstrip (T004).  ‍ The package features an accurate rendition of eight airfields in the Milford Sound Region in New Zealand, with fully 3D modeled terminals, hidden adventure locations, multiple points of interest, 76 animated custom watercraft, custom animal and bird life, biome enhancements, custom water masking, mountain texture improvements, animated rivers and waterfalls, and more.  ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $21.86, requiring at least 2.19 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse024</id>
    <title>FSExpo 2024’s Location Unveiled</title>
    <updated>2023-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse024" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/5d47269777c5819a23cbedb5_Image11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1240912"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The FSExpo organizers have unveiled the results of the community-wide survey to decide on the next location, published in a press release that follows below, along with the dates: ‍ LAS VEGAS – September 14, 2023 – Flight Simulation Association (FSA) is excited to announce that FlightSimExpo 2024 will be held June 21-23, 2024 at Tropicana Las Vegas - a DoubleTree by Hilton. The location was selected following a community-wide survey in which more than 500 simmers selected Las Vegas as their top location choice.  ‍ “We are excited to bring FlightSimExpo back to Las Vegas,” said Evan Reiter, FSA co-founder. “The space at Tropicana is perfect for our event, while the destination offers a great backdrop for families, resort-seekers, and those who love gaming and entertainment.”  ‍ FlightSimExpo is one of the world’s largest dedicated flight simulation events and has welcomed more than 5,000 attendees to shows in Las Vegas, Orlando, San Diego, and Houston since 2018. The expo features developers from across the community, including representation from the four of the five most popular simulation platforms: Microsoft Flight Simulator, X-Plane, Prepar3D, and Infinite Flight ‍ FSExpo 2024 will kick off on Friday, June 21 with a series of product announcements and reveals from community developers. Then, over the weekend, in-person attendees will have access to a 40,000 square foot exhibit hall featuring the latest in home flight simulation technology. Developer roundtables and educational seminars will take place throughout the weekend. As in previous years, simmers will be able to watch portions of FlightSimExpo from anywhere with the event’s Online-Only registration. The 2024 venue is centrally located on the Las Vegas Strip and features an award-winning pool, spa, fitness center, and more. FlightSimExpo attendees will have access to a special average room rate of just $188/night over a threenight stay—including all taxes and resort fees. When booked as part of FlightSimExpo’s special room block, the stay includes free self-parking, WiFi for up to 5 devices, 2 bottles of water, unlimited fitness center access, and more. ‍ “Save the dates, start thinking of plans, but please don’t lock travel in yet,” says FSA’s Phil Coyle. “As always, we are working to secure airfare and car rental discounts along with awesome add-on activities on Thursday, Friday, and Monday for our attendees. You’ll want to have the full picture before you start booking.”  ‍ ‍  The organization will publish more information about hotel options, attractions, and travel later this year. Attendee registrations will open in December, and people are welcome to join their Discord server to share ideas, feedback, and suggestions.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drepaa</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Studios Releases Palo Alto Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drepaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6505f012de11be490fb059ab_palo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1943875"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Dreamflight Studios has recently released their rendition of Palo Alto Airport (KPAO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the city of Palo Alto in California.  ‍ The airport was built between 1934-1936, replacing the former Palo Alto airport (adjacent to Stanford Stadium). It covers an area of 41 hectares, with a single 743-meter-long runway. ‍ It houses various repair shops and four flying clubs: Stanford Flying Club, West Valley Flying Club, Sundance Flying Club, and Advantage Aviation Flying Club. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with high-resolution PBR textures, custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.60, requiring at least 150.13 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/darx26</id>
    <title>Dark Space Updates xEnviro for X-Plane 12.06</title>
    <updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/darx26" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6505f92efbbb8e2f46cc7e9d_xenviro.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1724659"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Dark Space has recently updated xEnviro to work with X-Plane 12.06r3, following up on a bigger update from late August that added a series of enhancements to both X-Plane 11 and 12.  Update 1.26 brought dithering technology to reduce sky banding, X-Plane 11 compatibility, in-cloud light scattering, and 1.27 warranted the compatibility with the latest version of X-Plane 12.  The developer team says they are actively working on reintroducing the features that were held back during the transition from X-Plane 11 to X-Plane 12. The following updates aim to reflect that. ‍ xEnviro is available on its official website, Threshold Store, and X-Plane.Org for $69.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aricea</id>
    <title>Arif Studio Releases Chicago Executive Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aricea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650601bef9412547ee6dd6de_chica.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1679752"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Arif Studio has recently released their rendition of Chicago Executive Airport (KPWK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public airport serving northwestern Chicago with a yearly average of 108,000 aircraft movements.  It opened in 1925 as Gauthier’s Flying Field in the village of Wheeling (Cook County, Illinois), purchased and developed by George J. Priester in 1953, who installed paved runways, lighting, hangars, and an ATC tower. It was then sold in 1986 by George’s son, Charlie, to the city of Prospect Heights and Wheeling, when it was renamed Palwaukee Municipal Airport. ‍ The current name was given in late 2006 after trustees from the village voted to approve a name change, better positioning the airport as a private aviation gateway to Chicago due to its proximity to the city. ‍ ‍ According to 2022 data, 80% of the yearly movements correspond to general aviation traffic, 20% to air taxi, and less than 1% are military. There are 296 aircraft based at the airport. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a recreation of all the hangars, numerous static objects, landside buildings, non-PBR texturing for file size optimization, custom night lighting, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.52, requiring at least 31.18 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
