<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-02-12T18:20:42.072109+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/davmal</id>
    <title>David Rosenfeld Previews Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/davmal"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c0be78cc4a845f0e5e8598_malpensa.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. David Rosenfeld has recently previewed his rendition of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Milan metropolitan area with a yearly average of 26.1 million passengers.  ‍ The site where the airport was built has more than a century of aviation history, with records dating back to 1910 when the Caproni brothers flew their Cal biplane. It became a popular prototype testing site in Italy, eventually leading to its upgrade to an actual airfield.  ‍ During that same period, the Caproni brothers decided to build a factory there, and Giovanni Augusta followed suit. It became the largest aircraft production center in the country.  ‍ In the following decades, the airfield hosted two Royal Italian Air Force squadrons.  ‍ In September 1943, the German Luftwaffe captured the airfield, building its first concrete runway, which didn’t last long: the airfield was heavily bombed during WW2.   ‍ With the retreat of the German forces from Italy and the eventual end of the war, the runway was rebuilt and extended to 1,800 meters. A small terminal was built to shelter passengers and cargo from adverse weather conditions. ‍ Its official inauguration happened in 1948 as Aeroporto Città di Busto Arsizio, with Sabena and TWA being one of the first international carriers to serve it.  ‍ In 1952, now under the control of the municipality of Milan, it was decided that Malpensa would become Milan’s international airport, and Linate (Milan’s other airport) would handle domestic services.   ‍ As Milan’s main airport, it needed a respectable terminal, which was built between 1958 and 1962. The runways were also extended and were the longest in Europe then.   ‍ Even though their original intent was to make Linate domestic-only, major European carriers preferred it over Malpensa because it was closer to the city center, transforming it into a secondary airport for over 20 years.  ‍ Things were only to change in the 1980s when Linate was forcibly downgraded to domestic, and Malpensa underwent heavy upgrade work. Construction started in 1990, and it only reopened eight years later. ‍ ‍ It’s an operating base for AlbaStar, easyJet Europe, Malta Air, Neos, Ryanair, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air France, Air India, AirBaltic, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad Airways, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom jetways, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini105</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini105"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658e3cd4374e2720154dbc55_inia3002.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an emergency update for their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing an LNAV issue introduced in the previous update from a few days ago.  Given its “hotfix-ish” nature, the fifth update’s changelog is relatively small, with only four changes:  ‍ ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hacu24</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Aeronautical Charlie Update</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hacu24"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c12696ff74397cd5d6f7d0_honeycomb-aeronautical-charlie-peddals.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Following a lengthy post to their Facebook page Honeycomb Aeronautical has made an official announcement on their website regarding the shipments for pre-orders and eventual retail release for their long-awaited Charlie Rudder Pedals. The announcement comes just a week after Founder and CEO Nicki Repenning took to Honeycomb's Facebook page to inform the community of what's been happening behind the scenes and why there's been an overall lack of communication from the company, which you can read about here. At the time of writing, the page the update was posted to has been taken down. ‍ The update that was released on Honeycomb’s website outlines the current plan for honoring refunds, pre-orders, and the eventual rollout for retailers. Honeycomb states that pre-orders will be shipped June 24th and those who have canceled their pre-orders can expect a refund sometime in February, these units will be available through the Honeycomb store later and will start shipping with the pre-order units. Retailers are expected to have the Charlie in stock after the second half of August 2024. You can read the full announcement here. ‍ Be sure to watch Threshold for all your up-to-date Flight Simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniabu</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Abu Dhabi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniabu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c51f570a32f7765a4be02a_abu.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently previewed their upcoming rendition of Abu Dhabi International Airport (OMAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Abu Dhabi in the United Arab Emirates with a yearly average of 5.2 million passengers. ‍ It was conceived in 1974 as part of the government’s plan to modernize the nation. It used to be served by Al Bateen Airport, which was deemed too hard to access due to its location on an island connected to the mainland by a single bridge.  ‍ A site for the construction was found sometime in the mid-1970s, and construction work started in 1979. Inaugurated in 1979, the new airport featured a circular satellite terminal with a single connection to a semi-circular terminal, allowing more aircraft to park simultaneously. Upgrades were conducted in the 1990s and 2000s to expand its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ A new terminal (Terminal 2) was opened in 2005 to relieve stress on the main terminal. It did not feature any aerobridges and depended on buses to move passengers from terminal to plane.  ‍ Terminal 3, inaugurated in 2009, was built to allow for extra passenger traffic before the opening of the new midfield terminal, scheduled for 2017. It boosted the passenger capacity from 7 million to 12 million. ‍ The former terminals were all closed in 2023 and replaced by Terminal A, the so-called Midfield Terminal, which has a capacity for up to 60 million passengers yearly. Covering an area of 780,000 square meters, it’s one of the largest terminals in the world. It can handle 79 A380s and 11,000 passengers per hour at peak.  ‍ It’s a hub for Air Arabia Abu Dhabi, Etihad Airways, Etihad Cargo, and Wizz Air Abu Dhabi. Aeroflot, Air France, Air India, British Airways, Hainan Airlines, IndiGo, Pakistan International Airlines, Pobeda, Smartwings, SunExpress, Turkish Airlines, and Vistara serve it, among many others. ‍ The scenery will feature a highly detailed rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, terminal interiors, custom ground service equipment, and more. ‍ There’s no release date or price information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpsal</id>
    <title>RDPresets Announces Salzburg Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpsal"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c5253e65bfc9b92f662fc8_salzburg.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced their rendition of Salzburg Airport Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (LOWS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Salzburg, Austria, with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers. ‍ Salzburg Airport was a race track when the first powered aircraft taxied on its surface in 1910. Sixteen years later, Lufthansa inaugurated a route from Munich to Bad Reichenhall with a stop in Salzburg. Austrian Aviation AG followed suit a year later with a Vienna-Salzburg-Innsbruck route.  ‍ The Luftwaffe seized it in 1939, where it was used by the Luftgaukommando VII and routinely visited by the Messerschmitt Me 262 during its development phase. The United States Air Force heavily bombed the city in 1944 (15 air raids), but the airport somehow remained undamaged. It was the first Austrian airport to return to scheduled traffic after WW2. ‍ A new control tower was built in 1958, and a new passenger terminal was opened in 1966.  ‍ It’s a hub for Eurowings Europe and is served by Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Finnair, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Transavia, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air. Most of them only operate seasonally. ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail buildings, interiors, 3D people, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ The release date is scheduled for Saturday (10/02). The pricing isn’t known yet.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2car</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Carlisle Lake District Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2car"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c52c8347065c7f3f5edc06_carlisle.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Carlisle Lake District Airport (EGNC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the region of Cumbria, in England, with a yearly average of 8,000 passengers (before the passenger terminal was closed until further notice in 2020).  It started as RAF Crosby-on-Eden in February 1941, housing the No. 59 Operational Training Unit and providing day training for Hawker Hurricane pilots until its replacement by the No. 9 Operational Training Unit in 1942, specializing in training long-range fighter crews, air-firing, and night-flying.   ‍ The station was closed after the war as it had no postwar use or need. It was returned to Carlisle City Council to continue as a municipal airport.  ‍ It was purchased by the Cumberland City Council in 1960 and renamed Carlisle Airport. After a slight refurbishment, it was licensed in 1961 for training and civilian operations.   ‍ The 1980s saw the airport again being used for military purposes, training military personnel on flying helicopters and fixed-wing aircraft. It was responsible for training Iraqi pilots during the Iran-Iraq war.  ‍ Its current name came to be when WA Developments purchased the site from Haughey Airports, intending to develop the airport and bring back scheduled service. There were plans to include a new passenger terminal and a 70,000-square-meter distribution center. Nothing came to fruition, and Stobart Aviation purchased it from WA in 2009. ‍ Plans to build a 36,600 square-meter Air Distribution Center were implemented in 2010, but they only got the authorization four years later. It’s now leased to Eddie Stobart Logistics. ‍ A new ADC was built in 2016, with an industrial warehouse and distribution buildings ranging from 1,400 square meters to 31,000. ‍ ‍ The passenger terminal has been closed UFN, so there’s no scheduled passenger service. It currently faces an uncertain future. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, custom static aircraft, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.77, requiring at least 26.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jstnic</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Nice Côte d’Azur Airport NG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jstnic"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c533e7b5f6be0a92de5d8a_nice.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. JustSim has recently released their “next generation” rendition of Nice Côte d’Azur Airport (LFMN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Bouches-du-Rhône, Alpes-Maritimes, and Monaco, with a yearly average of 14.1 million passengers.  It covers an area of roughly 3.7 square kilometers partially reclaimed from the sea, with 72% of it utilized by its two parallel runways and the passenger terminals, which can handle 52 aircraft movements per hour.  ‍ Terminal 1 has 25 gates and a total area of 52,000 square meters, handling domestic and intra-European flights. Terminal 2, the newest one, has 29 gates, a total area of 57,800 square meters, and can take up to 8.5 million passengers annually.  ‍ ‍ It’s a focus city for Air France and easyJet. It is served by Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air Transat, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, Delta Air Lines, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, Icelandair, KLM, Jet2.com, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, Transavia, and more.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality 3D models, custom ground textures, custom jetways, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.75, requiring at least 2.72 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2axbx</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2axbx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c58016fb9f5ea4f152b1bc_comancheupdate.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently issued a new update to their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding Xbox compatibility and a list of fixes and improvements. ‍ Version 1.4.7 - the sixth update since its release in mid-2023 - makes the aircraft compatible with the Xbox and brings engine physics improvements, bug fixes, new localizations for aircraft description, and more. The changelog follows below: ‍ The aircraft is available on the A2A website / MSFS Marketplace for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini106</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini106"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659886e01a7b6d14ad882974_a300update3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing further LNAV tweaks, sound fixes, and more. Update 1.0.6 - the sixth since its release - brings further LNAV tweaking, fixes missing sounds on the MCDU, and adds custom tail registration and SELCAL options. The changelog follows below: v1.0.6 - Fixed further issues with AP not following LNAV. - Fixed MCDU missing some sounds. - Added custom reg and selcal options. The airplane is available on the iniBuilds Store / MSFS Marketplace for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/abudha</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Abu Dhabi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/abudha"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c64178791916208d5d8f36_zayed.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Abu Dhabi International Airport (OMAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Abu Dhabi in the United Arab Emirates with a yearly average of 5.2 million passengers. It was conceived in 1974 as part of the government’s plan to modernize the nation. It used to be served by Al Bateen Airport, which was deemed too hard to access due to its location on an island connected to the mainland by a single bridge. ‍ A site for the construction was found sometime in the mid-1970s, and construction work started in 1979. Inaugurated in 1979, the new airport featured a circular satellite terminal with a single connection to a semi-circular terminal, allowing more aircraft to park simultaneously. Upgrades were conducted in the 1990s and 2000s to expand its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ ‍ A new terminal (Terminal 2) was opened in 2005 to relieve stress on the main terminal. It did not feature any aerobridges and depended on buses to move passengers from terminal to plane. ‍ ‍ Terminal 3, inaugurated in 2009, was built to allow for extra passenger traffic before the opening of the new midfield terminal, scheduled for 2017. It boosted the passenger capacity from 7 million to 12 million. ‍ ‍ The former terminals were all closed in 2023 and replaced by Terminal A, the so-called Midfield Terminal, which has a capacity for up to 60 million passengers yearly. Covering an area of 780,000 square meters, it’s one of the largest terminals in the world. It can handle 79 A380s and 11,000 passengers per hour at peak. ‍ ‍ It’s a hub for Air Arabia Abu Dhabi, Etihad Airways, Etihad Cargo, and Wizz Air Abu Dhabi. Aeroflot, Air France, Air India, British Airways, Hainan Airlines, IndiGo, Pakistan International Airlines, Pobeda, Smartwings, SunExpress, Turkish Airlines, and Vistara serve it, among many others. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life airport landside recreation, custom night lighting, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, an up-to-date airport layout, custom jetways, accurate taxiways, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.92, requiring at least 4.14 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/imatla</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Updates Atlanta International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/imatla"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c6a6f0b362175f3bbbac7b_atlanta.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Imaginesim has recently issued an update to their rendition of Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport (KATL), serving the Atlanta metropolitan area with a yearly average of 104.6 million passengers, making it the world's busiest airport. ‍ The update, free for existing KATL customers, completely overhauls the airport, using the latest technologies and the latest SDK compiler. It features new models, multiple improvements, performance-friendly optimization, new buildings and objects, custom jetways, PBR, custom VDGS, and more. The complete changelog follows below: - Fantastic performance with comprehensive optimization. - New modelling and thousands of other improvements. - Custom interactive SafeGateTM Visual Docking Guidance (VDGS). - New landscaping, PBR and terrain modelling. - Fluid usage, even with complex airliner cockpits and high density AI coverage. - Interactive bespoke jetways and animations. - Instantaneous scenery cache loading and low simulator impact. - 15 square mile coverage of the KATL area. - Graduated ground extremities to seamlessly blend with any vector driven add-on. - Utilizes imaginesim's bespoke Operations Center configuration GUI. ‍ It's available at the Imaginesim Store for roughly $18.93. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssjin</id>
    <title>NSS Scenery Studio Releases Jinan Yaoqiang International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssjin"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c6aa80d93b79dbee3becb2_jinan.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. NSS Scenery Studio has recently released their rendition of Jinan Yaoqiang International Airport (ZSJN) for X-Plane 12, serving Jinan, Shandong Province, China, with a yearly average of 13.6 million passengers, making it the 25th busiest in the country. ‍ It was completed and opened for passenger traffic in 1992, covering an area of 7200 acres and a terminal building taking 114,000 square meters, built between 2003 and 2010 (a new terminal in 2005, and then a new expansion in 2010). It can handle up to 4500 people during peak hours and 100000 aircraft movements yearly. ‍ It’s the hub for Shandong Airlines, and Air China, Beijing Capital Airlines, Cambodia Airways, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Dalian Airlines, Donghai Airlines, GX Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Kunming Airlines, Lucky Air, Scoot, Shenzhen Airlines, Sichuan Airlines, Spring Airlines, Thai VietJet Air, and XiamenAir serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, accurate taxiway markings, custom jetways, custom night lighting, automatic marshaling, landside buildings, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.41, requiring at least 1.36 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpslz</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Salzburg Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpslz"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c7e0dadf678f630fac6474_salz.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets have recently released their rendition of Salzburg Airport (LOWS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Salzburg, Austria, with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers. Salzburg Airport was a race track when the first powered aircraft taxied on its surface in 1910. Sixteen years later, Lufthansa inaugurated a route from Munich to Bad Reichenhall with a stop in Salzburg. Austrian Aviation AG followed suit a year later with a Vienna-Salzburg-Innsbruck route. ‍ The Luftwaffe seized it in 1939, where it was used by the Luftgaukommando VII and routinely visited by the Messerschmitt Me 262 during its development phase. The United States Air Force heavily bombed the city in 1944 (15 air raids), but the airport somehow remained undamaged. It was the first Austrian airport to return to scheduled traffic after WW2. ‍ A new control tower was built in 1958, and a new passenger terminal was opened in 1966. ‍ It’s a hub for Eurowings Europe and is served by Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Finnair, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Transavia, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air. Most of them only operate seasonally. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models, a custom interior with 3D passengers, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, custom taxiway signage, custom ground clutter, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.38, requiring at least 1.42 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da42cw</id>
    <title>COWS Releases DA42 Series for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da42cw"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c7e722e50d09f026dff5e0_cows1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. COWS have recently released their DA42 Series for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a rendition of the DA42-VI and DA42-TDI variants of the Diamond DA42 Twin Star, a popular twin-engine four-seater first flown in 2002 and introduced in 2004. ‍ Christian Dries, Diamond’s founder and chief executive officer, approached their design team in the late 1990s with a concept for a twin-engined aircraft, which eventually became their first twin-engined airplane, with over 600 built since its inception. It was idealized to be simple, fuel-efficient, and luxurious.  Seating up to four people, it can cruise at 326 km/h with a total range of 2,250 km, making it a solid luxury commuter. The DA42-VI, the first variant, features improvements in the propellers and aerodynamics, allowing it to cruise faster and more efficiently.  The add-on features a high-fidelity visual model with photorealistic texturing, accurate placards, fiberglass scratching, an intricate interior model with moderate or heavy wear, two-panel color options, a flight model tried and tested by DA42 students and flight instructors, with accurate performance figures and handling, a true-to-life electrical system with circuit breakers and custom alternator voltage simulation, custom standby flight instrumentation, custom hydraulic gear system simulation, engine damage, state saving, a dynamic sound engine, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $30.18, requiring at least 2.88 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ibylel</id>
    <title>iBlueYonder Announces Lelystad Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ibylel"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c9440b56e9aebcc4620e8b_lelystad.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iBlueYonder has recently announced and teased their rendition of Lelystad Airport (EHLE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Lelystad and Amsterdam in the Netherlands. It's the country's biggest general aviation airport, home to an important aviation museum. ‍ It was idealized in 1966 and had its first flights in 1971, albeit not yet as an official airport, which only happened in 1973. With grass taxiways and runways at first, it was often closed because of muddy terrain, rendering it useless as a landing strip. It wasn't until 1978 that the taxiways were finally hardened, followed by runway paving in 1981. ‍ It was purchased by the Schiphol Group in 1993, the same company that manages Amsterdam Schiphol, the busiest and main airport in the Netherlands. ‍ A decade later, the Schiphol Group moved the Aviodrome Museum from Schiphol to Lelystad, where it has been headquartered ever since and holds various events every year. ‍ The airport is currently under expansion work, driven by Schiphol reaching its maximum capacity and its geographic proximity to Amsterdam. The House of Representatives begs to differ, though, with a motion in January 2024 that blocks the usage of the airport for commercial aviation.  ‍ Developed by Ronald Fleurbaaij, a new member of iBlueYonder, the scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport and is scheduled to reach completion before this year's FSWeekend in March. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orxswp</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases Swedish Triple Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orxswp"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c94769910be9d9d1f9245c_stp.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently teased the arrival of the Swedish Triple Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a package with three Swedish airport renditions developed by independent developer Marcus Nyberg. ‍ The Swedish Triple Pack features an accurate rendition of Umeå (ESNU), Kiruna (ESNQ), and Scandinavian Mountains Airport (ESKS), with snow piles during winter, custom high-resolution ground textures, custom GSX profiles, unique static aircraft, and more. ‍ Umeå Airport is the seventh busiest in Sweden, with a yearly average of 960,000 passengers. It was inaugurated in 1962. ‍ Kiruna Airport was inaugurated in 1960 and averages around 270,000 passengers yearly. ‍ Scandinavian Mountains Airport is one of the newest airports in the world, inaugurated in 2019. It was the first airport to feature a completely remote control tower.  ‍ There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
