<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-02-18T18:24:48.944176+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxcpt</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Shares A320 Cockpit Teasers</title>
    <updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxcpt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62001b0ca3800551eeea0919_cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="456023"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. As the MSFS community eagerly awaits the upcoming Fenix Simulations A320, it’s safe to say the team here at Threshold is equally as excited, that said, it's with shared anticipation and excitement, we present some newly released progress pictures from the team at Fenix Simulations, take a look:   As many will agree, one of the perks of being involved in the flight simulation world is being able to witness, first hand, the developments and advancements in visual integrity and animation capabilities. Microsoft flight simulator as a whole, has been a perfect example of this, with the jump between FSX and MSFS2020 truly showing how far we have come in replicating reality. The Fenix A320 appears to be no exception to this. These images display a level of texture work and detail that was once inconceivable. The texturing shown above, perfectly resembles that of the typical A320 cockpit surface, hard worked, worn and cold to the touch. Notice the swelling edges on the panels, the oily touch points, the dents and scratches, all randomly occurring. It is evident the team have been meticulous and extremely detail driven whilst composing this aircraft.  As mentioned in our previous article, the team at Fenix simulations have upped their resources and focus on the aircraft itself, in order to get us up and flying as soon as possible. With the aircraft having gone into beta testing not long ago, we all simply hope the release will be soon. Until then, stay tuned as we’ll be sure to keep you updated as and when information is made available.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/findul</id>
    <title>Nimbus Simulation Studios’ Dulles is On Final Approach</title>
    <updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/findul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6200202f83cb3da896348af0_cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2348396"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has recently teased that their much anticipated Washington Dulles International Airport scenery (KIAD) for X-Plane 11 is nearing release. The airport, announced more than two years ago, will become the first payware scenery for Dulles and will become the gateway for countless pilots to the American capital. From the pictures that accompanied the post, we can see that the modelling and texturing work on the various buildings, taxiways, and runways across the airport is already complete. Other details, such as cargo pallets, stationary aircraft, ground vehicles, and signs that are scattered across the field also look to be finished. Overall, it is reasonable to conclude that the scenery is very close to being ready for release. However, apart from the pictures, the developer hasn't provided any additional information regarding the upcoming airport, such as a feature list. Washington Dulles Airport is located some 45km outside of the nation’s capital and is one of the main international airports that serve the region. A hub for United Airlines, KIAD supports more than 40 different airlines and flights to over 125 destinations. In 2019, it saw more than 24 million passengers. Currently, Nimbus Simulation Studios has yet to announce a firm release date or pricing for the scenery. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Nimbus not only develop their renowned sceneries but also work on aircraft such as their BN-2 Islander and UH-1 helicopter.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lasham</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Lasham Airfield for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lasham" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6202fb72daa5d900ea61a1ba_Cessna_172SP_G1000-2022-02-0600.23.32_thumb_673c4cb6-e313-47f6-b9e8-8a67c102d64b.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1078329"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless Simulations has released yet another historical airfield for X-Plane 11. They have traveled over to Lasham Airfield to provide users with a custom visual rendition of the WW2-era airfield. The airfield was built in 1942 as a station for the Royal Air Force during the Second World War. It provided and launched support through many major battles in the European Theater of the war. When the war ended, the RAF ceased operations at Lasham Airfield in 1948, just 3 years after the end of the war. The General Aircraft company continued to operate out of the airfield. Today, Lasham Airfield is owned and maintained by the Lasham Glider Society. The development team has included a short yet down-to-the-point feature list upon release. Starting off, PBR textures have been used for airport buildings, and custom HD ground texturing. HD textured vegetation and static aircraft have been included. Alongside this, accurate night lighting and ground markings have been added as well to add on. Boundless has also included full support with the Traffic Global plugin. Finishing off, the team has made this scenery FPS friendly, for users with lower-end computers. You can find the full feature list below: If you are interested in picking up this scenery package from Boundless, you can find it over on their iniBuilds Store and selling for £8.99 GBP*. If you are interested in any other sceneries by Boundless, you can check out their catalog over on their website.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hs6527</id>
    <title>Hot Start Challenger 650 Receives v1.3.1 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hs6527" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62030e08ac0ff837e806dc4f_CL650_18.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="103701"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Hot Start has continued their proactive development cycle to continually improve and iterate their Challenger 650 development as they’ve released a new update for the aircraft. Version v1.3.1 features bug fixes and quality-of-life upgrades to enhance their users' experience. The team has also addressed mounting performance concerns by outlining procedures for users to perform to push their sims to their maximum potential. Cameron from the X-Aviation team published this guide to address performance issues caused by texture paging hindering other internal X-Plane tasks which in turn create a sluggish environment in-sim. On the topic of the update, CL650 users can update their aircraft through the X-Aviation instructional email, or by logging into your X-Aviation account and redownloading the file.  The most notable features of the update include exterior placards and markings, TCA throttle forward/reverse axis support, as well as various bug fixes. For those interested in the full update log, take a look at the feature list here. Users who aren’t familiar with the Hot Start Challenger 650 or desire to read more into its recent activity, peek at its penultimate update. Prospective CL650 pilots can obtain the fully-simulated aircraft on the X-Aviation store for 114.95 USD.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/egllms</id>
    <title>IniScene announces new Heathrow scenery for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/egllms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6205d87f46c5fa2211e1e71a_Cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1137301"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A video released by IniScene, in its entirety only 48 seconds long, shows the team’s progress in replicating the world’s original, big bird base, that is London Heathrow. As one will notice the scenery already looks absolutely incredible, living up to the quality and attention to detail we have come to expect from the Inibuilds brand at large.  iniScene London Heathrow for Microsoft Flight Simulator | Teaser Taking a closer look, it appears iniScenes wishes to use the video to highlight some of the landmark features of the airport, such as the Turkish Airlines Globe, as well as the majestic 45 ton Emirates A380 model display. What was particularly interesting, was the trademark purple lighting at Virgin Atlantic's check-in area in Terminal 3, a familiar site for many. It's these types of minor details that could have gone unnoticed, but make all the difference and create that immersion we all strive to gain. With IniScenes promising this to be their “most detailed and feature-rich scenery to date.” we can be sure there is much more to come. The video features so much to see in so little time, therefore it's with bated breath we await further updates. No feature list has been given at this stage. What we know for sure is, this product will undoubtedly come with much anticipation within the MSFS community, as Heathrow holds a soft spot in the hearts of many aviators, with many historical aviation events taking place here over the years. In addition to this, as Heathrow was for many years the world's busiest airport, it's statistically likely many of our readers would have spent some time here, making it a highly relatable product.  For those of us who have always marveled at the heavy metal that wallows in the sky above London and those lucky enough to visit Heathrow itself, it's without a doubt that iniScenes will do this airport justice; given their track record, and bring back those nostalgic moments for all who possess them. For more updates stay tuned and we’ll be sure to bring you the latest.  </summary>
    <published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxpra</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Prague (LKPR) Airport for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxpra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62060cc886dc128a78601a6c_lkpr.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1344245"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has released its rendition of Prague Václav Havel Airport (LKPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Completely decked out with accurate modeling, high-quality photorealistic textures, and PBR, the airport takes full advantage of MSFS’s technology. Also included with the scenery comes twenty-one custom “points of interest” to encapsulate the incredible landscape surrounding the airport.  In reality, “Václav Havel Airport Prague” serves as a hub for Czech Airlines, Smartwings, as well as a focus city for Eurowings and Ryanair. Responsible for providing airline service to the capital city of the Czech Republic, approximately 17 million passengers utilize the airport yearly. Nearly 65 airlines currently serve the airport with varying degrees, containing a plethora of international service and inter-EU hops. The airport contains two runways: 06/24 and 12/30 which both present lengths exceeding 10,663 ft (3,250m).  Returning to the airport’s MSFS counterpart, simmers can expect the following features:  Orbx’s LKPR Prague Airport for MSFS is currently on sale for $27.26 AUD/$19.41 USD/€17.18. Downloading the add-on is simple, buyers need to download Orbx Central to download and install the product. It’ll utilize approximately 3.27GB of hard drive space after being downloaded.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/2022ob</id>
    <title>Orbx Publishes 2022 Roadmap</title>
    <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/2022ob" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62060e0e79c1485ea89da916_5980722_Tim1.jpg.182bacdbdaa59a03a491d6f1e4bbd07a.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="129614"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently published its 2022 roadmap. On their forums, Orbx chief Anna Cicognani began with a belated “Happy New Year” then explained that in the short period between the real New Years to today, the team took some time to introspectively analyse their past achievements and how it can inform and drive their future direction. The team recently strengthened their relationship with Microsoft from the collaboration on the Australian World Update and the Fokker, propelling them to a strong start into 2022, Anna noted that the two projects is a labour of love that span many months:   Cigcognani moves on to wrapping up 2021 and what the team achieved, releasing a whopping total of 58 products that includes anything from 18 in-house airports, including their home airport Essendon across three flight simulators, 10 City renditions, 3 regions, and the team’s first aircraft (Edgley Optica), the rest are Indie releases from 3rd party developers. For Orbx, 2021 was a year with intense expansion into the new MSFS simulator, with 47 products being released for the simulator alone, followed by 8 released for P3D and 5 for X-Plane respectively. Looking into the future, Cigcognani has laid out a smorgasbord of releases, beginning with the (just) released Prague airport for MSFS, with eventual versions for Prepar3D and X_Plane forthcoming. Next on the release board is a detailed rendition of Panama Canal which is in the finishing stages “with lots of exciting features”. See here for the original list: Orbx’s independent partners are also involved in these projects. Cigcognani then turned the spotlight to some of the team’s prominent artists, featuring the team’s international reach. Including Marcus Nyberg, who is bringing a rejuvenated Stockholm Arlanda to MSFS from Prepar3D - decked out with brand new texturing to take advantage of the simulator’s rendering capabilities. Nyberg documents his progress on the project on a facebook page which can be accessed here: Arlanda Journal. Here are some of the highlights from the developments: Another Nordic artist, Finn Hansen, has taken on another Scandinavian airport, bringing a bespoke rendition of Oslo to the platform. Projected to be completed by the middle of this year, progress has been steady for the most part: Another associate, Andreas Hegi is working on Bolzano Airport, know for being the primary entry into the Dolomites. From the images it appears that the developer has recently made strides in developing the interior of the terminal complex:  On the note of interior modeling, Cicognani turns her attention to Rasha Tucakov, who is bringing the same Orbx detailing to the Balkans development is wrapping up for LYPG Podgorica:  Moving to the US, developer Matteo Veneziani is currently putting a new coat of paint on KBUR Burbank for MSFS in the same fashion as Nyberg of Arlanda, this follows closely after his recent work on LKSK Skiathos. Burbank will feature reworked models, textures, and new ground work. The MSFS development will serve to be the basis for the X-Plane port (with discounts for MSFS owners once the XP version is out). Following this, Veneziani will hop to Australia to revisit Gold Coast and wrap up LIPH Treviso.In the same continent as Gold Coast, developer Ken Hall is building a rendition of YMLT Launceston:  Hopping over to neighboring New Zealand, developer Tim Harris is chipping away at NZNV Invercargill, with his photorealistic approach to texturing: On the mesh side of things, the son of Orbx’s Global lead developer, Dmytro Krikunov, is putting the finishing touches on the highly anticipated New Zealand Mesh update, which features 1m LiDAR in selected areas, his efforts will continue into South America after NZ. This wraps up the rewind from Orbx as the team gears up with another productive year of releases. For the original update, please visit the forum post.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tls103</id>
    <title>ToLiss Releases Minor Update for A340</title>
    <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tls103" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6206cb3b45dad854ca703dfd_cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="961364"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane aircraft developer ToLiss has recently released an update for its popular A340-600. This new version, V1.0.3, brings new features such as improved engine models as well as an array of bug fixes that range from repairing the sounds and particle effects to readjusting the flight directors on takeoff rotation. According to ToLiss's post, v1.0.3 will not be bringing any major updates, rather it is an opportunity for the developer to patch up various reported bugs while introducing a few minor changes. Most notably, an improved engine model has been included, allowing pilots to "see through the bypass channel as in real life". Additionally, the aircraft will now give pilots the option to "automatically re-engage NAV mode" during a go around procedure. Finally, the new version also implements nurmous bug fixes, including range limited MCDU CI entry and "improved default wing flex magnitude". For the full changelog for v1.0.3, check out the developer's Facebook post. ToLiss's A340, released in October last year, is a sophisticated simulation of the iconic Airbus aircraft. It features highly detailed systems, accurate 3D modeling, and a custom designed FMGS that reflects the operations of its real world counterpart. For additional information on the aircraft, head over to a previous Threshold article. Currently, owners of the product can update their A340 via the SkunkCrafts Updater or by redownloading the aircraft from their store of purchase. For prospective users, a copy of the Airbus can be purchased on the X-Plane.org Store for $89.99.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12pv</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 Previews: A Summary</title>
    <updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12pv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6206e814be9152ff5f3f65c7_chrome_1102_2219.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="384958"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Various previews and trailers have been dropping thick and fast by Laminar Research over the past few days, with previews being shared of various aircraft within the simulator environment. Three of the four videos shared have been shared by Michael Brown, who is a close affiliate of Austin Meyer, but not directly involved with simulator development. Brown is also the owner of X-Force PC, another company with close ties to Laminar. The final video shared is an official trailer of the Cirrus SR-22, produced for Laminar Research by Aviation Lads, a flight simulation promotional content creator. Below is a summary of each video shared by Michael Brown, including a detailed breakdown of the snow and ice featured in the A330 preview video. The video first starts off with Austin showing off his personal aircraft, the Lancair Evolution, which has been integrated into the current Alpha build of X-Plane 12. The aircraft will be shipped as an included GA aircraft when the simulator is released to the public. The video demonstrates the various new additions that X-Plane 12 offers, whilst taking a look at the exterior of the aircraft, viewers can take notice of the ice patches on the runway and the new volumetric clouds. Austin then showcases the cockpit of the Lancair and all of the airframe unique features he has implemented in the real world aircraft, which has then been translated into the simulator. Austin rounds off his showcase of the aircraft by showcasing the simulator’s new volumetric lighting engine, thoroughly explaining what has been done and what is currently being done to make it smooth and flow as best as possible whilst climbing and descending. He then goes on to show the speed, and agility of the Lancair Evolution and explains why this GA aircraft is different from all others. Similar to the video featuring the Lancair Meyer, this video starts off with no delay and jumps directly into discussing runway icing conditions. According to Austin, the ice behaves as ice would naturally behave in reality. As temperatures climb, ice will turn to puddles and as temperatures drop below freezing, puddles turn to ice. While this may sound elementary, having this visually modelled and represented is unheard of. Briefly touching on a major detail that Austin vaguely mentioned, but we couldn't help but notice, was the taxiway and runway textures, which certainly are an improvement from X-Plane 11, to say the least. From ice to A330, Austin is quick to change topics and begins sharing his thoughts on their new default A330. His excitement is almost tangible and rightfully so, the aircraft looks fantastic. Giving praise to the artist responsible for the texture work, he highlights the intricacy in the textures and modelling, in particular the bump maps. Austin also discusses the depth of the systems in the aircraft, which appear to exceed the normal level of detail in X-Plane default aircraft.  An interesting aspect of the aircraft which was extensively discussed in the video was the “Eagle Claw” landing gear. Austin outlined the physics behind the shock absorption mechanics, explaining that the aircraft will simulate the softening effects that this landing gear design has on touchdown. While discussing the mechanics behind the landing gear, Austin is quick to reassure current users that the flight dynamics, which X-Plane is renowned for, are still the forefront of the team's focus and are not by any means traded for better visuals. As the video continues we get a glimpse of some magnificent sights X-Plane 12 holds such as the new 3D clouds, which Austin stresses are still a work in progress. Even more importantly, a highly discussed yet grey area in the X-Plane community for years was addressed, Austin mentioned he had put a team together in Eastern Europe to work specifically on scenery textures. I know hearing this will bring tears of joy to many current users, with the current versions of X-Plane being majorly shadowed by poor ground texturing by default. As we enter the last quarter of the video, the discussion focuses back on the flight dynamics of the A330 itself. For those who enjoy commanding heavy metal aircraft, be rest assured the aircraft behaves accordingly. With the restricted bank angels, sluggish reaction times and the almost untameable momentum, Austin makes it clear that no detail was missed in this respect. The video ends with a bang, which is a polite way to describe the landing, with Austin perfectly displaying the undivided attention such an aircraft requires, coming in at 300 Knots on final and overshooting. We know this is by no means a display of Austin's piloting skills, but rather a perfect example that this aircraft is no paper plane, and requires one's full undivided attention. Check out the video on A330 and everything icing below: The last video to be shared on Michael Brown’s channel is Austin “showcasing” the new F-14 Tomcat. The showcase features Austin taking the Tomcat out of New York’s JFK airport with full afterburners, followed by a swift climb to an altitude where the sunrise can be witnessed in its full glory. Austin then follows this by demonstrating the famous wing sweep of the aircraft and the full flight dynamics being modelled during different stages of the wing sweep. A quick aero refuelling is completed (within the X-Plane menus) after running out of fuel by running full afterburners, then video turns to Austin demonstrating a carrier landing. While the landing was rather impressive, the approach was less graceful with a steep descent from a high altitude being completed using full speed brakes, flaps as well as extended gear. The carrier landing also showcased the fully functional landing hook modelled on the aircraft. While the actual aircraft carrier in the video is the default one from X-Plane, Austin mentioned that a new one is being worked on for X-Plane 12, with a visual artist currently working on the asset, which will greatly improve the visual environment within the when flying over water bodies. Fancy exploring the F-14 Tomcat in more detail? The video below is the one for you: This summary of all developments is rounded off by Laminar Research’s official trailer of the new default Cirrus SR22. While not designed to compete with products such as Torquesim’s Take Command! series of Cirrus aircraft, the aircraft will most certainly be a welcome addition to the simulator. The video, edited together by Aviation Lads, runs in the format of a cinematic completion of a full flight in California taking in famous signs such as the Hollywood sign. The video also demonstrates various capabilities of the simulator itself such as the new rain and icing effects on the windshield. The aircraft itself seems to have a good level of systems modelled including the standard G1000 unit as well as an oxygen system, demonstrated in the video by the aircraft climbing to an altitude of FL150. Sounds are also demonstrated, where a high-quality sound set has been implemented for the aircraft, hopefully being ported to aircraft like the default Cessna 172, setting a higher standard within the simulator. Of course, the gorgeous new weather system is demonstrated as well such as in the screenshot above. Many different weather cycles were shown such as towering clouds, rain and icing conditions. Find all of the above mentioned in the official trailer below: Towards the end of the video where Austin is showcasing his Lancair Meyer, he briefly touches on the current status of X-Plane 12. He stated that there are about 100 current testers, 20 of whom are in direct contact with him. He also stated that work is hoping to be completed on the road network of X-Plane 12 and updates on coastline texturing. Austin addressed hopes for an Open Beta soon, but no date was given or specified as of today. That’s all for this week’s exciting spell of X-Plane 12 previews, check back on Threshold regularly to make sure you never miss the latest updates on the newest generation of the simulator.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/73ngbt</id>
    <title>PMDG Says 737 NG3 Has Entered Beta</title>
    <updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/73ngbt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6209b16078b45f2be1a2d595_image_15297.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1049348"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. News of the 737 NG3 has been pouring in for much of 2022 as PMDG gears up for a blockbuster release with the team’s head Robert Randazzo once again returned to the forums with another iterative weather update on the progression of the 737 NG3 for MSFS. The announcement broke the news that the series of products is now entering beta testing, the decision being made last Thursday with the state of the add-on “mostly conforming to the final product”. Priorities remain the same, though this week introduces further refinements to the 3D including the HUD and HGS rendering, scaling adjustments across the visual model, shadow models and visual refinements to the ground service vehicles. The technical side of things includes the introduction of TCAS II v7.2 for both online and offline traffic, increased pushback accuracy and validation work on equipment and hardware. See here for the breakdown from the forum post: Randazzo elaborated saying that much of the work revolves around polishing the aircraft, which the aircraft is at a stage where the team has addressed most of the msfs related issues and effort is now being streamed into "platform-PMDG issues", issues that stem from the team’s lack of familiarity with MSFS. Two screenshots were provided, demonstrating the collimated HUD and the graphical prowess of the simulator. For the HUD, Randazzo promoted that it “works well both in daylight and in night modes”, with support for variable dimming and flying modes normally used in flight: In the same respect as their previous DC-6 release, the lighting was all done from the ground up to take advantage of MSFS’s lighting system. The second image showcases the light flare as the sun shines against the glistening metal skin of the fuselage and wings. Subtle creases reflecting the surrounding environment are also visible from the picture: Randazzo then moves to address questions raised about the performance, which he provided an indefinite answer given that the aircraft and the equipment used in development wouldn’t accurately reflect the use-cases for the end user. The general consensus is that the performance is largely in line with other aircraft offerings. The development build lacks the optimisation effort which wouldn’t provide usable FPS numbers and it includes development tools attached such as a debugger. Once the testers delves into the beta copy, Randazzo would be able to supply more concrete numbers.  Randazzo also intends to follow up on this post with a demo video, with the intent to showcase features such as the collimated HUD - this week is the goal though Randazzo is wishful in that regard. That wraps up the development update for the NG3. As usual, Threshold will closely follow the development of the aircraft, stay tuned! Check the original update through their forums.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/12nava</id>
    <title>SimCoders Teases X-Plane 12 Plans &amp; Carenado Piper Navajo REP</title>
    <updated>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/12nava" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620b09b2f41e1f31c789b861_wo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="529061"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane.  Last week, X-Plane developer SimCoders published a series of previews depicting their upcoming Reality Expansion Pack (REP) for Carenado Piper Navajo and sharing their plans of bringing their trademark Reality Expansion Packs to X-Plane 12, discussing the full implementation of the experimental flight model currently available as an option in X-Plane 11. For the developers, one of the bigger challenges they have to tackle is the full implementation of the Experimental Flight Model (EFM), an option available to users since X-Plane 11.40 but will become the only model available in X-Plane 12. To facilitate a “smooth transition” to the new flight model, all REP from v4.6 onwards will run the EFM by default. Inn addition, the SimCoders are looking to “improve the flight dynamics of the older REPs” (Carenado F33, V35, Baron, C210, etc) based on community feedback, presenting users with the most realistic flight experience. Apart from the insights on their transition to the new simulator, the developers also teased the community with progress on their upcoming Navajo REP. The pictures showcase the aircrafts checklist, load/balance, and airspeed reference sheet. The plugin, according to the developers, will feature “all the usual REP improvements and a couple of powerful Lycoming TSIO-540-A2C”. However, it is difficult to judge how close the REP is to completion based on the pictures provided. Currently, SimCoders is yet to announce a release date or pricing for the Carenado Navajo Reality Pack. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. For those looking to purchase existing Reality Expansion Packs, all SimCoders products can be found on the X-Plane.org store.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctpw22</id>
    <title>Vote for VATSIM’s Cross The Pond Westbound Airports!</title>
    <updated>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctpw22" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620b2ae92872738f29dd88e3_banner_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="838369"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VATSIM’s team is maintaining its biannual tradition of Cross the Pond. The event will take place on April 2nd, in the westbound fashion. For those unfamiliar with the event, VATSIM hosts a transatlantic event where hundreds of pilots and full ATC coverage come together to participate in long-haul operations. Nearly 12 hours of full Air Traffic Control services will be in use for the entirety of the event. The team has opened up a vote for pilots to give feedback as to which airports they’d like to operate out of during the event.  As always, there’s a plethora of airports to choose from. Pilot’s are given the opportunity to choose three of their preferred airports from the lists below.  It’s critical to mention that aspiring CTP pilots must book a flight slot to ensure participation in the event. Whilst bookings are currently not available, the VATSIM team will keep the community updated regarding the results and booking availability later this month. Due to the large swarms of aircraft during the event, pilots can potentially expect delays to their slot times. Another small piece of information to add, is that Concordes are not permitted within the event and supersonic aircraft will not be recognized as event participating aircraft. Stay tuned with VATSIM’s Cross the Pond website to ensure up to date information regarding slot bookings, and event updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md11tf</id>
    <title>TFDi Announces MD-11 Pricing Details</title>
    <updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md11tf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620dbacd1a16115d5de2d91a_ext3.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1844197"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TFDi has updated their product page for their MD-11 to include pricing information. The team seems to follow the same a-la-carte pricing model of the forthcoming PMDG NG3 which lets users purchase a single aircraft variant of their choice, unlike previous pricing models which includes two or more main variants within the base package. TFDi stated that the pricing model was adopted to allow users to “select the exact features and options you want.” The base package comes in two flavours, the freighter to passenger variant, purchasing one of them will discount the other base package. For example, if you purchase the passenger variant, you don’t need to shell out another $89.99 for the Freighter base package, but $14.99. TFDi aims to also expand the breadth of the simulation with an add-on package labeled “Extended Simulation Package”, this package introduces operational failures, an advanced custom failures menu, and some circuit breaker functionality.Here is the original breakdown of the pricing: Other information on the product page promises a well rounded digital replica of the trijet, with support for all the modern ESP (namely, Prepar3D v4 and v5) platforms including MSFS. The team opened the possibility of adapting the aircraft for use on older ESP simulators such as FSX and Prepar3D v1 to 3. The supplied feature list is short but covers what you’d normally expect in a high end aircraft simulation, with a fully bespoke visual model that includes highly accurate 3D and textures, with support for PBR on simulators that support it. On the technical side, accurate flight dynamics, a full fledged onboard simulation system that features a completely simulated FMS and autopilot system simulation are promised. Lastly, the team partnered with Turbine Sound Studios for the soundpack. TFDi is still accepting suggestions in their forum for features people like to see included in the aircraft. Head over to their wishlist to contribute. That’s all for TFDi’s MD-11. We’ll be sure to keep you in the loop. For now, do visit their product page for the original source.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mag787</id>
    <title>Magknight Updates Boeing 787</title>
    <updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mag787" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620dcbdfb40718395f756bb5_Cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="53848"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The developers over at Magknight have updated their rendition of the Boeing 787 Dreamliner for X-Plane 11, bringing the aircraft version to 1.7.21. This update features many bug fixes and minor feature additions to help prepare the aircraft for its next major update. This is the latest major update to come out, the first in 2022 since August of last year. Since then, the team has been pushing frequent updates in smaller form, through their Cygnus and development-highlights channel. On the coding end, the team has been hard at work preparing for the custom FMC, and Mitchell has been reworking several of the exterior visuals which includes newly modellied wings and wingbox and a fresh set of landing gears - the former which are said to be featured in the next update for the aircraft. The Magknight team has been the sole developer to venture into the world of the Dreamliner in XP11, with FlightFactor shortly becoming their competitor with their 787 currently in development. This update mainly features various bug fixes and minor additions. The CDU help box and NAV RAD page have been added, along with a custom radio simulation. MFD screen pop-ups have been added also with an N1 prediction addition to the EICAS. New Avitab textures, ND graphics,  and CDU graphics have been implemented into the aircraft as well. Moving on to items that have been changed, the CDU will now display times in “real” UTC. Multiple changes have been made to the MFD, such as keyboard entries, mouse entry code, and movement code, which have all been changed. The PFD artificial horizon colors have been improved alongside screen dimming in the flight deck. Legacy panel art and BetterPushback buttons when the plugin is not installed have been removed in this version. If you are interested in further learning about this update, you can view the full changelog at Magknight’s Official Discord Server. If you are interested in purchasing this aircraft, you can find it on the X-Plane.org Store for $44.95. Threshold will keep you posted on any further updates from Magknight.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbwsup</id>
    <title>FlyByWire A32NX Systems Update Progress</title>
    <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbwsup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620f770095ca8029bf264ee7_fbw.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="763276"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Freeware aircraft developer FlyByWire has published a new community update outlining its future systems development endeavors. Ranging from the Fly-By-Wire systems to the Air Condition system, there’s a plethora of updates incoming for the A32NX. The team has provided the community with multiple videos to visualize these future updates, and to help pilots understand the functions of these systems.  Many system improvements have been made, such as adjustments to the pitch law, alongside confirming that yaw and roll laws are already realistic. Pitches at lower speeds have also been tweaked making the pitch law more sensitive. Pitch law has also been improved to help compensate for speedbreak deployment and speed changes. With these changes, brings adjustments to the joystick recommended configuration. FBW recommends users to adjust their +/- 30%, which will in turn, help better mimic the increased force needed to go full back or full forward. ‍ In correlation with the Fly-By-Wire system improvements, the autopilot has also received some tweaking. Conditions with arming the ALT and engaging the mechanisms have received several changes. Target load factors to help guide the AP are now seperated for every law that has been previously mentioned and situations. Speed/Mach laws have been improved with what the team refers to as “further edge cases''. Vertical speed limitations have also been tweaked for Open Descent and Climb modes. Autoland systems have also been tweaked to include a brand new filter to help recognize the flare law, which will measure vertical speed relative to the ground via radio altimeter. ‍ Moving forward, the Autothrust has received minor tweaking with the involvement of improved transitions between climb, descent, open descent, and open climb modes, which will help keep speeds at -5 or +10 knots on vertical approach. Thrust limits have been improved to help itself and its interaction with CLB limits during flex temp takeoffs.  SRS engagement and ATHR arming have been discord to be related, i.e. if SRS does not engage on takeoff, the ATHR will not arm. Lastly, speed control for acceleration and deceleration have been improved to achieve better speed control.  Whilst all of these updates have occurred, FBW has been hard at work developing a new warning system for the aircraft. When released, the Flight Warning Computer (FWC) will help trigger callouts such as GPWS at more accurate heights than before. Other features will include the famous “cricket” stall noise, and intermediate callouts. ‍ Work on a new AC system has begun. When finished, the cabin will be able to warm and cool with the outside temperatures. Air flow delivery systems have been overhauled to fit into the shoes of its real world counterpart. Users are currently able to try out and are invited to play around these new building blocks for the new AC system. If you’re interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can download it over on FlyByWire’s Website.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vc10no</id>
    <title>Just Flight's VC10 for X-Plane is Potentially Cancelled</title>
    <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vc10no" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620fa8be8e8ffe73defbe475_VC10XP_040820_10_cNNC0cvYC.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="230965"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. New evidence supports the claim that the Just Flight VC10 for XPlane has been cancelled. In May 2020, Just Flight announced their intentions to port their VC10 from the ESP platform into X-Plane. This was followed by previews uploaded to their Facebook Page: Despite promising images of the team’s progress, a long radio silence ensued, until XPlane users started to express their concerns online. On February 4th 2022, a user of the XPlane.Org Forums posted an email claimed to have been sent to them by Just Flight’s customer service in response to a query as to the whereabouts of the VC10. The email cites that the main reason for the cancellation of the project was the team’s inability to assure the quality of the product. This claim is corroborated by the fact that clicking the link to the progress blog on Just Flight’s website yields a ‘Page not found’ error. Whilst Just Flight have not yet formally made a public announcement, the evidence points toward the VC-10 port for X-Plane no longer being in development.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
