<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-11-22T18:28:19.969015+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rreetm</id>
    <title>RPSimulations Releases EMB-312 Embraer Tucano for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rreetm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636dd9a6c1bbc3157c34933a_fab1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2063413"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RPSimulations has recently released their rendition of the EMB-312 Embraer Tucano for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a low-wing single-turboprop basic trainer aircraft developed in Brazil by Embraer in partnership with the Brazilian Air Force (sponsorship). Designed in 1979, it took off for the first time in August 1980, and got its first production units in 1983. With a production span of 16 years, 664 units were built in total, operated by the Air Forces of Argentina, Brazil and Egypt. It was Embraer’s first international success. It features a highly detailed cockpit with PBR textures, an animated canopy, in-sim checklist, smoke effects, custom liveries, animated pilots, dimmable interior lights, and freedom to use either of the seats. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available on FlightSim.to for $19.90, requiring at least 2.2 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oadmaf</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Detroit Metropolitan Airport for X-Plane 12 and MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oadmaf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636e0378385263770baab23d_dtw1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2149364"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has just announced their latest project: Detroit Metropolitan Airport (KDTW) for X-Plane 12 and Microsoft Flight Simulator, with the XP version to come first. According to their announcement post, it’s developed by a group of independent developers, using real-world drawings and exclusive access to the airport as reference.  With a yearly average of 35 million passengers, DTW  is among the busiest airports in the United States, serving the city of Detroit, Toledo (Ohio), and part of Ontario in Canada. It’s a hub for Delta Airlines, with over 50% of the market share, followed by Endeavor Air and Spirit Airlines, with 12.95% and 11.69%, respectively. It’s DAL’s gateway to Asia for the eastern US, with frequent flights to Shanghai, Seoul, and Tokyo. Popular routes to Europe include Amsterdam, Paris and Frankfurt.  The complete feature list follows down below: They have also stated the intent to develop a Detroit City Pack and Coleman A. Young International Airport as a complement for the Microsoft Flight Simulator version.  There is no information on a potential release date or pricing, but we’ll keep you updated.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrbfm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Baden for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrbfm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636e6d2b8b7123cd5515064d_edsb_11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="380753"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has just released their newest scenery Karlsruhe/Baden-Baden airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Known as the international airport for Karlsruhe, Baden is a focus airport for Ryanair which operates routes over the majority of Spain and some other destinations within Europe. The airport was initially a military aerodrome in 1951 and then closed in 1994 to be turned into a regional airport as well as a business park. In 2001, the first commercial flights took place to destinations Ibiza and Palma De Mallorca by a former airline, Hapag-Lloyd Flug (now TUI fly Deutschland.) Below, you will find a list of key features Aerosoft have included in their newest scenery.   This scenery is available for purchase on the Aerosoft website and will cost €15.08. You will also need roughly 5GB of storage for the scenery to be installed.  Let us know your thoughts and keep your eyes peeled for future news!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mr4aeu</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases 40th Anniversary Edition Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mr4aeu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636eace77326516cd172c5aa_a1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2507698"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has just released the long-awaited 40th Anniversary Edition update (SU11) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing twelve new aircraft, four classic commercial airports, fourteen heliports and twenty-four classic missions. It is the most substantial update to date in terms of new content. ‍The aircraft list includes seven classics (1903 Wright Flyer, 1915 Curtiss JN-4 Jenny, 1927 Ryan NYP Spirit of St. Louis, 1935 Douglas DC-3, 1937 Grumman G-21 Goose, 1947 Havilland DHC-2 Beaver, 1947 Hughes H-4 Hercules), two helicopters (Guimbal Cabri G2, Bell 407), two sailplanes/gliders (DG Aviation LS8-18, DG-1001E neo) and a true-to-life airliner (A310-300).  ‍Airport-wise, we have the addition of Hong Kong Kai Tak, Chicago Meigs Field, Princess Juliana International (St. Maarten), and First Flight Airport in Kitty Hawk. The update also includes VRAM management improvements to the DX12 version, along with the addition of AMD FSR2 and Nvidia DLSS 3 (including frame generator). ‍ The complete feature list follows down below: 7 classic aircraft: 2 sailplanes/gliders: 1 true-to-life airliner: 4 iconic airports: 24 classic activities from previous Flight Simulator titles: 7 new tutorial missions for Gliders: New features The new update is available right now on the Microsoft Store and Steam, requiring at least 41 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssraia</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Akureyri International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssraia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636f18f3ecd52d6a68d41b1e_aku1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2039387"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently released their rendition of Akureyri International Airport (BIAR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a northern Icelandic airport with nearly 100 years of scheduled air travel history. It’s a hub for Niceair and Norlandair, with a significant domestic network. It’s also frequently visited by Icelandair, with daily flights to Reykjavik. The total yearly average is around 220.000 passengers.  It is home to the Icelandic Aviation Museum, founded in May 1999 and opened mid-2000, in a purpose-built hangar with 2,200 square meters of space. The collection includes classics like the Douglas DC-3, a Fokker F-27, and a Waco YKS-7, among others.   The scenery features an accurate model of the terminal, up-to-date apron and runway data, the Icelandic Aviation Museum hangar, custom static aircraft, high-detail textures, PBR materials, realistic taxiway markings, custom environment objects, and intensive terraforming work.   It’s available on FlightSim.to for $10.99, requiring at least 1.08GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/urtram</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Telluride Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/urtram" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636f21310710dedd803ff66d_tex2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2482311"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has just released their rendition of Telluride Regional Airport (KTEX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the highest commercial airport in the United States, and the second highest overall in the country, only behind Leadville Airport. The yearly passenger figures are around 17.000, with Denver being the most popular destination in terms of sheer volume.   The airport is famous for providing a challenging approach because of the surrounding geography, runway length, and steep glide path angle (3.55 on 9 and 4.0 on 27). The 2167 meters of runway feel a lot shorter because of the elevation.   The scenery features high-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, night effects, FPS-oriented optimization, custom vegetation, PBR materials, both tower and terminal with a modeled interior, and optional static aircraft.  It’s available on FlightSim.to for $9.99 and on their website for £9.99, requiring at least 105 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdrbfx</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Releases Bucharest for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdrbfx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637067d70a791e53e63f04b8_31-600x338.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="62954"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Chudoba Design have recently released their version of Bucharest Henri Coandă International Airport for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Known as Romania’s busiest international airport, Otopeni is located North of the highly populated Bucharest city which offers a major tourist attraction to tourists all around the world due to its iconic landmarks. The airport has seen well over 14 million passengers back in 2019. However, In 2020 the airport had seen almost a 60% decrease in total passengers for that year due to the COVID pandemic. Bucharest Henri Coandă International Airport offers a choice of numerous airlines that fly all around Europe and some parts of Middle-East Asia. There are two runways available at Otopeni International which are parallel to each other and are of the same length of 3500m. Below, is a list of key features this scenery contains: ‍ ‍ This airport scenery is available to purchase on SimMarket for $16.99 and will require at least 2GB of free space to be installed into X-Plane.    Keep your eyes peeled for future news from Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fhrwca</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Warsaw Chopin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fhrwca" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63729ffa7bd823f6a37ed48a_wa1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2342725"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Warsaw Chopin Airport (EPWA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Poland with nearly 19 million passengers in 2019, amounting to 40% of the nation’s total traffic in that year. It’s the central hub for LOT Polish Airlines, and focus city for Enter Air, Smartwings Poland, SprintAir, and WizzAir.   Warsaw is regularly served by many major airlines such as Air China, Air France, British Airways, Finnair, Lufthansa, and Scandinavian. The main destinations are London Heathrow (1 million passengers), Paris Charles de Gaulle, Kyiv-Boryspil/Kyiv-Zhuliany, Frankfurt, and Amsterdam (500.000 each).   The scenery features working VDGS modules (Aerosoft VDGS), a high-detail rendition of the airport, terraforming, PBR materials, custom aerial imagery, animated jetways, and custom static vehicles and objects.  It’s available on FlightSim.to for $18.00, requiring at least 3.7 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ahpalm</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Previews Avro Lancaster for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ahpalm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6372a853adf43d9d13449cf9_avro1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1002204"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Shortly after publishing a teaser on Facebook hinting at its eventual arrival, Aeroplane Heaven published some screenshots of their upcoming Avro Lancaster for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a British WW2 heavy bomber introduced in February 1942. Powered by four Rolls-Royce Merlin engines with 1280 horse power each, an impressive wingspan of 31.09 meters and able to cruise at 282 miles per hour with a load of 63,000 lb and a range of 2530 miles, it played a significant role during the aerial offensive over Europe. ‍ Announced in January with preview images of the Self-Defense turret, they have not previewed anything else since. The current preview doesn’t say much, aside from the fact it’s still being developed and shaping up. Stay tuned to Threshold for more information on the Avro Lancaster and all things flight simulation! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fxsf50</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces Release Date for SF50 Vision Jet</title>
    <updated>2022-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fxsf50" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6373d0b6cca66d2d388e15a3_VJ%20Launch%20Final.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="164830"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Nick Sdoucos and the FlightFX team has announced the release date and pricing for their rendition of the SF50 Vision Jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Bringing an all-new business jet to the MSFS. The Vision Jet has been included in both XP11 and XP12 packages right out of the box, but FlightFX has taken the challenge to create one of the most notable small jets in flight simulation. Nick from FlightFX has stated in his press release: It was also stated in the press release that the team is already at work preparing additional enhancements that will come in later updates which will include the refresh of the WT G3000. In addition to the team trying to capture the experience of flying in this aircraft. The SF50 Vision Jet will be available on the Marketplace on November 22, 2022, with a price of $24.99. Pre-release streams from TwoToneMurphy and TheFlyingFabio will available for users to tune in and see the aircraft for themselves before purchasing,</summary>
    <published>2022-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrnbum</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases New Beta Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrnbum" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63768baa272c5a36cf3c36cc_40th_Anniversary.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="804433"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently updated the Microsoft Flight Simulator beta branch to version 1.29.29.0, fixing specific CTDs related to missing or malformed waypoint, VOR or NDB, along with a patch for the newly released IniBuilds A310-300 that includes improvements to the electronic flight bag, sound tweaks, improved intercept calculation methodology on all SIDs/STARs, and lighting fixes. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ General Bug Fixes Several crashes have been fixed across the title ‍ Fixed potential crash when requesting missing or malformed Waypoint / VOR / NDB ‍ Guimbal Cabri G2 occluder has been improved to match the cockpit ‍ ‍ Airbus A310-300 Textures Parking Brake spelling fixed Some low-res textures improved on Base version EFB/IFE EFB - Added automatic METAR lookup based on To/From Airports ‍ EFB - Auto-populate Wind, Temperature, Runway Condition and QNH from the METAR ‍ EFB - Added manual METAR Search ‍ EFB - Added ability to enter numbers on flight planning page, as well as sliders for PAX, cargo and fuel (Click the text) ‍ EFB - Removed sound volume sliders ‍ IFE - Fixed erroneous ETA to destination ‍ Sounds Master audio control is now through in-game settings ‍ Fixes to volume levels ‍ Fixed AI A310 volume levels being too loud ‍ Fixed AI A310 rolloff distance being too great ‍ Fixed directionality of APU noise ‍ Fixed audio at rear of cabin being too quiet ‍ Tweaks to interior attenuation ‍ Tweaks to engine sounds ‍ Tweaks to engine/apu start sounds and their event cues ‍ Tweaks to brake fan and packs system sounds ‍ Adjustments to ground rolling audio ‍ Tooltips Hard coded aircraft type for external applications that were showing TT: ‍ Fixed spelling error in trivia text ‍ Chronometer tooltip fixed ‍ ND Brightness tooltip fixed ‍ Switches ‍ WX radar switch fixed ‍ Cameras ‍ Fixed Showcase QuickView4 under belly camera ‍ ATC Updated default livery ATC callsigns ‍ Lighting ‍ Cockpit lights toggled with L key bind ‍ Control Keybinds ‍ AP commands can now be bound to default key commands ‍ FMC/FMS ‍ Xbox fixed need to press A twice to enter characters on the MCDU ‍ Improved intercept calculation methodology on all SIDs/STARs ‍ FO VOR gauge animation fixed ‍ FMS Cruise Temp can now be edited ‍ Numerous FMS crashes fixed ‍ If you want to join the beta branch, refer to this guide. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jpnffd</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes New Fokker F28 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jpnffd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637699361dace64e9e1af253_fokker1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2423283"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published another Fokker F28 development update concerning its current state. In relation to last month’s update, they have implemented fully animated passenger and cargo doors, wheel chocks, and cones around the airplane. They also state the visual work is pretty much complete at this point.  They have also begun working on the F28 systems, which are unique to the aircraft, increasing the complexity and requiring close collaboration with their testing team of ex-F28 specialists (pilots, engineers, training crew) to ensure maximum fidelity. “You certainly won’t be mistaking this aircraft for your typical airliner!” says the developer.  The aircraft is now in a flyable state, with all animations, cockpit instrumentation, annunciators, and basic systems. It is now undergoing testing by their team. ‍  Credits to DragonRuins for the news scoop. Stay tuned to Threshold for further updates on the F28 development and more! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nafscs</id>
    <title>Navigraph Announces FlightSim Community Survey 2022</title>
    <updated>2022-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nafscs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6377df8c18ecde46917dfe83_af5f7129-37ab-4c16-ab6b-a0ce866bdb76.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="423388"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The yearly Navigraph Survey has been released to the FlightSim community where a selection of questions will be asked based on Partnerships, Demographics, Relation to any real life aviation and much more! ‍ The survey period lasts from today, the 18th November 2022 to the 28th November. It is a 10 day window where flight sim enthusiasts have their opinion on what they want to see in future development. ‍ Take part in the Navigraph FlightSim Community Survey 2022 by clicking here The questions asked in the survey will be straightforward and will give you an option whether it is optional or not. You have to be honest in the survey as this is the best way developers can get an idea of what people want to see in the future. Questions can range from age, overall income and education levels to what intrigues you about FlightSim and why you spend the hours you do being part of a massive aviation community. ‍ The 2022 survey is one of the largest survey’s of its kind and contains a much more broad selection of simulators as well as newly arose aircraft developers. As we all know Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 has seen a massive amount of development since it was released 2 years ago by developers such as PMDG, Fenix Simulations, FlyByWire, Orbx, Aerosoft, UK2000 and much much more. A few months ago Laminar Research had released the Early Access / Beta version of X-Plane 12 which the team at Laminar have been working incredibly hard on to provide constant Beta updates for the users of X-Plane. Again this newly released simulator has seen a massive amount of development from external developers such as X-Works, Threshold, Toliss, FlightFactor, Orbx and many more. This year should give some interesting results due to the recent development on these newly released simulators. Here is a link to last years results where we saw MSFS take the lead, who will take the lead this year? Let us know below. ‍ Unfortunately, Threshold are not shown in the partnerships in this year’s survey. Results will be announced on Navigraph’s blog in Mid-December, the survey is anonymous and no personally identifiable information is collected, and the results will only be presented in aggregated form. ‍ Again, to take part in the Navigraph 2022 Survey click here! ‍ We look forward to seeing the results!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prscu7</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases SU11 Compatibility Update for 737 Lineup</title>
    <updated>2022-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prscu7" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63781b919fa94377345ae198_11%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="833628"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has just released a new update to the 737 lineup, ensuring compatibility with Sim Update 11 and its new standards, built on the latest SDK. According to Robert Randazzo’s forum announcement, the main focus has been the tuning of the control law for the automatic flight control system in pitch, roll, yaw, and thrust, mitigating an issue with the previous update related to the atmospheric stability simulation that is claimed to be “significantly unrealistic” and requiring the creation of additional logic into the control law. PMDG also claims the 737 control logic improvements will pave the way towards greater realism in atmospheric stability without need for changes.   They have been working on bringing forward new features that are now possible with SU11, such as a weather radar, but the results are not yet up to the expected standard, thus still under development. A short list of other minor fixes follows down below: 0012072: [General - Documentation] Amend Introduction document to remove Wifi Antenna FWD/AFT option (hvanrensburg) 0012051: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Capt Stab trim clipping (vscimone) 0012052: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] MIssing pixel on Electrical Panel when using New pressurization panel option (vscimone) 0011821: [External Model - Geometry] Negative pressure relief valve text &amp; push panel mis-aligned (jbrown) 0011614: [External Model - Geometry] Paintkit Model Texture Distortion (jbrown) Work on the SU11 transition has delayed the progress on the 737-900, which they hope should be entering testing by next week. The EFB, on the other hand, is apparently well into testing and progressing well. Randazzo has mentioned that a preview will probably happen as soon as they feel it’s ready to be shown.  Regarding the marketplace addition, they claim it was submitted today to Asobo for approval, and it should become available soon.   The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Images are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iadmam</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Detroit Metropolitan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iadmam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637be7593237ab7a294cdf04_inidetroit1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2062258"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced their newest project for Microsoft Flight Simulator: Detroit Metropolitan Wayne County Airport (KDTW). It’s Michigan’s busiest airport, with an average of 35 million passengers yearly, covering a massive domestic and international network, with Delta, Endeavor, and Spirit taking a chunk of the market share.  ‍ According to the developers, the development of DTW took their scenery development to the next level, with a high degree of accuracy. It features custom jetways, GSE and taxi signs, high-quality textures, an animated train in the McNamara terminal, fully animated Laminar fountain, and deicing statics. “As part of our commitment to our customers earlier in the year, with each scenery we release, we want to push the boundaries in the features we are providing” says the developer.  They have also previewed an iniManager feature that will allow customers to customize their sceneries to their liking, such as static aircraft, people, and winter equipment. It will also be made available for their KLAX and EGLL.  There is no information on release date or pricing yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/opsapu</id>
    <title>Orbx Publishes Stockholm-Arlanda V2 Progress Update </title>
    <updated>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/opsapu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637c1cb90669e17eeec5d258_essacover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="319919"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has made a forum post with updates on the development of Stockholm-Arlanda V2 (ESSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It is the largest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 26 million passengers (70% international, 30% domestic). It serves Metropolitan Stockholm and known as the gateway to most of Sweden.   It’s a hub for Scandinavian Airlines and Eurowings Europe, and a focus city for Finnair, Novair, and Ryanair. London is the most popular European destination, with nearly 2 million passengers shared between Heathrow and Gatwick, followed by Copenhagen with 1,394,000. International-wise, Dubai tops the chart with 302000, followed by Doha with 284000, and the United States with 278000.  They have partnered with Jetstream Designs (creator of Paris-Orly, Toulouse, and Linate, among many others) and are “moving forward quickly”, with Terminal 5 to reach completion soon. The scenery will feature custom GSE items, and high-quality ortho imagery with an updated high-res mesh, “to be showcased soon”.   In regard to a potential P3D and X-Plane version, they say it will be looked at once the scenery is out, “as long as there is a market for it at that point.”  The developer made a Facebook page with progress updates and screenshots.  There’s no information on pricing and release date yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! Thanks to Luke on our Discord for the scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
