<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-06-12T18:34:39.934831+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350111</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683a36256e1b9e9f81f783e6_upsy1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued a significant update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which includes extensive overhauls and refinements across core systems, new features, and more. ‍ Update v1.0.11 comes with new fly-by-wire features, such as the auto de-rotation system, which assists pilots during the landing phase after the main gear has touched down. The system prevents hard nosewheel touchdowns by avoiding any abrupt or exaggerated pitch changes by the pilot, helping improve landing consistency across different weather conditions and pilot landing techniques.  Furthermore, the update also features enhanced GPS jamming, with the satellite signals becoming degraded, blocked, or completely unavailable upon entering a jammed area, impacting navigation accuracy, ADS-B reporting, and position data for the FMS. The A350 heavily depends on GPS for efficient and precise routing, even though it also has IRS and backup navigation sources to fly the route. However, functionality will be severely limited, alerts will be triggered, and a switch to alternate navigation models may be forced. Initially, their GPS jamming system was randomized and not region-specific. In contrast, the new version integrates live data for a much more realistic experience, only jamming where GPS jamming is going on. ‍ They calculate the regions using a system called H3 Geo to convert latitude and longitude into hex cells on a map that correlates the aircraft’s reporting of GPS data in those areas over 24 hours and dynamically updates it so the jammed regions are constantly changing based on real-world data. A throwback feature—present in their A300 and A310 for X-Plane—has finally made its way to Microsoft Flight Simulator, allowing pilots to print take-off data, flight plans, metars, mailbox, and more. They used a combination of 3D animations and show/hide attachments to simulate the print process and placement of the paper on the chart clip in the cockpit.  For Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 pilots, the planned route API is now in working order, making it possible to send and receive the flight plan from the sim FMS and vice versa. The tool built into 2024 uses the official LIDO navigation databases and real-world submitted flight plans to provide accurate routing information. This feature will be utilized in the sim’s career mode in the future. iniBuilds has also added a new condensation effect. The aircraft generates condensation on cockpit windows using the difference between outside air temperature and simulated cabin temperature, building up or dissipating over time depending on the conditions. The windshield heat status is also taken into account, just like the real aircraft. Due to sim limitations, the effect is exclusive to MSFS 2024. They have also added a wide range of new ECAM messages. Some of them were disabled in 2024, though, due to a bug in the simulator. The complete changelog for the update follows below: ‍ v1.0.11Systems⚙️FIXED: MFD approach: selecting via NONE displays [----]FIXED: Latched VDEV behaves like normal DES mode if the speed is reducedFIXED: FPLN erased during go aroundFIXED: After a 2nd go around the approach is no longer in the FPLN bugFIXED: Changing arrival runway but not inserting it still changes the drop down approach optionsFIXED: Duplicate UTC message in F-PlanFIXED: Activating ALTN doesn't clear original DEST dataFIXED: MCDU-FLAN modification in SECFIXED: EDDM 08L/R VNAV issueFIXED: OMDB, RIDAP 2F SID - min speed at DB570 is 180, but the max at DB585 is 220. Should managed speed therefore shoot for 220?FIXED: Issue when deleting HOLD as part of procedureFIXED: EFIS ND Mode Change Message not displayingFIXED: Floating arrowFIXED: MFD PERF: QNH inHG entry format errorFIXED: GO Around logic issuesFIXED: VLS conf full and conf3 are the sameFIXED: AFS Control Panel functionality incorrectFIXED: Takeoff trim out of limits when lightFIXED: Issue with glowing brakesFIXED: Pressing FIRE pb should turn the FADEC offFIXED: Engine oil capacityFIXED: OIL quantity indication oscillates during cruiseFIXED: Engine failure after V1 feedbackFIXED: XPDR behaviour from STBY to AutoFIXED: RMP 3 logicFIXED: Text overlap on fuel pageFIXED: RNAV SLS incorrect NAVAIDS tuningFIXED: SURV: can click through the confirmation boxFIXED: FADEC not powering off 15min after ENG shutdownFIXED: MAGVAR issue for display on AFS, PFD, NDFIXED: Brake cooling mid-airFIXED: Spoiler behaviour reversesFIXED: VNAV VSD de-synced from sequenced waypoint after inserting holdFIXED: RWY (armed) shows when flap lever is set to 0FIXED: Sim Pause triggering on user AP disconnection with protection onFIXED: ENG ECAMFIXED: FMS goes blank when selecting FMS1FIXED: Spoilers don't extend when overspeedFIXED: No zero on barometric altitude when below 100 feet MSLFIXED: Engine thrust doesn't follow cursor when set to idle reverseFIXED: No TAWS messages on NDFIXED: A. LOCK doesn't workFIXED: WIND UPLINK issuesFIXED: Cost Index vs cruise speed too low at normal cruise levelsFIXED: Battery draining during pauseFIXED: TCAS amber with NAV PRIMARY LOSTFIXED: ETP FMC calculationsFIXED: D-ATIS arrival request shows departure ATISFIXED: CMS formatting on NDFIXED: SEC Index page logicFIXED: PRED TO function not working as expected for typed FLFIXED: PRED CLB ECON not showing as referenceFIXED: PERF CRZ FL391 input reverts to ---FIXED: SPD to MACH reversion shows incorrect SPD window valueFIXED: Level-Off Arrow symbol rendering bugsFIXED: Constraint logic not functioning as intendedFIXED: AP disconnection due to low FPSFIXED: Mode reversion to heading mode in high windsFIXED: EFIS CP baro reference issueFIXED: C/L sensed items not staying green after takeoffFIXED: Suggested optimum step fieldFIXED: Nose drops automatically on touchdownFIXED: Auto sideslip control issues and side slip indicator behaviorFIXED: FO OIS brightness buttons affecting contrast barFIXED: No level off arrow in CRZ phaseFIXED: WPs missing from CMS/Step AltsFIXED: Roll feedback in FBW systemFIXED: TMPY inputs not resetting after FMC resetFIXED: FMS ALTN F-PLN scroll/view mismatch with NDFIXED: Wind data at cruiseFIXED: ND drawing of cross track errorFIXED: CP logic at power upFIXED: VSD not showing level-off altitudeFIXED: PFD LS distance info displayFIXED: GLS approach loading issueFIXED: SURV page misbehavior when IR unalignedFIXED: Aircraft takes off stick-free at low FLEX/TOGAFIXED: VAPP jumping erratically in strong windsFIXED: Cannot deselect FLS on LDA approachesFIXED: Step altitude logic revisions implementedFIXED: Level-Off Arrow Symbol rendering issues in multiple scenariosFIXED: WIND DES page and ALTERNATE entries in FMS not functioning correctlyFIXED: SELECTED FOR NAV tab not calculating RADIO NAV MODE and RADIO POSITIONFIXED: With engine out, automatic CLB phase no longer engages incorrectlyFIXED: Transponder functionality reversedFIXED: Window wipers function with no power (cold and dark, BATs off)FIXED: Pressing FIRE pb did not shut down FADECFIXED: ND did not indicate next waypoint correctlyFIXED: Issue with VHHH LIMES waypoint not rendering properlyFIXED: ALTN flight plan shows dashed line not matching ND routeFIXED: WIND DATA synchronization in FMS not workingFIXED: AFS CP logic failure with empty FMSFIXED: MFD crash when switching to SEC-FPLN (WASM issue)FIXED: ANF/EFIS crash scenario addressedUPDATED: Elevator trim blending logic proposal for smoother rotation handling when transitioning from ground to air OISFIXED: ROP warnings not workingFIXED: Activating ALTN doesn't clear original DEST dataFIXED: BRK MED disarming during go aroundFIXED: CMS issueFIXED: Navaid auto tuning feedbackFIXED: PRED TO function not working in any phaseFIXED: No FMA change box in engine out when selecting THR MCTFIXED: MAP waypoints in PLAN should be blue not greenFIXED: MAP constraints shouldn't have prediction circlesFIXED: BRK MED not workingFIXED: Missed approach showing 0nm to waypointsFIXED: ND display of departure airportFIXED: BTV not workingFIXED: T.O. THS out of range on spawnFIXED: ND LS-Mode with FLSFIXED: ND NAV mode, level-off arrow behind aircraft in selected HDG+VSFIXED: Brake cooling mid-airFIXED: Engine failure after V1 feedbackFIXED: LDG inhibit disappears too earlyFIXED: Auto callout RETARD issueFIXED: GSX passenger load count &gt; max capacityFIXED: GSX unable to disconnect GPUFIXED: Updating return information for TOPerf to FMGSFIXED: Fuel jettison shows ON and OPEN instead of ON and faultFIXED: ENG 1/2 MASTER ECAM logic with BLUE faultFIXED: Gear failed on left side not showing red down lockFIXED: SPD LIM TMPY input disappearing when editedFIXED: Engine out: ATHR off FMA keeps flashing LVR MCTFIXED: ISIS option and menu behaviorFIXED: MFD F-PLN selection should scroll to the topFIXED: ECAM WXR &amp; TCAS faults shown when IRS is offFIXED: SPD Brakes visually appear but have no flight model effectFIXED: SURV panel spelling issueFIXED: Display type &amp; status not synced on spawnFIXED: Track line missing when on HDGFIXED: VD bracket on ND should disappear when in HDG/TRKFIXED: Spawning mid-flight triggers AUTO EMER DES as cabin alt of 15kFIXED: Autoland at EDDLFIXED: Waypoints missing from CMS/Step AltsFIXED: Managed speed quick fluctuationsFIXED: SUGT optimum step fieldFIXED: Engine failure after V1, stuck in TO phaseFIXED: BRK MED: box around it on FMA when active present againFIXED: Incorrect order of memos on ECAMFIXED: PRIM1+2+3 fault, FD listed as INOP but still worksFIXED: "M" in PFD LS "NM" is hidden behind target bearingFIXED: REFUEL IN PROGRESS memo stuckFIXED: NW STEER DISC memo stuck EFB/OIS🖥️FIXED: GSX loading in the wrong orderFIXED: OIS Loadsheet page fields not updating correctly during/after GSX progressive boarding/refuellingFIXED: OIS charts issue and readabilityFIXED: No option to set departure time on the OIS FLT PLN Simbrief pageFIXED: OIS OFP page large fps drop when mouse within OIS bordersFIXED: OIS Screen brightness bar missing (CPT/FO)FIXED: SYNC FMS not workingFIXED: Cabin Language livery config takes priority over OIS setting – warning addedFIXED: Add load configuration button (Doors/Cargo)FIXED: Toggling fuel panel on MX page opens L1 doorFIXED: Typo: Dual Engine Failure SituationFIXED: Avionics Bay and Cargo Bay lights turning on simultaneously via EFBFIXED: Oil overflow indication on maintenance pageFIXED: OIS OFP text size not persistingFIXED: Enroute map route drawing error on trans-pacific flightsFIXED: Fuel weight calculation issueFIXED: GSX remote stand boarding not opening L2FIXED: GSX boarding does not continue automatically if fuel is upliftedFIXED: Region-based GPS jamming impact areas addedFIXED: New ZFWCG calculations integratedFIXED: Cannot print mailbox messages via MSG RECORD pageFIXED: Printer D-ATIS / MAILBOX page feedbackFIXED: Printer FPLN INIT page feedbackFIXED: Some ECAMs should be restricted to 2020/2024 onlyFIXED: OIS ENR SUGT – do not draw MAP (missed approach)FIXED: EHAM to EGBB chart crash in LIDO repositoryFIXED: Printer -T.O DATA- Page FeedbackUPDATED: EFB API enhancementsADDED: Preferred PF seat selection to options page,ADDED: Geo referencing for LIDO charts ART🎨FIXED: Condensation animation only shows on left wingFIXED: JA03XJ - Sustainability Goals decal should be removedFIXED: ETH 1000 liveries missing tail flashFIXED: Edelweiss -900 missing wing reg and decalsFIXED: OH-LWK export failureFIXED: Lufthansa winglets alignmentFIXED: JAL aircraft not rendering in simFIXED: Fuel ventilation overpressure discFIXED: DLH D-AIVA tailplane white texture instead of blueADDED: Hot brakes emissive SOUNDS🔊FIXED: No sound on belly door releaseFIXED: Missing gear door opening sounds on groundFIXED: No touchdown soundsFIXED: EXT APU sound too loudFIXED: Parking brake handle has no soundFIXED: Park brake sound plays once then not againFIXED: Brake fans missing spool up/down soundFIXED: Add varied flap motor noisesFIXED: External sound added to landing gear doorsFIXED: External hydraulic sounds no longer overly filteredFIXED: Adjusted hydraulic sound distancing from cockpit perspectiveFIXED: Missing system noise in walkaround viewFIXED: Reduced dip in engine volume after startupFIXED: Added variety to flap soundsFIXED: TCAS sound events not playingFIXED: Brake fan spooling sound missingFIXED: Exterior avionics volume increasedFIXED: FS20 exterior sound distancing muted at certain anglesFIXED: FS20 sunshades audio mix increasedFIXED: APU levels adjusted near the nose areaFIXED: Dropped intensity of maximum low-frequency gainFIXED: Delay on gear thump sound after rotationFIXED: FS20 touchdown sound inconsistencyFIXED: Retard callout louder than other GPWSFIXED: Hydraulic pump stopping sound plays after ENG shutdownFIXED: Post engine start sounds too quietFIXED: D-ATIS Auto Update not functionalFIXED: HYD pump sound when recharging accumulator should not be audible from cockpitFIXED: Taxi roll sound too loud and sounds oddFIXED: No belly door release soundFIXED: Wing to center tank xfer pb has double click soundFIXED: ELEC pushbuttons play double click when toggled ON &gt; OFFFIXED: PARK BRAKE sound plays once then stopsADDED: Printer sounds added ‍ The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dus101</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Düsseldorf Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dus101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683e5ce6048ae267d61f671f_dusup1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently issued an update to their newly released rendition of Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024, addressing issues, improving the level of detail, and more. Update 1.0.1 – released just a few days after the product’s release – brings a hefty changelog consisting of many improvements around the terminal, bug fixes, LOD tweaks, and more. The changelog follows below: The scenery is available on Contrail for roughly $20.56, requiring at least 4.38 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmwsss</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Singapore Changi Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmwsss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683f90219060370618258298_changi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels recently released their rendition of Singapore Changi Airport (WSSS) for X-Plane 12. It is one of the world's busiest airports, with a yearly average of 58 million passengers. It was inaugurated 42 years ago when the Singaporean government was forced to build a new airport to cope with the region's ever-growing demand for air travel.  At first, their original plan was to expand Paya Lebar, the former main airport in Singapore, but the 1973 Oil crisis changed everything. By 1975, they had already decided to build a brand new airport at the eastern tip of the main island of Changi, at the Changi Air Base. After its first year of operation, the airport had already handled an average of 12.1 million passengers, which led to the construction of a second passenger terminal in the 1990s. Terminal 3 soon followed in 2008, and then Terminal 4 in 2017. Terminal 5, which is planned to be larger than all four combined, is expected to open in 2030. It's a FedEx Express, Jetstar Asia, Scoot, and Singapore Airlines hub. AirAsia, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air India, Air New Zealand, All Nippon Airways, Cathay Pacific, China Southern Airlines, EVA Air, Garuda Indonesia, Hainan Airlines, IndiGo, KLM, Lufthansa, Qantas, Swiss, United Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made PBR ground textures, high-detail models, SAM jetways, performance-friendly optimization, weather textures (X-Plane 12), and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $26.48, requiring at least 1.86 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samqin</id>
    <title>SamScene3D Releases Qingdao Jiaodong International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samqin"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683f94b63bf970eb359418b6_qing1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SamScene3D has recently released their rendition of Qingdao Jiaodong International Airport (ZSQD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Qingdao with a yearly average of 21.4 million passengers. It was built to replace Qingdao’s former main airport, Qingdao Liuting International (same ICAO). The project was approved in 2013, and construction started in 2017. By 2020, the terminal building had already passed completion acceptance, greenlighting it for a 2021 inauguration. It features a single 478,000-square-meter terminal built to handle up to 35 million passengers a year, designed in a starfish shape with five concourses, and two 3,600-meter-long runways able to handle up to an A380. It’s a hub for Qingdao Airlines and Shandong Airlines and a focus city for Beijing Capital Airlines and China Eastern Airlines. 9 Air, Air Busan, Air China, Air Macau, All Nippon Airways, Cathay Pacific, China United, Donghai Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Jeju Air, Korean Air, Scoot, Shanghai Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tibet Airlines, West Air, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed terminals, detailed ground markings, custom jetways, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.09, requiring at least 3.90 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl302</id>
    <title>FSLabs Releases A321ceo Update Including MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl302"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de3df1ae2d10ada9d7bc_labsup2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently released a new update to its A321ceo product line, available via its Public and Experimental branches on the FSL Control Center. The update adds initial compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, many system enhancements, sound upgrades, and more. Update v11.0.1.302 is their first update to feature initial compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It makes several changes under the hood to support the new environment while also retaining compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The new update also brings system-level improvements, including bug fixes, performance optimizations, and refinements to raise the realism bar and reliability. They were driven by extensive internal QA and feedback from their community of pilots and testers. ‍ The sounds were also upgraded, substantially improving the soundscape around the cockpit and engines. ‍ Furthermore, FSLabs has also added the ROPS (Runway Overrun Prevention System)—not to be mistaken with the thing missing from some RTX 5080s and 5090s—an advanced safety feature designed by Airbus to help mitigate the risk of runway excursions during landing. It integrates two core functions: ROW (Runway Overrun Warning) and ROP (Runway Overrun Protection). The Runway Overrun Warning provides proactive in-flight alerts by continuously computing the aircraft’s predicted stopping distances on dry and wet runways, considering real-time factors such as weight, speed, configuration, wind conditions, and runway slope. If it determines the available runway length is not enough for a safe landing, it automatically issues visual and aural alerts: ‍ The visual alert has the PFD display “runway too short,” the navigation display indicates the predicted stopping points extending beyond the runway’s end. The aural alert, on the other hand, triggers below 200 feet, with a repetitive “runway too short” audio warning. ‍ The alerts are in place to prompt the crew to start a go-around procedure, as a landing attempt beyond that point is deemed completely unsafe. ‍ The ROP system takes over upon touchdown and continuously assesses the aircraft’s deceleration capability against the remaining runway length, providing immediate guidance may it detect insufficient stopping distance: ‍ A visual alert – similar to the ROW one –displaying a “runway too short” warning, and aural alerts issuing commands such as “brake max braking,” “set max reverse,” and “keep max reverse” depending on the situation at hand, ensuring maximum deceleration efforts. ‍ The feature was faithfully recreated to replicate Airbus logic, ensuring realism and immersion for the virtual pilot. ‍ The Flight Performance Model has also been tweaked, changing how it responds in roll. By closely analyzing the roll momentum and inertia characteristics of the real A321 and incorporating feedback from current Airbus-rated pilots, they have fine-tuned the control laws within the ELAC (Elevator and Aileron Computer). It involved reworking gain schedules and dynamic response parameters to replicate the plane’s roll behavior more accurately across different flight phases and load conditions.  ‍ Furthermore, the update now makes livery-specific EFB Backgrounds a possibility, no longer relying on Airline packs for that. ‍ The complete changelog for the update follows below: Simulator Platform Air Con APU ATSU/AOC CPC Effects EFIS/FCU Engines FAC Flaps FMGC Flight Guidance/ELAC/FM LGCIU/BSCU Fault logic fixed ROPS Sounds Techlog XPDR Others ‍ FSLabs has also briefly teased their upcoming A321neo with a single screenshot of an easyJet livery. The FSLabs A321ceo is available in their store for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dus102</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Düsseldorf Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dus102"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684207a442d3270a1953ea9c_mkdus1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios recently issued a second update to their newly released Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which includes bug fixes and improvements.  Update 1.0.2 adds more details to the terminals, new gate fonts, glass color changes in some objects, LOD fixes, AFCAD fixes, and more. The changelog follows below: The scenery is available on Contrail for roughly $20.56, requiring at least 4.38 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbne2</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Brisbane International Airport V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbne2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6842aa443d5e0df9bc79c95b_brizza1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their new rendition of Brisbane International Airport (YBBN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves South East Queensland and has a yearly average of 22.2 million passengers, making it the third busiest airport in Australia. It was built to replace Eagle Farm Airport, Brisbane's first airport - only 5 km away from the new airport's location - deemed inadequate by the 1960s standards for how big Brisbane was, eventually leading to the idea of constructing a brand new airport beside it, which started in 1980 and only saw its conclusion in 1988, with a domestic terminal and two runways. The international terminal only came to be in 1995 and has been progressively expanded. In 2007, the government approved the construction of a new parallel runway, which was expected to take eight years to build on swamp land 2 kilometers west of the terminal area. The unexpectedly long construction time was due to the settling period of the 13,000,000 cubic meters of sand gathered from Moreton Bay to cover the swamp. Work was completed in 2020, costing $1 billion and taking precisely eight years from start to finish. It's a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia. Air Canada, Air Niugini, Alliance Airlines, American Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, EVA Air, Fiji Airways, FlyPelican, Jetstar, Korean Air, Link Airways, National Jet Express, Nauru Airlines, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Skytrans Airlines, Solomon Airlines, United Airlines, VietJet Air, and Virgin Australia also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, high-resolution orthoimagery, updated ground polygons, realistic night lighting, enhanced airside clutter, and an animated monorail. It's available on OrbxDirect (2020/2024) for roughly $16.90, requiring at least 7.71 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bnexp1</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Brisbane International Airport V2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bnexp1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6842ad4c167fa3623d34acd0_brix1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx recently released their new Brisbane International Airport (YBBN) rendition for X-Plane 12. The airport serves South East Queensland and has a yearly average of 22.2 million passengers, making it the third busiest airport in Australia. It was built to replace Eagle Farm Airport, Brisbane's first airport - only 5 km away from the new airport's location - deemed inadequate by the 1960s standards for how big Brisbane was, eventually leading to the idea of constructing a brand new airport beside it, which started in 1980 and only saw its conclusion in 1988, with a domestic terminal and two runways. The international terminal only came to be in 1995 and has been progressively expanded. In 2007, the government approved the construction of a new parallel runway, which was expected to take eight years to build on swamp land 2 kilometers west of the terminal area. The unexpectedly long construction time was due to the settling period of the 13,000,000 cubic meters of sand gathered from Moreton Bay to cover the swamp. Work was completed in 2020, costing $1 billion and taking precisely eight years from start to finish. It's a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia. Air Canada, Air Niugini, Alliance Airlines, American Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, EVA Air, Fiji Airways, FlyPelican, Jetstar, Korean Air, Link Airways, National Jet Express, Nauru Airlines, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Skytrans Airlines, Solomon Airlines, United Airlines, VietJet Air, and Virgin Australia also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, improved 3D vegetation, SAM jetway compatibility, high-resolution orthoimagery, updated ground polygons, realistic night lighting, and an animated monorail. It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $19.48, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kdfw24</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Releases Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kdfw24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684591974b4e7f149299ecde_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Imaginesim has just launched the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW). After releasing this airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 a few months ago, the team is excited to introduce the highly anticipated MSFS 2024 version. Dallas Fort Worth International Airport is the third busiest airport in the world and serves a variety of airlines. It is a hub for American Airlines, Ameriflight, Southern Airways Express, and UPS Airlines. Since opening in 1974, the airport has undergone several expansions and improvements. It features a total of seven runways and five terminals, with a sixth terminal currently under construction. With nearly 750,000 aircraft movements each year, the airport accommodates approximately 88 million passengers annually. The scenery is filled with features like detailed terminals, high-definition building texturing, custom jetways, Skylink train animation, and much more. The recently released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport is now available from Imaginesim for approximately $33.81. Customers who own the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version are eligible to receive it for free. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inirho</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Rhode Island T.F. Green International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inirho"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6848c21fb73891b4af4d1d51_pvd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently released their rendition of Rhode Island T.F. Green International Airport (KPVD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which serves Providence with a yearly average of 4 million passengers. It was dedicated in 1931 as Hillsgrove State Airport, and its first passenger terminal was only built in 1933. Its original layout consisted of three 910-meter-long concrete runways. It was used for flight training by the United States Army Air Force during 1942 and 1945, hosting the 435th Army Air Force Base. The WW2 occupation period led to several upgrades, including runway extensions (300 meters each) and slightly improved infrastructure. In the 1960s, a new terminal was built, as the old one was not large enough to handle a metropolitan area with over a million people.  It wasn’t until 1996 that it would see another upgrade, entirely replaced by a new passenger terminal with 18 gates. Four extra gates were added in 1997. It’s a hub for Wiggins Airways and an operating base for Breeze Airways. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, BermudAir, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a true-to-life landside, realistic dynamic lighting, custom jetways, real-world signage, LOD-optimized objects, and much more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $13.51 (introductory price), requiring at least 3.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vpibog</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases El Dorado International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vpibog"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6848cb0873eb6eb8d8d2b3a1_bog1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. V Pilot Designs has recently released their rendition of El Dorado International Airport (SKBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Bogotá and its surrounding areas with a yearly average of 45.8 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in Latin America. The airport was conceived during General Gustavo Rojas Pinilla's government as part of his intent to modernize Colombia. Construction started in 1955, and it opened its doors for passengers within four years. It ultimately replaced Techo International Airport, Bogota's former main airport. By 1973, the airport was already handling over 3 million passengers, leading to concerns about over-congestion in the near future, which led to plans for a new runway. The second runway only came to be in 1998, much to the dismay of the locals, as that meant more noise. In 2017, the airport's Terminal 1 was significantly expanded, going from 173,000 square meters to 235,000, and can now handle up to 43 million passengers annually. Two years ago, plans were made to expand the airport further, bringing its capacity up to 60 million passengers annually. The project, funnily enough, was named El Dorado Max. It's a hub for Aerosucre, Avianca, Avianca Cargo, Avianca Express, Copa Airlines Colombia, LATAM Colombia, LATAM Cargo Colombia, and SATENA, and an operating base for AerCaribe, Central Charter de Colombia, Clic Air, Helicol, SADELCA, SAEP, and Wingo. Aerolineas Argentinas, Aeroméxico, Air Canada, Air Europa, Air France, American Airlines, Arajet, Avior Airlines, Copa Airlines, Delta, Emirates, Gol Linhas Aéreas, Iberia, JetSmart, KLM, Lufthansa, Spirit, Turkish, United, Viva, and Volaris also serve it. The scenery was rebuilt from scratch for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, featuring an up-to-date ground layout, high-resolution PBR textures, performance-friendly optimization, highly detailed terminals, custom jetways, and much more. It's available in the MSFS 2024 Marketplace for $21.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsrdss</id>
    <title>Black Square Announces Release Date and Pricing for the Starship for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsrdss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684955697bbd27a5f2469b47_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has announced the release date for its highly anticipated Starship for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The aircraft is scheduled to be released on June 19th, just over a week from now. The upcoming Starship is being promoted as one of the most advanced aircraft simulations available for the simulator. It will feature an accurate recreation of the Collins avionics suite, a sophisticated pressurisation and cabin temperature simulation, and over 230 potential failure scenarios. Additionally, a new tablet interface will allow users to configure all options, manage payloads, control failures, monitor engines, and more, all from one convenient location. A complete list of features can be found on the product page. The aircraft will be available exclusively on the Just Flight website initially, with plans for releases on both the marketplace and other third-party websites to follow. The highly anticipated Starship from Black Square is set to launch with a price tag of around $54.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/chrlsv</id>
    <title>Cardinal Horizon Relaunches SimVector With New Data Platform</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/chrlsv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6849feb5e6fc0d79b38e79ea_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Cardinal Horizon has recently released SimVector, a subscription-based platform designed to provide affordable, dynamic schedule data for the flight simulation community. ‍ First launched in 2019 as a live VATSIM map, SimVector has been reworked to address the growing need for up-to-date airline schedules. Today, many virtual airlines rely on static spreadsheets, which are prone to falling behind real-world changes, such as new routes or equipment swaps. ‍ “For many months, the communities that use our products have complained about stagnation in the market, data quality, and more with existing schedule offerings”, said Taylor Broad, owner of Cardinal Horizon. “SimVector is our answer. We want to provide data and products that allow our customers and their staff to focus on building communities, and not the minutiae of maintaining these datasets on their own.” The platform's standout feature is SimVector Direct Delivery, available on the Plus plan, allowing purchased data to be synced directly with a user’s phpVMS v7 installation. This removes the need for manual downloads or uploads, keeping schedule data current with minimal user intervention. ‍ Data is formatted for phpVMS v7, and available in CSV and JSON formats. Pricing follows a points-based model, where the number of points required per airline is proportional to the cost of acquiring the data. This results in notable cost savings compared to traditional providers. For example, a dataset for Delta Air Lines costs $4.32 under the Plus plan, versus $20.31 on a competing platform. ‍ The Basic plan includes 50 points for $10 per month, while the Plus plan offers 250 points for $29 per month and unlocks Direct Delivery.  A general aviation apron model is also provided, with potential for more features as development progresses. ‍ Although the platform currently focuses on flight schedules, Cardinal Horizon has confirmed the development of additional datasets in the future. ‍ You can learn more by visiting simvector.net. ‍ For more updates on SimVector and the latest in flight simulation, keep an eye on Threshold. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737m24</id>
    <title>iFly Releases Experimental 737 Max Compatibility Patch for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737m24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684a682255cee2412867f4a9_ifly1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iFly has recently issued an experimental compatibility patch to their 737 Max for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with an addendum that there are still issues with it, hence the “experimental” tag. “The changes introduced by Asobo have been difficult for developers to deal with, and we want to say up front there are remaining issues due to the base sim still being work-in-progress by Asobo,” warns iFly. They also add that people are welcome to try it if they want, but it’s an experimental release, if anything. They complement, “There are still multiple, unresolved compatibility issues remaining. Any future progress by us depends on Asobo supplying the complete backward compatibility they promised.”  iFly believes that despite the many issues, it’s already possible to fly from A to B with their 737 Max and have fun. Some features, such as the airport maps and RAAS, do not work due to the way everything is now streamed, but these options will be made available again at a later date. Running iFly Manager 1.0.4.0+ is required to install the update, which appears once you select “MSFS 2024” within it. ‍ The add-on is available on their store for $69.95, requiring at least 5 GB of hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wkbo24</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases El Dorado International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wkbo24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684a6b769c774a16da1e214b_boggers1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. WingSim has recently released their rendition of El Dorado International Airport (SKBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves Bogotá and its surrounding areas and has a yearly average of 45.8 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in Latin America. The airport was conceived during General Gustavo Rojas Pinilla's government as part of his intent to modernize Colombia. Construction started in 1955, opening its doors to passengers within four years. It ultimately replaced Techo International Airport, Bogota's former main airport. By 1973, the airport was already handling over 3 million passengers, leading to concerns about over-congestion in the near future, which led to plans for a new runway. The second runway only came to be in 1998, much to the dismay of the locals, as that meant more noise. In 2017, the airport's Terminal 1 was significantly expanded, going from 173,000 square meters to 235,000, and can now handle up to 43 million passengers annually. Two years ago, plans were made to expand the airport further, bringing its capacity up to 60 million passengers annually. The project, funnily enough, was named El Dorado Max. It's a hub for Aerosucre, Avianca, Avianca Cargo, Avianca Express, Copa Airlines Colombia, LATAM Colombia, LATAM Cargo Colombia, and SATENA, and an operating base for AerCaribe, Central Charter de Colombia, Clic Air, Helicol, SADELCA, SAEP, and Wingo. Aerolineas Argentinas, Aeroméxico, Air Canada, Air Europa, Air France, American Airlines, Arajet, Avior Airlines, Copa Airlines, Delta, Emirates, Gol Linhas Aéreas, Iberia, JetSmart, KLM, Lufthansa, Spirit, Turkish, United, Viva, and Volaris also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, custom jetways, rebuilt interiors for MSFS 2024, and much more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $8.00, requiring at least 1.08 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prjeff</id>
    <title>Propair Releases Rocky Mountain Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prjeff"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684a74dfdc14765c5a7ad5d6_jeff1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Propair has recently released their rendition of Rocky Mountain Airport (KBJC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, serving Denver, Colorado, with a yearly average of 262,000 aircraft movements. The airport’s history stretches back to the late 1950s, when the increased demand for private air travel required something beyond Stapleton International Airport (Denver’s former main airport), as that one was operating at capacity. The idea was to create an airport dedicated to general aviation, offering a convenient alternative for private aircraft, corporate jets, and flight training operations that were increasingly constrained at a large hub such as Stapleton. The airport has experienced exponential growth through the 1960s and 1970s, thanks to the rise of corporate aviation. Its strategic location close to Denver and Boulder made it extremely attractive and way easier to access than Stapleton ever could. In 1995, with Stapleton’s closure, Rocky Mountain Airport (then Jefferson County Airport) rode their first high wave, as Denver International Airport had no intent whatsoever to be general aviation friendly, meaning JeffCo would take all of the GA traffic that was once meant for Stapleton. Many investments were made during that period to ensure the infrastructure was always up to the highest standard. In the early 2000s, the airport’s administration decided to be more than just a general aviation airport and embrace regional tourism, changing their name to “Rocky Mountain Metropolitan Airport” and solidifying its role as the gateway to the Rocky Mountains.  JSX currently serves it, with flights to Burbank, Dallas—Love Field, Las Vegas, and Scottsdale. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, PBR materials, custom night lighting, custom ground poly, animated people, and much more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.14, requiring at least 2.66 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
