<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-12-03T18:20:42.305438+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc12sw</id>
    <title>Simworks Studios announces the offical release date of the PC-12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc12sw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6561238366e6d436424a547f_392788910_804891734971842_7296539669171357453_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="448005"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simworks Studios has finally announced the much-awaited release date of their new Platus PC 12. The official release time is scheduled for Wednesday, December 6, at 12:00GMT. The aircraft will be available for download on the Simworks Studios website and the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace as soon as approved. Simworks has indicated that the console version will be released later due to some issues that the team has been addressing. This PC12 will be Simwork's most complex flight model, custom in-house avionics, and engine model, making it the most complete add-on ever released by Simworks. They have promised to keep updating the PC12 over time. The team is currently working on the manual to have it available for release. Simworks is also working on the failure expansion models to allow failures to occur organically while being more "portable" to future aircraft projects. Moreover, they have mentioned ongoing discounts, stating that this is an excellent time to pick up other Simworks products. Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dddcia</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Charleston International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dddcia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65641c996b5eb360c5a7f829_charle.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1565265"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam has recently released their rendition of Charleston International Airport (KCHS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Charleston County with a yearly average of 5.3 million passengers.  ‍ It was built in the late 1920s by the Charleston Airport Corporation on 280 hectares of land from a mining company, with help from the City of Charleston in the 30s (they purchased a part of the land for passenger service). Within a decade, the runways were paved and lit up for nighttime operations.   ‍ Control was briefly handed over to the US Army during WW2, but civilian services continued throughout the war.   ‍ In 1949, a new passenger terminal was built from scratch. ‍ It was once again handed over to the Army during the Korean War, with the city and the USAF reaching an agreement that has been renegotiated over time (and continues to this day).  ‍ Boeing built a 787 manufacturing plant in 2009, with the first completed aircraft rolling out of the assembly line in early 2012.  ‍ The passenger terminal has recently been overhauled, with a complete interior renovation and the construction of five new gates.  ‍ Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, custom ground textures, custom jetways, and more.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.10, requiring at least 1.22 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ae1000</id>
    <title>Aerobask releases the E1000 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ae1000" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6564d1ed9136a848f5ee9d2a_405770034_825327319389923_440592706304683165_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="362804"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The E1000, built by Epic Aircraft in Bend, Oregon, is a sleek single-engine turboprop powered by Prat and Whitiney's renowned PT6A. Epic aimed to create the fastest single-engine civil aircraft during the time of its introduction and production. The PT6A-67 puts out 1,200 hp with a four-bladed Hartzell prop attached, bringing this aircraft to a maximum speed of 333 knots and a service ceiling of 34,000 feet. With a pressurized cabin the E1000 can transport five comfortably in club seating arrangements while achieving a 1560 NM range. The airframe uses composites to save weight, increasing performance.  ‍ ‍ You can now experience jet-like speeds and altitudes with Aerobask's recreation of the E1000 for X-Plane 12. Aerobask focused on the flight model in team with X-Aerodynamics, allowing the sim model to match the latest prototype certification performance metrics. The visual model includes 4k PBR textures and a wholly remodeled airframe that's packaged with eight liveries.  ‍ The aircraft's avionics are powered by Laminar's version of the Garmin G1000 suite and work together with the GFC700 autopilot. The PT6A comes with custom parameters to resemble its real-world counterpart. The systems and operational procedures match the functional circuit breakers of the actual aircraft, and a fully simulated EIS500 Stand-by Attitude Module is also included. ‍ Ease of use features an Avitab tablet for controlling various options on the aircraft. To learn more about Aerobask's Epic 1000, see their X-Plane.org listing, website, or Facebook in the links below. The Epic E1000 is currently on sale as of 11/27/2023 for 22.72 (regular pricing 34.95). ‍ As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uft085</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates Universal Flight Tablet for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uft085" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65655962ddfb39fe58cd1c74_1250410_20231107220658_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2460875"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG recently issued a new update to their 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including a series of fixes and improvements, as disclosed in their previous development update.  ‍ Update 3.00.0085 brings the Universal Flight Tablet to version 1.4.0, with the main highlight being the tablet’s ability to pick up changes made on the FMS, always showing an up-to-date flight path. The complete changelog follows below: 0012645: [EFB - General] Tablet map should pick up changes made on the FMS (rmurdoch) 0012692: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Landing Dispatch Data should be imported into Landing Enroute fields (cbpowell) 0012775: [EFB - General] Tablet namespacing still not working correctly (rmurdoch) 0012551: [EFB - General] Need Handling of Reroutes &amp; Diversions (cbpowell) 0012475: [EFB - Simbrief] CO RTE field not showing CO RTE name (cbpowell) 0012771: [FMS - Initialization] Two click SimBrief integration of RTE/PAYLOAD/FUEL/PERF INIT loading into FMC (emvaos) 0012722: [EFB - General] Metars stop functioning between 0000z and 0100z (rmurdoch) 0012788: [EFB - General] PMDG map tiles names are fuzzy (rmurdoch) 0012777: [EFB - General] Fully convert to JSON for tablet-plane comms (rmurdoch) 0012782: [EFB - General] UFT 1.2 "New route loaded" message appears too often (rmurdoch) 0012783: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Arrival Airport Calls for Runway, not ICAO code. (cbpowell) 0012792: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Imported Flight plan times do not match Simbrief (cbpowell) 0012698: [EFB - General] Make all wind fields, changeable units (rmurdoch) 0012609: [EFB - General] Charts app, should fullscreen in the same way as maps app does (rmurdoch) 0012665: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Calculate button shows loading circle in case of Calculation error message appears (rmurdoch) 0012721: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Weather Import INOP (rmurdoch)​ ‍ It’s currently only available for PMDG.com customers, with the Marketplace update to follow later. Update 3.00.082 is on its way to the Marketplace and is scheduled to release this Thursday (Nov 30).   They have also announced the arrival of a new update for the UFT coming early next week, with cleanups and quick fixes. It’s part of their “3 and 1” cycle, where they take three weeks to push major change updates, followed by a week of stability/correction builds.   The UFT is still not working on Xbox, and they are waiting for guidance from Asobo on how to address it.   PMDG also warned SimBrief users always to select an airline and flight number for their flight plan, or else it causes the airplane to fail upon importing the flight plan.  PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navfaa</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates Charts with FAA Sectionals</title>
    <updated>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navfaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6565df2af78ff7afc655cc55_sectional.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="214934"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has recently added FAA Sectionals to their Charts app, providing flight simmers with an increased awareness of the terrain underneath, landmarks, airspace classifications, airstrips, frequencies, and more.  ‍ In a nutshell, sectional charts are detailed maps designed to facilitate navigation through the skies, covering specific regions with a wealth of crucial information such as topographical features, airspace boundaries, navigational aids, airports, and more. Symbols and lines are color-coded, helping identify cities, mountains, and other landmarks. Furthermore, it also serves as a flight planning tool, allowing for more accurate decision-making during the pilot’s journey.  ‍ They also included Terminal Area Charts (TACs), offering in-depth depictions of specific metropolitan areas. It’s crucial for pilots during the arrival and departure phases of flight, offering a comprehensive view of the airspace structure, runway layouts, navigational aids, and important landmarks near airports. It assists pilots in navigating through complex terminal airspaces, highlighting specific procedures, altitudes, and radio frequencies essential for safe and efficient operations. It is crucial to enhance situational awareness and dramatically contribute to the overall safety of air travel. ‍ Navigraph has also included IFR High and Low Charts from the FAA. ‍  The charts are available on all Charts platforms for Navigraph Ultimate subscribers. Click here to subscribe or learn more. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/1208rc</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12.0.8-rc-1 Is now live!</title>
    <updated>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/1208rc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65662ba00a1e5550d32fa39f_345075846_194035403450906_419649011760514412_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="129073"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Release Candidate One of Update 12.0.8 is now released, addressing several bugs in the simulator, including CTD in certain instances, issues with Better Pushback, and more.  The 12.0.8-rc-1 update has fixed bugs related to the Skyhawk assertion failures when loading the SkyHawk floats on solid ground and crashes when popping up the ATC window at EGPR. Various PNG iCCP warnings with the Zibo 737 and 12.0.08-beta 2 have also been addressed. Better Pushback error has been retitled to "impossible to push back....". Further issues like the rotating tips during loading screens and the performance regression reading "sim/aircraft/view/acf_livery_path" have also been fixed. The erratic catapult behavior of the Aircraft Carrier, which violently snapped aircraft to location when taxing close, has also been resolved.  Furthermore, the freezing mode, which was not working correctly, has also been resolved. All these fixes come after the significant release of version 12.0.8, which includes new engine model improvements, landing gear physics, fuel temperature models, graphics fixes, and more.  You can find more information about the changes in the latest update by watching Austin's update video, in which he discusses the evolution of these features and how they affect flight dynamics and other sim parameters. ‍ As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates.  Special thanks to Joandreas on the Threshold Discord for this news tip!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avrojf</id>
    <title>Just Flight releases the Avro Vulcan</title>
    <updated>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avrojf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6566394c0111a7871cd8f437_avro-vulcan-b-mk2-k2-mmr-msfs_55_ss_l_231120113053.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="184332"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The highly anticipated Just Flight Vulcan project is now available for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It is the most accurate and detailed recreation of the Avro Vulcan for any Flight Simulation. The Just Flight team has put tremendous effort and resources into the project, gathering hours of data, sounds, and details from the latest surviving airframe. Thanks to the Maintenance and Preservation Society, the Just Flight team gained access to detailed sound recordings, resulting in two engine types of sound sets – the Olympus 200 Series and the Olympus 301 Series engines.  Vulcan's interior is modeled to exact details based on XM655 sampled for this recreation. The cockpit, with hundreds of functional switches, knobs, and controls, is also modeled to perfection. Lighting includes over 25 functioning lighting controls, bringing the ambiance of the real aircraft at night to the simulator. The rear crew panels are also modeled in outstanding detail, as well as the texturing and modeling, which is as close to the real aircraft as possible, with 8k PBR texturing bringing out all of the details from the inside out. The package includes various liveries (19) fitting the time of the Vulcan's service history. The aircraft simulation includes realistic payloads like Blue Steel, 1000-pound bombs, and bomb bay tanks. The bomb bay doors function and are fully animated, along with other animated features such as lift dumpers and the tail-mounted air brake. Further simulations cover the complex electrical, fuel, and engine management systems and CAN and VOR NAV radio systems. Vulcan's flight model has undergone extensive work to bring realistic and accurate flight characteristics to the sim.  Feedback from former Vulcan crewmembers was used to create the most accurate flight model for the sim. Custom effects like compressor exhaust haze, exhaust, and the Houchin GPU bring in the immersive level expected for this historic aircraft. These systems are coded based on real-world manuals. The operations and EFB manuals can be downloaded from the links below. The Vulcan sales for 32.99 on Just Flights website.  Operations Manual  EFB manual  Just Flight has published extensive video coverage of the model on their YouTube page, which you can check out below! ‍ As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msdsr</id>
    <title>Microsoft Dev Stream Recap: World Update XVI and Famous Flyer Announced, and More</title>
    <updated>2023-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msdsr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6567ec140e1af05379d50769_Screenshot%202023-11-29%20at%207.04.46%E2%80%AFPM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3150024"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In their latest monthly developer livestream on Twitch, Microsoft has announced World Update XVI, along with the upcoming Famous Flyer, and other details about Sim Update 14. The one and a half hour long stream also covered some new features coming to Sim Update 15 as well as the upcoming World Hub. ‍ Starting with the World Update, it was announced that the focus area for the upcoming update would be the Caribbean, specifically  This update will feature new Digital Elevation Maps, new aerial imagery, and new technology that brings the bright blue shallow waters around the islands to the sim. There will also be 3 new bush trips, 3 landing challenges, and 3 discovery flights. On the scenery side, Microsoft and Asobo are again working with Gaya Simulations to bring over 100 points of interest and seven new bespoke airports to the sim. The seven new airports included are Vilo Acuña, Puerto Plata, Antoine-Simon Airport, Crown Point, Sangster, North Eleuthera, and Les Saintes.  During the stream, Microsoft also revealed that the Famous Flyer 8 will be the Cessna 207. Developed in partnership with Carenado, the Cessna 207 will be released along with Sim Update 14, which comes out in just a few days. The Cessna 207 is known for its expanded seating capacity of up to seven people, and the popular design language borrowed from the Cessna 172. Not much about the features included in the Carenado 207 have been announced as of the time of writing, but it will feature high-quality textures and multiple variants of the C207. The team at Microsoft and Asobo also covered some additional information about the upcoming release of Sim Update 14. Multiple topics were covered, such as the new snow coverage system, the highly-requested improvements to the atmospheric lighting system, the avionics overhaul for the Cirrus SR-22 by Working Title, and many fixes and improvements. They also shared new previews for the sun and ozone changes. There was also an extensive section covering a new update to ground handling. Microsoft and Asobo were able to accomplish this by taking some of the physics model changes from the rewritten engine for the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 to MSFS 2020. This allows the airframe to shake and respond to forces such as moving control surfaces and engine vibration. For the developers out there, they’re going to be adding a new parameter to define the flexibility of the airframe. This update is set to launch with the release of Sim Update 15. ‍ Finally, the team shared a new preview image of MSFS 2024, showing what looks like a beautiful rendition of the Grand Canyon in the United States. ‍ You can watch the full stream on the Official Microsoft Flight Simulator Twitch channel here. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mklemg</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Malaga Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mklemg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6568513f4e26b2f730bd785b_malaga.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1482728"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Málaga-Costa del Sol Airport (LEMG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Spain with a yearly average of 18.4 million passengers, only behind Madrid, Barcelona, and Palma de Mallorca.  ‍ It’s one of Spain’s oldest airports, dating back to 1919, with scheduled air service starting that same year with Didier Daurat flying passengers to Barcelona, Toulouse, Alicante, Tangier, and Casablanca. ‍ The runway had its first extension work in 1960, followed by the construction of a new passenger terminal at the very center of the site. ‍ ‍ In 1991, a new passenger terminal (now Terminal 2) was opened, designed by Ricardo Boffil. The old one was converted into a general aviation terminal four years later. ‍ Terminal 3 was opened by King Juan Carlos in March 2010, starting operations a day after the ceremony. ‍ Only two of the three terminals are currently operating (Terminals 2 and 3). Terminal 2 is low-cost oriented and hosts EasyJet, EasyJet Switzerland, and Ryanair, and Terminal 3 is used by the other airlines. ‍ Being one of the busiest airports in Spain, the list of operators is substantial: it’s a focus city for EasyJet, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, and Vueling, and most European carriers regularly visit it. London Gatwick is the busiest destination, with an average of 885,608 passengers, and Barcelona is a close second with 778,527. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, LiDAR-based elevation data, custom ground polygons, handcrafted 3D models, realistic lighting, AI compatibility, and custom interiors.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket and OrbxDirect for roughly $18.13/18.51, requiring at least 1.32 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/leedv2</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Leeds Bradford V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/leedv2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569c87618f0567e522dfd9b_leeds1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="485221"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced a new rendition of Leeds Bradford Airport (EGNM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving North and West Yorkshire with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers. ‍ It was opened in 1931 as Leeds and Bradford Municipal Aerodrome (or Yeadon Aerodrome), mostly used for general aviation and training during its initial years, with scheduled flights starting in 1935.  Work on the main terminal started around the late 30s but only reached full completion after WW2.   Avro constructed a shadow factory during that WW2 period called the Leeds Bradford Airport Depot, with over 5,000 aircraft before its closure in December 1946.  In the early 1980s, the runway was extended, allowing it to be classified as a regional airport. After the extension, Wardair commenced international flights to Toronto in a 747 in 1984.  The airport underwent expansion work in the late 90s and early 2000s, allowing it to reach an 88% increase in passenger traffic by 2007 (2.9 million passengers visited the airport that year).  The highest airport in the United Kingdom (681ft!) is an operating base for Jet2.com and Ryanair and is served by Aer Lingus, Aurigny, easyJet, KLM, and WizzAir.  The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date 2023 airport layout, fully-reworked PBR ground poly, custom lighting, LOD optimization to ensure best performance, animated custom jetways, a high-detail ATC tower with animated air traffic controllers, detailed walkway interior, hand-placed animated horses, a detailed spotting area west of runway 14, updated signage, and more.  There’s still no information on the release date and pricing, but the product page is already up with screenshots. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflana</id>
    <title>AirfoilLabs Releases C172 NG Analog for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflana" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569cdc493dc44bf355019da_ana1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="411196"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AirfoilLabs has recently released their rendition of the Cessna C172 NG Analog for X-Plane 12, one of the most popular trainer aircraft ever produced, with 44,000 units built since its introduction in 1956.  The Cessna 172 stands as an iconic figure in aviation, often serving as the initial aircraft for many aspiring pilots. Equipped with a 175hp piston engine operating at 2400rpm, it maintains a cruising speed of 125 knots and can ascend to a maximum altitude of 13,000 feet.  AFL’s new C172 features a new 3D model built from scratch, using X-Plane 12’s brand-new flight model to provide a realistic simulation experience. The engine performance was tuned and correlated with performance tables, warranting accurate behavior under different circumstances and weather. The complete feature list follows below: New X-Plane 12 Features: 3D Model FMOD Sound Flight Model Aircraft Systems Electrical System Engine Logic Failure Management System and Scenarios Saving C172 Knowledge Base User Interface and 2D Panels Aircraft Options Checklist and Performance Ground Operations Walk Feature and QuickLook Camera with Collisions   It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $49.95 (temporary discount). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwarl</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Arlington Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwarl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569d17f4abb95f11cc0f49e_arl1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="637406"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Arlington Municipal Airport (KGKY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Arlington, Texas, with a yearly average of 151,000 passengers (as of 2006).  It’s a reliever airport for DFW and DAL and housing companies such as the Bell Helicopter division of Textron.   Unlike most US airports, KGKY doesn’t have an IATA code.  97% of the airport’s yearly operations consist of general aviation traffic, with only 3% corresponding to air taxi.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled terminal building, custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures, custom night lighting, and animated people.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.53 and requires at least 1.10 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Cristian Ionescu for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phenom</id>
    <title>Cockspur reveals their next project, the Phenom 100</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phenom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569fc0ad20d9edb4524fa12_image_2023-12-01_093018018.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1024570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur has recently published a new video on Facebook and Discord, showcasing what appears to be an almost finished Embraer Phenom 100. Cockspur is renowned for its Cessna Mustang and its latest Cessna 162. The one-and-a-half-minute video provides a quick look at the intricate details that Cockspur is known for—the avionics in the video feature the GARMIN 1000, similar to those present in the real aircraft. The video also showcases the exterior details, which look intricate based on the close-up shots. The cabin is fully modeled, as expected. Although the developer has yet to release much information regarding specific features, we can expect to receive more details on this project soon. The Embraer Phenom 100 is a part of the Phenom corporate jet brand, manufactured by Brazilian aircraft manufacturer Embraer. The Phenom 100, the smallest model in the range, is classified as a VLJ (Very Light Jet), with the larger model being the 300E. Phenom 100's first flight took place on July 26, 2008, and since then, it has brought Embraer immense success with the Phenom brand. A new configuration of the Phenom will cost you around $3 million. With over 400 built, it is one of the most popular light jets in the market. The Phenom is powered by two Prat and Whitney turbofan engines, producing 1,750lbs of thrust each. This engine configuration gives the Phenom 100 the ability to cruise at 400 knots with a maximum altitude of 14,100 feet with a range of about 1,300 NM. The Phenom has a single pilot rating thanks to many of its automated features. With its Prodigy Touch flight deck and Garmin 1000, these systems are highly streamlined to reduce pilot workload. The Phenom's BMW-designed cabin can comfortably carry up to five passengers. To see more, check out the video of the Phenom by Cockspur here. ‍ As always, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f14tom</id>
    <title>Heatblur and IndiaFoxtEcho provides F14 pricing and potential release date.</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f14tom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656a06ee7a31e43cb4e38e1d_339315414_586097866798612_8442083217038018754_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="261332"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Heatblur and IndiaFoxtEcho have provided a potential release date for the F-14 Tomcat! The much-anticipated F-14 Tomcat project update was communicated to users via the Heatblur and IndiaFoxtEcho Discord. IndiaFoxtEcho also gave a preview of the Jester toggle wheel function, which allows you to control different elements and features of the F14, departing from the usual "Tablets" seen in various other aircraft addons. According to IndiaFoxtEcho, the F-14 will be available on the Flight Simulator Marketplace (unarmed), the Heatblur store, SimMarket, Orbx, and more. The team is in its final stages, waiting for the green light from Microsoft. The wait is on for the Xbox version tests to complete, and it will likely be released alongside the PC version, which will be identical except for the radar functionality on Xbox.  The pricing and a possible release date of December 7th have been proposed for USD 34.99, with discounts for previous DCS F-14 owners. However, IndiaFoxtEcho has indicated issues with the system, which currently keeping the discounts unconfirmed at this time.  As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulator news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vssy</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases KMSY For X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vssy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656b85d7ad9b3d899545267a_m5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1211252"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Scenery developer Verticalsim has released an updated version of their Louis Armstrong New Orleans International Airport (KMSY). The release is an update to the X-Plane 11 version of the same sceneries and includes up to date airport layout.  Louis Armstrong New Orleans International Airport is located in Kenner, Louisiana, just over 10 miles west of downtown New Orleans. The airport features two runways with the longer of the two being over 10,000 feet long. The airport sees nearly 12 million passengers and over 100,000 aircraft operations each year.  The X-Plane 12 release of Verticalsim’s KSMY features 2k UHD PBR texturing, animated ground traffic (via the Groundtraffic plug-in, colour graded Satellite imagery, SAM jetways, and native X-plane weathermaps. Those who previously purchased the X-Plane 11 version of KMSY can enjoy the new one for just $4.99 USD on both the X-Plane.org store as well as VerticalSim’s website. To stay updated on all things flight sim be sure to keep your eye on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jffkf1</id>
    <title>Just Flight Posts Fokker F70/F100 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jffkf1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656b8cc21ad6b55384be0a08_5_F100_Ext_5_MzSZJ3QCJ.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="79790"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Coming shortly after their recently released Avro Vulcan, Just Flight has posted an update on their website regarding their upcoming Fokker F100 and F70. The development update mainly highlights the door and cabin configurations available for the aircraft at launch. The Fokker F100 and F70 were developed from the earlier F28. Both airframes offer a larger cabin and payload than the F28 and updated avionics. The F100/F70 features 2 Rolls-Royce Tay Mk 650-15 or Mk 620-15 Turbofan engines. The larger of the two engine options has a thrust output of 67 kN which allows the F100 to cruise at Mach 0.77 for a maximum range of over 1700nm. The upcoming F100/F70 will include 4 different door options as well as an interior that is customizable through the included paint kit. Just Flight also teased a fan favourite feature from the F28 that will be making another appearance, and that is the music reproducer panel that allows users to use custom boarding music for the enjoyment of their virtual passengers. The update goes on to state that moving forward they will be working on fine-tuning the artwork of the aircraft as well as improving other things such as cabin lighting. Currently Just Flight have not revealed a planned release date or pricing. Be sure to keep an eye on Threshold to stay up to date on all your flight sim news!  </summary>
    <published>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
