<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-30T18:21:06.520716+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrda2</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Releases Diamond DA20-C1 Eclipse for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrda2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e5313b1e6ad5bfe58d9196_da20.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="391112"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimSolutions has recently released their Diamond DA20-C1 Eclipse for Microsoft Flight Simulator, marking their debut on the platform with a high-detail rendition of the popular two-seater introduced in 1992.   The Eclipse is the improved version of the DA20 Katana, with rear windows, better visibility, and improved equipment aimed at private use.  ‍ It’s powered by a 125 hp Continental IO-240-B, cruising at up to 138 knots with a range of 629 nautical miles with a 30-minute reserve. ‍ The aircraft add-on features an accurate 3D model, 4K PBR textures, a GTX 327 transponder, a DAVTRON clock system, a checklist, a flight model based on real-world experience, and more.  ‍  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.77, requiring at least 992 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fl2jej</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Jeju International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fl2jej" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e59790b1ee2a82591ecbf4_jej1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="729523"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Jeju International Airport (RKPC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in South Korea with a yearly average of 31.3 million passengers.  Built as Jeju Airfield during the Japanese colonial period by the hands of enslaved Jeju locals, then taken over by the US Army after World War 2 and used by the Korean government as an extermination field during the uprising, where an estimated 700 Jeju citizens were shot to death (known in South Korea as the April 3 massacre, or Jeju uprising. The total death toll surpasses 30,000) and buried. Only 237 of the bodies were found during a full-scale excavation in 2007.  The airport was built in the late 1960s as part of a governmental effort to develop the island’s tourism. It was inaugurated in 1968 with a 1,200-meter runway and a modestly sized terminal, initially aimed at domestic operations. Expansion work was only conducted in the 80s and 90s, lengthening the runway and upgrading the terminal facilities to accommodate larger aircraft and more passenger traffic. ‍ The international status was granted in 2002 with the construction of an international terminal, kickstarting a massive growth in passenger traffic (from a 9 million/year average to almost 20 million within a decade). The numbers peaked in 2019 at 31 million passengers.  It’s a hub for Jeju Air and a focus city for Air Busan, Asiana Airlines, Eastar Jet, Jin Air, Korean Air, and T’way Air. Visitors include China Eastern, China Southern, HK Express, Scoot, Spring Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan.  ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, highly-detailed models, performance-friendly optimization, and an official GSX profile.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $21.88, requiring at least 8.21 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ugdf16</id>
    <title>The return of the beloved Falcon series!</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ugdf16" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e618643273e84c6e077ec5_falcon.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="278774"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The return of a classic, MicroProse announces, Falcon 5.0 after requiring the Falcon brand. Recently, MicroProse announced the successor to the Falcon series, Falcon 5.0. The Falcon series was one of the most sophisticated combat simulators of its time. Falcon 4.0 was released over 25 years ago and focused on a detailed, accurate simulation of the F-16 Falcon. Some rated it as close to 90% system accuracy. MicroProse was ahead of its time by coding the complexity of the "Vipers" flight systems, avionics, flight characteristics, and PvE AI combat. The simulator campaign is based on a South Korean/North Korean conflict with allied forces such as the United States providing military support and aiding South Korean defenses against invading North Korean aggression. You take on the role of a Viper Pilot under the United States Air Force. You are tasked with air-to-ground bombing runs, holding air space superiority, and more. ‍ Starting with training, learn the nitty-gritty of jet combat and F16-specific combat maneuvers amidst dogfight scenarios. Learn armed tactics, weapon behaviors, and characteristics through 30 training missions. I wouldn't skip over them! Ahead of its time was a pilot rating system based on detailed kill reports and kill quality. The player's kills and actions directly affect the path of the game as well. In addition, Falcon 4.0 supported online multiplayer PVP dogfights, incredible for its time. Falcon 4.0 claimed some of the best reviews of any combat flight simulator for its time. The simulator reaches back to 1987, with Falcon 4.0 Allied Force as the most recent iteration. June 2005.  Hopefully, MicroProse will give us that ringed flight ops manual. ‍  ‍ PC-Pilot Magazine's Derek Davis interviews David Laettie of MicroProse covering the push and goal to get Micropose back into Flight Simulation. The interview has exclusive screenshots of a new aircraft addition to the Viper's simulation. Derek Davis also inquired about other flight simulation projects during the interview. Access to the article and exclusive cockpit shots of both aircraft can be viewed on PC-Pilot with a subscription.  ‍ Falcon is still alive at the hands of Benchmark Sims Team akaBMS . BMS has worked to keep the title current with today's technology and modern software capabilities. MicroProse thanked the team for keeping the simulation alive through the years. It looks like an exciting acknowledgment and upcoming teamwork to bring the best out of Falcon 5! Benchmark Sims Team announced on Twitter that they have resolved the intellectual property subject with Falcon 4.0 and will continue development with minimal disruption. A highlighted version of the contractual agreement can be found on BMS's forum post.  ‍ ‍ Falcon 5.0 is expected to be on the markets before the holiday season.  ‍ Stay tuned and expect more from Threshold for more information covering this evolving project! ‍  ‍  ‍  ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a300ini</id>
    <title>The Official IniBuilds summer event with A300 progress details.</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a300ini" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e63f0d7679ac0d760c9893_image.png.f0a0792817c4133a8cd65d50db72e3ac.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2540029"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Official IniBuilds summer event starts tomorrow! iniBuilds reminds you to have your iniManager up to date for downloads. Each day IniBuilds will feature discounts for 24 hours only on new products by iniBuilds or a production partner. Expect the debut of two new partners as well! Event dates are August 24 at 5 pm BST and new deals daily at 5 pm BST. The Grand finale product announcement is on August 28! ‍ IniBuilds sheds light on the build progress of the highly-anticipated A300-600 since its debut at FSExpo last June. Their forum post showcases high-res images of details like rivets, screws, and panel gaps, as well as the usage of high-resolution decal sheets. The photos highlight the distinctive work the team is doing. ‍ IniBuilds showcased the recreated animations of A300's cargo door, as well as the fully operational nose gear model. They also discussed the systems and flight model.    “In the last update we provided, we talking about some of the key features this product is going to include such as comprehensive systems simulation, realistic flight model, full ACARS, CPDLC simulation, and a whole lot more! “ ‍  IniBuilds used the latest simulation techniques within the flight model CFD simulations flowing over the wings tail ending by reinjection into the A300 fight model. Improved ground effect using CFD technology, accurate drag, and engine thrust simulations throughout the flight envelope. Lastly mentioned was the complete overhaul and rebuild of the autopilot systems. Key highlights are new operating flight directors providing smoother operations and a new auto land system with LOC and GS laws. LVL Change V/S will be much smoother in the Auto Pilot handling overhaul. Improved core system logic and a new LNAV system improve with processing more complex SIDs and STARs.  The pricing/release timeline shapes up like this.  “To those of you, who were concerned about the PW variant; I have some good news. We are going to introduce this into the package for FREE.  Stage 1 Release: GE Freighter &amp; Passenger (v1.00) before the end of 2023. 🥳GE FreighterGE PAX Stage 1 Hotfix before the end of 2023 (free update) 🔥 Stage 2 Update: PW Update, IDC addition &amp; Bug fixes early 2024 (free update) 🥳PW FreighterPW PAXIDC Panel update in cockpit: This is the modern radio panel option, whereby we will simulate full CPDLC &amp; ACARS via Hoppie along with the modern radio unit function. Stage 3 Update: EPIC Mod variant (paid expansion) sometime 2024 🔥GE/ PW Freighter w/ EPIC Mod Cockpit w/IDCWe hope you are excited for iniBuilds Summer Surprises &amp; the upcoming iniBuilds A300-600 🥳 💖 ‍ ‍ As always stay tuned to Threshold for more updates on the IniBuilds Summer event and A300 news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mscciv</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update IV: Western Europe for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mscciv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e66e1206ef14ecb6def4a1_cityupdate.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="832365"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released a new city update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding five Western European cities (Annemasse, Geneva, Ghent, Luxembourg City, and Rotterdam) and one airport (Cologne-Bonn Airport).  ‍ Annemasse is a commune in the French Alps with 5 square kilometers of total area and 36,250 residents, making it the second most populous commune after Annecy. ‍ Geneva is Switzerland's second most populous city, with 201,818 inhabitants as of 2018. It's situated in the country's southwest, near the French border.  ‍ Ghent is a city in the Flemish region of Belgium (the Dutch-speaking part), the third largest in the country with 265,086 inhabitants, only behind Brussels and Antwerp.  ‍ Luxembourg City is the capital of Luxembourg, lying at the heart of Western Europe, with a population of 132,778 people. It has the highest per capita GDP in the world as of 2022. ‍ Rotterdam is the second largest city in the Netherlands, situated in the province of Zuid-Holland. The municipality has 664,311 inhabitants, but the metropolitan area is nearing 2.5 million. ‍ Cologne-Bonn Airport (EDDK) serves the city of Köln in Germany with a yearly average of 9 million passengers. It's the seventh-largest passenger airport in Germany. ‍  The update is available right now for free on PC and Xbox. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vssvij</id>
    <title>Velocity Studios Releases Vijayawada Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vssvij" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e674849294960b0d11df03_vij1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3148728"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Velocity Studios has recently released their rendition of Vijayawada Airport (VOBZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Vijayawada with a yearly average of 966,383 passengers. ‍ Built as an army base during World War 2, it was later converted into a civilian airport. Scheduled services were only introduced in 2003, with Air Deccan’s route to Hyderabad. Kingfish followed suit until 2011, when Air India, SpiceJet, and Jet Airways also introduced daily flights (canceled not soon after). ‍ A new terminal was built in 2017, allowing a yearly average of two million passengers. International status was granted a few months later, with the inaugural international flight a year later, an Indigo flight to Singapore Changi.  ‍ Air India, Air India Express, Alliance Air, and IndiGo currently serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, dynamic night lighting, custom ground markings, realistic navigation aids, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.59, temporarily discounted from its full price of $11.96. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxid3</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Idaho’s Deadly 3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxid3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e7049e4b2f6fb91ac11e5c_idaho.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="480078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their newest scenery pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including three challenging airstrips in Idaho and a bonus makeshift helicopter area with a STOL landing zone.  The “Deadly 3” are three famous - and challenging - strips in Idaho, known for requiring a lot of technique to get the landings right. Dewey Moore, Simonds, and Vines Airstrip are as barebones as a landing strip can get, with no basic infrastructure, making it ideal for hardcore camping. ‍ Dewey Moore, the first of the airstrips, is located on the north side of Big Creek, 19 miles west of the junction of Big Creek and the Middle Fork of the Salmon River, with a 700 ft long gravel runway at 4,494 feet above sea level. It’s recommended for highly experienced mountain pilots only (in real life). ‍ Simonds is a very difficult airstrip located on Monumental Creek, close to where it joins up with Big Creek. It’s often used for guided hunting trips and has no infrastructure, meaning pilots should bring tie-downs and camping equipment. It has a 900 ft long gravel runway, and pilots are instructed to watch for traffic from the nearby Monumental Ranch private airstrip. ‍ Vines Airstrip is located on the south side of Big Creek Canyon, two miles west of Cabin Creek Airstrip, close to where Big Creek joins into the Middle Fork of the Salmon River. It’s a 1,100 ft gravel strip at 4,110 feet above sea level, and pilots are instructed to land on runway 27 and take off from runway 9. Real-life recommendations include instructions on short field operations, and pilots are generally advised to follow Big Creek to avoid trees on final approach and watch their airspeed very carefully as a 10 percent increase in approach speed means a 21% increase in landing distance.  ‍ The three strips are a short flight away from 85U Soldier Bar and McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL), both developed by Milo Taylor, the author of Idaho’s Deadly 3. His new creation features substantial terraforming work, custom animations, custom vegetation, and much more. The complete feature list for the package follows below:  ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.91, requiring at least 697.99 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ahlanc</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Lancaster Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ahlanc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e7791e74375c96a60fc797_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="452383"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aeroplane Heaven has made an announcement regarding the development of their upcoming Avro Lancaster for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Lancaster project was originally announced back in 2022, it has been a main focus for the company since the release of their DC-3 for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 40th anniversary update.  ‍ ‍ ‍ The Avro Lancaster was a highly significant aircraft developed for the RAF during World War Two. It proudly served not only the Royal Air Force but also the Royal Australian Air Force and the Royal Canadian Air Force. The Lancaster was designed with a spacious bomb bay, allowing it to accommodate the largest bombs utilized by the RAF. It is most notable for its pivotal role in Operation Chastise, better known as the Dam Busters raid. In this operation, British flight crews skillfully dropped cylindrical-shaped bombs, ingeniously spinning them before release, to have the bombs skip across the water to effectively destroy the Möhne and Edersee dams. ‍ ‍ The development update, which was posted to Aeroplane Heaven's Facebook page, states that the modeling and textures are nearing completion, however, there's been no announcement regarding a release date other than that it's expected to be released in the second half of 2023. Aeroplane Heaven has stated they're also working on "some cool coding ideas to bring extra functionality" to the aircraft, though it hasn't been announced what these extra functionalities may include. Aeroplane Heaven has also hinted at the possibility of additional model variants (Mk I, Mk III, etc.) if "time allows". The developer has however confirmed that the aircraft will include custom flight crew models that feature period-correct uniforms and equipment.  ‍ ‍ Threshold is excited to bring you this and other updates for your favorite simulators! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hccr</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Corpus Christi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hccr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e7dcd796fdf5a42c9bd7a7_corpus.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="393446"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Corpus Christi International Airport (KCRP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Corpus Christi, Texas, with a yearly average of 645,000 passengers.  The airport was built in 1960, replacing Cliff Maus Airport, which formerly served the city (since 1928). Cliff Maus couldn’t grow any further, restricted to its 400-acre area, rapidly becoming a problem as the demand for air travel increased. In October 1956, voters approved 3.2 million USD in funding to build a new 1,800-acre airport.   A new terminal was opened in 2002, with six gates, 15,300 square meters of built area, and a modern infrastructure to meet the new demands.   American Eagle, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express currently serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, highly detailed buildings, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $9.53, requiring at least 2.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/100itu</id>
    <title>OneHundred Simulations Releases Itumbiara Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/100itu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e92638daa1adf5f3dfcc5c_sbit.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="663877"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. OneHundred Simulations has recently released their rendition of Itumbiara Airport (SBIT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Itumbiara, Goias, Brazil.  ‍ It’s mostly a general aviation airport, serving the local farmers and UHI (Usina Hidrelétrica de Itumbiara, a hydroelectric plant) personnel. The plant - depicted in the add-on - was built in 1974 and produces 2.082 mW, serving most of Goiás, Minas Gerais, and Mato Grosso do Sul.  ‍ With a 1,752-meter runway at 1651 ft above sea level, it can accommodate most general aviation aircraft and even medium-sized jets.  ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models, custom ground markings, realistic ground layout, PBR texturing, and custom terraforming for the hydroelectric plant. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.58, requiring at least 36.74 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdcmf</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases H. A. Clark Memorial Field for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdcmf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ea750558072a84ea51b34d_1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="913390"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Burning Blue Design has recently released their rendition of H. A. Clark Memorial Field (KCMR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use general aviation airport in Williams, Arizona, with a yearly average of 16,100 operations. ‍ It was built in 1925 as Webber Field, yet left to deteriorate during its initial years until the advent of the Civilian Pilot Training Program in 1939, which helped to rekindle the interest in aviation in Williams. On the other hand, the airfield's development predated the increased interest, with work starting in 1935, followed by a further $140000 investment in 1940 from the Civil Aeronautics Board. ‍ The many upgrades eventually drew the attention of the US Army, which used the field from 1942 to train cadets. Seven army instructors were stationed there during that period, training 30 people. ‍ Its 1,830-meter-long runway might seem long, but the aerodrome’s elevation (6,691ft) makes it somewhat challenging.    The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airfield, with over 120 custom objects, accurate taxiways, a high-detail terminal building interior, detailed hangars with interiors, custom flags and windsocks, custom night lighting, and color-corrected ground textures.  It’s available on Burning Blue Design’s website for roughly $13.78. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwsdun</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Dunedin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwsdun" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ebd612d4a58c326e647516_dunedin.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="310402"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios has recently released their rendition of Dunedin Airport (NZDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the entire region of Otago with a yearly average of 1 million passengers, making it the third busiest airport in the country.  The airport was built in 1962 to replace Dunedin’s former airfield (Taieri), which was deemed unfeasible to expand in the future. Commercial service started that same year with NZAC and their Fokkers.   The terminal was upgraded in the late 60s-early 70s with automatic sliding doors, a new mezzanine floor, and an aircraft viewing deck.  It’s currently served by Air New Zealand and Jetstar, with flights to Auckland, Christchurch, and Wellington (Jetstar only flies to Auckland).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with updated aerial imagery, custom ground poly, hand-made animated jetways, HD PBR models, a basic interior for the terminal and hangars, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $7.54, requiring at least 4.05 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddrpae</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Paine Field Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddrpae" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ed223ff3e2806961377355_pae.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1084667"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Seattle Paine Field International Airport (KPAE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Snohomish County, Washington, with a yearly average of 377,000 passengers.  The airport was built in 1936 as a Works Program Administration project, envisioned as a job creator, economic booster in the region, and one of the future “super airports” in the United States. ‍ It was taken over by the Army during World War 2, only to be transferred back to Snohomish County in 1948, with the Air Force still maintaining various Air Defense Command units at the airport as military tenants. ‍ The “super airport” plans were revived briefly because the Korean War forced the airport to become an air force base. It was only returned to civilian use in the 1960s.  ‍ Boeing chose Paine Field as the construction and testing site for their Boeing 747 project in 1966, where it also made its first landing three years later. ‍ After years of debate about using the airport for commercial service, they finally reached an agreement, with a passenger terminal being constructed in 2017, featuring 30,000 square meters of area, two gates, and the ability to handle up to 16 flights a day. ‍ It’s served by Alaska Airlines (Anchorage, Las Vegas, Los Angeles, Orange County, Phoenix–Sky Harbor, San Diego, San Francisco) and Kenmore Air (Eastsound, Friday Harbor, Victoria). ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with the Boeing factory and their 777X production line (fully animated), performance-friendly optimization, custom animated people and vehicles, GSX Pro compatibility (using Cartayna files), modeled interiors, custom jetways, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $24.86, requiring at least 1.40 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inihnl</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Honolulu International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inihnl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ed2ae391d63c813e891f12_hnl.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="816786"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Daniel K. Inouye International Airport (PHNL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Hawaiian city of Honolulu with a yearly average of 18.3 million passengers.  It opened in March 1927 as John Rodgers Airport, after a WW1 naval officer. It was the first full airport in Hawaii, as they only had landing strips, fields, and seaplane docks beforehand. ‍ After Pearl Harbor, the airport became Naval Air Station Honolulu, with a control tower built by the Navy, a terminal building, and passenger traffic was even allowed during daylight hours. It was returned right after the war, in 1946.  ‍ It was renamed “Honolulu Airport” in 1947 and internationalized in 1951. It became an important stop for many transpacific flights, rapidly becoming one of the busiest airports in the United States. It even had the longest runway in the world (back in 1953), at a then-impressive 3,992 meters.  The original terminal was replaced by a new one in 1962, which was eventually modernized in the 70s by Vladimir Ossipoff, who entirely remodeled the terminal and added new concourses.  In the early 2000s, Ossipoff’s modern terminal was not so modern anymore, and the “forward-looking” and flexible design was showing its age, facing the challenges of the modern standards of accessibility, comfort, and security. In response, the government unveiled a 2.3 billion USD modernization program for all Hawaiian airports over 12 years, with 1.7 billion for Honolulu alone.  Many infrastructure upgrades were made during that period, and a new concourse was built between 2018-2021, featuring gates that can easily accommodate widebody jets, making life easier for Hawaiian Airlines passengers that will no longer have to walk between terminals for overseas departures.  The current layout sports three terminals, with 54 jetways and six stands. Terminal 1 has 25 jetways, 2 has 29, and 3 has parking stands.   It’s a hub for Aloha Air Cargo, Asia Pacific Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, Mokulele Airlines, Transair, and Corporate Air. The visitors’ list includes Air Canada, Air New Zealand, Alaska Airlines, Asiana Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Fiji Airways, Japan Airlines, Jetstar, Korean Air, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, WestJet, and Zipair Tokyo. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout,  hand-made textures, high-quality surrounding POIs, true-to-life landside recreation, an official GSX profile, dynamic lighting, and a detailed terminal interior.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $25.17, requiring at least 5.36 GB of free hard disk space. 10% of all revenue will be donated to the American Red Cross for the Hawaiian Wildfire crisis.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs2cre</id>
    <title>FS2Crew has announced all MSFS products are updated as of today.</title>
    <updated>2023-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs2cre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c6dea0678309534b81c1b3_fs2c.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="91424"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ FS2Crew specializes in creating highly immersive software that enables users to simulate the standard operating procedures (SOP) used by airlines. Their software is designed for use with Microsoft Flight Simulator, Prepar3D, and FSX, providing users with a realistic and engaging experience. With FS2Crew, users can experience what it's like to operate an airline and gain valuable insight into the SOP processes used in the aviation industry.  Today, via FS2Crew's official press release. ‍ The team has announced that all FS2Crew MSFS products are updated as of today (PMDG 737, Fenix Airbus, CRJ, RAAS, Pushback Express and Leonardo Maddog). Significant changes were made with a groundbreaking "human-animated FO" for the FBW A32NX.  FS2Crew has fulfilled your requests for a female First Officer figure choice; she's activated by selecting a female voice within the settings.FS2Crew has significantly expedited the FO flows, allowing the FO to perform much faster than before.  ‍ For more information on changes made by Fs2Crew, please visit their website, where an official change log is published. To update your MSFS FS2Crew product, please use the Product Manager software located here. FS2Crew can be purchased here for €14.99 or $16.20 discounted from €19.99/ $21.61. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and releases! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tomcat</id>
    <title>Heatblur has provided some updates regarding the highly anticipated F-14 Tomcat.</title>
    <updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tomcat" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ee99172a8f0bfca9726c15_326002749_1538428839969569_2182637673520684022_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="326302"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ Heatblur Simulations has recently shared a brief update regarding the development progress of the F-14 Tomcat for Microsoft Flight Simulator. According to Heatblur, the alpha testing phase commenced last month in collaboration with Indiafoxtang, and the beta testing phase is progressing rapidly. This promising development indicates the Tomcat is drawing closer to its anticipated release.  Heatblur has dedicated their decades of research and Tomcat expertise to the MSFS version, building on its successful par with the F14 in DCS. The team acknowledges that the MSFS simulation engine presents unique challenges but remains ahead of the curve with their partnership with IFE. Additionally, they have not forgotten about their DCS users and have included many new details, including artwork and boarding ladders, that will be incorporated into the DCS F-14. Overall, the progress of the F-14 Tomcat for Microsoft Flight Simulator looks very promising, and Heatblur Simulations continues to demonstrate its commitment to the progression of simulating the F-14 Tomcat! Check out the video here on their Facebook page! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
