<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-01-15T18:28:06.481054+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrpvi</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases Iloilo International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrpvi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/677134fce3f78e3a0a8f9c6b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airwil Sceneries has recently launched its latest scenery for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12: Iloilo International Airport (RPVI). As the fifth busiest airport in the Philippines, Iloilo International Airport welcomes over 2.3 million passengers each year. Commercial traffic at the airport began in 2007, serving as a replacement for the former Mandurriao Airport. Although it did not operate as a commercial airport before 2007, the site of the current airport has been involved in various aviation activities since 1942. During World War II, an airfield was constructed in 1942. After the war, this airfield gradually transitioned into a civilian airport, accommodating both military and general aviation traffic. Over the years, the airport underwent several changes and construction projects before commencing commercial operations in 2007. ‍ Today, the airport serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific and PAL Express, offering flights to destinations including Cebu, Manila, Singapore, Hong Kong, and many others. Airwil Sceneries' depiction of the airport boasts numerous features, including hundreds of custom-made objects, a modeled interior of the passenger terminal, a modeled interior of the control tower, and more. The scenery requires 1.99 GB of storage space and is now available at SimMarket for approximately $11.46. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1213</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12.1.3 Released</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1213"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/677405a51140e8830db3ab17_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane 12.1.3 has just been fully released, one and a half months after the first beta release. ATC, the user interface, and sounds are among the most improved aspects of this update. ‍ ATC and sounds According to Laminar Research, the ATC system has undergone a significant overhaul. Radio communications have become much more realistic, including features such as radio checks, clearance requests, and VFR and IFR procedures that support SIDs and STARs. Additionally, the default navigation data has been updated to AIRAC 2306. Users can now copy and paste routes from tools like Navigraph and Simbrief directly into their flight plans. They can also request alternative SIDs and STARs, ask for altitude exceptions, and receive per-turn instructions. Furthermore, X-Plane can now be configured to output ATC audio to a separate audio device. Weather A full weather update is planned, but some changes have been made in version 12.1.3. Issues with sudden altitude and pressure changes during mid flight have been resolved. Additionally, improvements have been made to cloud visualization and interpreting METAR information and wind data. Errors related to the NEXRAD display for document number G1000 have also been addressed. User interface The flight configuration menu now provides more detailed information about gates and ramps. Additionally, the map highlights active runways and shows taxi routes. Several smaller improvements have also been made, including fixing rendering stutters that occurred when displaying UI elements and ensuring that VR windows maintain their positions. X-Plane identity In preparation for the X-Plane Store, the X-Plane identity feature has been released in early access. This feature allows you to link your purchase key to your X-Plane identity. Once you complete the migration, your X-Plane key will no longer be necessary; a simple login will grant you access to the simulator. In the future, purchases from the X-Plane Store will be linked to your X-Plane identity. According to Laminar Research, migrating to X-Plane identity is entirely optional. Several other changes have been implemented, including a handcrafted overhaul of The Downtown Manhattan Heliport (KJRB) and enhancements to the default A330, Cirrus SR22, and Cessna Citation X. ‍ The full list of changes can be found on X-Plane.com. ‍ Version 12.1.4, “The Flightlessons Update” is next up. ‍ For more on that, and more, stay tuned to Threshold. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksdus</id>
    <title>MK Studios Publishes Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksdus"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6775dc412102eff05c4cba15_dus2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios recently published a short development update concerning the status of their ongoing projects, future products, MSFS 2024 product compatibility, and finally, their new scenery in the Pacific Northwest. Their upcoming rendition of Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) is coming along nicely, with a late Q1 2025 release date in mind. MK Studios has also shared four work-in-progress screenshots as an extra appetizer.  Their next project, briefly mentioned last time as an airport in the Pacific Northwest, will be Seattle-Tacoma International (KSEA) in the United States.  Helsinki and Rome Rebooted—the new name for their V2s—are also progressing nicely and will be totally focused once they get Düsseldorf and Seattle out of the way. In the meantime, they are collecting pictures and data, and any help is greatly appreciated. ‍ Regarding the new simulation platform, MK Studios is working on compatibility issues. Montreal and Dublin will soon receive an update that includes major fixes and improvements, with other airports to be updated in the coming months. They are trying to find a good balance between updating pre-existing products and developing new stuff, which is said to be a tricky task due to how unstable the new sim and SDK can be at times. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgflo</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Releases Florianópolis International Airport V3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgflo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6775e6cdcfe1f86fcb489621_floripa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Brazil Land Games has recently released its rendition of Florianópolis —Hercílio Luz International Airport (SBFL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 (MSFS 2024 compatible). The airport serves Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 3.9 million passengers. It was initially built in the late 1920s as Campeche Field, and the French aviators of the Compagnie Générale Aéropostale used it for their operations to and from Florianópolis. In the 1940s, a proper runway and basic infrastructure (apron, control tower, and passenger terminal) were built. As the airport was shared with the Brazilian Air Force, some military infrastructure improvements were also made. The passenger terminal was rebuilt and modernized in the early 1950s and remained in use until the 1970s when a brand-new terminal was opened. The terminal was then expanded in the late 1980s and in 2000, reaching a total area of 8,700 square meters.  In early 2017, Flughafen Zurich AG won a concession to operate and expand the airport, which kicked off shortly after in 2018. This included the construction of a new terminal with fourteen new gates, costing 570 million BRL. At the time, the main runway was also extended by 100 meters. It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Flybondi, Gol Linhas Aéreas, JetSmart Argentina, JetSmart Chile, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Chile, Paranair, Sky Airline, Sky Airline Peru, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, custom landside buildings, a custom terminal interior, and more. It’s available on their website for roughly $8. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmksfb</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Orlando Sanford International Airport for MSFS 20/24 and X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmksfb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6776d2394c5864217e932caa_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Taimodels has recently released its rendition of Orlando Sanford International Airport (KSFB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, as well as X-Plane 12. Located in Sanford, Florida, this airport serves as the secondary commercial airport for the Orlando area, alongside Orlando International Airport. Last year, nearly 3 million passengers traveled through the airport. The airport was established as Naval Air Station Sanford in 1942 and was utilized by the United States Navy until 1969. That year, the city of Sanford took control of the airport and renamed it Sanford Airport. For the next 25 years, the airport was primarily used for general aviation. In the mid-1990s, a new passenger terminal designed for jet airliners was constructed, marking the beginning of commercial flights to the airport. Since then, the airport has undergone various improvements. Today, Allegiant Air operates the majority of flights from the airport, offering destinations across the country. Both the MSFS 20/24 and X-Plane 12 versions of Orlando Sanford International Airport feature an accurate depiction of the airport, realistic buildings, and a variety of other features to make it as realistic as possible. The MSFS 20/24 version of the airport is priced at roughly $17.95 on SimMarket, while the X-Plane 12 version is available on SimMarket for approximately $19.49.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cows40</id>
    <title>COWS Previews DA-40XLS for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cows40"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6777ba733775d04f1b4677f9_IMG_0221.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS recently previewed its upcoming aircraft on their YouTube channel - the DA40-XLS. This marks the second aircraft they have developed, after the DA42. The Austrian single-engine light aircraft is one of the most popular trainer aircraft, with over 2,200 DA40s produced. Based on the also successful DA20, Diamond Aircraft Industries designed a four-seat prototype, named DA40 Diamond Star.  The COWS DA40 is based on the XLS version. Considered as a “deluxe” version, it features a G1000 glass cockpit with WAAS (Wide Area Augmentation System) capability, Garmin GDL69 datalink, and a TAS traffic alert system.  Their rendition will feature custom-designed systems with interactive circuit breakers, EIS, and custom cylinder simulation. While the price and the release date for X-Plane 12 are still undisclosed, the developers have mentioned that they are targeting the release of FS20 and FS24 in early 2025.  As always, Threshold will keep you updated with any news and updates about the COWS DA40-XLS! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/in350l</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases Liveries Launching with their A350</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/in350l"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6778e2ab7a1ff80d75622940_Skjermbilde_2025-01-03_223440.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iniBuilds has released another teaser for their upcoming A350, showcasing the liveries that will be included at launch through a video shared on their social media. The video showcases six liveries belonging to airlines from around the world: Delta, Japan Airlines, Scandinavian Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, Lufthansa, and Emirates. This is in addition to Cathay Pacific, Iberia, and British Airways, which have also been teased previously. Highly anticipated, the iniBuilds A350 aims to become the first study-level A350 in Microsoft Flight Simulator. According to iniBuilds, the aircraft will feature detailed 3D cabins, a comprehensive flight attendant panel, custom terrain radar, and intricate system simulation. It also includes Navigraph integration, SimBrief import, complex maintenance simulation, and a multitude of failures and emergency situations. ‍ The aircraft was originally scheduled for release in 2024, but its launch has been postponed to 2025 to ensure a "fantastic product at launch." Additionally, the aircraft will be available for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and 2020, despite it being initially planned as an exclusive for the 2024 version. IniBuilds cited stability issues with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 as the reason for this decision. Stay tuned to Threshold for additional updates on the iniBuilds A350, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/headwind-simulations-previews-custom-cockpit-for-airbus-a339x</id>
    <title>Headwind Simulations Previews Custom Cockpit for Airbus A339X</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/headwind-simulations-previews-custom-cockpit-for-airbus-a339x"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6778e366f5752188801a943d_Skjermbilde_2025-01-04_023619.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Freeware developer Headwind Simulations has recently showcased a preview of the upcoming custom cockpit for its A339X project, in a video posted on the AviatorCro YouTube channel. Until now, the aircraft has had a cockpit based on the FlyByWire A32NX [...] According to Headwind, the footage presented does not feature a completely new model or a full A330 cockpit; however, it represents a significant improvement in quality. Several changes are immediately apparent, with the design and geometry of the main panel standing out as the most notable. It is no longer a "hybrid" between an A320 and an A330. Additionally, a third Multi-Function Control Display Unit (MCDU) has been added, and lighting controls have been fully integrated. Some systems have also been improved, such as adding the "north reference" feature, which allows for switching navigational reference from magnetic to true north. This update is Phase 1 and will not include a redesigned overhead panel, as that will be part of Phase 2. Headwind Simulations has also indicated that Phase 2 will be released once the necessary systems are in place.  The update is scheduled for release in January 2025 and will be exclusive to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 for the time being. ‍ For additional updates on the Headwind Simulations A339X, and more, stay tuned to Threshold.  Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeda20</id>
    <title>Aerobask Releases Diamond DA20 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeda20"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/677eface2fec9895be78714f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerobask has recently launched its version of the Diamond DA20 for X-Plane 12. This small two-seat aircraft is now available for flight simulation enthusiasts looking to expand their general aviation options in the X-Plane 12 hangar. The Diamond DA20 is a Canadian-built aircraft that originated from the Austrian-built DV20. It is manufactured by Diamond Aircraft. Over 1,000 DA20s have been produced, and production is still ongoing. The DA20 serves as the predecessor to the larger Diamond DA40. This aircraft is utilized for both civilian and military purposes and is particularly popular among flight schools around the world, where it is used to train future pilots. Aerobask's version of the DA20 features a 3D cockpit, PBR textures, a flight model by X-Aerodynamics, custom dual Dynon SkyView Touch, Synthetic Vision, a full FMOD environment, windshield effects, and more. The newly released Diamond DA20 is now available at the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $34.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/akdupd</id>
    <title>AKD Studio Updates GLF550 and GLF650</title>
    <updated>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/akdupd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678034ce29020b7a799c59d2_GLF650ER_AKD%20-%202024-11-07%2021.09.37.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AKD Studios has released the first update of the year for its whole lineup. The v2.21 for GLF550 and v1.02 for GLF650 improve engine performance and MCDU, along with many bug fixes. The update introduced the new SASL (3.18.0), engine start-up times, and external light improvements for both aircraft, while the 650 received interactive window shades in the passenger cabin, as well as the option to store the RAT. The bug-fixing part brought in various fixes for the MCDU, logic improvements for TCAS, AP, and air condition temperature management. The full changelog is as follows: • Added option to stow the RAT(use option in the Menu)(XP11/XP12) - GLF650 ONLY • Added windows shades in the cabin (XP11/XP12) - GLF650 ONLY  • Mapped flight number in MCDU to x-plane dataref "sim/cockpit2/radios/actuators/flight_id"(XP12/XP11)  • Added improvements to Engines Start-UP time(XP11/XP12)  • Added improvements to external lights(XP11/XP12) • Updated SASL to 3.18.0(XP12/XP11)  Fixed:  • Fixed Map line disappears when proceeding to a waypoint with a holding pattern(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed MCDU Flight plan list page (Part of the text not visible on the screen)(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed MCDU HOLD page sometimes not working in XP11(XP11) • Fixed MCDU "Check IRS Position" msg bug(XP11/XP12)  • Improved logic for changing from IAS to MACH(XP12/XP11) • Fixed Overspeed sound and Stall warning(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed minor bugs with air-cond temperature logic(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed LAT/LONG waypoints entering(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed display of N2/N1 on EICAS(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed FMOD clicking sound bug(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed Custom TCAS logic bugs(XP11/XP12)  • Fixed Minor bugs(XP12/XP11) The update can be downloaded via the Skunkcrafts updater, or downloaded from the X-Plane.org store. The GLF business jets are available for purchase at the X-Plane.org store for $44.95. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdtro</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases Troll Airfield for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdtro"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6781d8ab03eaea950555458b_troll1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Colombian Virtual Design recently released their rendition of Troll Airfield (ENOE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which serves the homonymous Norwegian Research Station in Antarctica. Opened in 2005, the airfield was purpose-built to serve as the center of the Dronning Maud Land Air Network (DROMLAN), which is essentially a multinational cooperation using Troll as a hub to provide intercontinental service to Antarctica, supporting up to long-range planes such as the 767. With a 3,000-meter-long ice runway and no infrastructure, it can only operate under visual flight rules. The airport itself doesn’t have any buildings or structures, and the research station provides all services, including ground handling. ‍ They follow strict safety protocols to prevent damage to the Antarctic soil. These protocols include storing all fuel in large barrels or tanks placed on special absorbent mats, and there’s a plethora of equipment to handle any potential spillage disaster. It’s served by Hi Fly, Icelandair, Norse Atlantic, Royal Air Force, Smartwings, and PrivatAir on a chartered basis. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airfield, sporting a highly detailed modeling of the research station, true-to-life landmarks, ground clutter, and much more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.73, requiring at least 61.84 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bornor</id>
    <title>Borgillios Scenery Releases Norrköping Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bornor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6781dc88da0536d7773933d9_norr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Borgillios Scenery recently released their rendition of Norrköping Airport (ESSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves Norrköping and has a yearly average of 103,298 passengers.  Founded in 1934, Norrköping is Sweden's oldest commercial travel airport. Although mostly commercial throughout its history, the Swedish Air Forces briefly used it during World War 2.  The airport's traffic peaked in the 1980s, followed by a significant decline shortly afterward due to the rise of high-speed rail connections and the development of larger commercial airports.  Despite the challenges, efforts have been made to revitalize the airport and attract new airlines and routes. The airport's location in a strategically important region and its history and infrastructure offer potential for future growth and development. Nowadays, the airport only gets seasonal charter traffic from Braathens International Airways, Pegasus Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, high-detail buildings (terminal, hangars, etc), and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $10.30, requiring at least 166.64 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmltbj</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Teases Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmltbj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6782dd3880656284ae181f69_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently teased its next project, likely for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, based on the teaser. The team is travelling to Turkey, specifically to the city of Izmir. It appears that Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport (LTBJ) will be the next scenery developed by MM Simulations. Izmir is a popular holiday destination in Turkey, renowned for its beautiful coastal views. It attracts numerous vacationers from across Europe. Each year, Izmir Airport handles over 10.5 million passengers and serves a wide range of destinations, including scheduled seasonal, and charter flights. ‍ Details regarding the release date, features, and pricing have yet to be announced, but we will keep you updated as soon as this information becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrpns</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases Sayak Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrpns"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67863c34bfe29fd5a5b0a5d6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airwil Sceneries has just released its rendition of Sayak Airport (RPNS) for both X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Located on Siargao Island in the Philippines, the airport is also referred to as Siargao Airport. Originally built in 1963 under former President Diosdado Macapagal, the airport was designed to accommodate small 19-seater planes. However, significant changes occurred in 2008 when the airport underwent renovations as part of a program aimed at boosting economic activity. Following these improvements, the airport could handle larger aircraft capable of carrying over 70 passengers. Further modernization and expansion took place in 2013. Today, airlines such as Cebgo, PAL Express, and Sunlight Air operate flights to destinations including Cebu, Clark, Davao, and Manila. The newly released rendition of Sayak Airport is rich in features, offering a realistic representation of the airport, including a detailed passenger terminal, a modelled control tower, and more. The scenery requires 1.27 GB of storage space and is now available at SimMarket for approximately $6.15. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xskttn</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Trenton-Mercer Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xskttn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67868dd52f5e0ed382d2481d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. XWind Studios has recently launched its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024: Trenton-Mercer Airport (KTTN). Located in Trenton, the capital city of New Jersey, this airport is a hub for Frontier Airlines, serving approximately 600.000 passengers annually. Trenton-Mercer Airport's history dates back to 1907 when the first airplane landed on Alfred Reeder's field in Ewing. Skillman Airport opened to the public in 1929. During World War II, the local General Motors plant transitioned to manufacturing torpedo bombers, leading to airport expansions to accommodate test flights for these aircraft. The airport was later renamed Mercer County Airport and eventually became Trenton-Mercer Airport in 1995, linking it to the city of Trenton. In 1998, the airport replaced human weather observers with an automated weather system. Although the county plans to replace the old terminal, residents have opposed this idea. Today, Frontier Airlines is the only airline operating at the airport, offering flights to destinations such as Atlanta, Orlando, Tampa, Fort Myers, and West Palm Beach. The newly released scenery features a host of features, including high-quality, optimized textures, detailed terminal interior designs, custom taxiway signage, comprehensive imagery of the entire airport, and much more. The scenery requires 3.95 GB of storage space and is available on iniBuilds for $10.38. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jlgrp4</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Rhodes International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jlgrp4"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67869650a2fb9d490056cc95_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. JustSim has released its first scenery fully adapted for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, revisiting a previous destination: Rhodes International Airport (LGRP). Rhodes is a popular summer destination in the Greek Islands, attracting over 6 million annual passengers. Civil aviation on the island began after World War II with the opening of Rhodes Maritsa Airport, which served as the main airport until Rhodes International Airport, also known as Diagoras International Airport, was inaugurated in 1977. Over the years, the airport has seen improvements, including expanded taxiways and a new passenger terminal that opened in 2005. In 2015, the airport was privatized and is now managed by Fraport AG/Copelouzos Group for a period of 40 years. Today, Rhodes International Airport hosts numerous airlines offering scheduled, seasonal, and charter flights to various destinations across Europe. The new scenery features high-resolution ground textures, high-resolution building textures, highly detailed 3D models, custom animated ground vehicles, and much more. The scenery requires 1.66 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $17.28. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
