<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-02-25T18:31:37.375983+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prifer</id>
    <title> PhotoRico Releases Fernando Luis Ribas Dominicci Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prifer"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67aa3e2cb61abb5ebf52e943_fer1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PhotoRico has recently released their rendition of Fernando Luis Ribas Dominicci Airport (TJIG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024. The airport serves the municipality of San Juan in Puerto Rico and has a yearly average of 37,000 passengers. Constructed by the US Navy in 1929 as Naval Station Isla Grande, it served as Puerto Rico’s main international gateway until 1954, when it was ultimately replaced by Isla Verde International Airport. All international airlines moved there shortly after. The airport’s future was questioned a few times in the early 2000s, but a definitive—favorable—decision was eventually reached in 2006 due to its key function as a primary reliever for Puerto Rico’s main airport. In early 2011, the airport’s future went through another scare: the FAA wanted to close the airport’s control tower because they operated it themselves and intended to cut costs. Air Flamenco, Fly the Whale, M&amp;N Aviation, and Vieques Air Link regularly serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail buildings, custom ground textures, detailed landside, real static GA aircraft, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.70, requiring at least 873.59 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsaw25</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Awards 2025 at FSWeekend Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsaw25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ab94377fd2a9c99ad186bd_16_9_static.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Threshold, cruiselevel, and FSElite are excited to announce the Flight Sim Awards, taking place at FSWeekend 2025! The Flight Sim Awards aim to celebrate the developers, creators, and innovators who make our enjoyment of flight simulation possible. The jury, selected from members of the Threshold, cruiselevel, and FSElite teams have reviewed all product releases from 2024.  After careful deliberation, the nominees have been narrowed down to a select few finalists in each category. In MSFS and X-Plane, there are three categories: airliners, aircraft and scenery. Additionally, the best add-on for DCS has its own category, along with the best tools, hardware, and freeware for the entire flight sim genre. To conclude, there is a special Content Creator category where you, along with thousands of other fans, determine the winner! ‍ Members of the jury are not the only ones who have a say in the decision. Starting this Friday, February 14, you can vote for your favourites! The final result will be determined by a 50/50 split between the jury and the public votes. Categories will be scored using a point system. Award five points to your favourite, four points to your second favourite, three points to your third favourite, and so on for your top five. Juries will follow the same scoring system. The entry with the most combined points at the end will be declared the winner! ‍ The flight simulation community has no shortage of great content creators. The Flight Sim Awards aim to recognize your favourites, and this category will truly showcase who your top choice is, as 100 percent of the points are determined by the public. ‍ The 2025 Flight Sim Awards will take place on Friday, March 14, the eve before FSWeekend in Lelystad at the Captain's Dinner. For those who cannot attend the event in person, a live stream will be available. ‍ As we celebrate this year’s achievements, we also look ahead to the future. The jury is eager to hear your thoughts and feedback to make the 2026 Flight Sim Awards even better! ‍If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbsan</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Sandane Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbsan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b179b7fc990e8699d30e42_sandane1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their rendition of Sandane Airport (ENSD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves the village of Sandane in Norway and has a yearly average of 37,000 passengers.  The airport was built in the early 1970s and opened in 1975, then the only airport serving the district of Nordfjord. Due to its geography and low regularity, its initial years were plagued by severe turbulence, which was eventually partially mitigated in the following decades by a terminal expansion and a runway extension. The regularity issue was addressed relatively recently by installing navigation systems, ultimately reducing the canceled flights to a mere 5% in 2022. Its pre-ILS days were rather grim, with airplanes often dealing with low visibility, extreme winds, and insufficient runway. It’s served by Widerøe, which has obligatory public service flights to Bergen, Oslo, and Sogndal, flown with Dash 8-100 airplanes. The Norwegian government subsidizes all of the routes. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 2K PBR textures, custom ground decals, crisp orthoimagery, custom approach lighting and ground equipment, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $11.97, requiring at least 842.51 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/salbgn</id>
    <title>Salvuz Releases Bergen Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/salbgn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b22a23c1e0ca1d9b332a9c_bgn1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Salvuz recently released their rendition of Bergen Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It is the second busiest airport in Norway, with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. Dating back to the early 1950s, Bergen Airport was partially funded by the municipalities of Bergen and Fana with 4 million Norwegian kroner, securing the construction of a terminal and a 1,460-meter-long runway. NATO funded an expansion in 1953, warranting a 2,440-meter-long runway instead. When the first flight landed at the airport in mid-1954, only 800 meters were complete. It was a chartered flight from Bergen to Oslo, transporting a local football team. It’s a hub for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe, with an extensive domestic and intra-European network. According to 2014 data, Scandinavian Airlines had 46% of the market share for domestic flights, Norwegian had 38%, and Widerøe 15%. Internationally, Norway led the way with 36%, SAS with 23%, and KLM with 18% (with a single route to Amsterdam).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed buildings, high-resolution PBR textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date layout (as of 2024), and it also supports MSFS 24’s new lighting and LOD system. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.85, requiring at least 1.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd216</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd216"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67007455f9c93f4f4c4607ef_randy4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published a new development update concerning the status of their product lines for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, including further information on the upcoming 777-200ER and the 747 Classic project. The upcoming 777-200ER’s beta testing phase has finally started. The plane will feature all three engine variants (GE, RR, and PW) with their correct performance figures, indications, and sounds.  ‍ While there is no timeline for the beta testing phase to end, Randazzo suspects they will have a better feel for the qualitative state of the product in the next 7-10 days. ‍ Like the 777F, the 777-200ER will be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 first, with a 2024 version to be released later. ‍ PMDG has also announced a new Operations Center (3.0), which is currently under beta testing as well and will eventually replace their current Operations Center, sporting a fresh new look, the ability to manage all product installations from within it, update management, rollbacks, and multiple channels (stable, experimental, beta, streamer builds). It will also handle activation and install rights and significantly improve PMDG’s ability to diagnose and resolve any problems that might occur with their products at hand.  Furthermore, the new Operations Center will eliminate the need for installers, which used to be one of their biggest choke points during product releases. ‍ It’s scheduled to roll out soon and coexist with 2.0 until they are wholly comfortable with the new methods. ‍ Regarding the status of the 777’s conversion to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, PMDG has managed to build its lineup inside the new platform with great success, but some stability issues were found that would ultimately break the experience.  Despite the slightly underwhelming results, PMDG remains optimistic that their “relationship” with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will improve as Asobo updates the platform. ‍ On the other hand, the DC–6— which they assumed would be an easy conversion—has proven to be one of the trickiest, with numerous problems with the animations (including cockpit controls, levers, buttons, and other items). They have been unable to determine what is causing the problem so far. ‍ They have reported the issue in Asobo’s dev community forums, but it appears to have not caught their attention yet, and no other developer has encountered anything similar. In light of this, PMDG has provided no ETA for its eventual conversion to the new platform. ‍ 737NG-wise, they have not yet evaluated it in the new platform, as they are using the 777 as a testbed to learn the ropes. As for the upgrade pricing, PMDG’s position remains the same: while they ideally do not want to charge, they might have to charge depending on the amount of work required (they haven’t fully gauged how much effort will be necessary yet). ‍ Work on the 747 fleet has been accelerating while everything else remains relatively stagnant due to the compatibility stalemate. Randazzo reiterates that things are still moving, though slowly.  ‍ While the 747-400 doesn’t have any images yet, they have shared two pictures of the flight deck work on the 747-100, showcasing the newly started labeling work, custom weathering, etc.  Coding is also progressing nicely, with PMDG taking full advantage of the “stalemate” to move developers on and off the 747. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their official website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99 If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse26v</id>
    <title>Vote Now: Dates and Location for FlightSimExpo 2026</title>
    <updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse26v"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b3be5532cc84d8a9e2e6da_2023_20.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The Flight Simulation Association has recently released a survey to decide the venue and dates for FSExpo 2026. FSExpo is North America’s largest flight simulation conference, drawing thousands of attendees each year and featuring exhibitors from across the industry, from developers to content creators, and more! “As North America’s community-driven flight sim convention, attendee and partner feedback is a key input to where and when we host the show”, says FSA’s Evan Reiter, a volunteer air traffic controller on VATSIM and an organizer of the show. “Three of the options on our survey were suggested to me in Discord DMs or comments from attendees at FSExpo—keep them coming!” ‍ ‍Click here to vote and influence one of flight simulation’s largest events! ‍ As for this year’s expo, Registration is open for FSExpo 2025 in Providence, RI from June 27 to 29 at the Rhode Island Convention Center. ‍ While Expo organizers are already looking ahead to next year’s event, FSExpo 2025 is just a few months away, and Threshold will be there on site covering all the latest from the event! However, we would not be able to do this without the support of our amazing community, so consider supporting us on Patreon, and joining our vibrant Discord community!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42dee</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes Deep Dive Video on Upcoming ChasePlane for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42dee"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67980a55024e3305b1018fc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently published a video on their YouTube channel showcasing ChasePlane’s onboarding tutorial. The video walks you through setting up all the necessary items to get the best experience and provides further information on the optional community access. The 10-minute video covers the entirety of the introductory steps, walking you through removing your bindings in Microsoft Flight Simulator (ChasePlane “kidnaps” the camera system), configuring your bindings, setting up different camera presets, enabling cinematics, and sharing views with the community. ‍ It’s important to note that—unlike Flow, one of their best-selling products for MSFS—cloud storage can’t be provided for free, as it takes significantly more space. Therefore, they have chosen to make the cost optional, lowering the product’s final price tag and allowing customers to decide whether they want to pay extra for community access. The prices for community access range from 5 dollars for the yearly subscription to 20 dollars for a lifetime.  ‍ P42 also reiterates that community access is NOT needed to share camera views, as they have built powerful importing and exporting methods that allow you to share camera views via any platform outside of their community ecosystem. ‍ Refer to this blog post for further information on the optional community access system. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdmon</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Monastir Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdmon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b75a1f81f063cb854f0eb5_mon1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDG recently released their Monastir Habib Bourguiba International Airport (DTMB) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Monastir, Tunisia, and has a yearly average of 1.6 million passengers. Its origins date back to World War 2, when it was known as Monastir Airfield and utilized by the United States Army Air Force during the North African Campaign. In the following decades, Monastir Airport experienced significant growth and expansion, driven by Tunisia's increasing popularity as a tourist destination. It's a hub for Nouvelair and is served seasonally by Air France, Air Serbia, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Discover Airlines, Eurowings, Smartwings, Sundair, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, and Tunisair. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, custom ground clutter, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $14.02, requiring at least 872.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350feb</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases 2nd Trailer for Upcoming Airbus A350</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350feb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b80e68c27ff464d40bbd80_fiddy1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released the second trailer video for their upcoming Airbus A350 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showing glimpses of its exterior and interior through elaborate cinematics. They have also published a FAQ section for the airplane in their forums, containing relevant information on operating the aircraft and the differences between the MSFS 2020 and 2024 versions.  As previously informed, the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 will not feature a cabin, avionics bay, crew rest area, LIDO charts (MSFS 2024 exclusive), dynamic weathering, or per-livery configuration.  The airplane will be available sometime next week for roughly $75.96.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukegae</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases City of Derry Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukegae"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b862c2c399a1d9c4a43cad_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 has just released its latest Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 scenery. This time, the team has focused on the City of Derry Airport (EGAE) in Derry, Northern Ireland. The airport serves approximately 150,000 passengers each year. The airfield opened in 1941 as a Royal Air Force base and was used for military purposes until the 1950s. After that, the airport saw limited usage, with Emerald Airways operating a route to Glasgow. The airline constructed a new terminal building and control tower for the airport, with the first Glasgow flights commencing in 1967.  ‍ A little over a decade later, Loganair began offering a few routes from the airport. Over the years, the airport has undergone various extensions and upgrades as it continued to grow and new airlines started to operate there.  ‍ Today, airlines such as easyJet, Loganair, Ryanair, and Volotea serve the airport, providing destinations like Edinburgh, London, Manchester, and more. As a result, the airport handles approximately 7,000 aircraft movements and welcomes around 150,000 passengers annually. The scenery includes features like detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, night effects, highly detailed airport vehicles, vegetation, PBR materials, and static GA aircraft. The newly released City of Derry Airport is now available on SimMarket for approximately $15.69. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdsxpl</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Releases GTNXi for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdsxpl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b8aa3b775bfb8b837cd407_Torquesim_CJ525_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TDS Sim Software has recently released GTNXi for X-Plane 11 and 12. The GTNXi is a rendition of the Garmin 650Xi and 750Xi navigation with support for both Navigraph charts and data. Like its real-life counterpart, the GTNXi provides the pilot with various features, such as full autopilot control laterally and vertically (including support for LPV approaches), 8.33kHz COM frequency spacing, the ability to fly RF legs, a Glide Range Ring, a Smart Glide, and a Nearest Airport Indication Arrow. It also supports dual GPS/Flight plans, per-device CDI, mouse wheel zoom-in/out of the map page, full VC integration and a 2D pop-up available concurrently, worldwide live METAR, SmartGlide, and much more. The full list is rather lengthy, but it can be found in the .pdf manual included with the addon. The TDS GTNXi comes with VC integration support for X-Plane 12 for the following add-ons: If your favourite general aviation plane isn’t on the list, don't worry! The GTNXi comes with Legacy VC Integration, which can detect and install the TDS add-on into all add-on aircraft that provide a legacy GTN 3D bezel unit. According to the developers, this will be useful for users with X-Plane 11 aircraft, as those will not come with TDS GTNXi VC Integration standards. More information about this can also be found in the .pdf manual. If the aircraft doesn’t have VC-integrated GPS support, you can always use it as a 2D pop-up. The TDS Sim Software’s GTNXi can be purchased here for roughly $ 68.20. It requires X-Plane 11/12, Windows 10 (version 1909) or Windows 11, Intel Core i5-12600K or AMD Ryzen 5 3500, at least 16GB of RAM memory, Nvidia RTX2070 or AMD Radeon RX 5700XT, with at least 4GB of video card memory, and at least 6GB of free space on hard disk. Navigraph subscription is also required for database updates and charts. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcejf2</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family Version 2.0 in Open Beta</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcejf2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bafc7338327ff2605895b8_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The E-Jets Family for X-Plane, developed by X-Crafts, has just launched version 2.0 in an open beta. The full release is expected in just a few weeks. This update includes a variety of new features, improvements, and fixes, and introduces a rendition of the Embraer Lineage 1000. The latest update is filled with exciting new features. The E-Jets now offer three distinct lighting options: X-Plane default, dynamic, or natural lighting. Please note that these features are only available in X-Plane 12 and not in X-Plane 11. Additionally, users can now simulate the real-life noise-cancelling headsets used by pilots. The Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) has also been updated significantly. Both the fuel and auto brake systems have been completely overhauled. These are just a few highlights of the changes; for the complete list, please refer to the release notes. The current price for the full E-Jets Family is $134.95. It is important to note that once version 2.0 is fully released, the price will increase to $149.95. Additionally, the upgrade price will rise to $74.48. If you choose to purchase or upgrade to the full E-Jets Family before the 2.0 release, you will receive the Lineage 1000 for free. The full release is currently estimated to be on the 1st of March. The E-Jets Family can be found at the X-Plane.Org Software Store. For instructions on using the open beta for the E-Jets, refer to the helpful guide provided by X-Crafts. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtind</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Indianapolis International Airport v2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtind"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67baff41eb25e6456b1a9a05_kind1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. DominicDesignTeam recently released their new rendition of Indianapolis International Airport (KIND) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Indianapolis with a yearly average of 4.7 million passengers, making it the busiest in Indiana and the 43rd busiest in the United States. It opened in 1931 to replace Stout Field, which used to be the city’s main airport at the time.  Indianapolis was one of the main transcontinental flights and rail service stops between Los Angeles and New York City. It was started by Trans World Airlines’ precursor, Transcontinental Air Transport. Its original terminal used to be on the east side of the airfield, now demolished (1957-2008). It was replaced by a new terminal in late 2008, with 110,000 square meters of built area between parallel runways.  It’s a hub for FedEx Express and an operating base for Allegiant Air and Republic Airways. Aer Lingus (to begin in May), Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines,.and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, custom ground markings, custom jetway, custom animations, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.41, requiring at least 960.10 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddipkk</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Kraków John Paul II International Airport V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddipkk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bb05fb1759e5bb4273fc8d_epkk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their new rendition of Kraków John Paul II International Airport v2 (EPKK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the city of Kraków, Poland, and has a yearly average of 11 million passengers, making it the second busiest airport in Poland. Its construction began in 1964, with its eventual opening for civil aviation three years later, in 1967.  During its first four years of operation, Kraków Airport didn’t have a passenger terminal, which was only built in 1971. The 1970s also brought a runway extension, new taxiways, and the installation of high-intensity runway lights. In the late 1980s, the administration decided to build a new terminal, which opened in 1993. Shortly after, in 1995, an apron modernization followed. Further modernization was carried on in 2002 to ensure readiness for more international operations. A brand new terminal was constructed between 2013 and 2016 to ensure it could handle the extra traffic brought by Ryanair’s second Polish base, which opened in 2012. Two years ago, Kraków became Poland’s first regional airport to pass the 9 million passenger threshold. Such impressive traffic figures and eventual projected growth led to plans for a new terminal to better accommodate the extra influx.  The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, custom night lighting, a high-definition terrain mesh, performance-friendly interior modeling, an up-to-date ground layout, static aircraft, custom ground service equipment, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.88, requiring at least 1.52 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cploot</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes More ChasePlane Footage</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cploot"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a03568493d826e0a991328_cp1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 has recently published two more videos showcasing their upcoming ChasePlane add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, going through setting up custom views and shortcuts. ‍ The first video goes in depth about views and smart views, demonstrating how to import default views, adjust and rename views, delete and create passenger views, use smart views in the cockpit and cabin, create external views, and reorganize views. The second video, on the other hand, demonstrates the shortcut system, including their mini-bar HUD, view configuration, compatible devices, camera mode assignments, view, group, and world shortcuts, rotating through views, and flyby and tower cameras. Please refer to this post for further information on ChasePlane's many features. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cplpri</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Announces Changes to ChasePlane’s Pricing System</title>
    <updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cplpri"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bca30a67eda37f60e7572b_chase.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently made a blog post announcing their decision to stop charging an extra fee for cloud storage and offer the full experience in a single lifetime package. The community did not take too well to their original idea of charging extra for cloud storage due to how much it would cost Parallel 42 to keep the structure running. The options ranged from 5 dollars for a yearly subscription to 20 dollars for lifetime access.  ‍ Even though community access was not required to share camera presets, as ChasePlane also features a powerful importer/exporter tool that allows people to simply share the files over on Discord or any file hoster, the backlash was immense due to how negatively the subscription system is generally viewed by simmers and gamers alike.  ‍ With that in mind, Parallel 42 has decided to include the access with the base package without any extra charges. They will commit to the ever-growing expenses of running such cloud infrastructure while meeting their original price target.  ‍ Such a decision was not made haphazardly; they conducted a very deep cost analysis to ensure it wouldn’t eventually backfire.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
