<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-08T18:24:10.598968+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxkm</id>
    <title>Orbx Kola Map Previews and Features</title>
    <updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxkm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66321d2ea471ee5009516050_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Threshold recently received exclusive screenshots of the upcoming Kola Map for DCS, and today, we have three more exclusives to share with you. The community has highly anticipated the new Kola Map, which will cover large parts of Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia. As of now, the project is listed as "coming soon," with the release of the early access version imminent. The Kola Map will first be available for early access and will be feature-packed with a multitude of airports. There will be two airports in Finland, five in Russia, two in Norway, and three in Sweden. Additionally, early access ensures a complete base terrain, highly detailed topography for the entire map, and lots of POIs, road and railroad networks, night lighting, and many landmarks to explore. Although early access will be available first, many future features have already been planned. Winter textures are scheduled to ensure the representation of the cold and harsh climate up North. A multitude of military airfields like Bardufoss and Kirkenes and a variety of civilian airports, including Tromsø and Luleå, are also planned. Also, general improvements to landscape features have been scheduled. The official store page for the Kola Map is now available on Orbx. Be sure to check it out for more information and screenshots. ‍ We will update you with more information as soon as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thnlx</id>
    <title>Threshold Newsletter going live</title>
    <updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thnlx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663299e7db7880a89ef3635e_2023-06-04%2016_41_26-X-System.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The first-ever Threshold Newsletter is now live! Our new monthly newsletter is here to stay, and we'll provide you with a roundup of all the biggest flight simulation news, as well as the editorial of the month. You can find the April newsletter on our website and sign up now to receive future newsletters. 2024 has been an outstanding year for us at Threshold, as we have been committed to delivering the highest quality content to you. Our team has written a remarkable 223 news articles and 18 full-length articles, covering a diverse range of topics and providing valuable insights to our audience. We are proud to have achieved a new record this year, and we look forward to continuing to provide exceptional content to our readers in the future. ‍ ‍ The Newsletter will evolve over time and we encourage you to give us feedback in our Discord on how what you would like to see published. This is new to us too =) ‍ The entire team at Threshold would like to express our gratitude to everyone who has joined us on our journey thus far. We hope that this newsletter will continue to help us grow and remain a go-to destination in our community. Thank you! ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mjcupd</id>
    <title>Majestic Software Posts Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mjcupd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633a13adbc1928e7050a1ab_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Majestic Software recently posted an update on their forum regarding the progress of their aircraft development for Microsoft Flight Simulator. According to the post, the team has completely reworked the EFIS screens and custom flight dynamic for MSFS. They are also adding a new EFB, which will be included in not only the MSFS version of the aircraft but also the current Prepar3D version. Majestic Software has announced its intention to bring both the Q400 and Q300 for MSFS, and the Q200 is also highly likely. However, the team hasn't shared a specific timeline for the project yet. They hope to complete the plane by 2025 if everything goes according to plan.  We will keep you updated when the team shares more information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ahhawk</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Releases Hawker Hurrican Mk.1 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ahhawk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633a7639ed49c1fd0c01774_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aeroplane Heaven has recently released its version of the Hawker Hurricane Mk.1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a British fighter aircraft that first flew in 1935. The single-seater plane was built by Hawker Aircraft Ltd. and was initially used by the Royal Air Force (RAF). The aircraft was introduced in 1937 and a total of 14.487 planes were built between 1937 and 1944. Although it initially flew for the RAF, it was also used by other countries such as Australia, Belgium, Greece, Poland, and more throughout its lifespan. The new add-on comes with a range of features, including high-fidelity models, detailed features, animations, accurate flight dynamics, a variety of liveries, and more. The add-on requires 2.81GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $28.85. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xejets</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Updates Free E-Jets for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xejets"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633b28dcd8ab9aec417e180_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts have released an update for their freeware E-Jets, bringing the plane to version V3.0. This new version is compatible with X-Plane 12 and comes with many improvements and new features. The previous version (V2.5) remains compatible with X-Plane 11. The Embraer E-Jet family consists of a multitude of Brazilian-made narrow-body airliners. The project was initially revealed by Embraer in 1997, but it was not officially unveiled until two years later. In 2002, the first E-Jet had its maiden flight. The E-Jet family comprises of four commercial airliners, including the E170, E175, E190, and E195. The free E-Jets series by X-Crafts includes both the E175 and the E195 models. The new X-Plane 12 version of the E-Jets comes with a range of new features, such as an enhanced flight model, improved modeling, updated lights, cockpit fixes, and more. The new version is now available for download on the X-Crafts website. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inprmm</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Freeware Milwaukee Mitchell International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inprmm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633b8599606ada829410cf4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has provided a sneak peek of its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport in question is Milwaukee Mitchell International Airport (KMKE), which will be released for free to the community. As the busiest airport in Wisconsin, KMKE boasts over 160 destinations to explore from the airport. The freeware package will include a multitude of features such as hand-made ground textures, custom ground decals, vegetation, dynamic lighting, highly detailed models, an up-to-date airport layout, a GSX profile, and much more. The developer has announced that the scenery will be available tomorrow, and the store page is now live on the iniBuilds Store.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777bpr</id>
    <title>FightFactor Releases Beta Pre-Release Version of 777v2 for Invited Members</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777bpr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633bf3190d08942b64aadcf_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has just released a beta pre-release version of their 777v2 airplane for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. This version is only available to invited members, who are not allowed to post any information or screenshots outside a dedicated forum. While the store page for the airplane is up, the official price for the airplane has not yet been revealed, and the $9.999 price tag currently shown is not the normal price. The store page offers a detailed description of the aircraft, along with plenty of screenshots. The 777v2 boasts a range of features, including an accurate flight model, 3D modeling, accurately simulated systems, ground services, custom sounds, failure model, EFB, and much more. FlightFactor has not yet announced when the 777v2 will be available to the public, nor what the price will be, so stay tuned for updates on that front. In the meantime, you can check out the current store page over at the X-Plane.Org Software Store. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inkmke</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Freeware Milwaukee Mitchell International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inkmke"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6634be8c1177cdcedf7e156c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released its newest airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Milwaukee Mitchell International Airport (KMKE). It is a freeware package, making it accessible to everyone in the community. KMKE is the busiest airport in Wisconsin, providing access to over 160 destinations for flight exploration. The package includes various features such as hand-crafted ground textures, custom ground decals, dynamic lighting, detailed models, an up-to-date airport layout, and a GSX profile, among others.  The scenery is now available for free on the iniBuilds Store.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/okolar</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases DCS Kola Map in Early Access</title>
    <updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/okolar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66352677036edef647f49316_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Orbx has released the highly anticipated Kola map as an early access add-on for DCS. The map contains a multitude of airports, including two in Finland, five in Russia, two in Norway, and three in Sweden. In addition to the airports, the early access version provides a complete base terrain, detailed topography, and many landmarks, POIs, and road and railroad networks to explore. The early access version of the flight simulation game includes numerous features already, and further updates are expected to provide winter textures, more military airfields, and additional civilian airports. Currently, the team is working on developing military airfields such as Bardufoss and Kirkenes, as well as civilian airports like Tromsø and Luleå. The Kola map also includes large parts of Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia, as well as large parts of the Barents Sea and Norwegian. The add-on is available on Orbx for approximately $55.99 during early access and will increase to $69.99 once the product is fully released. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42sfx</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases SimFX for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42sfx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66352e9941336be14421eb6a_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently released its latest add-on, SimFX, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. SimFX is a visual effects utility that adds a range of immersive features and effects to the simulator. The add-on is compatible with a variety of aircraft and other add-ons, and a compatibility page shows what is compatible and what is not. SimFX comes with a wide range of features, including contrails, engine heat blur, APU heat blur, engine blast, wing wash, rotor wash, thrust reverser effects, engine pollution, touchdown smokes, wave effects, dirt effects, rain effects, auroras, and much more. The website also offers a live aurora tracker to see when and where you can experience the aurora in the simulator. The add-on is now available at the Parallel 42 Store for $25.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stebac</id>
    <title>Stellar Simulations Releases Bacolod-Silay Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stebac"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663556114517c0a446b242b9_bacolod1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stellar Simulations has recently released their rendition of Bacolod-Silay Airport (RPVB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Bacolod Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers as of 2022. The airport’s site was initially used as an airfield during World War 2 but was abandoned immediately after. Parts of the airfield became a sugarcane plantation. In 1997, a Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) study indicated the need for expansion at four Philippine airports, and Bacolod City Domestic Airport was one of them. It was relatively small for the traffic it was getting, and expansion was impossible, which led to the construction of a brand-new airport. Construction started in 2004, with a 900-day deadline to complete it. During the digging work, the remains of the former WW2 airfield and aircraft wrecks were found. The airport’s construction was considered complete by mid-2007, but there was debate at the time due to a pending runway extension that wasn’t complete yet. Commercial operations started in January 2008, replacing the old Bacolod City Domestic Airport.  Cebgo, Cebu Pacific, PAL Express, and Philippines AirAsia serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a custom terminal interior, landside buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground clutter, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.69, requiring at least 360.74 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmpet</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases St. Pete-Clearwater International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmpet"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663699602c7a5f3bd8629a57_pete1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of St. Pete-Clearwater International Airport (KPIE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Tampa Bay Area with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers as of 2023. Construction started in 1941 and was acquired shortly after by the United States Army Air Forces to be used as a training base. It was returned to the County after the end of WW2, renamed Pinellas International Airport. Its current name only came to be in 1958 because Pinellas County was not a very attractive name from a tourist standpoint, according to the airport manager (people didn’t know where it was). The administration spent $22 million on heavy renovation work in 2009, which included larger gates, jetways, new plumbing, and overall modernization. ‍ It’s an operating base for Allegiant Air, which flies to a wide range of destinations. Sun Country, Minneapolis’ local airline, also flies to St. Pete seasonally. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, LODs for optimization, a simple terminal for optimal performance, custom static models, custom taxiway signage, high-resolution PBR texturing, custom aerial imagery, an official GSX profile, and more. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $16.99, requiring at least 1.76 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc6tp12</id>
    <title>Thranda Releases PC-6 Turbo Porter for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc6tp12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6638e7992dbb7609a6801316_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda has just released their rendition of the Pilatus PC-6 Turbo Porter for X-Plane 12. Thanks to its superb STOL performance, and easy-to-maintain design, it is used all around the globe to deliver goods where regular aircraft cannot fly. With its first flight in 1959, the PC-6 Porter was produced at Pilatus Flugzeugwerke in Switzerland. It has been built in both a piston engine version and a turboprop-powered version and was also produced under license by Fairchild Hiller in the USA. After 604 planes were built, during a span of 63 years, Pilatus ended its production in 2022. ‍ Powered by a Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-27 turboprop 550 hp engine, the Turbo Porter can cruise at an altitude up to 26.800 feet, with a maximum speed of 125 knots. This gives the plane a range of 1,612 km (870 nm) or 730 km (390 nm) with maximum payload. Due to its amazing STOL capability, the Pilatus PC-6 can take from a runway as short as 195 meters (640ft) and land within a distance of 130 meters (427ft). Thanks to its performance, it holds the record for the highest landing by a fixed-wing aircraft, at 18.865 feet (5,750 m), on the Dhaulagiri glacier in Nepal. ‍ The Thranda PC-6 is a part of the DGS - Dynamic Generation Series, which takes full advantage of X-Plane’s flexibility and in-sim modifications. Some of the included features are: customizing a livery in-sim, changing instrument layouts with different panel configs, switching between different airframe configurations, high-fidelity and precise flight dynamics, and much more. Some of the notable features available in the XP12 version are:  The EFB has loads of apps, such as the Aircraft Options App, Weight and Balance app, Instrument Options app, Dynamic Panel app, Static Livery app, DynaFeel app, Log Book app, Checklist app, Ground handling app, Dynamic Livery app, Flight Computer app, and more. Thranda Pilatus PC-6 Turbo Porter is available for purchase on the X-Plane.org store for 44.95$, requiring at least 4.1GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrda5</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Releases DA-50RG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrda5"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66390d796daaee72c63eda15_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyward Simulations has just released their rendition of the Diamond DA-50RG for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The DA-50RG is a single-engine aircraft made out of a carbon fiber airframe, mostly used for general aviation and training purposes. Introduced in 2007, it was designed to replace the aging single-engine DA-40. After the Economic Recession in 2009, the DA-50 project was put on hold, and by 2019, no model other than a prototype was made. In 2020, a new version with a Continental CD-300 engine and retractable gear was announced. Later on, it became known as the DA-50RG. With a service ceiling of 20,000ft and a maximum speed of 191 knots, the Diamond DA-50 has a range of 750 nm (1389 km). Skyward Simulations DA-50RG comes with an accurate 3D model, True-to-life definition textures, Custom-coded systems, including ECU &amp; TKS, Ground Idle function simulated, Accurate flight model, Working Title Garmin G1000NXI integration, Included handpainted liveries, and immersive custom sounds by Boris Audio Works. This addon is available for purchase on the Orbx store for roughly $16.39 USD and will require at least 2.08GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fokker</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker 70/100 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fokker"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663a88bea8c3082851548d9e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has just released a development update for their upcoming project, F70/100 Professional for MSFS, on their website. Since the last dev update, developers have been busy working on implementing Hydraulic, Flight Control, and Landing Gear Systems, as well as fine-tuning engine and flight models to match the Fokker 70/100 performance. For the first time, the functioning displays were previewed. The next systems to be worked on will be Autopilot and Autothrottle. On the artistic side of development, JF has made quite an impressive list of liveries, representing the extensive use of Fokker 100s worldwide. Ranging from the old but golden American Airlines bare-metal livery, European classics such as KLM and Air France Regional, to today’s operators of this quite rare aircraft; QantasLink, Virgin Australia, and Alliance. Additionally, the list includes the Fokker Services House livery and the Slovak Government livery. The list features a variety of eras and operators, such as:  Unfortunately, we only got Fokker 100 previews in this update, however, the next update will feature screenshots and more info on the shorter variant, the Fokker 70! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsedds</id>
    <title>Backwood Studios Releases Eddsfield Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsedds"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663b73c6525a1cc25aa4900c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Backwood Studios have recently released their rendition of Eddsfield Airfield for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a little airfield in East Yorkshire. Edd Peacock created the airfield in the early 90s and is still in operation today. Offering a peaceful escape from everyday life, Edd wanted an airfield to fly from without politics, committees or hassle. Nestled in the Yorkshire countryside and surrounded by hills and endless green fields, it gives out a specific, calming charm.  ‍ Old Edd’s Trailer Cafe can be found in the heart of the airfield. This antique-like building offers a feel of how life used to be during the good ol’ times. It doesn’t matter if you came here to grab a bite between your flights, or to listen to stories from other aviators and veterans, Eddsfield is ready to welcome you! This scenery features automated hangar doors, animated people and animals, night lighting, custom 3D-modelled vehicles and buildings, a fully functional fuel station, GA parking, and over 50 km of custom-added roads. Eddsfield Airfield is available for purchase on Orbx for 7.52 USD and requires at least 0.97GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
