<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-17T18:21:51.262817+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpnbr</id>
    <title>RDPresets Announces Bergen Flesland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpnbr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639390e458c4aa2d4c611a84_bergen1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="743439"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced their rendition of Bergen Flesland Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6.5 million passengers. It’s owned and operated by Avinor (state owned company).   It’s a focus city for Bergen Air Transport, Bristow Norway, CHC Helikopter Service, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe, making for a huge domestic and international network. CHC and Bristow feature an unusual type of passenger traffic, transporting people to offshore oil platforms in the North Sea. It’s visited by many other airlines such as Air France, airBaltic, Finnair, Flyr, Icelandair, KLM, Lufthansa, and WizzAir, along with seasonal carriers.  The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with a modeled interior, custom ground textures, and detailed landside buildings.   It should be available tomorrow on the RDPresets Store. There’s no information on requirements yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxmyl</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases McCall Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxmyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6393997608813abdd302ff66_kmyl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2065484"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, by their newest independent developer Mark “Milo” Taylor, which already made a rendition of MYL under MSX Creations. This new rendition is an overhaul of the previous work, with custom library objects, scenery placement and re-texturing.   It is a city-owned public-use airport in McCall (Idaho), categorized by the FAA as a general aviation facility. It had 43,600 aircraft operations between August 2009 and August 2010, averaging 119 flights per day, 84% of which comprehended general aviation traffic, and 16% were air taxi, with the remaining 1% being military traffic.    With a 1862m long runway, McCall Mun. Airport can accommodate most private jets and medium-range airliners.   The scenery features true-to-life ground and apron texturing (including the recent apron resurfacing), realistic night lighting, PBR texturing, level of detail work to warrant good performance, multiple custom static aircraft, airport specific windsocks, over 160 custom objects, multiple custom animations, and hand-placed vegetation.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $19.06, requiring at least 3.64 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdscae</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Teases São Paulo Catarina Executive for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdscae" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394c9ab55496a9252a993a0_catarinacover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1999138"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently teased their rendition of São Paulo Catarina Executive International (SBJH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the Metropolitan Area of São Paulo, Brazil. It’s the first private executive airport with International status in the country, built on 5.2 million square meters of land and situated near the main business centers of the state.  The airport development project aims to bring together characteristics from the best general aviation airports in the World, such as Teterboro and Paris Le Bourget, with help from companies such as Airport Consulting Vienna (ACV) and Ramboll, a Danish consulting engineering group. Built to accommodate up to 200,000 take-offs and landings per year, including long range jets, thanks to its 2500 meter long runway. It's the only executive airport in Brazil with authorization to operate flights to New York, London, and Paris. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR models, a "98% accurate" terrain mesh, fully updated satellite imagery, custom objects, and models built based on projects sent by the airport administrator. There’s no information on install size or release date yet, but said to be coming soon (awaiting Marketplace approval).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfluns</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases UNS-1 Custom FMS for the 146 Professional</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfluns" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394db9693646f7f44a95546_ansett%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1453796"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a developer update covering their progress on the UNS-1 Custom FMS for their 146 Professional, an old style FMS released in 1982 and widely used until the early 2000s, providing GPS navigation with LNAV output to the autopilot and horizontal situation indicator. Users can toggle between the modern FMS, the UNS-1, or no FMS in the Electronic Flight Bag Configuration Menu, without reloading the aircraft.   The new UNS-1 will be capable of loading and saving MSFS flight plans, along with full SID/STAR support with transitions and approaches. It also includes advanced features such as real-time fuel monitoring, as long as the user inputs the necessary information (passenger count, cargo, fuel quantity, etc.).   Like the real unit, it features VNAV, but it doesn’t communicate with the autopilot, making it the user has to manually manage the climbs and descents with IAS and VS, although the built-in VNAV will be able to calculate the top of descent and target vertical speed.  The developer claims it is still under extensive testing, with guidance videos to come once it’s closer to release. Cover picture is courtesy of DragonRuins. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpbea</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Bergen Flesland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpbea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394e7f5f994d3f539c94e08_enbr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2371006"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has just released their rendition of Bergen Flesland Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. It is an important Scandinavian destination, served by many airlines such as Scandinavian Airlines, Norwegian Air Shuttle, and Widerøe, with a significant intra-european route network.   The origin of the airport dates back to the early 1950s, when a national military communications project secured the construction of a 1460 meter long runway, and 4 million norwegian krone were provided by the municipalities of Bergen and Fana to build a terminal and a road. Additional NATO grants in 1953 warranted a longer runway (2440 meters) and better infrastructure. A DHC-3 Otter was the first aircraft to land on Bergen Flesland, on 18 June 1954, when only 800 meters of the runway were complete. The first revenue chartered flight was a leg to Oslo, transporting SK Brann to play a football match.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models, PBR texturing, 3D interior, more than a thousand clutter objects on the apron, realistic and functioning VDGS, custom ground textures, performance optimization, accurate night lighting, custom taxi signage, and ground traffic.  It’s available on the RDPresets Store for roughly $21.07 or on SimMarket for $19.00, requiring at least 1 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dwdewr</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Teases Newark Liberty International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dwdewr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63963e2f2c7c446aca562cac_kewr6.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3572706"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently made an Instagram post showcasing the development progress on their rendition of Newark Liberty International Airport (KEWR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in the New York airport system, only behind JFK, with an average of 33 million passengers a year as of 2021.  It’s a United Airlines hub, with 66.5% of the yearly figures. JetBlue (7.6%), Spirit Airlines (5.5%), American Airlines (5.5%), and Delta Airlines (3.8%) take the rest of the share. It’s also a cargo hub for FedEx Express.   The developer claims it’s already on Beta 5 and potentially becoming the first release candidate, allowing them to prepare the installer, make promotional media, and get the marketplace stuff ready. It’s claimed to be “incomparably more detailed” than the previous KEWR for P3D.  There is no information regarding features, installation size, pricing, or release date. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/snocph</id>
    <title>SimNord Previews Copenhagen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/snocph" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6397ebd629334ae31cc57c3e_ekch1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1624727"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimNord has recently previewed their progress on Copenhagen Airport (EKCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second largest airport in the Nordic countries, serving Denmark and Southern Sweden with over 30 million passengers yearly. It’s the main hub for Scandinavian Airlines, and an operating base for Sunclass Airlines and Norwegian Air Shuttle.   Aside from the local airlines, it’s visited by over 50 airlines from around the World such as Aegean, Air Canada, Air China, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, Finnair, Qatar Airways, Turkish Airlines, etc. Oslo, Amsterdam, and Stockholm are the busiest European routes as of 2021, with roughly 400,000 passengers each. Dubai (105,000), Doha (104,794), and Newark (66,034) top the charts of busiest intercontinental routes.  There is no information regarding features, pricing, or release date. Threshold will keep you updated on the matter once there’s new information. Shout out to PopFizzels for the news scoop. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrgla</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Updates Glasgow Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrgla" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6397fb1b4add32cae71a9eb2_egpf1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="193892"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently updated their rendition of Glasgow International Airport (EGPF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the ninth-busiest airport in the United Kingdom with nearly 10 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic). It is owned and operated by AGS Airports, which also own Aberdeen and Southampton.   It’s a hub for EasyJet, Loganair, Jet2.com, and TUI Airways, with many domestic and intra-European routes. British Airways features three domestic routes to London City, London Heathrow, and London Gatwick. As far as transcontinental flights go, it’s visited by Air Transat with a leg to Toronto, and Emirates to Dubai. The busiest routes as of 2019 are London Heathrow (865,008), London Gatwick (641,566), and Dublin (500,441), operated by British Airways and Aer Lingus.  The scenery update features a new terminal glass, minor fixes to terminal geometry, static aircraft v2, major taxiway lighting improvements, minor changes to ATC Tower interior, GSX integration (with dynamic doors), added vehicle paths for ground service equipment, ground polygon adjustments, airline specific parking codes, static people replaced with animated ones, trees on the approach to runway 23 were removed, and other minor fixes and improvements.  Update 1.1.7 is now available on Orbx Direct, for roughly $20.26 (update is free for current owners). Other storefronts will follow shortly, according to the developer. At least 2.65 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. The new GSX Profile is available on FlightSim.to, free of charge. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflfst</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews FS Traffic for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflfst" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63992d42091a99ed93aa6418_fstraffic1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1981461"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently uploaded a video previewing the Regional AI Aircraft for their upcoming FS Traffic add-on. The regional set includes 12 different airplanes (A220-100, A220-200, ATR-42, ATR-72, CRJ-700, CRJ-900, CRJ-1000, Dash 8-Q400, ERJ-145, E-170, E-190, and E-195) with multiple livery combinations from around the World. The video showcases some of the new planes, the AI traffic interaction with ground service equipment, and the newly added animations and effects.  ‍  FS Traffic promises to add tens of thousands of real-life commercial flights from different periods, with worldwide coverage from a popular data source. The data covers the summer of 2022, with 2021 and 2019 to come later through a free update. The traffic will be controlled by the date and time of the day, with different densities. It also offers model-matching compatibility with platforms such as VATSIM.  On the latest developer update, they claim all the core features are fully functional, with all the liveries, including additional paint jobs based on feedback from the public. Their testing team is undergoing expansion to maximize efficiency and ensure compatibility with other products.   There is no information on pricing and release date yet, but they claim to be aiming for an early 2023 release. Shout out to genista for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flyams</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flyams" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639b9017d3660fbe433258d4_eham1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="397934"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlyTampa has recently released their rendition of Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for X-Plane 11 and 12, the world’s third busiest airport in terms of international passenger traffic (as of 2021) and the third busiest in Europe volume-wise, with 70 million passengers yearly.   Schiphol is a hub for Corendon Dutch Airlines, KLM, KLM Cargo, KLM Cityhopper, Transavia, TUI fly Netherlands, and Martinair, and a base for easyJet. As previously mentioned, being the third busiest airport in international passenger traffic, the destination network is significant, covering most of the globe. Due to KLM’s extensive International coverage, the intercontinental visitor’s list is not too big, although not tiny either.   The airport’s origin dates back to 1916, when it opened as a military airbase for WW1, gradually losing its military role after the war, with plenty of civilian use. By the time it was captured by the Germans in 1940, it already had four runways at 45-degree angles. It wasn’t long until the airport was rendered useless by multiple bombings, yet soon rebuilt and crowned the main airport of the Netherlands.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, high-resolution ground textures with custom weather maps, detailed surrounding scenery with numerous custom buildings, tridimensional terrain including tunnels and bridges, surrounding photoscenery, animated apron and local road traffic, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, and VDGS (requires SAM).  It’s available on FlyTampa’s Website for $28.00, requiring at least 3.78 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42flw</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Announces Flow for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42flw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639bcd97d166e025c5e168ae_flow1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="43968"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 recently announced Flow, their latest project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an easy and intuitive navigation wheel with many features and multiple customization options, for each user or aircraft. It replaces MSFS’ default toolbar with similar functions and more, including the possibility to convert units on the go. Time and weather control, cameras, door controls, server change, TOD calculator, METAR request, scripting, etc., are demonstrated in the two minute video.   According to the video description, the product will feature three tiers: Flow, Flow Essentials, and Flow Pro. There isn’t enough information on the differences between the tiers (other than what is shown on the teaser), aside from the fact that there will be a free tier with limited features.   It’s said to be coming soon to Orbx Direct. There’s no information about install size or pricing yet.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/impcan</id>
    <title>Impulse Simulations Releases Canberra International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/impcan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639cc4678530475333ab3c72_canberracover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1775547"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Impulse Simulations has recently released their rendition of Canberra International Airport (YSCB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the eight-busiest airport in Australia with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. Being the Capital city, it serves direct flights to all Australian state capitals, and regional airports from the East Coast.   It’s served by FlyPelican (Newcastle, Port Macquarie), Jetstar (Brisbane, Gold Coast, Melbourne), Link Airways (Hobart, Newcastle, Sydney), Qantas (Adelaide, Brisbane, Melbourne, Perth), QantasLink (Adelaide, Brisbane, Cairns, Darwin, Hobart, Melbourne, Sunshine Coast, Sydney), Qatar Airways (Doha, resuming in April 2023), Rex Airlines (Melbourne), and Virgin Australia (Adelaide, Brisbane, Gold Coast, Melbourne). Melbourne is the busiest destination overall, with 1,175,695 passengers handled in 2018. Sydney (953,333) and Brisbane (643,328) are second and third, respectively.   The scenery features realistic ground and apron texturing, realistic night lighting, replicated airside terminal interior, custom jetways, VDGS system (not Xbox compatible), full PBR texturing, custom animations, improved vegetation and grass, detailed static aircraft, custom taxiway lighting and signage, over 50,000 hand placed objects, over 150 custom objects, and 20cm resolution custom imagery.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $23.11, requiring at least 4.11 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflrjp</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews RJ Professional for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflrjp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639ccb3fe8cbc403ae47aa6d_rj1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1806703"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently released a video showcasing the RJ Professional’s Center Console with its all-new avionics in relation to the 146, demonstrating the functionality of each panel, from the radio stack to the flight deck door controls.  It is their first development update since October, where they stated the airplane was undergoing extensive testing to ensure it was behaving just like the real-life counterpart, and the digital displays were alive with the work on the now showcased center console having just finished. The Inertial Reference System (IRS) and the fully-automatic pressurization controller were pending and yet to be demonstrated.  The Avro RJ is an improved version of the British Aerospace 146, which entered production in 1992. It is the most successful British civil jet airliner program, with 387 units (including the 146). Due to its quiet engines, it was ideal for small city-based airports such as London City. Just Flight’s rendition will include all three variants of the airliner: the RJ70 (26.2m long), the RJ85 (28.6m long), and the RJ100 (31m long), along with 25 brand new liveries covering operators from all over the World. There’s no information on the release date or pricing yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for further updates on the RJ Professional and more!Shout out to Petter on Discord for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdsspc</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Releases São Paulo Catarina Executive for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdsspc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639cd2f8b07e136a1cc5e679_cat1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2935330"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently released their rendition of São Paulo Catarina International Executive Airport (SBJH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the first executive airport in Brazil with international status, and only a 30 minute drive away from São Paulo, the biggest city in the country and the nations’ business center.   Designed by Sig Bergamin, a famous brazilian architect, the airport features state-of-the-art terminals and a large hangar area, both using sustainable architectural methods, aiming for ultimate comfort and privacy. The project was aided by ACV (Airport Consulting Vienna), Ramboll (Danish engineering company), ALG (spanish consultancy company), and others (not mentioned by the airport owner’s website). The airport was built to withstand 200 thousand take-offs and landings yearly, including intercontinental executive jets. With a 2,500m long runway, it can easily take a 738 BBJ, for example.   It is the only executive airport in Brazil with authorization to operate flights to New York, London and Paris. It is the sole executive gateway to the country for business fliers.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, modeled and textured with the help of over 3000 photos sent by the airport management, with a performance-friendly approach regarding the interior modeling, bearing brazilian customers in mind. It includes updated satellite imagery, an accurate mesh, and an open hangar. The developer stated plans to update the scenery once the hangars under construction are completed, along with a new taxiway.   It’s available on the GearDown Simulations Store for $10.01.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbbol</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Bolzano Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbbol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639ce656b9acb4125be3f1f4_lipb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2969325"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has just released their rendition of Bolzano Airport (LIPB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a small regional airport in South Tyrol, Northern Italy. The yearly traffic figures sit at less than 20 thousand passengers, with regional carriers like SkyAlps and Luxwing connecting the city to Berlin, Düsseldorf, and Hamburg, 7 times a week (as of December 2022).   In mid-2016, there was a public poll concerning the future of the airport, because the populace was unhappy with it costing chunks of money every year, with an eventual decision to liquidate the operator company and return the license to the Italian authorities, with potential closure in case of inability to find a new operator. Over 120 million euros were spent without reaching the intended result. Three years ago, the South Tyrol government managed to sell the airport to ABD Holding for 3.8 million euros. The new holders went on to extend the runway to 1,462m in mid-2021.   The scenery features realistic HD textures created from on-site photography, an updated layout with the new runway extension, custom static DC-3 and helicopters, main terminal with interior modeling, and a custom ortho.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $16.57, requiring at least 2.74 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fss175</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Previews E175’s Systems for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fss175" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639ced42504128bbf622120f_systems1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1249685"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG (in cooperation with X-Crafts) and AviationLads, have recently previewed the systems on the upcoming Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. In one minute and fifty six seconds of footage, they showcase an APU start, followed by an engine start and an - almost - take-off roll.   According to an AviationLads Facebook Post, the next preview is the last one.   The E175 is part of the Embraer E-Jets family, seating 78 to 88 passengers in different cabin configurations, with a range of 1800 nautical miles on the standard variant. There are 12 operators around the World, with SkyWest being the largest (193 aircraft).   There is still no information regarding system depth, pricing, or availability. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
