<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-02-02T18:24:21.558210+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdscaa</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Previews Campo dos Amarais Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdscaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d3d85d2f64d3db09fb342d_campo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3280059"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently previewed the progress on their rendition of Campo dos Amarais - Prefeito Francisco Amaral State Airport (SDAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving Campinas, the fourteenth most populous city in Brazil.  Despite not having scheduled flights throughout the year, the traffic figures sit at nearly 40 thousand passengers a year, all of that being general aviation, divided between executive jets, air taxis, and student pilots. With a total of 25 hangars and compatibility with nocturnal operations, it’s the ideal business alternative to Viracopos, the main airport in the region. It’s operated by Rede Voa, a private Brazilian airports consortium responsible for sixteen airports scattered around the country. They won the concession to Campo dos Amarais and four airports in the São Paulo state back in March 2017, when the previous owner, DAESP (the Airways Department of São Paulo State), had to give up on most of their airports due to financial problems.  Developed in close contact with the operator (Rede Voa), the scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with an 85% accurate mesh, custom ground textures, custom vegetation, and more.  There’s no information regarding the release date or pricing, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inila1</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Los Angeles International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inila1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d50186a37ae1edfaa71088_la1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3130666"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an update to their rendition of Los Angeles International Airport (KLAX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, reducing the VRAM overhead, adding LOD tweaking for extra performance, control panel options to allow for extra frames, and more.  Los Angeles International Airport (LAX) is the primary international airport serving Los Angeles and the surrounding area. It is one of the busiest airports in the world, with over 87 million passengers passing through in 2019. LAX has nine passenger terminals and serves as a hub for several major airlines, including American, Delta, and United. In addition to domestic and international flights, LAX also offers a variety of transportation options, including buses, trains, and taxis, to help passengers get to and from the airport. A Major renovation and modernization project is currently underway at the airport, which is expected to be completed by 2023, including new terminals, parking structures, and other facilities to enhance the passenger experience.  Update 1.10 aims to improve the airport’s performance, with lowered VRAM consumption, an option to enable and disable features to increase the framerate, lodding on all assets was greatly optimized, removal of duplicate items, and guids were changed to prevent clashing with other iniScene products. The complete changelog follows down below: - Greatly reduced VRAM overhead - LODs for all assets have been revised and tweaked for improved performance - Control panel options to allow performance customisation - Tunnel entrance under 25L/R has been completely reviewed and should no longer impact terrain along Charlie or the T7/T8 stands - Added stop points 42 and 43 along Lima and Kilo - Fixed duplicated items have been removed - Guids have all been changed to prevent clashing with other iniScene products  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $24.82, requiring at least 5.76 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfskuc</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Kuching International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfskuc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d5081985cd49dd3df52a5e_kuching1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="413129"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Kuching International Airport (WBGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Kuching International Airport (KCH) is the main airport serving the city of Kuching and the surrounding area in Sarawak, Malaysia. It is located approximately 10 kilometers south of the city center and offers domestic and international flights. KCH has one terminal building that handles both departures and arrivals and serves as a hub for several airlines including AirAsia and Malaysia Airlines. The airport has undergone several expansions and renovations in recent years to accommodate the growing number of passengers. Amenities include duty-free shops, restaurants, and transportation options such as taxis and buses to take passengers to and from the airport.  The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with custom photoreal terrain, custom jetways, accurate taxiways and ground markings, and custom night lighting.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.21, requiring at least 116 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsrv1</id>
    <title>Sim Works Studio RV-10, Release Info Announced</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsrv1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d511bf9a22c998bd12851b_rv10.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="874119"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SWS has announced important information surrounding the release of their upcoming Vans RV-10 aircraft. The much anticipated Microsoft Flight Sim addon is now set to release on Friday, February, 3rd at 1700 GMT. According to the developers, the RV-10 will retail for €14.99 and will be available for purchase on their website initially, while later availability in other stores will be announced.  Now a little about the upcoming RV-10 and its history:  The Van's RV-10 is a four-seat, single-engine, homebuilt aircraft designed and produced by Van's Aircraft, a U.S.-based manufacturer. It features a low-wing design and a conventional tail layout. The RV-10 is usually powered by a Lycoming IO-540 engine and has a maximum speed of around 200 mph. The RV-10 was first introduced in 2001 and is considered one of the most popular homebuilt aircraft on the market, known for its reliability and ease of construction. The RV-10 kit is sold in both quick-build and standard form, and it can be built as a taildragger or tricycle gear configuration. The RV-10 has also been used in a variety of roles, including personal transportation, flight training, and aerial photography.</summary>
    <published>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thr337</id>
    <title>Thranda Design Releases Cessna C337 Skymaster for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thr337" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d5268327f740e76987d6a6_thranda1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="249679"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Design has recently released their rendition of the Cessna C337 Skymaster for X-Plane 11 and 12, part of their Dynamic Generation Series aircraft. It is a unique light aircraft produced by Cessna Aircraft Company, known for its distinct design, featuring a twin-boom tail configuration and a rear pusher propeller, and a tractor propeller in the front. It was first introduced in 1963 and produced until 1982. The Skymaster was available in piston and turboprop versions, with the latter having a longer range and higher cruising speed. The aircraft also features retractable landing gear, making it versatile for land and water operations. It is a highly sought-after aircraft by enthusiasts and collectors, due to its design and historical significance.  Thranda’s C337 features a fully configurable 3D instrument panel, VR compatibility, interchangeable yoke styles, over 50 instruments to choose from (movable), four panel presets (customizable), full 3D lighting, savable presets, dynamic livery editor, high-resolution PBR materials, a fully modeled Continental IO-320-F front engine, windshield ice and rain effects, and individual functional circuit breakers.   The fly-out menu offers a variety of features for a realistic and customizable flying experience. It includes controls for electric tug, chocks, tie-downs, covers, lights, and the option to enable or disable a Cargo Pod with realistic weight and drag characteristics. Users can also choose to start in a "cold-and-dark" state for realistic startup procedures. The menu also allows for control over landing lights, strobes, beacon, and navigation lights, as well as a detailed weight and balance manager with a visual chart and the ability to save and load configurations. Additionally, users can hide or show individual seats to create a hybrid passenger/cargo version, adjust the field of view, control audio channels in real-time, move the plane around the world with slew control, fine-tune instrument positions, swap pilot and co-pilot seats, and select different yoke styles.   This aircraft boasts detailed and accurate flight dynamics and weight and balance, developed with the help of multiple real-world active Stationair pilots, ensuring a proper "feel" and accurate performance during takeoff, climb, cruise, and landing. The C337 is a twin airplane where the props spin in opposite directions, canceling out torque on the airframe. In the event of a single engine failure, the flight behavior is not greatly affected as the engines are in line and do not produce a net yaw force on the plane. Additionally, tie-downs and chocks are included to keep the plane from moving in high winds. The aircraft also features DynaFeel, which simulates the strength of the control surfaces affected by oncoming air, and how much would be necessary to overcome these forces.  The aircraft features high-fidelity, multi-track sounds with smooth transitions, calculated to minimize "muddy" sounds by using the precise beat frequency for each section. It also includes atmospheric effects, allowing the user to adjust the volume of different aspects of the sound experience in real time. The sounds are divided, with different sonic characteristics for the front and back engine, and panning around the plane in exterior view yields 3D audio effects such as a "blade slapping" sound when viewed perpendicular to the prop. Far-away sounds include aerodynamic interaction effects between the front and rear propeller, and the cockpit buttons and switches each have their own unique sound. The engine also has a cool-down ticking sound based on temperature. The sounds also give clues about what's happening under the hood, and the outside wind intensity is affected by slip and AoA, making the sound louder when the surface area of the fuselage is hit by oncoming wind. Opening doors and windows also lets in outside sounds.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $39.95, requiring at least 1.4 GB of free disk space to install. Shout out to Lazerzen on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/apne33</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews New EFB Features for Upcoming A330</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/apne33" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d59d1d9924b9f06e04e6b6_ascover-min%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2661521"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently made a post on their A330 forum thread with new screenshots and details on the ongoing work with the Electronic Flight Bag, with tweaks on the flight plan display page, a nearly completed performance tab, and more. The charts page will now allow users to display their approach charts in DAY mode regardless of the theme, as seen below:  They have also shown a little bit of the performance tab, which is still being worked on but nearing completion:  The flight plan display makes a reappearance, with tweaks. It was first seen here when Aerosoft previewed the EFB on YouTube.  The saved state makes its first appearance, with a demonstration of a “ready for taxi” state being loaded up. They mention it "seems to work":  They finish it off with two 4K pictures, showing the exterior (cover picture) and cockpit, respectively:  The Airbus A330 is a wide-body twin-aisle airliner, first flown in 1992 and with its commercial two years later. It’s available in several variants, including the A330-200 and A330-300, with the latter being the most popular. The A330 is known for its long-range capabilities and fuel efficiency, seating up to 440 people in a typical two-class configuration.  There’s no information regarding the price or release date yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hpoz</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Poznan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hpoz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d679116132057bbc7d7aaf_poznan1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2370061"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Poznań–Ławica Henryk Wieniawski Airport (EPPO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the seventh busiest airport in Poland with a yearly average of 2 million passengers. Poznan Lawica Airport has a long and rich history dating back to the early 20th century. The first airfield in Poznań was established in 1912 and was used primarily for military purposes. In the 1920s and 1930s, the airport underwent expansion and modernization to accommodate commercial flights. During World War II, the airport was damaged by bombing but rebuilt after the war. In the 1950s and 1960s, the airport underwent further development, with the construction of a new terminal building and the expansion of the runway. The airport continued to grow in the following decades, with increasing numbers of passengers and flights. In recent years, the airport has undergone a major renovation program, with the construction of a new terminal and the expansion of the runway to accommodate larger aircraft. Today, it's a modern and well-equipped airport that plays an important role in the region's transportation network. It’s served by a variety of airlines, including Ryanair, Wizz Air, Lufthansa, and LOT Polish Airlines. Ryanair and Wizz Air are low-cost airlines that offer flights to destinations throughout Europe, while Lufthansa and LOT Polish Airlines are full-service airlines that offer flights to destinations in Europe, Asia, and North America. Other airlines that operate flights to and from the airport include Enter Air, Smartwings, Sun Express, and KLM.  The scenery features an accurate replica of the airport, with correct apron layout and markings, dynamic lighting, terminal interior, PBR materials, and sporting performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.29, requiring at least 1.41 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simhua</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Hua Hin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simhua" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d7bcd7cc3fd232e9b019dd_vtph1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1038685"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Hua Hin Airport (VTPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Hua Hin District in Prachuap Khiri Khan, Thailand.   It’s the 32nd busiest airport in the country with a yearly average of 80 thousand passengers, served by Thai AirAsia with flights to Chiang Mai on Sundays, Wednesdays, and Fridays.   The airport is currently undergoing heavy upgrading, the process of which started in 2018 with the national Department of Airports spending over 3.5 billion baht to improve the airport over five years, with an enlargement of the current passenger terminal (and the construction of a second one), expansion of hangar space, and runway expansion (concluded in 2022). The number of passenger traffic is expected to increase tenfold once the work is finished.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with the new extended and expanded runway and its characteristic slope, custom scenery objects (including the terminal, hangars, tower, and more), moderate terminal interior details, hand-placed taxi signage, custom night lighting, many Hua Hin landmark buildings (more to come in a later update), and hand-crafted ground markings and textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.03, requiring at least 85 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simcph</id>
    <title>SimNord Showcases Progress on Copenhagen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simcph" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d95d63ff424ac4ab5a34ee_cope1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1604017"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimNord has previewed the development progress on their rendition of Copenhagen-Kastrup Airport (EKCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Denmark with over 30 million passengers yearly.   Copenhagen-Kastrup is the main airport serving Copenhagen, Denmark. It was established in 1925 as the city’s first airport and has undergone several expansions. During WW2, it was occupied by German forces and used as a military base. After the war, the airport underwent modernization and became a hub for Scandinavian Airlines. In recent years, Copenhagen Airport has become one of the busiest airports in Northern Europe. It has also been recognized for its sustainable practices and won several awards for its eco-friendly initiatives.  It’s served by numerous airlines, international and regional, including Scandinavian Airlines (SAS), Norwegian Air Shuttle, easyJet, KLM Royal Dutch Airlines, and Lufthansa. In addition, the airport also serves as a hub for several low-cost carriers, such as Ryanair and Wizz Air. With its strategic location and well-developed infrastructure, Copenhagen-Kastrup Airport offers a wide range of direct and connecting flights to destinations all over the World, including cities in Europe, Asia, North America, and Africa.  The new development update focuses on Concourse A and its surrounding buildings, which are nearing completion.   There’s no information on pricing or release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! Shout out to PopFizzels for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsaau</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 1 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsaau" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d99dd8aecde94372e05ce4_aau2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1107672"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has released the first installment of the Aircraft &amp; Avionics update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing several key issues in the game, along with major upgrades to the GNS 430W/GNS 530 W GPS units, and revamped avionics on many of the default aircraft.  The update resolves a problem with unflyable helicopters when users had the legacy flight model realism settings set to less than 100%. It also repairs a control loss issue with the Pitch axis on helicopters when the anti-stall assist was turned on. The update also addresses the issue of snow covering 100% of airport tarmac and roads, as well as fixing the problem with the deletion of VOR, NDB, and waypoints every time the DeleteNavAtAirport was used. Additionally, the update resolves an issue with secondary aerials being overridden by Bing aerial on terrain with photogrammetry and fixes the terrain level of detail issue on Xbox.  The GNS 430W/GNS 430W GPS units were massively upgraded, introducing a comprehensive visual overhaul that provides a more accurate font, symbology, look, operation, and feel. The update also brings advanced flight plan support, including the ability to handle complex departure, arrival, and approach procedures such as arcs, holds, procedure turns, and more, all with correct real-unit limitations. The GPS system now supports full RNAV simulation, including LPV, LP, LNAV/VNAV, and +V vertical guidance during approaches. Additionally, the GPS satellite and SBAS simulation have been improved, with real satellite positions based on orbital mechanics and accurate SBAS coverage areas. The VNAV profile calculator page and associated reminders/alerts have also been added, along with support for missed approaches and missed approach holds. The system also includes a fully specification-accurate ADS-B-based Traffic Avoidance System, more accurate map symbology, procedure previews, and the ability to enter waypoints, navaids, and direct-tos via keyboard. Customization options, such as metric/imperial unit settings and map data field settings, found on real units are also available. The update also includes satellite weather overlay support (NEXRAD). These units have been added to the following aircraft in AAU1:   The avionics system of the Cessna Citation CJ4 underwent a major upgrade to provide a more authentic and immersive experience for pilots. The visual aspect of the system has been completely overhauled to accurately reflect the look, feel, and operation of the CJ4 avionics. The system now supports independent MFD and FMS operation, advanced flight plan features, and a VNAV system with customizable constraints and smoothing. The autopilot system has also been upgraded with additional armable modes, and the aircraft features a full specification-accurate TCAS II traffic system. Other improvements include a complete Crew Alerting System, accurate takeoff and landing speed calculations, integrated engine FADEC systems, and enhanced display modes. The flight model has also been improved, with enhancements to takeoff and landing performance, fuel consumption accuracy, and handling. In addition, the engine and interior sound effects have been refined to provide a more realistic experience.  The Garmin G3000 and G5000 Avionics Suites have been updated to offer a comprehensive and realistic avionics experience. The visual aspect of the system has been overhauled with accurate font, symbology, and operation, and includes a faithful representation of the Garmin Touch Controller (GTC) complete with UI animations. The flight plan support has been advanced to include features like arcs, radius-to-fix, intercepts, holds, and procedure turns. Custom waypoints, including lat/lon, point/bearing/distance, and present position, are also supported. The VNAV system has been improved with two (aircraft-dependent) styles of coupling: Simple VNAV with descent path VNAV only and advanced VNAV with climb constraint and descent path VNAV, editable constraints, and vertical path smoothing. The PFDs and MFDs have full split-pane support, and the system includes a comprehensive traffic system implementation with Garmin TIS, TAS, and TCAS-II. The avionics suite also supports multiple layout styles, including horizontal or vertical GTCs, and offers a multitude of customization options including measurement units, V-speed bugs, and HSI moving map. The system has JavaScript plugin support for loading custom displays, navigation, and pages, and simulates aircraft systems and instrument styling. Additionally, the system includes AHRS alignment and startup sequence.  The complete changelog is available here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/awlgsi</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases General Santos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/awlgsi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d9a6d5ef3a10e0b446e66f_santos1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4142654"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Airwil Sceneries has recently released their rendition of General Santos International Airport (RPMR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the greater area of Soccsksargen in the Philippines. It’s the largest airport (in total area, not traffic) on the island of Mindanao, transporting a yearly average of one million passengers.   Inaugurated in 1996, built to replace the old and much smaller Buayan Airport, funded by the United States government and their own Department of Transportation and Communication, occupying 5,994,577 square meters of land in Barangay Fatima, just 14 kilometers away from the center of General Santos. It was then upgraded in 2017, with a facelift on the terminal that took four years to finish.   It’s served by Cebu Pacific (Cebu, Iloilo, and Manila), PAL Express (Iloilo), and Philippine Airlines (Manila).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of General Santos International as it currently stands, with more than 100 custom handcrafted objects, a realistic control tower, highly-detailed landside, custom ground textures, accurate depiction of the runway, Filipino houses, jeepneys, and buses, along with GSX and FSLTL compatibility.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.04, requiring at least 88 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shadla</id>
    <title>Shadescene Releases Labuan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shadla" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d9ab8be1a7a8e6c1a1b969_lab1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1277367"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Shadescene has recently released their rendition of Labuan Airport (WBKL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the federal territory of Labuan in Malaysia. With a yearly average of 600,000 passengers, it lies within the 20 busiest airports in the country and features in the top 10 for cargo.  The airport has a long and rich history, dating back to World War II when it was used as a military airfield by the British Royal Air Force. In the post-war period, the airport became a key hub for commercial and industrial activities, serving as a gateway to the island and the surrounding region. In the 1990s, the airport underwent modernization effort to upgrade its facilities and accommodate the growing demand for air transportation in the region. Today, Labuan Airport is considered an important regional hub, connecting passengers from various parts of Malaysia and beyond to the island of Labuan and its many attractions.  There were plans to transform Labuan into a regional hub for connecting flights within the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), later postponed due to perceived unsuitability. It’s served by AirAsia (KUL only) and Malaysia Airlines with frequent flights to Kuala Lumpur International, Kota Kinabalu, and Miri. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, an animated radar tower, moderate terminal interior details, hand-placed taxiways and runway light system, dynamic lighting, and hand-crafted ground markings and textures. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.80, requiring at least 125 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/car181</id>
    <title>Carenado Releases Piper PA28-181 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/car181" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63da7786728b024567bdb1e1_arch1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="50545"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Established developer Carenado has released their Piper PA28-181 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release follows Carenado's other single-engine piston aircraft products and brings another well-known training aircraft to the sim.  ‍ The Piper PA28-181 is an evolution of one of the most popular training platforms in the world, with over 51,000 PA28 family aircraft being built in the almost 60-year production run. The Archer II features a Lycoming 180HP engine, a max speed of 154 KTS, and a range of 670 NM.  Features of this aircraft include;  ‍ ‍ This is an appealing addition to any general aviation enthusiast’s hangar. This aircraft is currently available for 19.99 USD and can only be found in the Microsoft Flight Simulator In-Game Store.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/breaking-ini-announce-an-225-for-msfs</id>
    <title>Breaking: Microsoft Announces Antonov AN-225 in Cooperation with iniBuilds </title>
    <updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/breaking-ini-announce-an-225-for-msfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dac683833efb0722aeb239_BANNER.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="938152"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Established developers iniBuilds have just now revealed their latest project, the famous Antonov AN-225 for Microsoft flight simulator. The Antonov An-225 Mriya was a Ukrainian six-engined super-heavy cargo aircraft, and one of the most significant cargo aircraft in the world. Developed by the Antonov Design Bureau, it was initially designed to transport the Soviet space shuttle and has since been used to transport oversized cargo, including disaster relief supplies, industrial equipment, and even military hardware. The news, which was revealed in a Livestream has shed light on the expected release date and other details about the upcoming aircraft. INI has stated that their intended release date for PC is around the 27th of February with the Xbox version coming around the same time as Sim update 12. The significance of the intended release date is to line up with the date that the real AN225 was destroyed in the ongoing war. Microsoft has also revealed that the aircraft will cost around $20 with all proceeds going toward assisting in the rebuild of the mighty AN225 in real life. It was also revealed that iniBuilds had the opportunity to meet the crew of the real AN225 in order to prepare the upcoming release and make it as realistic as possible.  The aircraft will feature a detailed model of both the exterior and interior along with an incredibly in-depth payload system which will allow detailed payload configurations, this will be managed through an EFB-type system. We can see from the images revealed in the live stream just how far along the project is, and how stunning it looks.  Threshold will endeavour to keep you updated as we learn more information!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aaudc6</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates DC-6 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aaudc6" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dbc7c29e481ef99faad793_dc61.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2678907"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued an update to their Douglas DC-6 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including the new Working Title GNS 430, flight model and autopilot improvements, and other bug fixes.   The Douglas DC-6 is a piston-powered airliner and cargo aircraft built by the Douglas Aircraft Company from 1946 to 1958, intended as a military transport near the end of WW2, but was eventually reworked to enter the commercial transport market, a task which was done rather successfully with over 700 units built. With its 2400hp radial engines, the DC-6B could fly nonstop from the eastern United States to Europe but required a fuel stop on the way back because of the winds.   The new update is currently available on PMDG’s Operations Center, with the marketplace edition still pending approval by Microsoft. As mentioned by Randazzo in the update announcement post, many of the changes are small and focused on details, with the highlights being the implementation of the Working Title GNS 430 for the GPS and autopilot, flight model stability alterations and improvements, autopilot tuning, the increment of resolution and sharpness of some overhead panel placards, and more. The complete list follows down below: ‍ ‍  The DC-6 is available on the PMDG Store and the in-game Marketplace for $59.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsfsr</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios along with FSReborn Announces the Boeing 727-200 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsfsr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dbee4007c5c3bc93c0ba18_Boeing_727-200_N474DA_(P49355).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="541634"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. On a Twitch stream with streamer “TheFlyingFabio,” SimWorks Studios and FSReborn have announced their plans to collaborate on a Boeing 727-200 advanced for Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS). The Boeing 727 marks a large step for the two companies in MSFS, with the two previously sticking to smaller propeller aircraft, this is the first time the developers have ventured into the jet space within the simulator. The original announcement can be viewed below. SimWorks Studios have established itself as a well-trusted aircraft developer within MSFS, with the releases of their Kodiak 100, Vans RV-14, Zenith CH701 STOL, and other upcoming projects. FSReborn have also garnered a lot of respect with their Sting S4, a highly detailed propeller aircraft for MSFS.  Unfortunately, no further information is known, and it is unclear how detailed the aircraft will be. However, the developer did say “the key point is to do it right.” For any further developments that arise, Threshold will make sure to keep you updated.</summary>
    <published>2023-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
