<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-09-07T18:29:55.199372+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/keaant</id>
    <title>Kea Skies Releases Auckland Narrated Tour for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/keaant"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b8a38a14819b23b2000157_1%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Kea Skies has recently released their Auckland Narrated Scenic Tour, a narrated, guide-led flight for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The package centres on a 90-minute route out of Ardmore, with a local guide providing history and narration. If you have ever circled Auckland’s skyline and wondered what you were looking at, this aims to supply the context, not just the view. The tour is structured, with On-screen markers and heading cues that point out landmarks as they come into view, while audio triggers roll in time with each point of interest. Expect a circuit that touches Manukau Harbour, the Waitākere Ranges, the CBD and Sky Tower, the Hauraki Gulf islands, and the Hunua Ranges, before returning to Ardmore. You can read the feature list here: For the full announcement, visit Kea Skies’ website. Auckland Narrated Scenic Tour is available on Kea Skies’ website for $7.99, as well as on SimMarket. Threshold will keep you updated on all the latest in flight simulation! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mdsepu</id>
    <title>TFDi Design Shares Work on MD-11 Update, Xbox/MSFS 2024 support</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mdsepu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b8b31512480ab94e53eb44_ext_klm_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TFDi Design has posted a sizeable development update on its MD-11, covering progress across art, systems, and the new Extended Simulation package. While the original 60-day target for MSFS 2024 support has now slipped, the aircraft is receiving a significant visual overhaul, enhanced systems depiction, and a clearer roadmap, towards both MSFS 2024 and Xbox. As previously teased, the aircraft has received a major art overhaul, starting with a completely rebuilt exterior model. Animations have been corrected, surface textures reworked, and missing details have been filled in. Service ports now carry legible labels, while flap and slat internals animate with a new layer of mechanical fidelity, with more physical parts depicted. Rivets, dirt, and fine panel work have also seen major attention, overall raising the visual fidelity of the aircraft. Furthermore, Pratt &amp; Whitney engine options will be released alongside the upcoming art update. Behind the scenes, the throttle control system and engine simulation have also been reworked. Moving to the interior, the cabin has seen a similar overhaul of visual fidelity, being almost entirely reworked. Included are new textures, remodelled geometry, and glass/rain surface effects on the windows, with the team also hinting at a few surprises yet to be shown.  In the cockpit, smaller missing items are being addressed, including the manual gear handle, oxygen test buttons, and a few immersion items, including openable cockpit windows. Another large iteration on the code side is the Extended Simulation package. TFDi has implemented more than 160 failure scenarios, with user controls to adjust likelihood and scope, so that IVAO and VATSIM flying remains viable.  A new maintenance system has replaced the instant “fix all” pop-ups with maintenance flows, repairs, and routine service checks. Each airframe also builds its own local log over time, tracking its own maintenance history. When it comes to core systems, PROF descent logic has been overhauled for steadier vertical profiles, step climbs now handle multiple S/C and T/C points, and support for ATO waypoints has been added. A custom simulation for oil, vibration, and EGT has also been implemented across both P3D and MSFS, alongside display improvements and many bug fixes. While the art update and Extended Simulation package are nearly complete for MSFS PC, work on FS24 is taking longer than expected. TFDi plans to split the model where necessary, adopt the sim’s new texture streaming format, and integrate FS24-native features, so the aircraft feels at home in the new platform. Xbox releases are expected to land alongside FS24 PC, once testing is complete. There is still no firm release date.  TFDi reports that QA feedback on the refreshed model and Extended Simulation has been positive, and the team maintains that it remains focused on delivering the MD-11 as "originally envisioned". The team admits the delay is not ideal, but states the wait will be "worth it", and TFDi characterises the remaining work as a matter of “a few weeks”.  ‍ For the full details, you can read TFDi's development update on their website. Threshold will keep you updated on all the latest. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdf33a</id>
    <title>Thranda Design Releases F33A Bonanza for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdf33a"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b8d7b62774feb8e7ce649b_Thranda_F33-2025-08-0216.26.30.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Design has recently released the F33A Bonanza for X-Plane 12, positioning the classic Beechcraft as the next step in the studio’s Dynamic Generation Series.  As with other aircraft in the Dynamic Generation Series, the Bonanza’s panel is not fixed in place. More than 60 instruments can be mixed and matched, moved between pilot and co-pilot positions, and saved as reusable presets. Support is included for RealityXP, as well as TDS GTN 650/750 units, GNS 430/530 swaps, and even G1000-style layouts, allowing the aircraft to be configured to suit various training needs, vintage tastes, or IFR touring preferences. Paintwork is handled in-sim, through Thranda’s dynamic livery editor. Liveries can be adjusted on the fly, with colour selection, roughness and metallic variables, and optional wear layers, before being rasterised to the textures for later use.  The EFB provides options such as covers, chocks, doors, and lighting, a visual weight and balance tool, ground handling, a panel layout editor, and quality-of-life apps, including checklists, a logbook view, and AviTab integration, when installed. Tip tanks can also be toggled from the EFB, with corresponding changes to weight, drag, and handling. Under the skin, the model is built around 8k textures and full PBR materials, with per-instrument post-lighting and rain effects. An FMOD sound set is used for sounds, layering cockpit clicks, airflow cues, and exterior perspectives, aiming to reflect changes in load, slip, and angle of attack. The Continental IO-520-B piston engine is modelled with detailed performance envelopes, and the electrical system includes buses, tie breakers, and failure modes. Thranda says flight dynamics were tuned with input from real-world F33A pilots, so numbers for take-off, climb, cruise, and landing are intended to sit close to the book, while still leaving room for the Bonanza’s quirks, when pushed. For upkeep, support forr the SkunkCraft Updater is in place to handle incremental changes. Feature-rich Universal Electronic Flight Bag (UEFB) with pop-up/pop-out capability with the following features: For full feature information, visit the F33A's product page. The Thranda Design F33A Bonanza is available via the X-Plane.org Store for $37.95, currently on a 16% discount. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1230</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.3.0 Beta, Weather Update, Aircraft Rework</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1230"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b9902421a2d9942ee67742_WXRUpdate_TItle_3%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has just rolled out the first beta of X-Plane 12.3.0, and it is one of the most ambitious updates we have seen yet. Headlining the release is a fully simulated weather radar system, alongside a major overhaul of the default Airbus A330, and a bundle of new tools for both pilots and developers. The new weather radar is available across several default aircraft, including the Boeing 737-800, Airbus A330-300, Citation X, and Baron 58. Being fully simulated, the system is capable of tilt and gain control, turbulence detection, ground clutter suppression and more, with accurate attenuation and reflections. For GA flyers, the X1000 GPS now integrates radar returns directly onto the display, and the Baron has received an open-source Bendix RDR2000 implementation. This new functionality, however, only integrates with the default fleet at launch, where third-party developers can integrate the new technology with their own updates, should they want to. As part of this beta, Laminar Research has also reworked the native Enhanced Ground Proximity Warning System (EGPWS), which should result in better terrain and obstacle alerts, when flying into challenging conditions. Combined with the weather radar, situational awareness takes a serious leap forward in 12.3.0. The default Airbus A330 has not been left out either, and the widebody was given a “complete overhaul”. The exterior now sports micro-textures, subtle dirt and weathering effects, and even animated engine wobble. Inside, both cockpit and cabin lighting have been rebuilt with backlit instruments, spill lighting, dynamic cabin lamps, and even an auto-adjusting cabin brightness function. Moving on to systems, work has been done on refining VNAV logic, flight control laws, and autopilot behaviour, while also introducing a functional SEC F-PLN: Secondary Flight Plan Page.  Another big addition is Synthetic Vision for the X1000 avionics, a feature widely used in modern GA avionics. This system can paint a 3D representation of terrain, runways, and obstacles directly onto the Primary Flight Display, ensuring safer low-visibility operations. Not content with just systems and avionics, Laminar has also added a new, hand-crafted rendition of Dubai International Airport (OMDB) in the United Arab Emirates. The airport features custom terminal buildings and detailed surroundings, making the world’s busiest international hub a more authentic stopover for long-haul operations in the sim. Another subtle addition in is the new Engine Health system, this being a fully native wear-and-tear implementation. Here, developers can assign different “ages” to each engine at load, so one might behave like a well-worn unit with 7.7 years behind it, while the other is a fresher 3.2 years old. This results in small variations in spool-up times, fuel flow, and overall efficiency, between the two powerplants.  Elsewhere, X-Plane 12.3.0 now introduces the option to load historical weather conditions up to a year in the past, allowing real-world flights or test scenarios to be recreated under authentic conditions. Scenery developers have also gained some new tools, including vegetation annotations for 3D objects, updated ground textures, and fresh airport assets. For cockpit builders, avionics displays, such as the G1000 and G530, can now be assigned directly to hardware screens, rather than pop-ups. The G-Loaded Camera now comes with an intensity slider, and a command to suspend the effect altogether, based on user feedback.  You can read the feature list below: For the full list of fixes, features, and improvements, you can check out the complete release notes on the official X-Plane website. X-Plane 12.3.0 is now available for all who opt into the public beta. Steam users can join via the “beta” branch, while Laminar Direct customers can tick the beta box in the X-Plane 12 installer. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ss3tct</id>
    <title>SamScene3D Releases Tokyo City Times for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ss3tct"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b9f8598f8435ecd49d2147_tk05_3151342a-0f17-4d23-8685-aa0792078e35_1600x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SamScene3D has taken the wraps off Tokyo City Times, a new cityscape add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, that reimagines Japan’s capital and its neighbour, Yokohama. The package includes over 500 handcrafted buildings, new landmarks, and more. SamScene3D describes the project as a redesign of the Tokyo and Yokohama metropolitan areas, rebuilding missing structures and fixing artefacts in the default scenery. Bridges, rivers, and textures have been cleaned up, while dozens of iconic locations have been modelled from scratch. Expect detailed JR Railway stations at Shibuya, Shinjuku, Ikebukuro, Ginza, and Ueno, as well as shopping complexes, hotels, museums, banks, and hospitals spread across the city. Haneda Airport also sees its surroundings improved, with bespoke buildings. Helicopter pilots will find multiple landable rooftops across Tokyo City, while Yokohama comes bundled as a bonus area. Most eye-catching is the inclusion of the life-size animated Gundam statue on Yokohama Bay. The real-world version may have already been dismantled, but in MSFS, it stands tall, once again. The scenery features custom night lighting, blending hand-placed assets with MSFS’s photogrammetry, to create a vibrant, lived-in Tokyo after dark. Tokyo City Times is available from the SamScene3D store for $19.99 USD (tax included), as well as other merchants, such as Contrail, Orbx and SimMarket. Owners of the developer’s previous Tokyo Landmarks Enhanced will receive a $5 discount upon purchasing. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimord</id>
    <title>Nimbus Simulations Previews Chicago O’Hare Update for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimord"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b9fee24155ffa22d908e7c_539608604_1322550685931796_8116617624974369642_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulations has recently shared fresh previews of their Chicago O’Hare International Airport (KORD), and its upcoming update, courtesy of the official X-Plane account. Currently out for X-Plane 11 only, the new images show the airport in development for the X-Plane 12 platform. As one of the busiest hubs in the world and the most connected airport in the United States, O’Hare is a major undertaking. Nimbus appears to be tackling the project with an eye for scale and detail, drawing on years of experience with the airport through earlier versions, released for X-Plane. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg777su3</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777 Lineup for MSFS 2024 </title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg777su3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670074421902159c8c578804_randy5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently issued a new update for their 777 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, addressing LOD issues introduced with SU 3. Furthermore, they have also provided a new development update on their upcoming 737NG conversion for the new platform. Due to PMDG’s decision to wait until SU 3 was out to ultimately work on a fix, as Microsoft kept changing things around during the beta, it took a while longer than expected, but they are currently testing everything, and they should all be out by the weekend at the latest. ‍ The update might take a while to land in the marketplace due to an issue with texture corruption that has yet to be fully mitigated, as they don’t know the root cause. There is a temporary way to “fix” the issue by going to the EFB and repairing the tires.  ‍ The 777-200LR’s marketplace release is also being held back due to the texture corruption issue, and they hope to push it for intake before the weekend. ‍ The long-awaited sound updates for the 777 lineup should be coming soon, with new features, layers, and proper balancing to make the sound as convincing as possible. It’s “the best sounds they have ever produced,” according to Randazzo, PMDG’s founder. “We have really captured the character and vibrancy of the engines and added a bunch of new sounds from the aircraft flight deck and cabin environment that we think you will really enjoy”, he concluded. The 737-800’s MSFS 2024 conversion is nearing completion, and they plan on handing it to their beta testers on Thursday evening (yesterday?), and they expect a quick but robust testing, meaning it should not take long. The build will include several new features, like openable cockpit windows, an openable cockpit door, and “other goodies”. The initial release will be the -800, as it’s the most popular model, and the rest will follow shortly after. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/austoo</id>
    <title>AUscene Releases Toowoomba Wellcamp Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/austoo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ba6c44e688d181d603ed0f_too1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. AUscene has recently released their rendition of Toowoomba Wellcamp Airport (YBWW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Wellcamp, in Queensland, Australia, and has a yearly average of 157,000 passengers. The airport’s history is fairly recent, with its construction beginning in April 2013 with an ambitious timeframe: ready by October 2014. Surely enough, by November 2014, the airport was already getting its first scheduled action with Qantas, establishing a route between Wellcamp and Sydney. QantasLink currently serves it by offering flights to Sydney. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, featuring high-quality models, high-resolution aerial imagery, over 200 custom assets, custom ground clutter, custom vehicles, custom ground textures, realistic PBR textures, custom vegetation placement, and more. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $22.16, requiring at least 4.43 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctfa50</id>
    <title>Contrail Shares Development Update on Falcon 50 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctfa50"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb15bc9466d872618e4d52_FlightSimulator2024_FSjGnYnxD1_76daefb2-83fb-4c31-8e58-0b805ccfe780_1080x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Last month, Contrail published the second development update on its upcoming Dassault Falcon 50 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, offering us a glimpse at the current stage of development. The biggest milestone stated so far is that the flight model and sound package have wrapped their first development phase. The next step will see the aircraft evaluated by real-world FA50 pilots, who will put performance and fidelity under the microscope. Contrail says this testing will be crucial in ensuring the Falcon 50 behaves and sounds as close to reality as possible. Avionics and core systems are also nearing completion, while the walkaround mode in MSFS 2024 is already functional, complete with chocks, pitot and engine covers. For simmers looking ahead to MSFS 2024, the Falcon 50 will use the default EFB, but Contrail is adding its own custom app for weight and balance, ground services, and more, with full Navigraph integration baked in. Interestingly, Contrail also shed some light on the cabin blinds, which can be adjusted manually or left to move automatically as time and altitude change. It is a small but telling detail that hints at the level of immersion the team is aiming for. First announced back at FSExpo 2025, the Falcon 50 project is shaping up to be an ambitious project, this being Contrail's first in-house aircraft. With testing about to begin, and a targeted release for this year, the classic French trijet looks to be moving steadily toward the finish line. We'll keep you updated on the Contrail FA50, and future developments! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff7rel</id>
    <title>FlightFactor 777V2 Leaves Beta Phase, Details Future Roadmap</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff7rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb1b9254391719e12cc24d_777-200ER_xp12-2025-07-2303_29_27.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After more than a year in open beta, FlightFactor has finally confirmed that its flagship 777 v2 has shed the beta tag, with the first release candidate of version 2.1.0. In practice, this means each future update will now have a stable, roll-backable build for those who value reliability, while development continues at the same pace, with fixes, refinements, and new features. Version 2.1.0 itself is a sizeable step forward. Alongside numerous fixes, it introduces a suite of training scenarios, including intercepts, TCAS events, UPRT drills, and windshear encounters, giving simmers more tools to sharpen their flying skills. Other highlights include gear door unsafe lights, a new keyboard input for the EFB performance calculator, and a clutch coupling sound. Lighting has been refined with reduced nav, strobe, and beacon brightness, while a host of bugs, from SimBrief import quirks, to emergency lighting issues, have been addressed.  The full changelog follows below: 2.1.0 Read the full release notes here. The team says the aircraft has now reached the internal milestones required to be considered “mature,” and attention has now shifted to the future roadmap. Planned additions include further engine options for the Extended Edition, deeper FMC capability (with winds and an alternate page), tighter integration of CPDLC, ACARS, EFB, and FMC, and optimised display rendering, with improved Zink compatibility. Quality-of-life updates for the EFB’s Charts and Document Viewer apps are also on the horizon. On the airframe side, FlightFactor has reiterated that additional variants are coming, including the -300ER, Freighter, and -200LR, with the first two having already been teased, during the summer months. A new weather radar is also planned, powered by the new X-Plane weather API introduced in the 12.3.0 beta.  You can read FlightFactor's full roadmap here. Support, bug tracking, and community discussion remain centred on the 777 Club on X-Plane.org, with a dedicated forum for the v2 Ultimate. With the beta label removed, the focus now is on steady iteration, broader variant coverage, and completing long-requested systems. The FlightFactor 777V2 is available for purchase on the X-Plane.org store for $89.00, requiring at least 7 GB of free disk space to install. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atelux</id>
    <title>Atelic Releases Luxembourg Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atelux"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb3a5f083a00c5cb28dfdb_u_4402c455-ee71-4e86-ae6e-7324d3e5d585_1600x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Atelic has recently released Luxembourg Airport (ELLX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, featuring an up-to-date rendition of the major 747 hotspot. Expect the full landside and airside treatment: a fully modelled terminal interior, a sloped 4,000-metre runway, custom jetways, authentic signage, and a tidy night environment.  If cargo is your thing, this is the home base for Cargolux, and a very busy European freight hub, featuring detailed hangars and the appropriate modelled logistics centres. Luxair’s network gives plenty of passenger routes, with Luxair’s side of the airport also modelled in detail. There is even an animated airport tram with working signals, plus key landmarks around the field, to make the approaches into Luxembourg City even more enjoyable. Ground textures show wear and rubbering, the tower and two GA hangars have interiors, and the package rounds things out with bespoke clutter, vehicles, and vegetation.  The scenery features high-quality PBR throughout, accurate terrain profiling, and custom roads, so taxiway flow and the feel of the apron are consistent with the real ELLX. The full feature list follows below: Atelic’s Luxembourg Airport is available through Contrail for $16.43 (excluding taxes). You’ll also find it on the iniBuilds Store, simMarket, and OrbxDirect. Whichever shop you choose, a single purchase includes both MSFS 2020 and 2024 versions. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/35a180</id>
    <title>Flysimware Updates Learjet 35A for MSFS 2020/2024, Including New Boris Sounds</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/35a180"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb45da598f5b9e1ec1bf1d_340832_L35_46.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flysimware has released two updates for its Learjet 35A in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, adding a sound pack from renowned Boris Audio Works, as well as several fixes. Version 1.8.0 introduces a brand-new Garrett TFE731-2 sound set by renowned Boris Audio Works, alongside updated logic for RPM, and trim clacker cues in MSFS 2024, a tidier ambient-occlusion pass on the throttles, and a lower bleed-air volume. It also tidies several long-standing quirks, including the control-wheel master switch not disabling trim, a gear-horn edge case after electrical loss, a copilot NAV/GPS mode snag after adding the GNS430, and the right turbine’s N2 hundredths drum, reading above 100%. Hot on its heels of the first release, version 1.8.1 builds on the audio refresh with reverser sounds from Boris, improves base landing and ground-roll effects, and trims bleed-air volume for a second time. More importantly, it addresses a flame-out and fuel-transfer issue, triggered by an Asobo aircraft editor bug, with Flysimware confirming a fix is now in place. Below are the full changelogs for both updates: Updates: Bugs: ================= Updates: Bugs: As a reminder, the Learjet 35A features custom gauges, 4K PBR textures, interactive ambience, and multiple avionics options, including PMS50 and TDS GTN 750 integrations, the Garmin GNS 530, and an AS330 fit. A tablet covers checklists, state saving, fuel and payload, weather, and configuration, while exterior details include chocks, plugs, tie-downs, and icing effects. The Learjet 35A is available on the Flysimware store for $39.99, including taxes, with listings also on simMarket and the in-sim Marketplace.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350115</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350115"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb63dcdd32a6ba83221cf7_iniA350updatePost115.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released v1.1.5 of its A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, marking another step forward in stability and polish for the long-haul twinjet. This update is heavily focused on squashing bugs and improving reliability. A wide range of WASM crash scenarios have been fixed, including issues tied to autosaves, rollouts, and go-arounds. Flight management has also received attention, with improvements to speed targets, climb performance in hot conditions, descent predictions, and ECAM logic. Avionics consistency has been tightened too, covering everything from TCAS behaviour to HUD symbols and ECAM displays. Alongside stability fixes, iniBuilds has slipped in new quality-of-life updates and features. The Onboard Information System (OIS) now supports night-time LIDO charts, while additional refinements to flight displays, TAWS alerts, and autopilot behaviour make day-to-day operation smoother. Visual adjustments to SU3 LOD handling and animation corrections have also been done, and the soundscape now features better cabin callouts. Perhaps most notably, v1.1.5 also introduces Beyond ATC CPDLC support.  As always, the full changelog follows below: V1.1.5SYSTEMS ⚙️ADDED: Beyond ATC CPDLC supportFIXED: WASM crash when reapplying autopilot after touch and go at LFBO 32LFIXED: WASM crash when loading autosaveFIXED: WASM crash during rollout phaseFIXED: WASM crash due to BTV disengagementFIXED: WASM crash + CTD on XboxFIXED: Flight control test – elevator display reaches full deflection before sidestickFIXED: Managed speed target continues to jumpFIXED: GA-Soft not targeting 2000ft/min  on initial climbFIXED: T-P estimated time becoming false after ADESFIXED: Engine underperformance in climb in hot conditionsFIXED: Block/Flight-time not persisting after autosave loadFIXED: REC MAX FL below OPT in edge casesFIXED: Loss of control on go-aroundFIXED: EFOB prediction during descent phaseFIXED: VLS not masked in ALTN or DIR LAWFIXED: Offset behavior protocol tweaksFIXED: F-PLN INFO menu remains open when changing F-PLNFIXED: HDG SEL: Current heading not captured during turnFIXED: TAWS messages missing from PFDFIXED: Brake pressure green bars displaced on ECAMFIXED: Phantom TOC symbols appearing on NDFIXED: Blue VD range staple angled incorrectly to flightpathFIXED: HUD latched symbol remains when not in DES modeFIXED: PFD altitude ticks disappearing during climbFIXED: Pressing SEC in KCCU not always showing SEC INDEX, SEC 1FIXED: Incorrect SEC page opens from ACTIVE F-PLNFIXED: Active hold showing as white instead of greenFIXED: DES PERF page missing speed restrictionsFIXED: DES PERF PRED TO value flickeringFIXED: Previous/old D-ATIS subpage behavior updatedFIXED: BTV shown as engaged on FMA during float/bounce when braking not activeFIXED: PFD Switching behavior feedback from earlier versionsFIXED: TCAS RA warnings not disappearing from alt tapeFIXED: Text overlay on ATC COMM pageFIXED: OIS on Center button display logicFIXED: Metric- Selected Alt does not update in ALT CRZ modeFIXED Missing ABEAM button on pilot waypointsFIXED: VOR Autotuning inputting wrong freqsFIXED: FO TERR display inopFIXED: Manual UTC does not update predicted timeFIXED: VSD behaviour in PLAN modeFIXED: SEC PLAN logic with PD waypointsFIXED: VPA incorrect on ILS approaches great than 3 deg.FIXED: Cannot edit approach course on NAVIADS pageFIXED: FO HUD wind info missing ART 🎨FIXED: SU3 LOD changesFIXED: THS not animating OIS💻FIXED: C&amp;D: HUD is ON by defaultFIXED: RESET BRAKE TEMP function addedADDED: Nighttime LIDO Charts SOUND 🔊FIXED: “Cabin Ready for Landing” callout plays post-departure If you want to read the full update post, you can do so on the iniBuilds forums. Version 1.1.5 is available now via the iniManager, free for existing owners. New customers can purchase the iniBuilds A350 Airliner through the iniBuilds Store for $80.59, requiring 13.05 GB of free storage to install. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini340devu2</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares New Development Update for their Airbus A340-300</title>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini340devu2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb72c19c0635307a81a413_gulf.png.41861ae39501d48194b57abff263c2e0.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently provided updates on the development of their Airbus A330-300 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The engines, which previously spun clockwise, have now been corrected to spin counterclockwise. In addition, iniBuilds has improved the wing flex, making it more sensitive and reducing the amount of flex during takeoff. Videos showcasing these advancements were also included. Additionally, iniBuilds has been updating the ES1 Displays to enhance the authentic CRT experience. They have also improved the weather effects by adding wipeable rain masks to the windscreen, along with other existing effects like engine condensation. The slides have also improved, visually deploying automatically when the doors are armed, just like in real life. According to iniBuilds, the flight model of the A340 has been developed from scratch using MSFS 2024's latest aerodynamic systems. iniBuilds states that the handling of crosswinds, sideslip behaviour, and drag modelling should be more accurate thanks to the fuselage object implementation, a new feature that allows the simulator to take into account the entire shape of the aircraft. The aircraft should also handle better on the ground, due to MSFS 2024’s new ground model, which, according to inibuild, gives the aircraft a more direct and weighty feel on the ground. Improvements have also been made to nose wheel inputs, meaning that overly aggressive inputs while taxiing can cause skids and even leave behind marks on the taxiway. The engine simulation of the A340 now simulates EGT, fuel flow, FADEC behaviour, oil pressure, and consumption, along with an enhanced thrust model that accurately reflects the aircraft’s notably underpowered performance. iniBuilds says the fly-by-wire system has also been calibrated to simulate the A340’s heavier and less responsive handling characteristics. Rolls are smooth and progressive, rather than snapping back to level as seen in newer Airbus models. iniBuilds aims to bring the A340-300 to life with “an uncompromising focus on system depth and accuracy”. A detailed FMS with SID/Stars, SEC flight plans, custom LNAV/VNAV, and custom hydraulic and electrical systems can be expected. Other systems have also seen extensive work. A fully functional printer, in addition to an option through the overhauled EFB to equip the aircraft with a PVI (Para-Visual Display), will be included. DCDU and ACARS will also be integrated with third-party ACARS systems, enabling direct communication with online controllers through the MCDU and DCDU. Additional features will include differences in EIS1 and EIS2 ND logic, cabin temperature simulation, and the MORA Grid (Minimum Off-Route Altitude) display. Autosave, a feature previously seen on the A350, will also be included. iniBuilds provided an update on the EFB, which has undergone an overhaul. The logic has been improved, and improvements to the interface have enhanced the workflow, according to iniBuilds. GSX support has also been “rewritten”, and is fully controllable through the EFB. For more details on the iniBuilds A340-300 Airliner, check out iniBuilds’s website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bstbm4</id>
    <title>Black Square Updates TBM 850, Now Native for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bstbm4"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bc49f7fc4f8d2f46ae50bf_black-square-tbm-850-msfs-04_1600x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has released v0.1.4 of their TBM 850, introducing native MSFS 2024 support and a comprehensive list of upgrades, fixes, and quality-of-life enhancements. In the MSFS 2024 version, the new walk-around feature is fully supported, letting you interact with chocks, pitot and engine covers, door handles, baggage doors, and more. The aircraft now also has a proper collision model, allowing the walk-arounds to feel more authentic. Avionics get attention too. The Bendix/King KAS 297B now supports vertical speed arming, while new GTNxi 750 and 650 bezels are included, alongside an improved model-switching method. Black Square has also introduced Magnetic Compass Effects, with physics filtering and realistic interference from onboard fields, so your whiskey compass behaves like the real thing. Inside the cabin, interior lighting has been retooled for MSFS 2024, and the EFB tablet has received upgrades. This includes an Ear Discomfort Index on the visualiser page, payload unit selection that persists between sessions, and an option to enable exterior registration meshes, as a workaround for a known MSFS 2024 dynamic registration bug. There is also a fix for 2024’s light-flare bleed-through. V0.1.4 also adds engine-driven fuel pump failure modelling, with corresponding visualiser behaviour. It also introduces custom toe-brake animations and sounds to stop jitter, along with a revised torque source, for faster indication changes. Black Square has corrected cases where a complete electrical failure would inhibit essential variables from updating, restored air conditioning operation on ground power, and tied the cooling turbine to proper bleed-air logic. Fuel pressure and pump cycling now behave correctly when tanks are empty or the selector is off. The TBM 850 v0.1.4 update is available now for all existing customers. You can pick up the aircraft on Contrail for $42.14, including taxes, and it is also offered through other stores, such as Just Flight. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhhems</id>
    <title>LHSimulations Releases HEMSOB Pack Hungary for MSFS 2020, 2024 to follow</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhhems"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bc51d02f2a7ee49b2ff46e_lh20_7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. LHSimulations has released its HEMSOB Pack Hungary for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, adding three authentic emergency medical bases to the sim.  Designed for realistic scenarios, the pack gives a look into air ambulance operations across Hungary. Support for MSFS 2024 is planned, though the team says a technical issue has caused a short delay. The acronym HEMSOB stands for Helicopter Emergency Medical Service Operational Base, facilities designed for air ambulance crews to launch rapid-response missions from. The pack, developed in close cooperation with the Hungarian Air Ambulance Nonprofit Ltd., recreates three real-world bases used by EC135 crews in Hungary. These include Budaörs (LH10), the country’s main HEMS base, located just west of Budapest, Balatonfüred (LH20), which covers the busy Lake Balaton region, and Marcali (LH30), providing coverage for the southwest of the country. Each base features accurate buildings, hangars, ground textures, and realistic helipads, complete with ambient details, such as fencing, lighting, and parked vehicles. For added immersion, you can even open the hangar doors yourself, using COM1 set to 128.15.. Beyond the visuals, LHSimulations has leaned on authentic references, to create a faithful representation of Hungarian HEMS operations. The bases were built with input from active crews, in pursuit of also making the scenery a tribute to the Hungarian Air Ambulance.  Each base is equipped with an animated heliport transfer platform, a movable dolly, often running on tracks, that allows the helicopter to land outside, and then be transferred into the hangar. For sim pilots, this means a perfect environment to practise medevac scenarios and low-level VFR, or simply explore Hungary with a helicopter.  The HEMSOB Pack Hungary is available exclusively through the in-sim Marketplace for $19.50, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
