<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-04-15T18:21:51.550303+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo412</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Publishes New San Francisco International Previews for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo412"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618c5f30f4701d3b78d30e8_ksfo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam Studios has recently shared new images of their upcoming San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing the progress on the terminals, ground texturing, and custom jetways. San Francisco International is the second-busiest airport in California, with a yearly average of 57 million passengers, only behind Los Angeles International.  It’s a hub for United Airlines (44% of the market share) and Alaska Airlines (10.66% of the market share) and is visited by multiple international carriers such as Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air New Zealand, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, and WestJet. ‍ Mir, the developer, emphasized that it’s still a work-in-progress project, with one of the showcased concourses (United’s Concourse E) not featuring jetways yet. It was previously stated to be their most detailed work yet, sitting high above their previous projects regarding visual complexity, quality, and performance. It’s said to be inching closer to completion, and if things go according to plan, it could be released before summer. Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdogru</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations &amp; db Scenery Announce Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdogru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618c9dead3989329b5a7ebe_gdru1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations and db Scenery have recently announced the development and imminent release of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves São Paulo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 41.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in the country. The airport's planning started back in 1967, when the government first considered renovating the airport infrastructure in the country and ran some studies to figure out which step to take next, leading to a straightforward conclusion: Congonhas (São Paulo's main airport at the time) was not big enough to sustain the ever-growing demand, nor could it be easily expanded, which led to a plan B: transforming a former Air Force Base into a full-fledged international airport. After decades of planning, construction started in 1980, with three runways and four passenger terminals in mind at first, which turned into two runways and two terminals due to time and cost constraints. It was inaugurated five years later and quickly became the city's primary airport.  ‍ Four years after the inauguration, the runways were extended, and the passenger terminals were expanded, bringing the overall capacity from 7.5 million passengers a year to 8.5.  A third terminal, planned for 2001, was built a decade later, along with Terminal 4. The first phase (of Terminal 4's construction) had it holding up to 5.5 million passengers a year, and the second phase brought it to its intended capacity of 8 million passengers, making it so the airport could handle 28.5 million passengers in total. The terminals were renumbered in 2015, with Terminal 4 becoming Terminal 1, Terminals 1 and 2 becoming Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 retaining its numbering. ‍ It's a hub for Gol Transportes Aéreos and LATAM Brasil and served by Azul, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and more. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, an up-to-date taxiway layout, custom landside, custom terrain mesh, custom ambient sounds, dynamic lighting effects, detailed ground markings, and more. It's set to release next Thursday (18/04) for roughly $9. Refer to the product page for further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bs0or8</id>
    <title>Backwood Studios Releases 0OR8 Sutton On Rogue Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bs0or8"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618cb5b66e52cd9b310c08b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Backwood Studios has recently released their rendition of Sutton On Rogue Airport (0OR8) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located in the U.S. state of Oregon and has a 2,500-foot (762 m) grass runway and a helipad. It is situated approximately 3 nautical miles north of White City and has enough space for small GA aircraft operations. ‍ ‍ Sutton On Rogue Airport is located along the Rogue River, and it is a great destination for those who love water sports and fishing. If you prefer to stay dry, you will still enjoy the stunning panoramic views of the area. The airport has a 24-acre horse ranch in its estate as well. ‍ ‍ ‍ The airport features a grass runway, helipad, helicopter hangar, airplane hangar, and a pilot house for relaxation and entertainment. ‍ Backwood Studios' latest release provides a highly accurate rendition of Sutton On Rogue Airport, custom PBR textures, animated elements, tailored night lighting, custom 3D-modeled buildings, detailed interiors, and more. ‍ ‍ ‍ The add-on requires 1.98GB of storage space and is available on OrbxDirect for approximately $11.25. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/semmmd</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Mérida International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/semmmd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661a59cc983ceb6caca518d5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulación Extrema has recently released their version of Mérida International Airport (MMMD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the Mexican city of Mérida, the airport has a yearly average of around 3.67 million passengers. The airport is located 3.1 miles (5 km) southwest of the city center of Mérida, lying in the famous State of Yucatán. Mérida International Airport was established in 1929, when Mexicana de Aviación began flying the Ford Trimotor to and from the airport. In 1964, the airport was acquired by the Mexican government and underwent a massive reconstruction in 1968. American Airlines began flying to Mérida in the 1960s, which helped grow the airport further. In the 1990s, the airport became part of the Mexican airport operator Grupo Aeroportuario del Sureste. This group operates several airports. Throughout the years, Mérida International Airport has had numerous passenger and cargo operations with airlines such as Aeroméxico, American Airlines, United Airlines, Viva Aerobus, and many more. As a result, passengers can fly to many cities such as Mexico City, Miami, Atlanta, Havana, and many more. The new scenery features custom jetways, custom taxiway and runway textures, PBR textures, hand-modeled exterior and interior, and much more. The add-on requires 957.05MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $13.85. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sesazb</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Bahía Blanca Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sesazb"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661a621b61b242db3f6ba1aa_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulación Extrema has released its version of Bahía Blanca Airport (SAZB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport, also known as Comandante Espora Airport, is located in Argentina and serves the city of Bahía Blanca. The airport is located 3.1 miles (5 km) from the city and caters to around 300,000 passengers annually. Bahía Blanca Airport was opened as Comandante Espora Air Naval Base in 1930 to replace the old Puerto Belgrano Air Naval Base, which lacked the necessary facilities for handling new aircraft types. From 1945 to 1964, the airport served as the Naval Aviation School, and in 1970, the Naval Command headquarters moved to the airport. It wasn't until 1968 that the airport started handling civil and commercial traffic. Today, Aerolíneas Argentinas connects the airport to multiple domestic destinations like Buenos Aires, Mar del Plata, and Trelew. The Bahía Blanca Airport scenery package boasts several features, including custom jetways, custom taxiway and runway textures, PBR textures, hand-modeled exterior and interior, accurate rendition of the Comandante Espora Air Naval Base, and much more. The add-on requires 875.96MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $13.85. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini111</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini111"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661a650af25ee1803d0c545c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an update for their Airbus A300-600R add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new version, v1.1.1, includes various fixes for systems, art, sounds, among others. However, to get this update out quickly, iniBuilds has temporarily disabled the SEC FLPN feature, which they plan to re-enable in the next update scheduled for release next week. The new version has a significant changelog with numerous fixes, which are listed below: ‍ v1.1.1 ‍ Systems Fixed - [VNAV] When in the turn VDEV reporting low on path but ending high after turn complete  Fixed - [SYS] When pressing N1 mode no ECAM is shown Fixed - [ENG] OIL TEMP to not be based on EGT Fixed - Double pressing +/- on IDC doesn't' switch between a + and -, just inserts + every time  Fixed - [IDC] AOC Enroute - Pos Rpt unable to change fuel from KG to LBS, regardless of units selected on EFB Fixed - [IDC] Squawk IDENT on ATC/TCAS CONTROL page doesn't send ident command to Vpilot Fixed - F-PLN B page when RSK should take to VERT REV B page also Fixed - [IDC]TCAS "TA ONLY" state doesn't show an indication in the TCAS control page Fixed - [SYS] ECAM TCAS STBY memo does not appear when ALT RPTG ON Fixed - [SYS] No Bleed air pressure indication with APU Bleed ON, ENG OFF Fixed - [SYS] Bleed air pressure gauge gets stuck to last value when R ENG BLEED = OFF Fixed - Can't step through ATLN/SEC F-PLNs Fixed - BRG/DIST should be to 1 decimal place Fixed - TO Config should read NORM FOR T/O Fixed - TCAS showing traffic at wrong relative altitude Fixed - STAR selection code crash Fixed - EFIS dials (DH, FPA) can be adjusted with FCU off Fixed - F-PLN B page wind format  Fixed - [FMGS] Speeds in plan do not account for transition alt Fixed - [ENG] N2 speed during crank Fixed - Manual changes to INIT B should be big font Fixed - Pressing GPWS switch when alert is active does not cancel warnings Fixed - PACKS OFF Operations Fixed - AP/AT Disconnect switches not animated via control input Fixed - [VNAV] Aiming for CST too early  Fixed - If a message is open on one idc, sending a message from the other messes with the message displaying IDC Fixed - ORIG/DEST have no input sanitisation Fixed - Switching panel button behaviour Fixed - Should be possible to modify sps/alt/wind dir/temp directly on F-PLN Fixed - Should be able to dial in a speed when in PROF like in the A320 for when you switch to LVL CHG or VS Fixed - Unable to change LAT/LON with slew keys INIT A Fixed - Navaid/REF pages Fixed - MCDU F-PLN page additions and corrections Fixed - IMM DESC is started with any right LSK on F-PLN page Fixed - Des arrow is few pixels off again Fixed - Wrong bearings on SID (FACT RWY19 TETAN 1A SID) Fixed - Tiller getting stuck left when used via rudder axis Fixed - [IDC] COM Presets not saving either Com1 or Com2 Fixed - Throttle locks to idle after turning off autothrust Fixed - [SYS] CTD/Plane stops responding when deleting HOLD/Waypoint from PROC in MCDU Fixed - Should be possible to modify sps/alt/wind dir/temp directly on F-PLN Fixed - ENG 2 PW EGT max pointer needle doesn't move Fixed - MCDU F-PLN page additions and corrections Fixed - Wrong bearings on SID (FACT RWY19 TETAN 1A SID) Fixed - PFD errors Fixed - Oil level mismatch on PW variant Fixed - FMS number rounding Fixed - ANTI SKID release indicators in flight on the wheel page are missing Fixed - Door SD Page improvements  ‍ Art Fixed - Cargo compartment smoke detection switch animation issue Fixed - APU exhaust still visible after being shut down Fixed - Missing GPWS Landing Flaps/ Slats selector switch text Fixed - [ART] Using the IDC panel - lose the lettering and the illumination around the ILS and VOR frequencies Fixed - [ART][PW] Eng 2 EGT Orange Needle INOP Fixed - [ART] Weird shadow on IGN/APU panel buttons Fixed - EGT warning light on GE engine config lighting up at PW limits Fixed - [ART] FO/CAPT switching lower sys indications should be boxed Fixed - Squib emissive should be white, not amber Fixed - [ART] FO Switching panel has red lines on buttons when CAPT side switching is set to SYS3 Fixed - Engine 1 Pylon labels mirrored Fixed - [ART] PW Pax house livery on the nose says Freighter (600RF instead of 600R) Fixed - [PW] Pilots Model missing from external view Fixed - Cabin light resets when zooming out ‍ Sounds Fixed - GPWS test plays in C&amp;D  Fixed - Alt alert C chord cuts off early if you rapidly adjust the alt knob on the ground Fixed - [SOUND] Exterior view engine sounds fade in and out Fixed - PW sounds on fuel injection Fixed - Increase ATC COM telex volume Fixed - RA Callouts playing on panel state change Fixed - Horizontal Stabilizer Trim animation inverted Fixed - Engine sounds disappear too fast on shut down Fixed - Sound Mix Feedback ‍ EFB Fixed - Pax EFB has toggle catering option avail in the air Fixed - [EFB] On-screen keyboard only shows numbers for HOPPIE field on settings page Fixed - [EFB] Enroute map - save/retain zoom level when switching between EFB apps Fixed - Landing calc RWY graphic units not syncing ‍ Other Fixed - MSFS Checklist TOGA highlights old ATC COM button click spot Fixed - CPT PFD brightness typo The updated Airbus A300-600R is now available on iniManager. It can be purchased from the iniBuilds Store for approximately $44.79 and requires 6.05GB of storage. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lax120</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Los Angeles International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lax120"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661a670a65f1e17d2446b6c2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has updated their Los Angeles International Airport (KLAX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, giving it a big overhaul and making the scenery even more realistic. The airport has received a new update that includes performance enhancements, remodeling, updated models, and layout changes. See the full changelog below: ‍ v1.2.0 ‍ - TBIT and TBIT satellite have largely been remade. Properly LOD'ed with a reduction in the overall number of materials and textures. - Terminal 3 updated to current layout. - Associated T3 parking/jetways etc updated - All building and terrain models have had lods updated and should now work correctly in normal flight ops. - HD textures reduced in size overall. - Some GSE has been replaced with newer models - GSE placements have been thinned out and inimanager options added for better control. - Taxiway D extension added - Taxi signs adjusted - Various taxiway designations corrected - Various terrain adjustments to reduce bumps - FedEx Cargo area Gate 2 shows as gate "Z" - All TBIT gates have the correct number of jetways - Taxiway Edge lighting misplacements - Airline terminal info boards corrected - United Hangar missing gate numbers on ground marking - Replaced default LOC arrays with custom versions - Replaced missing GS antennae - VDGS updated to the latest version The updated version of LAX is now available on iniManager. It can be purchased from the iniBuilds Store for around $24.89, but it's currently on sale for $19.19. The new version requires 5.76GB of storage space. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pngpk2</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack 2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pngpk2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661b98ac8490fab79f5bc5cb_papua1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released the PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a package with seven challenging airstrips in Papua New Guinea, the toughest country in the world to be a bush pilot. Bush airstrips in Papua New Guinea are generally the only gateway to certain remote villages, meaning it’s vital to their existence and the only way to bring supplies in. The weather is often harsh, the runways are often short and hand-carved, and the challenge is unparalleled. The new pack adds on to the previously released pack (back in October 2023), adding seven new destinations (Sapmanga, Isan, Tep Tep, Bambu, Nankina, Nahu, and Guhu), with well over 100 unique models, PBR texturing, LOD optimization for optimal performance, realistic terrain profiles, vegetation adjustments to facilitate STOL operations, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.32, requiring at least 2.79 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flyjri</id>
    <title>FLYT Simulations Previews Comte. Ariston Pessoa Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flyjri"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661ba016403f08565f28fdb5_jeri1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FLYT Simulations has recently previewed the development progress on their rendition of Comandante Ariston Pessoa Regional Airport (SBJE), serving Jijoca de Jericoacoara, Brazil, with a yearly average of 102,000 passengers as of 2023. Funded by a government plan to develop regional aviation in Brazil, construction work began in 2011 and concluded three years later. The inauguration, though, only happened in 2017 after a series of organizational mishaps.  The passenger terminal, designed by Francisco Antonio Laprovitera Teixeira, consists of a single block with departure and arrivals, food kiosks, bathrooms on each extremity, and—not many—check-in desks.  Its 2200m runway is long enough to accommodate an Airbus A320 and its Boeing counterpart, the 737-800.  It’s served by Azul (Belo Horizonte), Azul Conecta (Fortaleza, Parnaíba), Gol Transportes Aéreos (São Paulo - Guarulhos), and LATAM Brasil (São Paulo - Guarulhos). ‍ While there is no information on features, the images showcase special attention to the terminal’s interior. Previously revealed images from earlier this year also point to custom ground textures and realistic clutter. ‍ It’s said to be releasing in the next few weeks, exclusively on the MSFS Marketplace.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmaqsr</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Salerno Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmaqsr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661ba60fe5a7b520a8f1f7d5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon recently released their version of Salerno Costa d'Amalfi Airport (LIRI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Italian city of Salerno and has been closed for several years due to renovations and upgrades. It is scheduled to reopen in July 2024. The new scenery package from Barelli MSFS Addon features both a 2024 and a proposed 2026 version of Salerno Airport. The Salerno airport was established in 1926 by Italy's Air Force, primarily for flight training. Over the years, the airport underwent several upgrades. However, it wasn't until 2007 that it received check-in desks, boarding areas, luggage belts, and waiting rooms, allowing it to accommodate commercial traffic. In 2011, a project for the airport's further extension and new infrastructure was revealed, leading to its closure in 2016 for construction purposes. After a lengthy period of closure, the airport is set to reopen in July 2024. Airlines such as easyJet and Volotea have already planned numerous domestic and international destinations from Salerno. However, the airport will continue its construction until its completion in 2026. The new scenery package includes custom terminals, custom airport buildings, custom lighting, and much more. It offers two renditions of the airport, the current 2024 version, and the proposed 2026 version. Barelli MSFS Addon has stated that once the final changes for the airport are available, the scenery package will be updated accordingly. The add-on requires 227.11MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $13.86. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkklga</id>
    <title>MK Studios Previews LaGuardia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkklga"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661bf903db1049aa2f07f7cb_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios shared new screenshots of their upcoming LaGuardia Airport (KLGA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The team stated that the release of LGA is approaching. The team has expressed their gratitude to everyone who has contributed to the development of LaGuardia and has also shared some information about the scenery. They have decided to recreate the airport with all the new construction that is currently taking place and is scheduled to be completed in 2025. This means that they will include all the terminals, including the unfinished Concourse F of Terminal 3. Along with this announcement, they have also shared some screenshots to give us a glimpse of what we can expect from the new LGA. Although the pricing, release date, and exact features are not yet announced, MK Studios has confirmed that the airport is close to release. We'll keep you updated with more information as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwiipc</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Previews WWII Pacific Addons for DCS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwiipc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661c66fb749732555456aa09_In_Dev_12.04.2024.7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics have just released previews of WWII Pacific aircraft, sceneries, and aircraft carriers. Along with European WWII maps and aircraft, ED is working on both theaters in parallel. The Pacific will bring the Marianas from the 1940s, new AI aircraft, naval units, and ground units.  The USS Enterprise CV-6, commonly known as “The Big E”, one of the most famous aircraft carriers of all time will also be featured in the upcoming update.  Along with the USS Enterprise, the Pacific WWII update will feature the F6F Hellcat and B-17 Stratofortress. The Hellcat - one of the best fighter planes in World War II, with a kill-to-loss ratio of 19:1, is currently having its external details polished with various liveries, along with flight model development.  Last but not least - the Marianas WWII map will be a free addition to DCS! The development team has made great progress and has shared a couple of previews. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfarjp</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes RJ Professional Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfarjp"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661c6919d3fcc057d5eb7533_RJ%20InDev%20120424%201_Z-QqsxgIo.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just a week after the v2 update for the 146 Professional, Just Flight published a development update for their upcoming RJ Professional, which is based on the Avro RJ, a modernized variant of BAe 146. ‍ Thanks to similarities between 146 and RJ, the passenger cabins from 146 have been integrated into RJ and will include all cabin features that were present in the 146 Professional v2 update, along with small changes to reflect the difference in the RJ. One of the main differences between the two aircraft is the Flight Attendant panel, which has a switch for cabin lighting, as well as some different panels. Unfortunately, as of the posting of the development update, no screenshots of the cabin have been previewed. ‍ Significant progress has been made in the RJ cockpit. Most of the systems that were semi-automated in 146 are now fully automated in RJ, such as the pressurization system. Even though the system could’ve been ported from 146, JF has decided to recode the whole system from the ground up.  ‍ Along with the pressurization system, the development team has simulated the FADEC system as well. This system allowed all RJs to be fitted with auto-throttle, and also increased engine reliability and lowered fuel consumption. The modern GNLU-910A FMS will be integrated into RJ systems and will allow the implementation of LNAV and VNAV autopilot modes.  ‍ Another area of development that is not being left out is liveries. Currently, over 30 high-quality liveries have been made, ranging from the very first operators of Avro RJ, all the way to present operators.  ‍ Even though they have not shared any screenshots of the interior, lots of work has been done behind the scenes. Unfortunately, the release date is still not known, but, as always, Threshold will keep you updated with the progress of RJ Professional! ‍ Stay tuned for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx407</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 &amp; Delineates Plans for the Future</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx407"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661d010390dab0ef443ddf81_1250410_20240404225611_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently released a new update to their A320 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with a quick delineation of their next steps, pricing for the upcoming expansion, and more. The newly released V2.0.0.407 brings angle of attack tweaks in flight control law, external engine performance optimizations, CTD mitigations, GSX integration issues, sound optimizations and fixes, a rework on the LOD (level of detail) system to fix FPS loss, many EFB fixes and improvements, and more. The complete changelog follows below: They are also happy to report that the A319/A321 package development is progressing nicely, and beta testing should begin “very soon.” In celebratory fashion, the A320 is currently on sale for roughly $49.92 (the same price as the upcoming expansion) until 2200Z on Wednesday (17/04).  The aforementioned A320 base package includes the CFM and IAE variants of the Airbus A320 and their sharklet counterparts, albeit later in the year (after the release of the A319/A321 expansion). The upcoming expansion will, therefore, include the A319 and A321 with CFM and IAE engines and wingtip fences only at first, with sharklets to follow later in the year. It represents an average of $9.36 per variant! Based on customer feedback, their short-term plans include changes to the flare behavior and ground effect. While they won’t make significant alterations to keep the consistency at bay, they have identified areas where gentle adjustments can be made, especially regarding ground effect. Although satisfied with the lift/cushion effect, they feel like the drag addictive could be slightly increased, helping the aircraft “settle” on the runway a bit better.  While Microsoft Flight Simulator’s lift and drag of the ground effect are intrinsically tied to one another, the developers found a way around it with a custom solution that would allow granular control over the drag properties when under said ground effect.  Complaints about controlling the aircraft when on the ground were also listened to and the ground friction modeling was re-tuned in accordance with SU15 and its new ground friction model.  Both ground effect and ground modeling tweaks are expected to be rolled out as soon as possible, with the upcoming expansion not being an obstacle whatsoever.  The add-on is available in their store for roughly $49.99 (until 17.04), under a 20% discount. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzatrg</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases NZTG - Tauranga Region for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzatrg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661d23807ac725925069ce22_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NZA Simulations recently launched a new scenery package called NZTG - Tauranga Region for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The package includes Tauranga Airport (NZTG) as well as three other locations: Waihi Beach Aerodrome (NZWV), Motiti Island Airport (NZOI), and Tauranga Hospital Heliport (NZJA). Tauranga Airport is situated in Tauranga, New Zealand, and is the main airport serving the region, with an average of approximately 376,000 passengers in 2022. In 1935, the Tauranga Aero Club leased some land to establish an aerodrome in the Tauranga area. Due to growing demand, a permanent facility was required, and the aerodrome was converted into Tauranga Airport. The airport opened in 1939, but shortly after, the Royal New Zealand Air Force took control of it because of World War II. During this period, the airport underwent some upgrades, including runway extension and new hangars. In 1945, the airport was returned to the Tauranga Aero Club, and the first passenger flights were introduced the following year. The airport underwent several upgrades over the years, and today, it is the 8th busiest airport in New Zealand. Air New Zealand, Barrier Air, and Sunair are some of the airlines that operate from the airport, providing passengers with a broad range of destinations. The new scenery package features a precise depiction of Tauranga Airport (NZTG), Waihi Beach Aerodrome (NZWV), Motiti Island Airport (NZOI), and Tauranga Hospital Heliport (NZJA). The package also comes with custom 3D modeled objects, 3D interiors, animations, custom lighting, and numerous other features. The add-on requires approximately 1.58GB of storage space and is available on NZA Simulations' website for around $20.20. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerlua</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Lukla Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerlua"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661d32ac230cc802dfce1dac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently released a new add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, called Aerosoft Mt. Everest Airport Vol. 1 - Lukla. The add-on includes the renowned Tenzing-Hillary Airport (VNLK), also known as Lukla Airport. The airport of Lukla has gained notoriety for its challenging and risky approach and takeoff procedures. It is located in Nepal, surrounded by mountains, and has a runway length of only 1729 ft (527 m). Despite its short runway, the airport can still accommodate up to 150,000 passengers annually. Lukla Airport was constructed in 1964, after the original plan to build the airport on flat farmland was abandoned due to local farmers' unwillingness to give up their land. Instead, the airport was built at its current location, and Sir Edmund Hillary oversaw the construction process. He purchased the land from local Sherpas, but was dissatisfied with the soil resistance of the runway. It wasn't until 2001 that the runway was paved. In 2008, the airport was renamed Tenzing-Hillary Airport in honor of Sherpa Tenzing Norgay and Sir Edmund Hillary. Today, the airport is operated by several airlines, providing flights from destinations such as Kathmandu, Manthali, and Phaplu, and has become increasingly well-known. The newly released rendition of Lukla Airport features detailed 3D terrain model of Lukla Airport, high-resolution photorealistic textures, Lukla Helipad, detailed terminal building with interior, animated people and animals, realistic night lighting, and more. The add-on requires approximately 4GB of storage space and is available on Aerosoft for around $8.90. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
