<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-06-30T18:25:44.828772+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbfsep</id>
    <title>Bluebird Simulations Shows off 757 and More </title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbfsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675f026ae53391c81d96d3e_image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Sim Expo 2024 opened with a huge announcement from the team at Bluebird Simulations who are behind the long-anticipated 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The presentation opened with a preview video showing off the aircraft both on the ground and in flight. Shervin from the Bluebird team then moved into a slideshow detailing both the 757 and 767, we’ve summarized the slides below Goal:  ‍ Focus: ‍ 767 Update: Following the 757 and 767 updates, Shervin proceeded to surprise the audience with a surprise announcement of an upcoming 787. The 787 has reportedly been in production since November of 2023. There’s currently no release date planned for the 787 but we will stay updated on these developments</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fscfse</id>
    <title>FliteSim.com Reveals New Products at FSExpo 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fscfse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6675fe0699f26947dba0028c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FliteSim.com recently unveiled several new products during its presentation at this year's FSExpo in Las Vegas. After sharing fun facts about their current Force Feedback Yokes and Flight Consoles, they announced a total of four new projects. The first product to be unveiled is a G1000 Console. The new console will feature authentic buttons and knobs and has been developed from an FTD Level 5 Device. It is scheduled to be available in Q4 2024. After the G1000 Console was announced, the team proceeded to announce a new Boeing-style 737-800NG Yoke Handle. This new yoke, designed to pair with their current CLS-60/120 Yoke, will be a premium offering and will be available in Q4 2024. Furthermore, a new Force Feedback Stick Base has been unveiled. It will feature a dual motor with 15 Nm of peak force and will be available in Q4 2024 alongside the other announced products. Finally, to complete the new product lineup, the team is introducing Force Feedback Rudder Pedals. These pedals will be equipped with a single motor, providing a peak force of over 250 N. They are expected to be available in Q4 2024. To summarize, FliteSim.com announced at FSExpo 2024 that they will be releasing four new products in Q4 2024. These new products include a G1000 Console, a Boeing-Style 737-800NG Yoke Handle, a Force Feedback Stick Base, and a Force Feedback Rudder. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkskef</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Keflavik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkskef"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6676fdd9d54da70643bee8d7_FlightSimulator2024-06-1913-38-36_4472x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just released their rendition of Keflavik International Airport for MSFS. Serving the Greater Reykjavik Area, Keflavik International Airport has more than 7,500,000 passenger operations and more than 75,000 aircraft movements yearly. Built by the United States Military during WWII, the airport served as a replacement for British airfields in the northern part of Iceland. It consisted of two separate runways built 4km apart. After the war, the Meeks Field was renamed to Naval Air Station Keflavik, and in 1951, the US military returned to the airport. After the military air base in Keflavik was reestablished, passengers had to pass several military checkpoints before boarding the aircraft until 1987, when the separate civilian terminal was built. Two 10,000ft (3,000m) long runways are 200ft (60m) wide, which is enough to accommodate AN-225 and even a NASA Space Shuttle. This airport is also an important alternative in case of emergency during trans-Atlantic flights. Despite the low population of Iceland, it is a popular destination among travellers from both Europe and North America. Keflavik International Airport is a hub of two airlines: Icelandair - the flag carrier of Iceland, and PLAY - a low-cost airline. It also serves 25 airlines that fly to more than 80 destinations in the USA and Europe, as well as more than 35 seasonal destinations, mostly in Europe. Aside from passenger airlines, Icelandair Cargo flies to Boston, Liege and Los Angeles from Keflavik. MK Studios rendition of the airport features a detailed rendition of Keflavik Airport (BIKF) and Reykjavik Airport (BIRK), the up-to-date layout of the airport, custom jetways and vehicle models, modelled terminal interior, custom runway and taxiway lights and custom taxiway markings. This scenery is available for purchase on the OrbxDirect for $17.66, as well as Contrail store, Simmarket and iniBuilds. It will also require at least 1.93GB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcexan</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Provides Update on Management, Charlie Pedals</title>
    <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcexan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667735d349b77bf0627bd420_IMG_6781.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a press release provided to Threshold, Nicki Repenning of Honeycomb Aeronautical provides an update on the progress of the Charlie Rudder Pedals, management of Honeycomb, and RMA units for those who have returned their products.  Starting off with the replacement units, Mr. Repenning says that over the past few months, he’s “been trying to find a solution to replace approximately 110 faulty units that were sent out to customers and have been returned,” but has run into issues due to his former business partner, Mike Steup of Snakebyte-group, not replacing customer’s faulty units. As an alternative, Repenning says that he has been able to obtain replacement products that he will start shipping out to customers July 15th, and he plans to have them all shipped by the end of July. As for the Charlie pedal pre-orders, both Mr. Reppening and his former business partner at Snakebyte have started production of the pedals at different factories. According to Snakebyte, they will start shipping to customers on June 24th, but customers are still waiting for confirmation on the shipping. If that does not pan out, Reppening says, pre-order customers will get an email with an “alternative solution.” Furthermore, Mr. Reppening addresses questions about the future of management at Honeycomb. Reppening explains, “After months of trying to find a new partner to buy out my former partner’s interest in Honeycomb, I realized that it wasn’t a task I was able to handle by myself,” and he has “engaged capable business and legal advisors who are helping me move forward.” He continues to say that both Snakebyte and Honeycomb are working towards a “ solution that doesn’t require litigation and they [Repenning’s advisors] have done an excellent job,” and that he believes that “we [Honeycomb] are in the home stretch and will come to an agreement soon on the terms by which I will regain ownership and management of the full Honeycomb business.” Reppening adds that he hopes to make an announcement on that situation soon, but is cautious and is “not counting my chickens yet.”Additionally, Mr. Reppening says that he is at FSExpo 2024 in Vegas, and he is open to questions, but he will be “doing an AMA in the coming weeks, so everyone else will have the chance to do the same.” Reppening reports that they “have the first production units ready to ship but will also bring ten units to FS Expo which I will personally hand deliver at the show.” As for the second run of production, that will “be ready at the end of July and will be made available for purchase once the factory has confirmed the shipping date to us.” Finally, Mr. Reppenning thanks the community for “the incredible support that I and my team have received,” and he says that they “have also read the comments from people who have been critical and have taken that to heart.” He ends off with a message to the community, saying that “The only thing we can do right now is to look ahead, learn from the past and stay optimistic about the future,” and that if customers have any question for him, they can email him at: AskNicki@HoneycombSim.com. As for his former business partner at Snakebyte-group, they have not followed up on any questions in a request for comment sent by Threshold.Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kpnsv2</id>
    <title>FSDesigns Releases Pensacola International Airport V2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kpnsv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6677d6cf3c8a793c880facc1_pns1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FS Designs recently released an upgraded rendition of Pensacola International Airport (KPNS) for X-Plane 12. It is the second-busiest airport in North Florida, with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. Pensacola got its first passenger terminal in 1935, with commercial service to begin two years later with Atlantic and Gulf Airlines, although very short-lived due to financial issues. National Airlines took over in 1938 with flights to Mobile and Jacksonville. World War 2 saw the airport become a US Navy training facility, granting it a new control tower and runway.  The terminal was expanded 12 years ago at $35 million, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and modernizing the infrastructure. There are talks of a new concourse and parking expansion to come shortly. American Airlines, American Express, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Silver Airways, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. Delta tops the market share chart with 26.04%, followed by Southwest and PSA Airlines with 21.63% and 10.87%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ortho imagery, high-quality 3D modeling, animated hangars, reworked textures, PBR texturing, custom 4K ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, up-to-date layout, and wear and tear effects using the latest technology. It’s available on their store for $14.99, requiring at least 1.61 GB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners are eligible for a 50% discount. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimclt</id>
    <title>Nimbus Releases Charlotte Douglas International for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimclt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6677dda02107f43bc3fc4397_clt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus recently released their rendition of Charlotte Douglas International Airport (KCLT) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves Charlotte, North Carolina, and has a yearly average of 53.4 million passengers, making it the sixth busiest in the country. It opened 85 years ago as Charlotte Municipal Airport, funded by Works Progress Administration funding. It was the largest WPA project at the time, featuring a terminal, three runways, a hangar, and a beacon tower. ‍ The USAF took control of the airport shortly after due to World War 2, establishing an Air Force Base. Over 5 million USD were invested between 1941 (when the takeover happened) and 1946 when it was handed back to the city. A 6,500 square meter terminal was built in 1954 to accommodate the ever-increasing passenger numbers. It had two floors, with passenger operations confined to the ground floor.  ‍ Major renovation work started in the late 1960s to keep up with the harsh demands of the jet age and become a major player in domestic traffic. This led to its eventual consolidation as a hub after the airline deregulation of 1978.  A new 30,200 square meter terminal was built by Piedmont Airlines in 1979 and inaugurated three years later.  ‍ In 1990, a 7,400-square-meter international concourse was built, followed by an expansion of the central terminal building.  A regional concourse was built in the early 2000s, adding a 32-gate concourse (Concourse E). ‍ Expansion work followed in 2015 with “CLT 2015”, a 2.5 billion USD investment to modernize and accommodate the envisioned passenger figures for the following decade and beyond.  The airport currently has 115 gates on five concourses, all connected to the central terminal building. It’s a hub for American Airlines and is also served by Air Canada Express, Contour Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Lufthansa, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and Volaris. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 3D interiors, PBR textures, dynamic lighting, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ It’s available on the X-Plane.org Store for roughly $26.95, requiring at least 2.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spkspg</id>
    <title>SPINOZA Releases Albert Whitted Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spkspg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66784bc34acbc624d331cc3d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SPINOZA has recently released their version of Albert Whitted Airport (KSPG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located in and serves the city of St. Petersburg, Florida, which is renowned as the birthplace of the first scheduled commercial airline flight. Situated in the Tampa Bay area, the airport features a total of two runways. Construction of Albert Whitted Airport began in 1928, and the airport officially opened in 1929. In 1934, National Airline initiated service to the airport, but this ceased after World War II when the airline shifted operations to St. Pete-Clearwater International Airport. Upon its opening in 1929, the Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company stationed one of its airships at Albert Whitted Airport, marking it as one of the first airports to serve as a base for their blimps. Over the years, a Coast Guard Air Station was also established at the airport. Today, the airport remains a popular choice for general aviation in the area. The recently released scenery package provides Microsoft Flight Simulator users with a variety of features for the Florida-located airport. The newly released Albert Whitted Airport is now available on SimMarket for approximately $18.34 and requires 487.25 MB of storage space. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pfeyka</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Releases Kaunas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pfeyka"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66785abedc30d84b47cba670_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Propair Flight recently released its version of Kaunas Airport (EYKA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the Lithuanian city of Kaunas, it is the second busiest civilian airport in the country after Vilnius Airport, catering to approximately 1.3 million passengers annually. Kaunas Airport opened for flights in 1988. Flights were transferred from the former S. Darius and S. Girėnas Airport to the new Kaunas Airport. It wasn't until 1991 that the airport became an international airport. This happened after Lithuania acquired its independence. Throughout the years, the airport has seen a variety of airlines flying to different destinations, along with improvements to the airport and its infrastructure. Today, the airport is a hub for Ryanair, but also serves airlines such as Wizz Air, Corendon Europe, Freebird Airlines, and SkyUp. These airlines offer flights to destinations such as London, Madrid, and Milan, and the airport handles around 1.3 million passengers yearly. The newly released Kaunas Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator comes with numerous features, providing users with plenty of content to explore. The add-on requires 1.88 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $14.76. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bypdx2</id>
    <title>iBlueYonder Previews Portland International Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bypdx2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66796c6d44ace5b60c530cac_kpdx_next_preview_04.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iBlueYonder has just announced a new update for their KPDX scenery for MSFS. Serving the metropolitan area of Portland, Portland Intl Airport has over 16,000,000 passenger operations and 190,000 aircraft movements per year. ‍ Opened in 1936 as a “super airport”, it was a part of the New Deal, and was described as "Portland's most significant public works improvement during the New Deal era". It had five runways, and the terminal was on the northern side of the airfield. In 1952, a new longer runway was built, along with the new terminal. ‍ The first international non-stop flight from Portland was operated by Western, on Boeing 720B to Vancouver. By 1974, the airport was served by all major US domestic carriers: Braniff, Cascade, Continental, Eastern, Hughes Airwest, Northwest Orient, Pan Am, United and Western. The most popular route was to Seattle, with seven airlines flying with planes as big as Boeing 747-200. During the same year, the south runway was extended to 11,000ft and the terminal building was renovated and expanded a few years later. During the 80s, it was Delta’s hub for flights to Asia, as it lacked aircraft that could fly non-stop from Atlanta. In 1995, the carrier offered flights to Tokyo, Seoul, Nagoya, Taipei, and Bangkok. Unfortunately, due to other airlines introducing flights to Asia, Delta closed the hub in PDX in 2001. A couple of years later though, Northwest Airlines introduced nonstop flights from Portland to their hub - Tokyo Narita. Instead of opening more domestic flights like Delta did, NWA used code-share agreements with other airlines to funnel passengers to Portland. In March 2020, the main terminal began the 5-year long expansion process. The construction of the main terminal was estimated to be finished by May 2024, but due to construction incidents, it was delayed to August 2024. Today, PDX is served by 22 airlines to more than 80 destinations in North America and Europe and is a hub for Alaska Airlines. It is also a big cargo hub, as it receives flights from 13 cargo airlines, mostly in the USA. iBlueYonder’s rendition of KPDX will feature the new main terminal with a modelled interior, Concourses B, C and D with interior, and the new Concourse E, new toll plaza, FAA Administration building, custom animated jetways, new ground support equipment, and new animated objects and people. Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold to stay up to date on this and other flight simulation products! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukktrk</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Truckee Tahoe Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukktrk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667a9e452fe8177db3f0996d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has just released its latest airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This time, it's Truckee Tahoe Airport (KTRK) that has been created. Located in and serving the town of Truckee, California, this American airport averages 32.000 aircraft operations per year. Truckee Tahoe Airport opened in 1958 and is situated within the Sierra Nevada mountain range at an altitude of 5.900 feet. Over the years, various changes and upgrades have been made to the airport and its facilities. Currently, the airport features two asphalt runways and serves as a general aviation airport without commercial service. However, commercial flights are available at the nearby Reno-Tahoe International Airport. The airport accommodates a range of general aviation aircraft, and the presence of private jets is quite common. The scenery features Full Detail Buildings, Realistic Ground Markings, Hi-Res Ground Images, Stunning Night Effects, High Detail Airport Vehicles, Fencing, Vegetation, Static Aircraft, PBR Materials, and more. The newly released Truckee Tahoe Airport is now available on SimMarket for $12.86. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777625</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Boeing 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777625"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667b41b7049bb38e33cccfa8_pmdg1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently released their long-awaited rendition of the Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing an advanced simulation of all avionics and systems, hundreds of mechanical failures, a high-detail cabin, and much more. The Boeing 777-300ER, officially introduced in 2004, is an upgraded version of the 777-300, with strengthened wings, additional fuel tanks, and, therefore, a much higher range, facilitating non-stop flights between continents. Its fuel-efficient philosophy quickly became an airline favorite, making it the most popular 777 variant, with over 800 built since its inception. The add-on features an accurate simulation of all systems and avionics, electronic checklists for normal and abnormal procedures, animated flight deck elements, a realistic lighting system, a fully modeled auto flight director and autopilot system with fly-by-wire capabilities, an advanced brake system with wear and tear simulation, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ ‍ It’s available on PMDG.com for $77.73, and the Marketplace release is yet to be defined.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777sos</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Statement on 777 Launch Issues</title>
    <updated>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777sos"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667b6c00f4219d760e53957b_pmdg8.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG recently published a statement regarding checkout issues with their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, blaming it on a much higher demand than initially expected. Their Triple Seven, one of the most anticipated add-ons of 2024, allegedly exceeded 20 sales per second for more than four minutes after release. This significantly exceeded the figures from their previous major release—the 737-700 in 2022—and went well above their expected threshold, leading to orders being batched into holding. According to Robert Randazzo, the first-day unit sales of their 737 were surpassed within minutes, a demand much higher than they had initially planned with their eCommerce provider.  They have been actively working through the batches and providing everyone with a download link and license key. Customers are instructed to contact their support if the email is not sent within the expected time frame (60-120 minutes from their publication, with 60 minutes to go when our article is published). The brand-new airplane is available at PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jsnapp</id>
    <title>SharedFlight Release Date Announced</title>
    <updated>2024-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jsnapp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667d7bf97e68eee7eb39172d_Frame_103.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Developers of SharedFlight, a plugin for the shared cockpit for X-Plane 11 and 12, have just announced the release date of the highly-anticipated addon. After 4 years of development, SharedFlight will be released on June 28th.  It is supported for Windows, Linux and Mac, as well as X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Unfortunately, cross-compatibility between XP11 and XP12 is impossible due to differences between the two simulators. Unlike other addons for sharing cockpit for X-Plane, SharedFlight has built-in aircraft configurations, making it easier to use. In order for two (or more) users to connect and fly together, both of them will need to have the same aircraft version and AIRAC in sim.  The pricing will be tier-based. There are three tiers: Free, Basic and Premium. On release 13 aircrafts will be supported: Laminar C172 and C172 with G1000, Rotate MD-11, inBuilds A300/A310, ToLiss A319/A320neo/A321/A340-600, Zibo 737-800, Felis B747-200 and FlightFactor 757/767. More aircraft will be supported after release. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpar3</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Piper PA-28R Arrow III for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpar3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667edde7ee0551d22a850899_piper1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In partnership with Thranda Design, Just Flight has developed a rendition of the Piper PA-28R for X-Plane 12, featuring a highly detailed simulation of the popular four-seater first introduced in 1976. As the name suggests, the PA-28R Arrow III is the third iteration of the Piper Arrow lineup. It was launched in 1967 with the PA-28R-180, followed by the Arrow II. Five years later, it was majorly upgraded with a semi-tapered wing, larger fuel tanks (meaning increased range), and several other improvements and commercialized under the Arrow III moniker.  The add-on features high-quality 8K texturing throughout, reworked PBR materials, a brand new EFB tablet with aircraft configuration states, checklists, and customization options, a dynamic livery feature with color, design, and dirt level change on the fly, a high-quality FMOD sound set, and much more.  It’s available on Just Flight’s website for roughly $42.99, requiring at least 2.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777034</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates Boeing 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777034"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6680370f026bdbb7a3de9eb8_1250410_20240626232724_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued an update to their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing some WASM crashes, FMC bugs, and geometry fixes.  They also anticipate a series of updates in the next 14 days, aiming to mitigate user experience-disrupting issues (primarily), and the other teams (model, art, and sound) will also push their fixes. What hasn’t been fixed yet is an SU15-induced issue plaguing their 737 and 777, causing both to freeze entirely and stop responding. They have been working with Asobo to find out the root cause, and “victims” are encouraged to file a support ticket with PMDG so they can be surveyed.  Update 2.00.0034, issued via Operations Center, addresses the CLR bug that plagued many day one 777 pilots; hitting cancel on the EICAS no longer freezes the aircraft, and many model adjustments were made. The changelog follows below: ‍ The next update is already being tested and will fix long directory names preventing the installation process from working altogether.  The Triple Seven is available on PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ifly29</id>
    <title>iFly Previews Upcoming 737 Max 8 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ifly29"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66807e97309d17b67d3695b2_ifly1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iFly has recently published a new development update for their upcoming Boeing 737 Max 8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring a gallery with over 30 preview images. Other than the images (which say more than a thousand words, one could argue), iFly claims the development is moving along nicely. They have been considering creating a Discord channel to keep everyone updated on the project as it progresses. The 737Max is Boeing’s response to the A320Neo. It has bigger, high-tech, and very efficient engines, a different wing, and a completely new glass cockpit while operating in a similar fashion to its previous iteration, the 737NG. With that, airlines save money in training costs as the commonality is retained.  There’s no pricing or release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
