<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-03-03T18:19:58.050805+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxswe</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Swedish Triple Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxswe"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ddea8ef24015989fd20506_65d0fc3c65753f6a2982c302_triplepack.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has released the Swedish Triple Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a package with three Swedish airports (Umeå, Kiruna, and Scandinavian Mountains Airport) developed by independent developer Marcus Nyberg. The Swedish Triple Pack features an accurate rendition of Umeå (ESNU), Kiruna (ESNQ), and Scandinavian Mountains Airport (ESKS), with snow piles during winter, custom high-resolution ground textures, custom GSX profiles, unique static aircraft, and more. Umeå Airport, inaugurated in 1962, is the seventh busiest in Sweden, with a yearly average of 960,000 passengers. BRA Braathens Regional Airlines, Croatia Airlines, Jonair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic serve it. Kiruna Airport was inaugurated in 1960 and averages around 270,000 passengers yearly. Eurowings, Norwegian Air Shuttle, and Scandinavian Airlines serve it. Scandinavian Mountains Airport is one of the newest airports in the world, inaugurated in 2019. It was the first airport to feature a completely remote control tower. BRA Braathens Regional Airlines, Scandinavian Airlines, Transavia, and TUI fly Netherlands serve it, albeit seasonally. The scenery pack is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $29.98, requiring at least 8.53 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthslc</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Salt Lake City Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthslc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65dde389f848c07736c560a5_65d664e6115fe2515ffa658d_feelslc.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Salt Lake City International Airport (KSLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Salt Lake City metropolitan area and Wasatch Front with a yearly average of 26.9 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built on Basque Flats, a wide flat area on the Salt Lake Valley that was deemed appropriate for constructing a landing strip. In that same year, it held the Great International Aviation Carnival, with the presence of many aviation pioneers, including Glenn Curtiss and his newly invented Seaplane that took off from Salt Lake in front of 20,000 spectators, making international headlines. ‍ Nine years later, the United States Postal Service began flying mail to SLC, stimulating the city’s administration to improve the infrastructure further by buying a plot of land near the airport and building a hangar and other facilities.  ‍ The first terminal was built in 1933, costing $52,000.  ‍ With WW2, the airport became a USAF base, eventually getting a third runway. The post-war results were primarily positive, with 42 weekday departures in 1957. ‍ By 1960, a new terminal was needed, and Brazier Montmorency Hayes &amp; Talbot took on the challenge of designing it. Seven years and 8 million dollars later, it was ready to roll. That’s also when Salt Lake City got granted its international status, with a direct flight to Calgary. ‍ With the airline deregulation in 1978, SLC became a hub for Western Airlines, which had the same Brazier Montmorency Hayes design and built a terminal with murals by artist LeConte Stewart.  ‍ In 1987, Western Airlines merged into Delta Air Lines, with Salt Lake City remaining as one of their major hubs. ‍ A redevelopment program was started in 2014 to modernize the airport, gradually replacing its old infrastructure. Airport funds, passenger charges, and federal grants funded it. ‍ The first phase of the new terminal was opened in 2020, with Concourse A sporting 25 gates and B with 21, both connected by a mid-field underground tunnel.  ‍ As mentioned, SLC is a Delta Air Lines hub, flying passengers worldwide, directly or indirectly connecting via other hubs. They have 57.12% of the current passenger market share, followed by SkyWest with 18.77% and Southwest with 11.17%. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed buildings, PBR texturing, custom ground poly, custom animated jetways, an animated TRAX line train, an up-to-date AFCAD, improved taxiway lighting, custom ground clutter, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.59, requiring at least 683.61 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia37</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia37"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a9a2d24bcaac26dd4c31b3_a300mon.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their rendition of the Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing bug fixes, flight model improvements, and more. Update 1.0.7, the seventh so far, addresses the VS mode bug, improves the ground handling flight model, fixes an MCDU sound bug, and more. The changelog follows below: ‍ ‍ iniBuilds also states that a re-log-in on Navigraph in the EFB might be necessary after applying the update. The aircraft is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.55, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrp120</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Previews X-Plane 12.1.0 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrp120"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65dddb3892d3701f53710919_65d91a889df74096a227afca_xplaneupdate.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently previewed  X-Plane 12.1.0 on their blog, which is currently under private testing and set to release as a public beta soon, bringing graphical improvements, flight model tweaks, improved weather, and more. While the update was initially meant to be a graphics-focused release, Laminar has also implemented new aircraft systems, improved the flight model, weather, ATC system, and a physics-based camera that moves with the aircraft.  The graphics - their primary focus for this update - now feature cloud shadows on water, bloom lighting effects, robust contrast adaptive sharpening, softer ground shadows, MSAA improvements, improved CPU performance, better water opacity and turbidity, and a new screenshot utility with DoF and Exposure controls. It will also bring new particle effects, such as sparks from pavement collisions, ground spray from aircraft wheels and engines, and brown/white-outs while flying helicopters and powered lift aircraft. The aircraft systems were heavily upgraded, with additions to the G1000 simulation such as ADS-B simulation, stormscope page, traffic map page, airport METAR flags, NDB + VOR pages, WAAS/ Test Satellite Constellation, a boot-up overlay, and plugin interoperability, allowing third-parties to easily modify the G1000 for their specific needs. Glass avionics will now be implemented via plugin, making it easier for developers to integrate them into their aircraft.  The new flight model will bring a manual flap system (and a dial-a-flap functionality, too), electric clutches for helicopters, and single-lever control for turboprops, if equipped. The weather system will use a new server, and the METAR parsing will be improved, making it closer to real life. Clouds will look less blocky as a direct consequence of better data parsing. Last but not least, the new physics-based camera, which might come in 12.1.0 or a future update, with camera motion based on the aircraft's acceleration. ‍ There's no date for the official release yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbans</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Anacortes Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbans"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ddd9c711564e2d8ec0ba95_65d99124979f07a2186cdbe7_anacortes.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Anacortes Airport (74S) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use general aviation airport serving Anacortes, Washington, with a yearly average of 9,000 aircraft operations. ‍ It was built in 1968 and inaugurated in 1969 on land purchased by the Port of Anacortes using FAA grant money. ‍ It’s included in FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems for 2017-2021 as a local general aviation facility, corresponding to 73% of its yearly traffic as of 2014. Air taxis make up the other 17%. ‍ Developed by Andreas Hegi, the scenery was completely rebuilt for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with a 3D terminal interior, custom PBR textures, an accurate ground layout, custom airport signs and markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.35, requiring at least 1.89 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fe24ra</id>
    <title>FSExpo 2024 Moves to Rio Las Vegas; Dates Remain</title>
    <updated>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fe24ra"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65da7c26da23836dfae105c3__Z8A0350%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In an announcement made on both their website, the team behind FlightSimExpo have announced that the 2024 event will move resorts from the Tropicana Las Vegas, to the Rio Las Vegas, and being held on the same dates as originally planned, from Friday, June 21st through Sunday, June 23rd, 2024. The FSExpo team says no action is needed from those who have already booked rooms at the Tropicana, and more information will be coming soon.The event was originally planned to take place at the Tropicana Las Vegas, but the unexpected closure of the Tropicana that was announced last month, the event team scrambled to move resorts. In a herculean effort, the team managed to secure a venue contract in just 25 days, which is a remarkable feat considering the fact that this process usually takes months. The team also shared more information about the new accommodations at the Rio, which will feature rooms in the newly renovated Ipanema Tower, if rooms are booked through the FSExpo link. Starting in October 2023, resort-wide improvements have been introduced, including dynamic dining experiences, fully refreshed public spaces (including the pool), and a complete renovation of more than 1,400 rooms in the Ipanema Tower. Along with more than 15 full- and quick-service restaurants including a new food hall, there are four on-property shows including Penn &amp; Teller, WOW - The Vegas Spectacular, and Comedy Cellar. ‍ The nightly room rate at the Rio will be slightly cheaper than what was offered at the Tropicana, with $149USD on Friday and Saturday nights, and $69 on other nights, plus taxes and fees, and a booking link will be provided soon with more details, with a $25 food voucher included if you book with their link. ‍ If you have booked at the Tropicana and already paid the deposit, a full refund will be issued soon. Additionally, if you have not independently canceled your reservation, you will receive a $25 rideshare voucher to help cover your travel from the airport to Rio in June. ‍ If you have not booked yet, the FSExpo team strongly encourages you to book at the newly renovated rooms in Rio’s Ipanema Tower once their booking link becomes available. Along with enjoying a discounted rate of approximately $172/night (includes taxes/fees for a Thursday-Sunday stay), attendees can expect a $25 credit per booked room toward food and beverage at Rio. In Summary: ‍ Also, Threshold is proud to announce we are attending FSExpo 2024 in person! Look forward to interviews, and in-depth coverage on everything that happens during the event! We’re super excited to meet members of the Threshold Community in Vegas!Threshold will keep you updated once we get more information, so stay tuned for that, and more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ifl73m</id>
    <title>iFly Previews 737 Max 8 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ifl73m"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65dd0f7622df8a8caaf85024_iflymax.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iFly has recently shared an image gallery with ten work-in-progress previews of their upcoming Boeing 737 Max 8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator and a brief paragraph on the development progress. They emphasized in a forum post that it’s still a development testing build and not a beta, and they have just started flight testing on some of its systems.  Other than the pictures and the quick note on it not being a beta yet, there’s no further information available at the moment, but Threshold will keep you updated. ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksbar</id>
    <title>MK Studios Teases Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksbar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ddc28c2cb38294ff72d997_65dd1546a03010ad4fe3b563_barcelona1.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently shared two images of their upcoming Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator on their newly launched public Discord server.  El Prat is Spain's second-largest and second-busiest airport, with a yearly average of 49.9 million passengers.  ‍ It's a hub for Iberia, Level, Air Nostrum, and Vueling and a focus city for EasyJet and Ryanair. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air Transat, airBaltic, Avianca, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, ITA Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. ‍ Besides the two images, there's no other information regarding features, pricing, or a potential release date. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeng16</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Oslo Gardermoen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeng16"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ddbe87c8f84220e27edaea_65dd1790f44f63f61bf6c2d0_osloo(2).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Jo Erlend has recently submitted another batch of screenshots showcasing the progress on the Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Norway with 30 million passengers yearly.  ‍ Oslo Gardermoen is the main airport serving Oslo. It is located approximately 47 kilometers northeast of the city center and opened in 1998 to replace the outdated Fornebu Airport, which had been operating since 1939. It was built to modernize and expand Norway’s airport infrastructure and improve accessibility to the capital city, quickly becoming the Main hub for domestic and international travel in the Country.  ‍ The new previews were taken while Jo adjusted the AI traffic logic, which could denote its closeness to rollout. However, he says there’s still some back and forth between him and his initial group of testers with feedback being gathered, and it’s soon to reach a larger group of testers for that final bug squashing.  ‍ There’s no information on the pricing or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you updated!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fxb224</id>
    <title>Fenix A320 V2 Block To Release Tomorrow</title>
    <updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fxb224"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65de435bdd1aaa8e2c01ec55_8.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In an announcement made on their Discord server, Fenix Simulations CEO Aamir has said that the highly anticipated Block 2 of the massive V2 update of their immensely popular airliner will be released tomorrow, February 28th. According to Aamir, the timeline has been “updated from ‘weeks not months’ to ‘hours not days.’” This announcement comes after over a year and a half of development, in which many aspects of the aircraft are to be updated, including overhauled exterior and interior, brand new EFB backend, cabin announcements, full GSX integration, external engine model, and who could forget the IAE V2500 engine variant! Although the announcement was brief, Aamir thanked the Fenix community for their patience, and assured that we will get more “tidbits and some info in the following hours,” so stay tuned to Threshold for the latest updates on the Fenix, and for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsra2b</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases A320 V2 Block 2 Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsra2b"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65dfafa4c3392bf1dcef290a_b21.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently rolled out the V2 Block 2 Update for their Airbus A320 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding the IAE engine variant, a new external model, a vast list of bug fixes and improvements, and more. As previously mentioned during our coverage of their feature review video, the update brings a fully custom engine model, meaning it will no longer produce inadequate performance figures and fuel burn. Unlike the original plan, which was to release IAEs with the custom engine model and then later start the process on CFMs, Fenix has decided to do both simultaneously, bringing both up to the same standard at the cost of a slight delay. The update also brings a highly customizable PA system per ICAO/IATA, with the audio files playing randomly within a set time frame for each action (boarding, deboarding, landing, etc.) to simulate a real cabin crew. Furthermore, they have worked hard on integrating GSX, meaning refueling, boarding, cargo, and pushback will be handled automatically by FSDT’s add-on, saving a few clicks.  The Electronic Flight Bag was entirely rewritten and made more responsible, with finer control of settings and failures and a built-in quick reference handbook for dealing with the many possible failures the add-on packs in. The flight model has been significantly tweaked, with Fenix Simulations suggesting a specific sensitivity curve for both with and without stick dampening simulation - one of the new features of this update - aiming to make the sidestick feel much more like the real thing. They recommend -20 % on the sensitivities (positive and negative) of the  L-Axis X and Y, 0% deadzone, and 100% reactivity. Rudder-wise (Joystick R-axis Z), they suggest -40 % sensitivity (positive and negative), 8% deadzone, and 100% reactivity.  After a year and a half of development work, it’s no surprise there are so many changes, improvements, and new features. The changelog follows below: ‍ The add-on is available on their official website for roughly $63. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini109</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini109"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65dfb70fbfdc6dd323f94dbd_a300-slide4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing the spoiler arming code, numbers cutting off on VOR frequencies, and general system stability improvements. v1.0.9, the eight so far, brings a relatively modest changelog, which follows below: ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmmanc</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Manchester International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmmanc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e10409b0847eef65753e36_manchester1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 23.3 million passengers. Construction work began in 1935, and the airport was partially operating by 1937 (the official conclusion happened a year later). KLM was the first airline to launch scheduled commercial flights to the newly opened airport in 1938. It was converted into an RAF base during WW2 and played an essential role in military aircraft production and parachutist training. The post-war period saw its return as a commercial airport, with rapid growth during the 50s and 60s, where it eventually managed to be Britain's second busiest airport after London Heathrow. The airport was heavily expanded in the 80s and 90s to keep up with the exponential growth figures, eventually leading to the millionth passenger in a month mark in 1987. Plans for a new terminal were put in place, and it was opened by Princess Diana as Terminal A in 1989.  From 1997 to 2001, a second runway was built, leading to many protests from locals because natural habitats were disturbed and listed buildings had to be demolished, but they didn't have another option. New expansion work started in 2019 to keep up with the ever-growing passenger traffic figures. ‍ EasyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways have operating bases in Manchester. Many airlines from around the Globe serve it, including Air Canada, Air France, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad, Finnair, KLM, Kuwait Airways, Lufthansa, Qatar, Scandinavian Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish, Virgin Atlantic, and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, realistic lighting, custom jetways, performance-friendly optimization, realistic terminals, and custom ground textures. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $20.85, requiring at least 1.68 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdgtnp</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Releases GTNXi Pro with Full Navigraph Data Support for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdgtnp"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e10a649702b430b57a5395_tds1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TDS Sim Software has recently introduced the GTNXi Pro navigation suite for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring full compatibility with Navigraph’s navigation database and charts instead of only accepting the - rather expensive - official Garmin navdata.  The developers claim there are no setbacks or limitations from using the Navigraph database instead, with the overall experience being indistinguishably similar. The main difference, though, is the pricing: while one can subscribe to Navigraph for as little as $27 (navdata only), Garmin’s subscription plan can easily go past the four-digit mark for the worldwide database ($1869/year for the database and charts), which can be a bit steep for flight simulation usage. They have been developing this integration for two years, and it’s said to be their most challenging project yet. It’s the first time in history that a Garmin-trainer-based GTN was made compatible with Navigraph data.  The feature set is the same as the standard GTNXi, delivering an authentic replica of the real GTN 750Xi/650Xi with advanced navigation features, great levels of customization per the real unit, and high-resolution displays with great clarity. The Navigraph integration also features geo-referenced data where available, providing real-time aircraft positioning overlaid on the Jeppesen charts for extra situational awareness. Their data also allows for LPV (Localiser Performance with Vertical Guidance) approaches, RF (radius-to-fix) legs, and much more.  ‍ The GTNXi Pro subscription is available as an upgrade from the standard GTNXi for $26.95 or standalone for $70.15 on their official website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkbcn1</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkbcn1"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3a76961aaa3b024644a92_bcn1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Spain's second-largest and second-busiest airport with a yearly average of 49.9 million passengers. El Prat was Barcelona's second airport, built in 1918, after their previous airport (El Remolar) couldn't be expanded any further. It was a base for the Spanish Navy's Zeppelin fleet and was the headquarters of the Aeroclub of Catalonia. Regularly scheduled commercial service started in 1927 with Iberia. Following the end of World War 2, they built its first paved runway, making way for the first scheduled international flight in its history: a Pan American Airways Lockheed Constellation that would come over from New York regularly.  The subsequent years brought its first passenger terminal, taxiways, and a second runway, allowing the airport to keep growing. It would handle a million passengers annually within a decade of that construction effort. The airport's growth had halted after the 1970s, and the imminence of the 1992 Summer Olympic Games led to an urgent makeover: two more terminals were built, and jetways were finally introduced. It's a hub for Iberia, Level, Air Nostrum, and Vueling and a focus city for EasyJet and Ryanair. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air Transat, airBaltic, Avianca, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, ITA Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, VDGS, custom satellite imagery, elevation data based on LiDAR scans, custom ground poly, realistic night lighting, and more. It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $14.61, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bougpk</id>
    <title>Boundless Announces Glasgow Prestwick Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bougpk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3aaf22d46a53d71486979_egpk.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently announced the development of Glasgow Prestwick Airport (EGPK) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the second busiest airport in Glasgow (Scotland), with a yearly average of 445,211 passengers. It was officially opened in 1935 despite operating as an airfield for longer (since the early 1910s). Passenger facilities were added in 1938 and remained untouched until the government made them compatible with jet aircraft. ‍ The RAF used Prestwick to control trans-Atlantic flights during World War 2 as a gateway for US Army personnel and a training base for RAF pilots. ‍ Its commercial duties started right after the war, with a transatlantic flight between Prestwick and New York. ‍ The main runway was expanded in 1960 from the original 2,100 meters to 3,000 meters, which is still its current length. ‍ During the early 1990s, Prestwick was in shambles, desperately needing “rescue,” which came in the form of a takeover from a Canadian entrepreneur (Matthew Hudson), who constructed a railway station beside it, making it the first Scottish airport with its own railway station. To this day, Matthew’s rescue effort is unanimously recognized as heroic. ‍ Ryanair embraced Prestwick in 1994, with a route from Dublin and a second route a year later to London Stansted. A third one followed suit in 1998, taking passengers to Paris-Beauvais. ‍ 1998 also marks the ownership transfer from Matthew Hudson to the Stagecoach Group, a transport group based in Perth, primarily focused on buses, trams, and train services. They sold it three years later for 33 million pounds. ‍ Infratil, a Kiwi company, was the new owner from 2001 onwards, responsible for revamping the main terminal in 2005 and redecorating most of it with very controversial touches. ‍ After over a decade of ownership, Infratil called it a day and passed it on to a new owner, which was no less than the Scottish government. They paid an incredible sum of 1 pound for it. ‍ It’s currently served by Ryanair, with flights to Alicante, Faro, Lanzarote, Málaga, and Tenerife-South. ‍ There’s no release date, pricing, or feature information, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
