<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-01-22T18:22:23.642327+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffaxwb</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases New A350 Beta Update for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffaxwb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c37858aabe58274adca310_a350-2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="303520"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently updated their A350 beta branch to version 1.7.02, fixing a sim crash on replay, the reverser animation, and graphical bugs on X-Plane 12.  The FlightFactor A350 XWB Advanced provides realism in its depiction of the Airbus A350, featuring a highly detailed virtual cockpit, ground equipment, an advanced systems simulation with SIDs and STARS, customizable failures, and a fully integrated Airbus electronic checklist system. The ECAM monitoring system is fully customized, and the fly-by-wire simulation includes a realistic implementation of normal laws. All Airbus autopilot modes are included, except for a few non-precision approach modes, and the option for independent autopilots is also available. Additionally, it features a custom 3D stereo engine sound system and an interactive flight attendant helper.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $64.95, requiring at least 800 MB of free disk space to install. Shout out to Poptart in our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxbr</id>
    <title>ORBX Release Landmarks Brisbane For XP12</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxbr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c3fd3e668c5b7c461a89a7_3.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3271922"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ORBX, a leading developer of flight simulation software, has announced the release of "Landmarks Brisbane" for X-Plane 12. This highly detailed add-on package brings the Australian city of Brisbane to life in stunning realism, allowing virtual pilots to explore the city's landmarks and iconic locations in incredible detail. The package features highly detailed models of over 100 of Brisbane's most famous buildings and landmarks, including the Story Bridge, the Wheel of Brisbane, and the Queensland Cultural Centre. Additionally, the package includes high-resolution textures, custom-designed autogen, and accurate night lighting, all of which combine to create a truly immersive flying experience. According to ORBX, the package has been developed using the latest in 3D modelling and texturing techniques, ensuring that the city of Brisbane is depicted as accurately and realistically as possible. The package also includes a range of custom-designed Heliports. The package is now available for purchase on ORBX's website and is compatible with X-Plane 12. Virtual pilots can purchase the package for AUD$19.34 ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xdlicc</id>
    <title>Xometry Design Previews Catania-Fontanarossa Airport for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xdlicc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c490b73071c99c6a843262_licc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="278159"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry Design has recently previewed their rendition of Catania-Fontanarossa Airport (LICC) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the busiest airport in Sicily and fourth in Italy as of 2020, with a yearly average of 10 million passengers.   Catania is a focus city for Ryanair and WizzAir, offering flights to many European destinations. It is also regularly visited by major carriers such as Air France, easyJet, KLM, Lufthansa, and Turkish, along with many other airlines on a seasonal basis.  Catania-Fontanarossa was the region’s first airport, dating back to 1924. It was controlled by the allies during WW2 and used by the USAF as a military airfield, where it hosted the 340th Bombardment Group for a few months in 1943 and the 51st Troop Carrier Wing right after, until June 1944. Civil authorities took control not long after the end of the war. After the war, it underwent reconstruction and expansion, with commercial flights beginning to operate in the 1950s. In the following decades, the airport continued to grow in popularity and passenger traffic, becoming one of the busiest airports in Southern Italy. In recent years, there have been several modernization and expansion projects, including the construction of a new terminal, aimed at improving its facilities and capacity. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with high-quality custom buildings, high-resolution and color-corrected satellite imagery, high-resolution ground textures, SAM jetways, VDGS units, accurate ground markings, main terminal interior, custom ground clutter, and accurately placed dirt, wear, and tear. It’s going to be compatible with X-Plane 11 and 12. There’s no information regarding the price or release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blu757</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Previews Interactive Checklist &amp; Lighting for Upcoming 757</title>
    <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blu757" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c49f63a687cf2409895be5_blue1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1411643"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BlueBird Simulations has recently uploaded a video showcasing their interactive checklist feature and lighting (internal and external) for their upcoming Boeing 757 add-on.  They initially go through the before engine start checklist where you can witness a start from cold &amp; dark, followed by the IRS alignment procedure and the demonstration of the lights in the cockpit and externally. The BlueBird Simulations 757 aims to be a mid-level complexity airplane, with several degrees of extra depth over default aircraft. It says to feature highly accurate 3D visuals based on reference pictures and documents, a flight model built on real-world data, and the system complexity is yet to be confirmed, according to their website. The Boeing 757 is a mid-size, narrow-body twin-engine jet airliner produced by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. It was designed to replace the 727 on short and medium-length routes, first flown in 1982. It was popular with airlines due to its efficiency and range and was used primarily for transcontinental and transatlantic flights. The 757 was also known for its advanced technology, including fly-by-wire controls and a glass cockpit. Its production ended in 2004, but many are still in service today. There is currently no information on the price and release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inibuf</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Buffalo Niagara International for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inibuf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c5a0d0aa625f0407a23e77_nia1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1977554"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniBuilds has recently updated their rendition of Buffalo Niagara International (KBUF), adding compatibility with X-Plane 12. It is the third-busiest airport in the state of New York, serving the Buffalo Metropolitan Area and Niagara Falls in Canada.   With a yearly average of 5 million passengers, Buffalo averages over 100 daily flights, with over 30 destinations in the United States, Puerto Rico, and Mexico. Southwest Airlines is responsible for most of the market share, with 26.86% of the annual traffic figures as of 2021-2022, followed by Delta (13.69%) and American (11%).   The airport has a long history dating back to the early 20th century. The first airfield in the area, Curtiss Aerodrome, was established in 1916 and was used primarily for pilot training during World War I. It was later renamed Buffalo Municipal Airport and underwent several expansions in the 1920s and 1930s, including the addition of a passenger terminal and a new runway. During World War II, BUF was used as a training base for the US Army Air Corps. After the war, commercial air traffic increased, and the airport was renamed Greater Buffalo International Airport in 1967. In 1997, the airport was renamed Buffalo Niagara International Airport to reflect the broader regional reach of the airport.   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport terminal with a modeled interior, hand-made ground polygons, true-to-life airport landside recreation (with custom ground decals, signposts, vegetation, parking barriers, and more), accurately modeled and placed dynamic airport lighting, hand-placed (and high-definition) vegetation, accurate taxi signage as per the real-world, custom built jetways with PBR texturing, accurate logos and real-world decals scattered throughout the airport, hand-placed ground service equipment, and high detail models of all airport buildings, objects and surroundings.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $20.77, requiring at least 2.98 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teiavc</id>
    <title>Teikof Studio Releases Alfredo Vásquez Cobo International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teiavc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c5a9215f80041073b976f3_leticia1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="755447"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Teikof Studio recently released their rendition of Alfredo Vásquez Cobo International (SKLT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Leticia, Colombia's southernmost city and capital of the Amazonas Department.  It’s visited by Avianca, LATAM Colombia, and Viva Air, with direct flights to Bogotá. SATENA, a government-owned regional carrier, also operates in Leticia with routes to La Chorrera, La Pedrera, San José del Guaviare, and Tarapacá.  The airport has a relatively short history compared to other airports, as it was built in the early 21st century, beginning in the year 2000 and reaching completion in 2003. It was named after the former governor of the department of Amazonas, Alfredo Vásquez Cobo. The airport serves as the main gateway to the southern region of Colombia, including the Amazon rainforest, being a hub for air transportation of regional products, such as rubber and Brazil nuts. Today, the airport handles around 100,000 passengers annually, considered an important economic and tourism engine for the region. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with PBR materials, custom terraforming, detailed apron and terminal, and framerate-friendly optimization.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.13, requiring at least 124 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffa32u</id>
    <title>FlightFactor A320 Receives Update </title>
    <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffa32u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c703005633b15a05ee04e3_a320_15.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="85872"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Factor's A320, a popular and highly-regarded flight simulator add-on for X-Plane, has recently received a significant update. The update includes a variety of new features and improvements Some of the newest features to be implemented on the A320 include; the option to use sharklets and the new icing system which is said to be fully operational. Another much-anticipated feature which has been implemented is full SimBrief integration of the aircraft's EFB.  The full changelog includes:  1.5.6 Improvements: * Simbrief integration (through INIT REQUEST) * Icing effects * Anti-ice system * Sharklets * Dual input and sidestick priority logic * new cabin 3d-model * significant improvement of Flightplan calculation performance ‍ Fixed: * incorrect prebuilt holdings pattern * Go-Around procedure issues * Overspeed protection * incorrect prebuilt hold entries * go-around procedure activation * duplicate markers on the flight path when close to the MAP * EFIS BARO knob pull for 'active mouse wheel' input ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nettam</id>
    <title>NetDesign Releases Tamanrasset Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nettam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c7b0795784f11efd8bac87_daat1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="332356"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NetDesign has recently released their rendition of Aguenar - Hadj Bey Akhamok Airport (DAAT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Tamanrasset in Algeria with an average of 70.000 passengers a year.   It’s a small airport with one terminal building serving international and domestic flights, primarily used by tourists visiting the nearby Ahaggar National Park and Tassili n’Ajjer National Park, which are popular destinations for their natural beauty and cultural significance. It’s also a hub for military and cargo operations.  The scenery was created with the help of reference photos and satellite imagery, featuring the passenger terminal, tower building, and an Algerian military base with its buildings. Roads around the airport area underwent improvements to provide a realistic backdrop for pilots flying in and out, along with fencing around the airport perimeter. It also features static military aircraft, points of interest, and a nearby solar plant. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ - 4K PBR textures in multiple layers - Parallax windows based on real interior photos - Many details gleaned from tourist photographs - Reconstruction of the adjacent military base created using satellite imagery - Accurate Algerian Air Force Su-30MKA and Mi-8's on the tarmac featuring markings from real aircraft - SKTM solar power plant, which can cause glare for planes on runway 8 approach during sunset - POI: Tin Hinan Tomb POI not far to the west for sightseeing - ILS 8 (109.7) and ILS 20 (108.5) are functional - Runway 20 was tilted slightly to mitigate the misaligned default ILS 20 in order to preserve all navaids that came with the default airport - Redone aprons and markings matching recent satellite images - Redone taxiway system and airport/street night lighting  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.00, requiring at least 513 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/airsba</id>
    <title>Airworthy Designs Releases Saint Barthélemy Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/airsba" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c8967143a2d42372f719b6_sb1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3986117"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Airworthy Designs has recently released their rendition of Saint Barthélemy Airport (TFFJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third most dangerous airport in the world according to The History Channel’s Most Extreme Airports documentary, only behind Toncontin and Lukla.   With a 646-meter-long runway, it’s only served by small regional aircraft and charters, with the Dash 7 being the largest aircraft ever allowed to operate at St. Barths. It sees a steady average of 190 thousand passengers per year, on all sorts of small planes such as the Pilatus PC-12, the Cessna 208B Grand Caravan, the DHC-6 Twin Otter, and the BN-2 Islander.   It’s a hub for Tradewind Aviation, with flights to Antigua, St. Thomas, and San Juan. The visitors’ list includes Air Antilles, West Indies Helicopters, and Winair, taking people to St. Maarten, Pointe-à-Pitre, and Saba.   Cargo-wise, DHL Aviation offers a wide range of destinations between the nearby islands.  The scenery was developed with on-site photography, input from residents, and attention to detail to provide a very authentic experience. It features the whole island, with most of its points of interest like the Port of Gustavia, the industrial zone, and the residential areas. The mesh was corrected, fixing the final approach geometry, and matching the real-life counterpart as much as possible. It also features a fully modeled terminal with its interior, updated apron layout and markings as of 2022, night lighting, dynamic flag animations, and FPS-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.06, requiring at least 163 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/basmem</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Memphis International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/basmem" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c8e01effea5d8108520c10_mem1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2357667"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim have teamed up once again to build and release a rendition of Memphis International Airport (KMEM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the primary international airport serving Memphis, covering 1,600 hectares of land, sporting four runways, and averaging 4 million passengers a year as of recent.   Mainly a cargo airport, known as the FedEx Superhub, it processes a significant number of packages per year, featuring many nonstop destinations all across the globe, along with a network of domestic routes all over the continental United States. For 16 years (between 1993 and 2009), MEM used to be the busiest cargo airport in the World, overtaken by Hong Kong Intl. in 2010 but remained the busiest cargo airport in the country and the entire western hemisphere until 2020, when the COVID-19 eCommerce boom made it take the first place once again, although rather briefly.   Passenger-wise, it averages 80 flights a day, with Delta Airlines being the market share leader with 21.33% (828,000) of the total number of passengers between 2021 and 2022. American Airlines is second, with 20.36% (790,000), and Southwest is third, with 18.47% (717,000). As far as destinations are concerned, Atlanta is the busiest, with 422,000 passengers, followed by Dallas-Fort Worth and Charlotte, with 257,000 and 190,000, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with a fully modeled terminal interior, animated jetways, high-resolution custom ground textures, surrounding buildings fully modeled, parallax windows, airline codes assigned to each parking, and FSLTL compatibility.   It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $22.73, requiring at least 2.53 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxlau</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Launceston Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxlau" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c9d5f38c8a89332bff2688_launce1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="626040"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Launceston Airport (YMLT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second-busiest airport in Tasmania after Hobart, with a yearly average of 1,500,000 passengers (pre-pandemic).  Qantas Group is the biggest operator in the airport, with their subsidiary (JetStar) offering up to six daily flights to and from Melbourne, two daily flights to and from Sydney, and one daily flight to Brisbane. Virgin Australia offers a similar selection with five daily flights to and from Melbourne, one to Sydney, and seasonal flights on select days to Brisbane. Airlines of Tasmania and Sharp Airlines offer a variety of short legs to nearby destinations. Its origins date back to the early 1930s, when it was established as a small grass runway for regional flights, then called The Western Junction Aerodrome. It was officially opened as a government aerodrome in 1931 when over 20,000 people watched Colonel Brinsmead - then controller of civil aviation - “cut the inaugural ribbon.” From 1932 and beyond, small aircraft would fly from Launceston to Flinders Island.  During WW2, it was used by the Royal Australian Air Force as a flight school, preparing pilots for combat. It was the only RAAF air base in  Tasmania. Two of the hangars are still around to this day.  In the early 60s, plans for a Major redevelopment were approved, which included a runway extension, pavement strengthening, and a new terminal building. In 1982, the runway was once again extended to allow for the operation of Boeing 767s. The current privatization came in 1998, with joint ownership between the Launceston City Council and Australia Pacific Airports Corporation. The post-9/11 crisis and the rise of low-cost airlines made the airport grow in passenger traffic, reaching one million passengers for the first time in 2007.  Such exponential growth demanded another expansion, which doubled the size of the terminal and reached completion in November 2009, costing 20 million Australian dollars.  Developed by Ken Hall, an indie, who happens to be from the region and had exclusive access to the airport, taking hundreds of reference pictures to help with the accuracy and even allow for extra realism on the texturing side of things. It features a faithful recreation of the airport as it currently stands, with PBR texturing, static aircraft, detailed hangars, and terminal building. It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $17.03, requiring at least 2.65 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orppsw</id>
    <title>ORBX and PilotPlus Release Swansea Airport for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orppsw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cafddf53c71e39f5c8cc22_63be885504258-400x225.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="29143"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ORBX and PilotPlus have teamed up to release a highly detailed and accurate Swansea airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This new scenery package is set to give pilots an immersive and realistic flying experience as they navigate the airport and surrounding areas. With state-of-the-art technology and a wealth of information about the real-world airport, Pilots can expect an unparalleled level of realism and attention to detail. The scenery package boasts the following features:  You can purchase this stunning new scenery on the ORBX store for £10.68 today! </summary>
    <published>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdb7m</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Boeing 737-700 on MSFS' Marketplace</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdb7m" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cb996e473b13dd70d97940_zach1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1081091"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG’s Boeing 737-700 is now available on Microsoft Flight Simulator's marketplace, only on PC at this time and priced at $69.99 (pricing may vary per region).  ‍ The marketplace version is almost identical to the PMDG Store counterpart, featuring three different variations: passenger, BBJ, and cargo, all with accurately represented systems, a high-fidelity flight model, PBR textures, a realistic flight deck, and different cabins matching the chosen variation, along with the ability to pick between winglets or split scimitars. The only difference between both is that the Marketplace version does not come with the Operations Center, which is obtainable from their official downloads section. Updates might also take longer, as the files need to be approved by Microsoft before being pushed to the marketplace. The Boeing 737-700 is a single-aisle, twin-engine jetliner that is part of the 737 aircraft family. It was introduced by Boeing in 1997 as a shorter and more fuel-efficient version of the 737-800, typically seating between 110 and 149 passengers (depending on the configuration), and offering up to 2,950nm of range. Commonly used by airlines for short to medium-haul flights, it's known for its reliability and cost-effectiveness. ‍ Images are courtesy of ZachJaneway. There’s no information regarding the arrival of the -600 and -800 models to the marketplace yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw172</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases Cessna 172 Sound Set for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw172" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cba00350b9e2b761ab35e8_boris172.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1087078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Boris Audio Works has recently released their Cessna 172 Sound Set for Microsoft Flight Simulator, built on hours of real-life interior and exterior recordings made with industry-grade equipment. It is their second payware sound set for MSFS, released nearly two months after the first one.   Compatible with both the G1000 and steam gauge variants (and the WBSim 172 modification), featuring different specific sounds for both, such as battery and gyro noise on the steam gauges, which is silent on the G1000, as per real life. The sound set also includes dynamic engine sounds, wind and aerodynamic drag, dynamic touchdown and ground roll, multi-stage stall horn, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:  -Dynamic engine sounds -Wind and aerodynamic drag -Buttons, switches, knobs, and levers -Fuel pump -Batteries, gyros, and avionics fans* -Dynamic touchdowns and ground rolls* -Stall horn with several stages changing intensity depending on AOA -And more! ‍  It’s available on the Threshold Store for $15.00 and SimMarket for roughly $16.24, requiring at least 37 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mldias</id>
    <title>MLD Scenery Releases Iasi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mldias" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cc6a2b15b51488c4e41ee1_iasi1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3268316"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MLD Scenery has recently released their rendition of Iasi International Airport (LRIA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth-busiest airport in Romania with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers (pre-pandemic).  As one of the oldest accredited airports in Romania, its history dates back to almost 100 years ago (1926), when it first became a commercial airport with scheduled flights, operated by CFRNA (Compagnie Franco-Roumaine de Navigation Aérienne). Almost 30 years later, it got a new runway, a modern lighting system, and a passenger terminal followed in 1969, with another upgrade in 2001 to separate domestic and international flights.  A brand new terminal (T2) was built in 2012, increasing its passenger capacity and specially designated for Schengen and domestic flights. A long-term, multi-stage upgrade program started the year after, including a new runway (finished in 2014), a new terminal building (inaugurated in 2015), and an apron extension (completed in 2021).  In early 2022, the managers signed a €66 million contract with an Austrian construction company to design and build a new terminal (T4) and extend the parking lot, increasing the airport’s capacity to 3.3 million passengers yearly. The estimated completion date is sometime in December 2023.  The scenery features a high-fidelity rendition of the airport, with an updated layout (as of 2022), custom ground polygons, custom approach and taxi lights, custom night lighting, parallax windows, and photorealistic textures on the airport buildings. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.16, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdtgs</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Updates GSX Pro for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdtgs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cc77b9b0c560cfb0f3392e_gsxpro.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="51362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDreamTeam has recently updated GSX Pro for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding support for remote deicing, new menu colors, and several QoL improvements.  GSX Pro improves and expands the ground services with realistic pushback, catering, refueling, baggage loading, and marshaling, introducing unique features such as visible animated passengers, cargo loading, follow me cars, towbar pushback, de-icing, underground refueling, walk-in gates, VDGS docking systems, and more.   The newest update adds support for remote deicing, allowing the user to call for deicing on remote pads like in real life. FSDT claims it’s just the first step of the update, with the upcoming one featuring editing of custom deicing areas.   The deicing fluid simulation was also improved, with different colors per fluid type (one is yellow, two is clear, three is orange, and four is green) and varying saturation depending on concentration.   GSX’s in-game menu was modified, featuring a new color scheme that better matches the sim’s default color palette, and new icons to help differentiate between runway starts and custom deicing areas.  The update also added an option to ignore departure time when using SimBrief, internal support for the Aerosoft TwinOtter and PMDG DC-6, new safedock types, exclusion patterns to prevent jetways not being recognized correctly on some third-party airports using jetway links as simobjects, and more. The complete changelog follows down below:  ‍ It’s available on FSDreamTeam’s website for $29.99, requiring at least 8 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
