<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-02-28T18:26:06.030492+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthnas</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Nashville International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthnas" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f006fabb25c11a994ce745_nash1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1222254"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Nashville International Airport (KBNA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Nashville Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 18 million passengers.  Opened in June 1937, passenger service started a month later with American Airlines and Eastern Air Lines. It originally featured three runways, a three-story passenger terminal, a control tower, two hangars, and a beacon. The yearly figures hit nearly 190,000 passengers.  It was used as the headquarters for the 4th Ferrying Command during World War 2, ferrying aircraft to Europe at the height of the war. The ferrying operations demanded a lot of space, which implied an expansion to 1,500 acres of total area.   Nearly a decade later, the City Aviation Department made plans to modernize and expand the airport, with a new terminal, runway expansion, and a new crosswind runway to come in 1961.  As a curiosity, Nashville Intl. was the first municipal airport in the United States with a public reading room.   It has seen a lot of expansion work over the following years, with its peak in the late 1980s, when American Airlines made a hub in Nashville and attracted many companies to the city, such as Nissan and Saturn Corporation. The hub eventually closed in 1995, when American couldn’t afford to lose any more money (it wasn’t profitable even during its heyday).   The airport has been recently modernized, with operations starting in 2006 and reaching its conclusion five years later, expanding the ticketing and check-in areas, renovating and constructing new bathrooms, and bringing the total size of the terminal to 1 million square feet. In 2021, the operator made a plan called “New Horizon” to further improve the airport, at the cost of 1.5 billion USD. Construction is set to begin in 2023 and reach completion in late 2028.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with over a hundred custom-modeled buildings, taxi bridges, custom night lighting, custom jetways, and custom ground polygon.   It’s available on SimMarket and on FeelThere’s Shop for $21.39/$19.99 (respectively), requiring at least 609 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bb7572</id>
    <title>BlueBird Sim 757, One-Year Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bb7572" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f2505d1ab2a2cf1b8707b4_fuse.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="931493"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BlueBird Simulations have released a youtube video in which they celebrate the one-year anniversary of the development of their upcoming Boeing 757 aircraft for MSFS. In the update, the team thanked those who have contributed to the project, answered various questions the community has had and displayed some of the aircraft's features in flight.  BlueBird has confirmed the expected release date is q3/q4 of 2023. They have also confirmed that they are developing both a freighter and passenger variant of the single-isle jet, the passenger variant will come first followed by the freighter expansion. The freighter and passenger jets will be two separate packages according to the team.  The team have also disclosed that they are aiming for a mid-level simulation, in which every switch and system needed for normal operation will be operable. It will boast a fully custom FMS with full LNAV and VNAV capability. The team have also confirmed a full virtual cabin will be in the aircraft.  You can watch the video here: </summary>
    <published>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbkden1</id>
    <title>FlightBeam Updates KDEN to V1.1.0</title>
    <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbkden1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f2539d76f9542bb9be11f7_eba5cc_996d6fd0592741c498f891efdfd19e71_mv2.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="710378"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam has updated its Denver airport scenery to version 1.1.0! The new update brings a host of new features and improvements, including the new west side expansion with new gates (concourse B) It also incorporates the new and improved gen5 jetways from Flightbeam for added immersion.  The update is free to those who own the airport scenery and is a massive enhancement to the original scenery, this update brings Denver to the highest possible level of accuracy.  Full changelog:  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwsfar</id>
    <title>Realworldscenery Releases Fairbanks International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwsfar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f3eede681ebde1bcedc025_fair1-min.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1115507"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Realworldscenery has recently released their rendition of Fairbanks International Airport (PAFA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Fairbanks (Alaska), the smallest city in the country with regularly scheduled non-stop international flights.  The airport’s history dates back to 1951, when it replaced Ladd Army Airfield as the gateway to Fairbanks, serving as Alaska Airlines’ main hub up until 1967 when they moved to Anchorage, yet keeping the Anchorage - Fairbanks service. It was also an important stopover for Braniff International, Pan American World Airways, American Airlines, and Western Airlines in the 60s and 70s. To conform with the current TSA standards, the original terminal (from 1948) was entirely demolished and replaced by a brand new one in late 2009, featuring better design and security, an extra jetway bridge (six instead of five), handling an average of 1 million passengers per year.  It’s the hub for Everts Air, operating scheduled and charter airline cargo all across Alaska and Canada with a fleet of classic aircraft, including the C-46, the Douglas DC-6, and the Douglas MD-83. It also hosts Warbelow’s Air Ventures and Wright Air Service. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom-made buildings, performance-friendly optimization, and a realistic taxiway layout.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.58, requiring at least 1.3 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/salber</id>
    <title>Salvuz Releases Bergen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/salber" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f3fbca8a0b4eb5c41a7929_sal1-min%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3619390"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Salvuz has recently released their rendition of Bergen Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Dating back to the early 1950s, Bergen Airport was partially funded by the municipalities of Bergen and Fana with 4 million Norwegian kroner, securing the construction of a terminal and a 1,460-meter-long runway. NATO funded an expansion in 1953, warranting a 2,440-meter-long runway instead. When the first flight landed at the airport in mid-1954, only 800 meters of it were complete. It was a chartered flight from Bergen to Oslo, transporting a local football team.  It’s a hub for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe, with an extensive domestic and intra-European network. According to 2014 data, Scandinavian Airlines had 46% of the market share for domestic flights, Norwegian had 38%, and Widerøe 15%. International-wise, Norwegian led the way with 36%, SAS had 23%, and KLM with 18% (with a single route to Amsterdam).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, sporting handcrafted buildings and facilities with detailed interiors, PBR texturing in 2K or 4K, two custom jetway models, precise terrain markings according to the latest charts, sloped runways with accurate altitude profiles, and parking stands as per latest AIP charts.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.24, requiring at least 1.6 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inokla</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Oklahoma City Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inokla" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f6b84ae13839444842302f_mat1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1643375"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IniBuilds has recently released the next airport in the Iniscene line, Oklahoma City Will Rogers Airport (KOKC), for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Will Rogers airport is the busiest in the state of Oklahoma serving over 3.3 million passengers annually.  The airport started its life in 1911 as Oklahoma City Municipal Airport and served many squadrons of the United States Army Air Force during World War II. The airport was given its current name in 1941 in memory of Will Rogers, a famous comedian and cowboy native to Oklahoma.  Today the airport is home to several airlines and a few Oklahoma Air National Guard Wings. Southwest Airlines serves Will Rogers airport as a focus city serving over 10 destinations from the airport. United Airlines, American Airlines, Delta Airlines, Alaska Airlines, and Frontier all also serve the airport. Features of this scenery include: This airport can be picked up for £14.99 GBP ($18.15 USD) from the IniBuilds Store and will require roughly 4.87 Gb to install. Huge thanks to Tang0 on the Threshold Discord for bringing us this news scoop.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navmob</id>
    <title>Navigraph Releases Mobile Charts for Smartphones and Highly Detailed Airport Diagrams</title>
    <updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navmob" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f7cba22f3f85d204a6da43_Charts-Mobile-Screens.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1400015"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Navigraph has recently released the mobile/smartphone version of their recently released Charts 8 update, offering the same feature set as the tablet version but adapted to smaller screens. Charts Cloud, their browser-based version of the application, was also made compatible with smartphone screen aspect ratios.  The Charts 8 update came out in early November 2022, adding worldwide VFR charts coverage, drag-and-drop rubber band route construction, seamless zoom down to gate level, and 3D globe projection. It was developed with an emphasis on delivering a seamless and intuitive experience, reducing the pilot workload during a simulated flight. The new mobile app will allow users to experience said update on Android and iPhone devices.  Along with the new mobile charts for smartphones, Navigraph has also updated the Charts system with highly detailed airport diagrams rendered from the Jeppesen Airport Mapping Database (AMDB), featuring over a thousand airports around the globe. It’s said to facilitate a pilot’s situational awareness by allowing them to view essential references.  The Airport Mapping Database (AMDB) is a set of information on specific airports including their spatial layout, their geometry (taxiways, runways, buildings, etc.), and other characteristics such as runway surface type and slope, etc.  The update is available right now for Navigraph Unlimited subscribers. Click here to find out more about the Unlimited plan and its features. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzacia</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases Christchurch International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzacia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f8109287c96cd8ec4be544_chr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1118538"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NZA Simulations has recently released their rendition of Christchurch International Airport (NZCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in New Zealand with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. Opened in 1940 as RNZAF Station Harewood (the airport is located in Harewood, a suburb of Christchurch), it got its first bits of infrastructure around six years later, with the construction of a passenger terminal and hangars. The clearance for international operations came in 1950, making it New Zealand’s first international airport. It’s the hub for Air New Zealand, with a significant domestic network covering most relevant cities within the country, including Auckland, Dunedin, Hamilton, Hokitika, Invercargill, Napier, Nelson, New Plymouth, Palmerston North, Queenstown, Rotorua, Tauranga, and Wellington. The coverage also extends to Australia, with Brisbane, Gold Coast, Melbourne, and Sydney. The visitors’ list includes Cathay Pacific (returning in November 2023), Emirates (returning in March 2023), Fiji Airways, Jetstar Airways, Qantas, and Singapore Airlines. In total, there are 18 domestic and 11 international destinations, with 1057 weekly flights as of 2015. The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, with full 3D custom modeling including the surrounding business parks (roughly 300 in total), the runways and apron are built with PBR materials, realistic ground markings, realistic roads, high resolution aerial imagery, terra-formed runway, parking positions setup with correct airline codes, interiors for the main terminal, custom jetway sounds, animated jetways (custom for each gate, matching real life), animated 3D people, animated custom AI vehicles around the airport, and a working surveillance radar. It’s available on the NZA Simulations Shop or OrbxDirect for $25.46/$25.38, respectively. At least 4.27 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wupdnz</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XII: New Zealand</title>
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wupdnz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f81b62f108693de8e05de7_nz1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="326542"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released the 12th World Update, improving New Zealand with seven high-detail cities, multiple points of interest, nine handcrafted airports, new bush trips, discovery flights, and challenges. The new update brings together the latest geographic data, including satellite imagery, aerial photography, and digital elevation models (DEMs), with high-detail renditions of seven cities: Auckland, Christchurch, Hamilton, Nelson, Queenstown, Tauranga, and Wellington.  The complete feature list follows down below: Points of Interest ‍ Handcrafted Airports Bush Trips ‍ Discovery Flights   Landing Challenges ‍ The World Update is available for free on the MSFS Marketplace.   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inbf10</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Bf108 Taifun for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inbf10" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f8cf130fc60bf70eb8cad5_taif1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="374950"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of the Bf108 Taifun for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engine sport aircraft from the early 1930s.   Designed to compete in the 4th Challenge International de Tourisme in 1934, a major aviation event in pre-war Europe held in Warsaw, Poland, the Taifun was then just a prototype called M34, powered by a 247 horsepower Hirth HM 8U V8 engine, which didn’t manage to win the event but impressed with a low fuel consumption rate, good handling and it’s superb take-off/landing characteristics.  The Bf108a, the first variant, took off for the first time in that same year, powered by three different engines (on different airframes): the original Hirth HM 8U, the Argus As 17B with 217 hp, and later units had a Siemens-Halske Sh 14 radial, with 158hp. The Bf108b was a revision whose prototype rocked a Siemens-Halske Sh 14a radial, but the production units had either the Argus AS 10C (237hp) or the Argus AS 10E (266hp).  iniBuilds’ second classic aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator makes use of the latest CFD technology including the primary flight surfaces, control surfaces, and the propeller. It also simulates unique characteristics of the airplane such as the capability of landing as slow as 45 knots thanks to its advanced leading edge slats. Such slow speed allows it to operate on very short runways.  The engine is accurately reproduced with its correct performance and behavior, with a fully modeled and functional fuel system that makes use of the new fuel mechanics offered by the simulator.   A custom electronic flight bag allows for folding and unfolding the wings, opening storage compartments, choosing a custom rain cover, and changing the cockpit labels from German to English and from metric to imperial. It also features a moving map, weather information, a maintenance page, and other settings.  The aircraft is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.01, requiring at least 2.66 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mturku</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Turku Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mturku" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f9bd57d5c4ba3c1dfad474_turku1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="800719"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations has recently released their rendition of Turku Airport (EFTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Turku in Finland with a yearly average of 450,000 passengers, making it the fourth busiest airport in the country. Located in the airport district in the Maaria-Paatinen ward, which is the most sparsely populated district in Turku and includes half of the city’s area, it was built in 1955 when it was still part of Rusko, becoming part of Turku three years later.  Turku Airport underwent a heavy renovation process in mid-2014 when Finavia spent over 14 million euros on improving Terminal One and the passenger apron. Terminal 2 was closed and demolished a year later after an oil leakage, concentrating the low-cost operations on the first floor of the main terminal. It’s currently served by six different airlines: AirBaltic (Riga), Amapola Flyg (Mariehamn), Finnair (Helsinki), Scandinavian Airlines (Stockholm-Arlanda), Sunclass Airlines (seasonal legs to Gran Canaria and Tenerife South), and WizzAir (Gdansk and Rome Fiumicino). Gdansk is the busiest route as of 2019, with 117,261 passengers, followed by Helsinki and Stockholm, with 100,086 and 86,331, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with updated CGL data, real-world-based terraforming profile, PBR materials, ambient animated objects, custom interior modeling, and custom 3D people. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.86, requiring at least 2.44 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpgib</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Gibraltar International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpgib" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fa87ca5f80df35b501c500_gibby1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2502245"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently released their rendition of Gibraltar International Airport (LXGB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth most extreme airport in the World according to the History Channel’s Most Extreme Airports.    Dating back to early World War 2, it was built as an emergency airfield for the British Royal Navy, with runway extensions to happen later on once some of the land was reclaimed by using rocks from the Rock of Gibraltar (what remained of carving military tunnels).   The airport saw most of its business flourish in the early 2000s when Monarch began flying from Manchester. Iberia, easyJet, and British Airways followed suit not soon after. Nowadays, British Airways and easyJet are the only two airlines serving Gibraltar frequently with routes to London-Heathrow (BA) and Bristol, London Gatwick, and Manchester (EZY), roughing up to 400,000 passengers a year.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models, PBR texturing, a terminal interior with 3D passengers, more than a thousand clutter objects, realistic and functioning runway crossing (cars stop when turning the strobe light on), custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, accurate night lighting, custom taxiway signage, custom ground traffic, and over twenty animations.   It’s available on the RDPresets Store and SimMarket for roughly $21.13/$19.02, respectively. At least 1.3 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p73763</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p73763" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fa932fe014bebc53f436d6_pine1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2595376"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their 737 lineup to version 3.00.0063 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a range of minor fixes and improvements along with an Operations Center update.  In order to update the product, customers have to manually update the Operations Center, as the automatic update system is not working. The instructions are available on the announcement post here.   As previously mentioned, it’s a minor update with improvements to the whole lineup with the intent to "move the quality forward", as stated by the CEO. The complete changelog follows down below:  ‍ After the release of the -900, they claim to focus on general fixes, updates to the existing logic, and merging in the new navdata. Work also continues on the Universal Flight Tablet. They finished off with a note on the MSFS Beta Channel, especially regarding the SU12 compatibility, where it's stated they might hold off on updates until SU12 is out to the public, with an eventual beta channel on the Operations Center that would allow PMDG to push updates to both stable and beta (something for the future after the tablet is out and they are happy with all the pending improvements).   The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600), $49.99 (737-900), and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Pictures are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bwssan</id>
    <title>Borneo Wonder Sceneries Releases Sandakan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bwssan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fb6f9570220e8e9e9d34c1_sanda1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3358680"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Borneo Wonder Sceneries has recently released their rendition of Sandakan Airport (WBKS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Sandakan, the capital of the Sandakan District in Sabah, Malaysia.   Sandakan Airport’s history dates back to World War 2 when the Royal Air Force picked the site to build an airfield but didn’t actually get to do much other than get rid of the vegetation before the Japanese invasion of Borneo. The Japanese Army, on the other hand, needed a refueling stop between the peninsular Malaya and the Philippines, transferring over 1,500 prisoners of war from the UK and Australia to work on the construction. Work started in August 1942 and saw partial completion by December of that same year, when a bomber aircraft landed in Sandakan for the first time, opening it for service.   The runway was recently extended to 2,500m, with an expansion plan that goes all the way back to 2017, with operations commencing in 2019 but delayed due to the pandemic and finally reaching completion in 2022, allowing the operation of popular narrowbody aircraft like the B737, A320, and the A321. Widebody aircraft can also operate on it with payload/range restrictions.   It’s served by AirAsia (Kota Kinabalu, Kuala Lumpur), Malaysia Airlines (Kota Kinabalu, Kuala Lumpur), and MASwings (Kudat, Lahad Datu, Tawau), averaging around 900,000 passengers yearly.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled terminal (including interior), landside buildings, custom ground textures, custom ground markings, and a custom jetway model.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.63, requiring at least 899 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff3206</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Update’s A320 to Version 1.6.1</title>
    <updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff3206" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fbb4aac649c1c142244a67_a320%20-%202022-09-05%2022.53.26.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="255023"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor's A320 has been one of the most popular and well-regarded flight simulation aircraft for some time. The latest update to the A320 includes several improvements and fixes that enhance the overall experience of flying the plane. In this news article, we will take a closer look at the improvements and fixes introduced in the update. Cabin Visual Improvements: One of the most notable improvements in this update is the enhancement of the cabin visuals. The update brings improvements to the cabin, which helps to create a more immersive experience. These improvements make the cabin feel more realistic and add to the overall realism of the aircraft. Fixes: The update also includes several fixes which address issues that were present in previous versions of the addon. Some of these fixes are: ‍ Dimmed Cabin Floor Light Stripe: One of the issues addressed in this update is the floor light stripe. The update fixes this issue and ensures that the light stripe appears as intended. ‍ VSW Stuck and Not Moving: Another issue addressed in this update is the VSW stuck and not moving. The VSW (Vertical Speed Wheel) is an essential component of the aircraft, and when it gets stuck, it can cause problems for the pilot. The update fixes this issue and ensures that the VSW operates correctly. ‍ Overspeed Protection Too Aggressive: The overspeed protection in the A320 was too aggressive, which meant that the aircraft would automatically reduce its speed even when it was not necessary. This update fixes this issue and ensures that the overspeed protection operates as intended. ‍ Missed Doors in XP11 Version: In the XP11 version of the A320, some doors were missing. The update fixes this issue and ensures that all doors are present and functioning correctly. ‍ Missed Internal Lights in the Cockpit and Cabin in XP11 Version: Another issue in the XP11 version was the missed internal lights in the cockpit and cabin. The update fixes this issue and ensures that all internal lights are present and working correctly. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msf225</id>
    <title>MSFS Antonov 225 Released</title>
    <updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msf225" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dac683833efb0722aeb239_BANNER.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="938152"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The flight sim world is abuzz with excitement following the release of the AN225 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The AN225 Mriya, which means "Dream" in Ukrainian, is the world's largest aircraft and has a fascinating history. The INI Builds team along with Microsoft Flight sim has meticulously recreated this sorely missed behemoth of the skies in stunning detail, giving players the chance to experience what it's like to fly this iconic aircraft. The AN225 was originally designed in the Soviet Union in the 1980s as a heavy-lift transport aircraft for military and civilian use. The AN225 was used to transport the Soviet space shuttle, Buran, and was still used up until last year for heavy cargo transport, it was unfortunately destroyed in the ongoing Ukraine war. INI Builds has captured the essence of this aircraft in their simulation, from its massive wingspan to the distinctive six engines that power it. Pilots who purchase the MSFS/ INI Builds AN225 can experience the unique challenges of handling such a large and powerful machine. With great flight physics and attention to detail, the AN225 is sure to become a favourite among flight simulator pilots. MSFS have stated that 100% of the funds received from pilots who purchase the AN225 will go toward the cost of rebuilding the real aircraft.  You can pick up the AN225 on the MSFS store for just $19.99 </summary>
    <published>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
