<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-24T18:21:55.619482+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eghfms</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases Solent Airport (EGHF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eghfms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a0b2574c4015caf0a745e2_Screenshot%202022-12-19%20at%201.49.05%20PM-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1215958"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Burning Blue Design released their rendition of Solent Airport (EGHF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery, with its up-to-date airport layout and realistic 3D models, will deliver the most immersive experience for pilots when they are looking for a weekend get-away to coastal England. According to Burning Blue Design, the team has visited the airport multiple times in order to create the most realistic product possible for the community. The scenery will be based on the latest layout of the airport and will include custom light lighting, more than 200 custom-made models ranging from hangers to control towers, and high quality PBR textures. Additionally, certain hanger doors are designed to close automatically at night and must be opened by pilots using their taxi lights. Finally, the developers have optimized the airport to have it “blend in with local Photogrammetry” and added static aircraft as well as local landmarks. For the full list of features, check out the Orbx storepage. 	Solent Airport was built as Royal Air Force base HMS Daedalus and served as a vital role in both world wars. Post war, the airport served as a testing facility for hovercrafts before being closed in 1996. It was opened in 2015 as a civilian airfield with the name Solent Airport. Currently, Solent Airport can be purchased on Orbx or the developer’s own webstore for US$20.77, excluding any sales tax that may incur. The developer recommends potential buyers to have at least 1.31GB of free space on their hard drives in order to successfully install the product.</summary>
    <published>2022-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orxvol</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Major Volanta Update</title>
    <updated>2022-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orxvol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a0e9daee2ed9e6151074d8_volantacover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1266190"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently updated their popular flight tracking software to version 1.4, bringing new features such as Navigraph integration, stream overlay, a mobile app for premium users, and improved schedules. Volanta Mobile will allow users to remotely monitor their flights, with active flight statistics, and remote pause (P3D, FSX, and X-Plane), featuring the same map as the desktop version with a similar performance and feature set. It’s available for iOS and Android.   The FlightAware Schedules provide industry-leading data to Volanta’s Real-World Scheduling System, with good coverage around the World, and frequent updates, with increased reliability when it comes to aircraft type.   The Stream Overlay is a brand new addition to Volanta, featuring a dynamically updating overlay for content creators, with a range of pre-built color schemes for non-Premium users (further customization is available for Premium users), with more layouts to come in the future. The overlay can display information such as origin, destination, callsign, ETA, ground speed, vertical speed, heading, and altitude.  The Navigraph Integration will allow users with the Navigraph Charts Subscription to access their charts from within Volanta.  The complete changelog follows down below:   - Switched data providers for schedules to FlightAware. - Added a Navigraph Charts slideout panel - Added a stream overlay with varying themes, and custom theme for premium users - Released Android &amp; iOS companion apps for premium users. - Flights page no longer auto-zooms and pans as a result of user feedback. - Added more language translations. - Added links to official Volanta support and Discord to the settings page. - Added a setting to disable plugin install notifications - Added scenery scan caching to improve load times for some users experiencing freezing and stuttering on startup. - Added display of runway numbers in the SimBrief OFP panel, no more scrolling down to find them! - Added the ability to add your own flights to the roster. - Improved the design of Volanta's Discord rich presence, now showing the simulator in use and a link to view the flight. - Fixed aircraft icon for the users own flight not always updating on the map. - Fixed a bug with scanning local save files which could also lead to performance problems on startup. - Fixed roster flight line sometimes being stuck on the map. - Fixed roster flights not being removed from the map when a roster flight is deleted. - Fixed rare cases of flight saves not being saved when the aircraft title couldn't be detected. - Fixed modals being too wide in Firefox. - Fixed orientation of text in panels based on language (Chinese, Japanese and Korean are no longer inverted). - Updated Electron version with security updates and other dependencies. - Improved resilience of connection to our real-time update socket service with better retry and queueing of messages. ‍ Volanta 1.4 is available on their official website, free of charge.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inisat</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates San Antonio International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inisat" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a12669a612c58d1da437e7_inisat1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3243900"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated their rendition of San Antonio International Airport (KSAT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of San Antonio, TX with an average of 260 daily departures to 53 destinations in the United States and Mexico, with more than 10 million passengers yearly.  It’s served by Aeroméxico Connect (Mexico City), Alaska Airlines (Seattle-Tacoma), Allegiant Air (Las Vegas), American Airlines (Charlotte, Chicago O’Hare, Dallas-Fort Worth, Los Angeles, Miami, and Phoenix-Sky Harbor), American Eagle (Chicago O’Hare, Los Angeles, and Miami), Delta Air Lines (Atlanta, Detroit, Los Angeles, Minneapolis, and Salt Lake City), Frontier (Atlanta, Denver, Las Vegas, Orlando, and Philadelphia), JetBlue (Boston and New York JFK), Southwest Airlines (Atlanta, Baltimore, Cancún, Chicago-Midway, Dallas-Love, Denver, El Paso, Houston-Hobby, Las Vegas, Los Angeles, Nashville, New Orleans, Oklahoma City, Orlando, Phoenix-Sky Harbor, San Diego, Saint Louis, and Tampa), United Airlines (Chicago O’Hare, Denver, Houston, Newark, San Francisco, and Washington-Dulles), United Express (Chicago O’Hare, Houston-Intercontinental, and Washington-Dulles), Viva Aerobus (Léon/Del-Bajio, Mexico City, Monterrey), and Volaris (Guadalajara and Mexico City).   Dallas-Fort Worth is the busiest destination with 495,000 passengers a year, followed by Atlanta and Denver at 394,000 and 352,000, respectively. Southwest tops the chart regarding passenger share as of 2021, with 39% (1,274,000), with American in 2nd with 930,000 (28,56%), and Delta with 281,000 (8,62%).   The scenery update features another round of performance optimizations, better LODs for 3D vegetation and parked vehicles, ground polygon rework to correct deformed taxilines and asphalt materials, addition of a hangar interior with automated doors, added missing highway overpass bridges, night lighting rework, general enhancement to visuals with steady performance balance, and compatibility with iniManager configuration options.   It’s available on the IniBuilds Store for roughly $15.04 (promotional price), requiring at least 6.61 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mokchi</id>
    <title>Mokui Releases Chinggis Khaan International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mokchi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a12c853eb6d9075be6a77b_gengis1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="373758"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mokui has recently released their rendition of Chinggis Khaan International Airport (ZMCK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, also known as New Ulaanbaatar International Airport. Situated in the Khöshig Valley of Sergelen (Mongolia), it serves as the primary airport for Ulaanbaatar and region, replacing Buyant-Ukhaa International Airport as the Country's main airport.   Opened 17 months ago, Chinggis Khaan Intl was built to handle up to 1,100 passengers an hour (three million passengers a year) and 11,900 tonnes of cargo.   It’s the hub for all Major Mongolian airlines, which include Aero Mongolia (Altai, Dalanzagdad, Khovd, Mörön, Ölgii, Ovoot, Oyu Tolgoi, Tavan Tolgoi, Tianjin, Tokyo-Narita, and Ulaangom), Eznis Airways, Hunnu Air (Almaty, Bishkek, Harbin, and Ulan-Ude), and MIAT Mongolian Airlines (Beijing-Capital, Busan, Frankfurt, Hong Kong, Istanbul, Moscow-Sheremetyevo, Seoul-Incheon, and Tokyo-Narita).   The scenery features an accurate representation of the airport as it stands in 2022, with a detailed passenger terminal, cargo area, and facility buildings, with high-resolution textures, detailed ground textures, accurate elevation data, accurate ground markings, detailed night lighting, fixed vegetation, and missing SID/STAR data and ILS/RNP approaches from Mongolia AIP.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.65, requiring at least 95 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/parflw</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Flow for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/parflw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a17e9f6a09671055752c6a_flwbig2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="496765"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently released Flow, their customizable menu system for Microsoft Flight Simulator, replacing the default Toolbar with an intuitive and easy-to-navigate in-game interaction wheel. It’s said to challenge the status quo by offering a new and improved way of accessing and interacting with information within the simulator, easing the chore of navigating through the multiple options of the default toolbar.   The core features consist of fully resizable interface elements (helping people with vision or cognitive impairments), full access to the currently installed MSFS panels (including third-party), in-sim operability without external app requirements, and a sleek and interactive wheel offering a customizable - and toggable - alternative to the default toolbar, with static and dynamic wheels (static is always shown, dynamic is only shown on specific aircraft), and optimization for the Xbox One controller.  Flow also includes a Toolbar Enhancement feature, where you can either disable the old toolbar entirely or enable an enhanced version with better - and fluider - animations.   There are three different flavors of Flow, which follow down below:  Flow (free): The freeware version allows access to the default - and third-party - toolbar panels from an on-screen overlay, with a wheel that can be toggled on or off with a configurable key or button. It offers a modern approach to the menu system, allowing you to customize your experience for each user or aircraft.   Flow Essentials ($15): Essentials brings a selection of widgets made by Parallel 42, allowing the user to find friends, teleport, change servers, change the time of day, swap weather presets, discover different camera angles, toggle landing gear, and more. They have also included widgets for popular actions that people might want.  Flow Pro ($25): Pro caters to the power users with advanced features like the creation and sharing of custom widgets with JavaScript coding, along with Twitch integration for content creators, and Otto, a search bar for power users that allows for unit conversion, math, METAR data request, top of descent calculation, and more.  All the three flavors of Flow are available on Orbx Direct, requiring at least 10.26 MB of free disk space to install. Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avtfra</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Releases Frankfurt Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avtfra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a2431b13166c26ad4125b3_fra1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2260274"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aviotek Simulation Software has recently released their rendition of Frankfurt International Airport (EDDF) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the busiest airport in Germany and the 4th in Europe, with a yearly average of 69 million passengers. Offering more than 300 destinations in 5 continents, it is the airport with the most direct routes in the World. It is the Main hub for Lufthansa, the national carrier of Germany, with an extensive route network both intra-european and transcontinentally. The regional sister, Lufthansa CityLine, also operates out of FRA with their fleet of regional aircraft. It’s also a focus city for many LCCs like the Lufthansa-owned Eurowings, Eurowings Discover, Condor, and TUI fly Deutschland, with many seasonal routes to popular destinations in Spain, Greece, and Portugal.   The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, with a high-detail apron and terminal buildings, an updated layout, custom animated jetways (SAM compatible), up-to-date taxiways and runway signage, more than fifteen square kilometers of hand-placed high-resolution orthoimagery, custom animated airport vehicles and highway traffic, more than 150,000 custom hand placed objects, hand-made terrain and runway profiles made with special software, realistic high dynamic range night lighting, large amounts of ground service equipment and custom airport vehicles, and accurately placed custom static aircraft. It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $27.33, requiring 11.22 GB of free disk space to install. The developer warns about potential issues with X-Plane 12 because the platform is still under active development, and things might not work as expected. Customer support won’t be provided until then (only for X-Plane 11).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boupar</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Paris-Beauvais Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boupar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a24afa78b320aee260e3fd_lfob1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3878891"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released their rendition of Beauvais-Tillé Airport (LFOB) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the tenth busiest airport in France as of 2016, with a yearly average of 4 million passengers (pre-pandemic). It’s a popular destination for low-cost carriers such as Ryanair and WizzAir, which use it as a Parisian base.  Located only 85 km from Paris, it’s often called “Paris-Beauvais Airport” due to its proximity with the famous French city. With cheaper landing fees, less traffic and the convenience of not being in the middle of the fuss, it’s the airport of choice for many charters and LCCs. As a matter of fact, the airport has grown quite significantly after Ryanair embraced Beauvais in 1997, with the creation of a second terminal in 2010 to handle the extra traffic figures.   Other than WZZ and RYR with their extensive route networks to and from LFOB, the airport is also visited by Air Moldova with a single flight to Chisinau, HiSky with legs to Baia Mare and Chisinau, and EasyJet to Lisbon (flights to Milan and Nice to begin in mid-2023).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with real-world airport layout, up-to-date high-definition orthoimagery, 4K photorealisitc textures, PBR textures on ground and buildings, dynamic night lighting based of real-life color tones, 3D vegetation, 3D grass, nearby houses and farms, rain and seasonal effects on ground (XP12 only), custom high-definition PBR vehicles, and fully accurate ground markings with realistic wear and tear.  It’s available on Boundless Direct for roughly $17.05, requiring at least 880 MB of free disk space to install. Shout out to flightyler on Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hst650</id>
    <title>Hot Start Updates CL650 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12 </title>
    <updated>2022-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hst650" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a367517e5fd6c55ae56155_cl650.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="604525"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Hot Start has recently updated their popular Challenger 650 to version 1.7, adding X-Plane 12 support, a two-pilot shared cockpit, and a huge list of bug fixes and improvements. The “update highlights” follow down below: ‍ Please refer to the update announcement post, where you can find the full changelog with all the bug fixes and new features.  The Challenger 650 is part of the Challenger 600 family of business jets, introduced in the mid-70s, with its first flight in late 1978 and eventual certification in August 1980. Since then, many variants were created, with the 650 being the newest, dating back to 2015. It features a redesigned interior cabin, Rockwell Collins Pro Line 21 avionics, and an increase in take-off thrust. In real-life, the total cost nears 33 million usd (as of 2021). The X-Plane 11/12 version, on the other hand, can be yours for roughly $115.   The CL650 add-on features a high fidelity rendition of the real-world aircraft, with a complex simulation of its intricacies, along with a simulated FBO and all the things that go hand in hand such as full pre-flight duties, aiming for an unparalleled level of immersion.   It’s available on X-Aviation for $114.95, requiring a minimum of an i5 (or a quad-core equivalent), GTX 970 or similar, and 16 GB of RAM to function properly. An i7 or an octa-core equivalent, RTX 2070 or equivalent is recommended for optimal performance.  Shout out to Vinniethegreat on Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xdsege</id>
    <title>Xometry Design Updates Eagle County Regional Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xdsege" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a4e8c0f5f26b50ce2e35a5_ege1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2289836"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry Design has recently updated their rendition of Eagle County Regional Airport (KEGE), adding compatibility with X-Plane 12 and extra features. EGE becomes the second busiest airport in Colorado during the ski season, because of its proximity to popular skiing resorts, and the airport offers better landing conditions overall compared to Aspen (lower minimums).  Due to its seasonality, the scheduled passenger services come and go throughout the year, but it does not let down in terms of private flights,  featuring one of the best fixed-base private operators in the United States, the Vail Valley Jet Center, with eight heated hangars, over 30 acres of overnight storage, and planeside vehicle staging.  The new scenery update adds the aforementioned compatibility with X-Plane 12, a terminal interior, custom object rework, custom jetways, and a customized mesh with an Ortho4Xp patch, now making use of X-Plane 12’s 3D trees and bushes. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $13.57 (on sale), requiring at least 2.09 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simibz</id>
    <title>Sim-Wings Releases Ibiza Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simibz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a4eecf0ad2c13a66a9d182_ibi4.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1761747"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Sim-Wings has recently updated their rendition of Ibiza Airport (LEIB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding new features such as new jetways, texture improvements, terminal interiors, and more. The update is free for previous owners.   The airport serves the Balearic Islands of Ibiza, sitting 7km southwest of Ibiza Town. With a yearly average of 8 million passengers (pre-pandemic), it’s among the busiest airports in Spain, with a year-round domestic network and lots of seasonal Intra-European routes (mostly during summer). Vueling offers a fixed schedule with flights to Alicante, Barcelona, Bilbao, Madrid, Málaga, Paris-Orly, Seville, and Valencia, with seven extra routes during the summer, when they temporarily base some of their aircraft there.  The update changelog follows down below:  It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $15.99, requiring at least 5 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssmcd</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Previews E175’s MCDU for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssmcd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a63ac83eafb5b7ae8dc98b_crafts1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1606316"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG (in cooperation with X-Crafts) and AviationLads, have recently previewed the MCDU (Multi-Function Control and Display Unit) of the upcoming Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing a short route setup, performance initialization, and take-off data insertion. It’s the fourth and last preview video, with the next one being the official trailer and its eventual release under an early access program.  Yesterday, X-Crafts made a statement on their partnership with FlightSim Studio AG in order to bring the Embraer 175 to MSFS, where they clarified both are different products, developed by different teams and with distinct objectives, with the only commonality between both product lines being the 3D model, which is the same. They have also reinforced their commitment to bring the E-Jets to X-Plane 11/12 at one point in 2023.  The E175 is part of the Embraer E-Jets family, seating 78 to 88 passengers in different cabin configurations, with a range of 1800 nautical miles on the standard variant. There are 12 operators around the World, with SkyWest being the largest (193 aircraft).   There is no information regarding the release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cow206</id>
    <title>Cowan Simulation Releases Bell 206B3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cow206" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a642eecaf763b6416005a7_cow1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3532361"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cowan Simulation has recently released their rendition of the Bell 206B3 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a popular variant of the 206 family whose production ended in 2010 (later variants were to cease production in 2017). It is their first helicopter for MSFS, after releasing eight different models for X-Plane.  The Bell 206 had its first flight in 1962, after winning a competition held by the United States Navy to develop a Light Observation Helicopter. Their D-250 design went on to become the YHO-4, where it failed to win the contract bid, and Bell found themselves trying to market it as a civil aircraft (Model 206). The first attempt didn’t work well (terrible commercial success), but an eventual redesign aiming for a sleeker and aesthetic body made it a huge success. That one was launched as the Bell 206A JetRanger.   The first 206B JetRanger was introduced in 1971, with the 206B-3 coming in 1977 with a modified tail rotor, and improved engine. It got popular among TV channels for traffic and news reporting, armies, police departments, and private use.   The add-on features 4K PBR textures, realistic start up procedure, realistic flight dynamics, custom 3D instruments, virtual reality compatible, Wwise fully dynamic sound pack, detailed night lighting, and free future updates.   It’s available for purchase on CowanSim’s website for $32.99, requiring at least 2 GB of free disk space to install. Shout out to Henriks1 on Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ininan</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Nadi International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ininan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a64866724e8cdfd0eb8eec_nadi1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2708105"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has just released their rendition of Nadi International Airport (NFFN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport of Fiji and the main hub for Fiji Airways and Fiji Link. It averages 2.5 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic), handling 97% of the international traffic to the island, making it the gateway to Fiji.  It’s regularly visited by Air New Zealand with a direct flight to Auckland (and two seasonal hops to Christchurch and Wellington), Air Niugini with legs to Honiara and Port Moresby, AirCalin to Nouméa and Wallis Island, JetStar and Qantas with a hop to Sydney, and Virgin Australia with 3 aussie destinations: Brisbane, Melbourne, and Sydney. Fiji Airways, as the national carrier, offers a broader route network with flights to Adelaide, Apia-Faleolo, Auckland, Brisbane, Christchurch, Honiara, Honolulu, Los Angeles, Melbourne, Nuku’alofa, Port Vila, San Francisco, Singapore, Sydney, Tarawa, Vancouver, and Wellington.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Nadi International as it currently stands, with hand-made high-resolution ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation with custom decals, signposts, vegetation, parking barriers, and more; accurately modeled dynamic airport lighting (with its real positioning), accurate taxi signage, high-detail models of all airport buildings and objects, hand-placed vegetation, ground clutter, vehicles, and handling objects; accurate logos, real-world decals, and advertisements scattered throughout the airport; custom built jetways with PBR texturing, custom made tropical vegetation, terminals populated with people, Level of Detail optimization with performance in mind, and surrounding areas populated with churches, mosques, jetties, and boats.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for $12.03 (special Christmas Extravaganza sale price, expiring in 24 hours), requiring at least 5.37 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lowinc</id>
    <title>Low-End PC Studios Releases Inca Manco Cápac International v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lowinc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a65c47e100d7341a70d38a_inca1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="668943"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Low-End PC Studios has recently released their updated rendition of Inca Manco Cápac International Airport (SPJL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the highest airports in the World at 12,552 feet. It serves Juliaca, the Capital of San Roman Province in Southeastern Peru, the largest city in the region with 276,110 inhabitants. If being one of the highest commercial airports in South America was not enough, it also features one of the longest runways, with 4,200 meters of length.   It was named after Manco Cápac, the founder of the Inca Civilization in Cuzco.   It’s currently served by JetSmart Perú, LATAM Perú, and Sky Airline Peru, with scheduled flights to Lima and Cuzco (LATAM Perú only). Despite being an International airport, it doesn’t feature a single scheduled international flight.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D terminal and tower, PBR textures, and projected mesh for custom runway. The v2 update focused on correcting the windsock, adding two new city landmarks, a runway elevation profile, and runway texture improvements.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $6.58 (38% off), requiring at least 167 MB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffa350</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases A350 Beta Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffa350" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a6646d62ebc83521138d29_ff1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1143321"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor recently released a beta update (v1.7.01) for their A350 add-on, adding several improvements to the X-Plane 12 version, including a pitch behavior tuning for the new platform, lights and reflection compatibility, beacon light fix, and visual issues with some knobs.  The FlightFactor A350 XWB Advanced offers a high-quality rendition of the Airbus A350, with a high-resolution virtual cockpit, ground equipment, advanced systems simulation with SIDs and STARS, custom failures, Airbus electronic checklist system, fully customized ECAM monitoring system, full fly-by-wire simulation with realistic implementation of the normal laws, implementation of all Airbus autopilot modes (except for some non–precision approach modes), independent autopilots, custom 3D stereo engine sound system, and an interactive flight attendant helper, along with seven liveries. It’s available on X-Plane.Org Store for $45.47 (30% off), requiring at least 800 MB of free disk space to install.Images are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue, and special thanks to Poptart on Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd737</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd737" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a6d4c34c758f9f4b666bd5_boeing1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2415099"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently launched an update (3.00.0053) to their 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, focusing on increasing the quality and performance of the product. The highlights of the update include further work on the aircraft’s stability and prevention of eventual disturbances caused by the simulator’s exaggerated gusts, the addition of computationally derived stall angle of attack models for all wing configuration conditions on all of the three airplanes, reworked cabin collision models to allow native transition from cockpit to cabin, soundscape improvements (and expansion) in the cabin area, marked as a work in progress. The remainder of the changelog follows down below:  ‍ Regarding the 737-900, Robert Randazzo’s update announcement post mentions good progress on the testing, with a few areas they intend to clean up before the release.   The Universal Flight Tablet is partially working but not quite ready yet due to the fact they plan to build an universal framework that allows the EFB to work across their entire aircraft lineup, including stuff that is yet to come like the 777, the 737 MAX, and the 747. Such universality takes development time, but it’s said to be coming soon.   The DC-6 update is waiting on an Asobo update for MSFS that has to do with the avionics, and when that is out, PMDG will be able to roll out theirs with a greater range of GPS options, improved trim and flight characteristics, and extra stability for the autopilot when tracking a course or an approach.   They claim to have ‘quite a bit’ going on behind the scenes, which will be revealed once the 737-900 and the EFB are out to the public.  The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Images are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
