<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-05-12T18:30:30.506202+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrden</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Previews Denver 2.0 in X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrden" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6268218ff2a1995b5bd087a5_rs%3Dw_1280%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="235211"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has taken to their Twitter page to showcase previews of X-Codr Designs Denver 2.0 in X-Plane 12, an upcoming free update to the popular airport. The developer’s version two rendition of Denver is set to release with a multitude of exciting changes, these include the new terminal expansions, improved ground textures, revamped terminals, and more. You can view the full feature list below. It was also confirmed by the developer that they still plan on supporting X-Plane 11. As well according to X-Codr, they don’t believe that the X-Plane 12 version of the airport will require a separate download, as the X-Plane 11 version should ignore the X-Plane 12 features. Due to the strict NDA still in place for Laminar’s new simulator, the developer has stated that they won’t be making an official announcement on the forums until X-Plane 12 releases. As well, X-Codr Designs has assured users that progress on Sedona is still developing nicely, and will not be affected by Denver. It was also said that work has finished on the rocks, and the airport will be started, with previews coming soon. In the meantime, you can purchase Denver for X-Plane 11 via the X-Plane.org store for $29.95. As well, make sure to check out the source post for this article via the developer’s website, and join their discord for further information.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aseddf</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Previews Frankfurt (EDDF) for X-Plane and MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aseddf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6268e1178ebb2158d1285799_279167905_1891709774361480_3580936102275275336_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="63342"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Aviotek Simulation Software has published a short update on its upcoming Frankfurt Airport scenery for both X-Plane 11 and MSFS. The brief blog provides the community with a glimpse into the scenery’s progress and showcases new previews. According to the developers, they are trying to “integrate and include as many details as possible, as well as some unique features never seen before”, a process that will “take way longer than expected sometimes”. Therefore, at the current stage, it is impossible to estimate how much longer the team needs to complete the airport. From the previews accompanying the post, it is clear that the modeling for the passenger and cargo terminals, towers, and hangers are mostly complete. A few ground vehicles ranging from buses to pushback trucks are also showcased. In a previous post, the developers has revealed that the scenery will come with high quality PBR textures and custom animations for both simulators, promising to provide in-sim previews as soon as possible. Currently, the developers are yet to announce a release date or pricing for Frankfurt Airport. Based on Aviotek’s previous products, the scenery will likely cost between $18 and $26 USD. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vermyl</id>
    <title>VerticalSim Releases Myrtle Beach International Aiport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vermyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6269ad28c1744ed28d15fd52_MYR_4-uai-2064x1140.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="387250"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Verticalsim has released the highly anticipated Myrtle Beach (KYMR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. This scenery is not just the airport of the South Carolina city but it comes with the surrounding hotels too. Being used as an army base until 1948, the city of Myrtle Beach decided there was not a need for an airport in the area, though funds were allocated. With the land being annexed in 1977, the property was used as a join civil-military airport, though it severely limited the number of civilian flights. Years later in 1996, the airport gained international status with new terminals with an influence from the local beaches. The airport served over 2.4 million passengers in 2018, being the second busiest airport in South Carolina. The product comes with many features that portray the quality work of Verticalsim. Starting off, the 2022 layout of the airport is included along with proper taxi signage. Custom jetways compatible with the SAM plugin are also a part of this package. Some hotels outside the airport grounds have been modeled to add extra depth to the surrounding area.  If you are interested in picking this visual rendition of Myrtle Beach for yourself, you can find over on the simMarket store, and sells for $13.87. If you are interested in other various scenery packages developed my Verticalsim, you can check out their website to view the assortment of sceneries for XP11 and MSFS.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfs146</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases BAE146 for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfs146" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6270bcfd62dd5bfd6de0f2d1_146-professional-microsoft-flight-simulator_28_ss_l_220429142732.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="239780"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has pushed out their BAE 146 into Microsoft Flight Simulator after an extended period of development for the past year. The development came to a close after the past few days as the team went all hands on deck to wrap up development, and it is now out and about for all flyers to enjoy. This aircraft comes in eight variants which, they include: The regional jet is one that dates further back than the modern glass cockpits we know today, as such the design of the flightdeck may seem daunting to the novice or inexperienced - to address this, Just Flight has followed several other aircraft developers in publishing support materials including a 258 page manual detailing the systems across the add-on, a a 6 part video series on YouTube that goes through a full flight cycle for a BAE146 is also produced.  One other major addition in the aircraft, as an EFB, which is one of the first aircraft packages to ship with a in depth EFB. Its features can vary from fuel quantity in the aircraft, to making notes on a scratchpad, to adjusting ground services. The EFB adds accessibility to all users. A list of the EFB’s capabilities can be found on the product page on Just Flight’s website. Each variant also comes with a multitude of liveries. This is just the tip of the iceberg of how much work the team has done to make this aircraft amazing. You can find a full list of included liveries on the Just Flight Store as well. If you are interested in picking up this aircraft, it is on sale on Just Flight's store and sells for $64.99. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfsp22</id>
    <title>TFDI Design Publishes Spring 2022 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfsp22" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6270d2652429a82fb82754b1_MD-11%20Interior.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="427767"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Known developer for PACX and smartCARS, TFDI Design has published a Spring 2022 development update on their forums page. This update covers the continuous progress on their rendition of the MD-11, alongside developments for PACX, smartCARS 3, and updates for their sister company JetStream Radio. The team touched base that further modeling and texture work has continued along with progress on the systems and auto flight systems. Various engine variations have begun development with the PW Engine variant. The team expects to make great progress in the coming months. At the beginning of the update, the team addressed PACX’s latest update and its successes. Features like an IFE that tracks your flight, lets you access JetStream radio, and more were added to help add to the overall experience of the application. ‍ ‍ The team for the upcoming smartCARS 3 programs has begun finalizing the UI and adding more accessibility to virtual airlines that want to tailor to their pilots, in their own communities. It will improve the overall dynamic of the widely used program. ‍ In this section, it was addressed that the radio station is now “front and center” in the PACX IFE. With also the announcement of launching a new station to include a catalog of music from the 90s to now. ‍ If you would like to read the update in its entirety, you can visit the TFDI forums for more information. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iapdu</id>
    <title>Indiafoxtecho Announces New Projects and Publishes Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iapdu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6271d3009fdabc4c5d46a0b0_279572045_5661152563898158_7587075841842710172_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="412870"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Last week, aircraft developer Indiafoxtecho published a lengthy post on its Facebook page to announce new projects and bring development updates on existing ones. First off, the developers confirmed that their next project will be the Tornado for Microsoft Flight Simulators. Both the IDS and IDS-MLU will be developed, with the legacy IDS serving as the baseline model. Additionally, the developers hinted that “the GR1, ECR and possibly the ADV variant” will also be developed, though the feasibility of an ADV variant will be dependent on the resources available to the team.  A few previews depicting the plane’s  exterior modeling were also published with the post, though the developers warned that they were taken at preliminary stages of development and will be drastically improved later on.  	In addition to announcing the Tornado, the Indiafoxtecho also touched on the progress of their other products. According to the developers, the Aermacchi M346, which will use native MSFS FCS flight model, now has a completed HTML5/JS HUD , but is experiencing slight delays in texturing and system programming. The aircraft should be ready for beta testing in the coming weeks. As for the Eurofighter Typhoon, the developers has decided to model the plane from scratch since they are not satisfied with the commercial meshes and P3D model they originally planned to use as a starting point, a process that will take considerably more time to complete. Finally, the developers talked about bringing the team’s projects to DCS. They revealed that DCS development entails much more work than that for other simulators, requiring extensive planning and research beforehand. Therefore, their DCS team is currently only focused on “bringing the MB.339” to the market. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/min500</id>
    <title>GotFriends Teases Mini-500 Helicopter for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/min500" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6274add24ef344df75453f09_mini5001.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="474768"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aircraft developer GotFriends, known for their Gee Bee R3 Special, and upcoming Grumman F4F, have teased their forthcoming Mini-500 helicopter for the new simulator. The developer has not detailed the features of the rotorcraft yet but plans on keeping the community updated throughout the development process. On the "Skoots" YouTube channel, it was mentioned that the team is implementing the AirlandFS helicopter physics engine. The rotorcraft will also deliver with Asobo's native model with CFD when it's possible to do so, accounting for the current SDK's limitations.  The Mini-500 will also present with a few bold liveries. First produced in 1994, the Revolution Mini-500 is a kit helicopter featuring a Rotax 582 engine and has produced over 100 airworthy models. It contains a history with a poor safety record, with many component failures plaguing the design. It was a cheap alternative to other helicopters, such as the Robinson R22, as it featured an endurance of 3 hours and a 75mph cruise speed. GotFriends' Mini-500 doesn't have a release date yet, though it was mentioned that it would release sometime in 2022, but you can stay updated on their website here. </summary>
    <published>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737506</id>
    <title>PMDG Sets 737 Release Date for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737506" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62760542fbf0175a9b61a988_image_15258.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712230"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo at PMDG has updated the community regarding its development whereabouts surrounding its imminent Boeing 737 release. He reiterates that, even after the release, the plane is still due for some improvements and additional work, but the team is confident that the aircraft is in a "releasable" state. The project has been a long time in the making, having been announced within the same period as MSFS's release.  Not a Port! Randazzo has re-emphasized that the 737 for MSFS is not simply a port from the Prepar3D version. In his own words, "Microsoft Flight simulator, when it finally arrived, offered such a magnificent visual environment that it seemed we would be missing an opportunity to do something truly wonderful if we simply dragged the 737 as-is into the new environment and handed it off to you."  A Gentle Reminder The PMDG 737 for MSFS will release in six-week intervals following the -700s initial release. The MAX variants are included in the lineage of products, which will come "eventually." Also incoming for the new flightsim, albeit without any additional information or timeframe, is the 777 and 747 for MSFS. Though, both products are on the backburner for the time being while the team releases the 737 variants.  Some General Hype PMDG believes that Microsoft Flight Simulator "is the best simulation platform that any of the development team has ever put a product into." The developers gawked at the aircraft's beauty and performance in the simulator. As you can imagine, the 737 will deliver with a customized autopilot, flight model, systems modeling, and sound environment. Following the release, the team will be active with accomodating bug reports, and they warned users that the Ops Center would be very busy with updates in the next few days. Final Words A quick reminder for those who purchased the NGXu for P3D, you will receive a $99.99 credit towards buying the MSFS 737 product line if you acquired the aircraft before December 31st, 2019. The PDMG 737 for MSFS will be released on May 9th, 2022, as the team announced on their YouTube channel. Threshold will keep you updated regarding pricing and additional information at the release on Monday. </summary>
    <published>2022-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fenday</id>
    <title>Fenix A320 Incoming; Potential Release in "Days"</title>
    <updated>2022-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fenday" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6276fa11f962ee673df2cf52_ltu.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="829329"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aamir at Fenix Simulations has reappeared to mention that the A320 for MSFS is incoming and that he "expects everyone here to be flying the Fenix in days, not months." This message comes after a long hiatus from the team as they've focused their development resources on ensuring the aircraft comes out in due time.  Aamir mentioned that the plane's release is contingent on the status of the upcoming Sim Update 9 patch, which will determine whether the A320 is ready for release, depending on its effect on the aircraft's functionality. It's anticipated that the patch will be delivered to users between now and May 17th, the next World Update.  Fenix's A320 is arguably the most feature-rich airliner to be delivered to a simulator; the team has done a fantastic job documenting their progress and updating the community with blogs that outline the features of the Airbus. The team's Discord is often the medium for communication; you can join it here to become involved in the community. Though we have not received any additional information from the team, for the time being, we'll ensure to keep you updated when the Fenix team decides to publish more information regarding the release of the plane.  (just a little sidenote, the video embedded above is from previous updates and is not from any recent "developments", and we give thanks to BiologicalNanobot for providing the screenshot!)</summary>
    <published>2022-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bufmsf</id>
    <title>iniScene Announces Buffalo Niagara for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bufmsf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6276fee5e82221429982e380_280067634_1062951474646818_1866729130902131263_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712033"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds scenery division, iniScene has posted a preview of their upcoming Buffalo Niagara (KBUF) airport for MSFS2020. The developer claims that "it is one of (their) best creations yet" and will be delivered to the new simulator soon. Buffalo Niagara International Airport serves the Buffalo, New York, metropolitan area in western New York. It's served by a slew of airlines, notably Delta, American, Frontier, JetBlue, Southwest, United, and Sun Country. The airport typically hosts approximately five million passengers per year, with its most busy route being to Orlando, Florida. iniScene's rendition of Buffalo will serve as a faithful recreation of the airport; check out the preview video on their YouTube channel. As of now, the team hasn't shared any additional information, but stay tuned as the release nears. </summary>
    <published>2022-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737057</id>
    <title>PMDG Announces 737 for MSFS Pricing</title>
    <updated>2022-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737057" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62760542fbf0175a9b61a988_image_15258.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712230"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In the second volume of announcements today, Robert Randazzo at PMDG simulations has detailed the pricing structure for the 737 lines of products. The 737-700 will initially release via PMDG's site but eventually become available on the MSFS marketplace.  ‍Pricing PMDG will be providing promotional pricing for the 737-700, at $69.99. Upon the release of the subsequent -600 variant, the price will rise to $74.99. The 737-600 will cost approximately $50, the -800 will (most likely) cost the same as the -700, and the -900 will be announced. PMDG doesn't anticipate bundling or discounting their 737 product until mid-late 2023. Move-up Program If you purchased the 737NGXu for Prepar3D during November or December 2019, you're qualified for the PMDG Move-Up program, where you will be endowed $99.99 in credit on the website to utilize towards the MSFS 737 product line. These credits will remain available through December 31, 2024. More information on this can be found in the PMDGs post. Estimated Timeline for Future Variants PMDG 737-700 for MSFS: 09MAY22 PMDG 737-600 for MSFS: ~20JUN22** PMDG 737-800 for MSFS: ~01AUG22** PMDG 737-900 for MSFS: ~12SEP22** All dates are estimates and are subject to change. Final Tidbits Randazzo mentioned that the product would become available between 1700Z and 2359Z on May 9, but any delays to the product will be announced on the forums in that circumstance. If you're not up to date with the recent PMDG news, peek at our previous article before the product releases. Our team at Threshold is looking forward to seeing your screenshots on our Discord server!</summary>
    <published>2022-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg59</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737 for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg59" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/627a064fe00c4ec33aefefd3_pmdg1%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="354808"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG Simulations has released their rendition of the Boeing 737-700 for MSFS2020. This release includes the 737BBJ and -700 BDSF; following the second smallest NG is the -600 in approximately six-week intervals and every other NG variant thereafter. The new product is available on the PMDG store for $69.99 as a special introductory sale and will increase to $74.99 after the -600 releases. PMDG's 737-700 contains an all-new model, texture, sound environment, improvements, and fixes from its fellow counterpart in the 64-bit Prepar3D. The model delivers a plethora of features to the new simulator, including: The 737 is only compatible with the PC version of MSFS. PMDG intends on updating the aircraft in the future with an EFB, higher resolution cabin models, weather radar, and more, which will all be available via updates in the Operations Center.  Robert Randazzo has provided an in-depth "first look" series into the product on the PMDG YouTube channel for those who want to learn more about the aircraft and its systems. The 737 for MSFS can be found on PMDG's store for $69.99, and should consume approximately 5.2GB after download. </summary>
    <published>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orh202</id>
    <title>MXI Design Teases Worcester Airport for MSFS2020 </title>
    <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orh202" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/627a0be92a65881198a3ec0c_mxi.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="592343"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer MXI Design has teased their upcoming rendition of Worcester Airport (KORH) for MSFS via the AviationLads YouTube channel. The development team is responsible for other notable payware projects Svalbard, Dubrovnik, and Bern, and is diving into the United States scenery space for the first time. Worcester Regional Airport (KORH) serves the Worcester metropolitan area in Massachusetts. Featuring two runways, 7,000 and 5,000 feet, respectively, the airport hosts nearly 54,000 passengers per year. ORH is served in a limited capacity by American Eagle, Delta Connection, and JetBlue, all flights concluding in New York, with the exception of one flight to Fort Lauderdale.  Unfortunately, we don't have any additional information regarding the scenery's status. It's anticipated that the airport will fall within the 10-25 Euro range. If you're interested in MXI Design's Worcester Airport, keep in touch with Threshold, as we'll keep you updated with its development. special thanks to member, "Tang0" in our Discord for the tip!</summary>
    <published>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eidw11</id>
    <title>Boundless Publishes Trailer Showcasing Dublin for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eidw11" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/627cabfee4bcd345b743ac45_eidw_Product_Page.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="305994"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Scenery developer Boundless has published a trailer on their YouTube channel showcasing their upcoming airport for X-Plane 11, Dublin (EIDW). The developer also announced that the project would be released on May 13th.  Dublin is Europe's 12th largest airport, claiming service from airlines such as Aer Lingus, Air France, American Airlines, Finnair, Etihad, and many others. The airport is a hub for Aer Lingus, Ryanair, and Tui Airways. Dublin contains two runways, for the time being, both exceeding 6700 feet (2000m), which accommodate over 32 million passengers per year. Boundless' Dublin is their "largest project to date," featuring "heavily optimized objects and textures," as well as 3D vegetation and custom placed objects.  Feature List: Dublin airport for X-Plane 11 will release on May 13th on the Boundless store for £19.99 and is expected to utilize approximately 2.2GB of space.  another special thanks to "Tang0" in our Discord for the tip!</summary>
    <published>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tg0512</id>
    <title>Asobo Confirms Top Gun: Maverick DLC Release Date</title>
    <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tg0512" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/627cb0df4616ed2bc9ae4017_dab63fd14daa33f6ce9b4bfd044529cb.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="130375"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Top Gun: Maverick DLC for MSFS2020 has an official release date. The Xbox Twitter page announced that the DLC would release the day after the movie hits the screens. Users will be able to download the Maverick add-on on May 25th.  For the time being, users can immerse themselves in the Top Gun experience on the new "whatsmycallsign" website, so you can be prepared once the DLC releases. The movie, dubbed "Maverick," is the sequel to the original film, featuring Tom Cruise, Miles Teller, and Jennifer Connelly. Microsoft had also provided a reveal trailer from last June when they initially announced the additional military content for the simulator. Keep in touch with Threshold for future Top Gun Maverick DLC updates and news regarding its impending release! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/125909</id>
    <title>Asobo Releases SU9 Patch - 1.25.9.0</title>
    <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/125909" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/627cb4e7ee70f39ea5369f7f_capsule_616x353.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="108736"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 developer Asobo Studios has released a patch to counter some issues faced by users after the Sim Update 9. The team has admitted that their beta testing hasn't been sufficient in identifying problems and will continue to improve their processes to accommodate future updates better. General Bugfix 1.25.9.0 For PC users of MSFS, some packages in the community folder may have been excluded from the update, which may negatively impact MSFS's performance and behavior. Asobo advises all users to move their community package to another folder before relaunching the title, especially if they suffer from stability issues or untimely loading times. extending a special thanks to Tomcat_22 for the news tip!</summary>
    <published>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
