<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-07-08T18:23:06.034087+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ae3302</id>
    <title>Aerosoft A330 Trailer Released</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ae3302" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649dcdc5b9760918c8461994_aerosoft%20330.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="618639"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft, a popular development group for most major flight simulators since FSX, has sent ripples of excitement through the sim aviation community by releasing an exciting trailer showcasing their much-anticipated Airbus A330 for MSFS. The trailer, unveiled yesterday on the group's youtube channel, offers an exciting glimpse into the immersive experience that awaits flight sim pilots.  The trailer boasts some of the features we can expect. This includes; Accurate sounds, stunning exterior visuals and the much-anticipated EFB that Aerosoft has developed. The trailer shows that an effort has not been spared throughout the internal and external models.  ‍ Although no release date was provided in the trailer, the flight sim community is informed that the aircraft will release “soon” This is certainly an exciting time for Long Haul sim pilots who have been eagerly awaiting a new wide-body jet to traverse the globe in.  Threshold Will keep you informed on developments around the A330 and possible release dates, but for now… enjoy the trailer below! </summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmpbi</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Announces Palm Beach International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmpbi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649f3a504646220360145673_pb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="240981"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently announced the development of Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Miami metropolitan area and Port St. Lucie metro area with a yearly average of 6.6 million passengers.  ‍ It was opened in 1936 as Morrison Field, eventually becoming an important training airfield during World War 2 and operating as a staging base for the Allied invasion of France in 1944, with aircraft departing Palm Beach towards England in preparation for the D-Day.  ‍ After a brief return to being a civil airport, the airport was once again utilized for military purposes in the early 1950s as Palm Beach Air Force Base, training nearly 23,000 airmen during the Korean War. ‍ The Air Force Base was closed in 1962, and Palm Beach was back to being just a civilian airport.  ‍ Currently, the airport has 32 gates and three concourses. Concourse A houses Bahamasair and Silver Airways; B houses Air Canada, American Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines; C, on the other hand, holds Delta, Frontier, JetBlue, and Spirit. ‍ There’s no information regarding features, pricing, or availability yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbsmf</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Sacramento International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbsmf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649fa68662f546d6e10b3ff5_sm1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="643152"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of Sacramento International Airport (KSMF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the busiest airports in California with a yearly average of 12 million passengers. ‍ The airport opened in 1967 as Sacramento Municipal Airport, with an 8,600 ft runway. It was the first purpose-built public-use airport west of the Mississippi. ‍ In 1998, a new terminal - Terminal A - was built, followed by its subsequent renaming to Sacramento International Airport. The first international flight happened in 2002 when Mexicana started a nonstop route from Guadalajara.  ‍ The current layout consists of two terminals with 32 gates in total. Air Canada, American, Delta, and United operate out of Terminal A, and Aeromexico, Alaska, Frontier, Hawaiian, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, and Volaris operate out of Terminal B. ‍ Developed by Orbx’s indie Matteo Veneziani, the upcoming SMF will feature detailed ground markings and textures, animated jetways with sounds, dynamic airport lighting, custom airport clutter, custom ground service equipment, an animated train, basic terminal interiors, and orthoimagery of the airport area. ‍ There is no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pacslc</id>
    <title>PACSIM Releases Salt Lake City International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pacslc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a095339fd69120a91b39e4_slc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="162154"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PACSIM has recently released their rendition of Salt Lake City International Airport (KSLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Utah with a yearly average of 25 million passengers. The airport was built on Basque Flats, a wide flat area on the Salt Lake Valley that was deemed appropriate for constructing a landing strip. In that same year, it held the Great International Aviation Carnival, with the presence of many aviation pioneers, including Glenn Curtiss and his newly invented Seaplane that took off from Salt Lake in front of 20,000 spectators, making international headlines. Nine years later, the United States Postal Service began flying mail to SLC, stimulating the city’s administration to further improve the infrastructure by buying a plot of land near the airport and building a hangar and other facilities.  The first terminal was built in 1933, costing $52,000.  With WW2, the airport became a USAF base, eventually getting a third runway. The post-war results were primarily positive, with 42 weekday departures in 1957. By 1960, a new terminal was needed, and Brazier Montmorency Hayes &amp; Talbot took the challenge to design it. Seven years and 8 million dollars later, it was ready to roll. That’s also when Salt Lake City got granted its international status, with a direct flight to Calgary. With the airline deregulation in 1978, SLC became a hub for Western Airlines, which had the same Brazier Montmorency Hayes design and build a terminal for them, with murals by artist LeConte Stewart.  In 1987, Western Airlines merged into Delta Air Lines, with Salt Lake City remaining as one of their major hubs. A redevelopment program was started in 2014 to modernize the airport, gradually replacing its old infrastructure. It was funded by airport funds, passenger charges, and federal grants. The first phase of the new terminal was opened in 2020, with Concourse A sporting 25 gates and B with 21, both connected by a mid-field underground tunnel.  As mentioned, SLC is a Delta Air Lines hub, flying passengers worldwide, directly or indirectly connecting via other hubs. They have 57.12% of the current passenger market share, followed by SkyWest with 18.77% and Southwest with 11.17%. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom animated jetways, sharp PBR textures, VDGS on every gate, high-resolution orthoimagery around the airport, hand-placed vegetation, performance-friendly optimization, wear and tear on runways, taxiways, and aprons, and more. It’s available on their official website for roughly $25.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwcos</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Colorado Springs Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwcos" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a1e5ddf88f5d4aa493abfe_cos1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="706097"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Colorado Springs Airport (KCOS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Colorado with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1927 on 260 hectares of land seven miles east of Colorado Springs, initially featuring two gravel runways. During its initial decade of operations, it was mainly a stop for mail routes flying from Cheyenne, Wyoming, to Pueblo, in Colorado.  True regular passenger service would only come in 1937, when Continental operated a route from Denver to El Paso, stopping in Colorado Springs. In 1943, Braniff also added the city to their destination list.  The first passenger terminal was built in 1942, using a modern art deco style. Passengers would only get to use it properly after the war, as the army took control of the airport during that period.  In 1966, another terminal was built and expanded in 1980 with six new gates.   Thirty years later, with the growing demand for air travel, the city approved a new terminal with 26,000 square meters of total area and 12 gates. In that same decade, a five-gate concourse was built on the main terminal's east side.  They have been trying to expand service since the 1980s, with the best figures rounding up at around 5 million passengers in 1996. In late 2020, Southwest Airlines announced they would begin serving the airport in 2021, which has helped increase the yearly traffic figures.   With the recent growth, the airport administration plans to expand the airport by doubling the number of gates and relocating the control tower.  As of 2022, Southwest Airlines holds most of the passenger market share with 49.84% of the traffic, followed by SkyWest with 23.08% and American Airlines with 14.05%.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, custom ground markings, animated jetways, a detailed terminal interior, landside buildings, and FSLTL compatibility.  It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.67, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/twdcle</id>
    <title>TearWear Designs Releases Cleveland Hopkins International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/twdcle" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a1f00bcfd749e0381460f3_cle1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1776915"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane.  TearWear Designs has recently released their rendition of Cleveland Hopkins International Airport (KCLE) for X-Plane 12, the busiest airport in Ohio with a yearly average of 8.5 million passengers.  Founded in 1925, Cleveland Hopkins International was one of the first municipality-owned airports in the United States, the first airport to ever have an air traffic control tower, the first with a ground-to-air radio control system, and the first to feature a night lighting system. It’s one of the most historically relevant airports in the world. It was also the first airport directly connected to a local or regional rail system and the first to implement a two-level terminal design separating arrivals from departures.  The airport consists of a two-level passenger terminal, built in the late 70s and renovated in 2016, with four concourses, although only three are currently in use. Concourse A houses Frontier, Spirit, charter flights, and all international arrivals. Concourse B, on the other hand, houses Southwest and Delta. C, the last of the operational concourses, hosts Air Canada Express, Alaska, American, JetBlue, and United. Passenger market share-wise, United leads with 23%, followed by Frontier with 13.76% and Southwest with 12.61%.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as of 2023, with custom-made objects, an intricately designed passenger terminal, true-to-life texturing, a custom mesh designed for compatibility with Ortho4Xp, hand-placed autogen and vegetation, SAM jetways and marshallers, performance-friendly optimization, and a custom prebuilt ortho tile.  It’s free on the X-Plane.Org Store, requiring at least 3.5 GB of free hard disk space to install (the airport alone takes 1.5GB, and the orthos need an additional 2 GB). ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/katefb</id>
    <title>KatiePilot Announces efbPro, an Innovative Standalone EFB</title>
    <updated>2023-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/katefb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a335c131e338850d3e01f6_katiecover-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="908994"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. KatiePilot, the real-world Airbus pilot Twitch streamer and creator of the highly acclaimed Fenix Simulations Electronic Flight Bag (EFB), is now introducing efbPro, an innovative standalone EFB that goes beyond being a mere tool. With its ecosystem and customizability, it aims to provide a truly immersive and realistic flight simulation experience. The upcoming EFB will be fully customizable, based on real-world units, with the ability to change the background and accessibility settings and even manage its apps (efbPro will have an app store). It will also feature full SimBrief integration, weather monitoring and visualization for situational awareness, aircraft performance calculation, a built-in PDF reader for FCOMs, etc. efbPro is claimed to be entirely standalone, compatible with any sim or device, whether a tablet, a laptop, or a second monitor. Some of the apps will feature direct integration with MSFS, though. The app will be free, but developers may charge for specific apps on efbPro’s app store. There’s no release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/emb195</id>
    <title>Flight Procedures Simulation releases their Embraer 195 </title>
    <updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/emb195" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a6182a4cda3361ad488d9e_Screenshot%202023-07-05%20201651.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1222305"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Procedures Simulation has released an updated version of the Embraer 195 for X-Plane. In a post last week, the aircraft was described in detail. Interested buyers can purchase it for $55.00 USD at the X-Plane.org store. For previous owners, there is a discount of $11, bringing the price down to $44.00 USD. It is worth noting that Flight Procedures Simulation used to be known as SSG Supercritical Simulations Group, which was established in 2011. Ricardo Bolognini announced the new name of Flight Procedures Simulation in the original update post. ‍ Here is a snapshot of a few features from the X-Plane.org store page.  "This model is a complete X-Plane 12 upgrade from the iconic Ejets Evolution Series from SSG. Custom Systems description Check out the full list here on FPS's website. FPS has also addressed further updates to the E195 here in the support forum. ‍ As always keep an eye on Threshold for more updates regarding the Embraer 195 from FPS!  Thanks Airbus 737 from our Discord for the updated news scoop! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sssjjo</id>
    <title> Sierrasim Simulation Releases José Joaquín de Olmedo International Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sssjjo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a66f5ed856f4f9d54114a0_guaya1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2992402"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Sierrasim has recently released an updated version of their rendition of José Joaquín de Olmedo International Airport (SEGU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Guayaquil in Ecuador with a yearly average of 3.7 million passengers.  The airport was inaugurated in October 1937 as a small airfield, initially serving as a military base.  Sixty-six years later, the airport administration made plans to build a new terminal and extend the runway, both deemed too small for the city’s needs. At first, they had agreed to build a 28,000-square-meter terminal for international flights while using the old terminal for domestic operations. But later, they settled on a bigger terminal for both, occupying 50,000 square meters.  The current terminal can handle up to 5 million passengers a year. Once it reaches its maximum capacity, there are plans to build a new airport 20km from the city.  It’s a hub for Avianca Ecuador and LATAM Ecuador, flying people to many destinations in Latin and North America. The visitors’ list includes American Airlines, Copa Airlines, Iberia, JetBlue, KLM, and Spirit.  The scenery features improvements on all airport models (compared to V1), high-quality PBR textures, custom jetways, terminal interiors, new apron and airport lights, cargo terminal improvements, improved ground textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.48, requiring at least 845.02MB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners are entitled to a free upgrade. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pksgrp</id>
    <title>PKSIM Releases Gustavo Rojas Pinilla International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pksgrp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a68466cbdb22e3c1928f60_sksp1-min.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1150390"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PKSIM has recently released their rendition of Gustavo Rojas Pinilla International Airport (SKSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the archipelago of San Andrés, Providencia, and Santa Catalina, in Colombia with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport was built in the 1950s to link the airport with continental Colombia by order of President Gustavo Rojas Pinilla, whose name is now shared with the airport.   ‍  It was granted its international status in 1993, allowing it to handle international traffic and consequently helping boost the traffic figures, leading to its eventual expansion and modernization in the 2000s.  It is the sole gateway to the island and is essential to local tourism and its residents.  It’s served by Avianca (Bogotá, Medellín), Copa Airlines (Panama City), Latam Colombia (Bogotá, Cartagena, and Medellín), Satena (Providencia), and Wingo (Barranquilla, Cali, and Cartagena).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airports (it also includes the smaller Providencia Airport), with detailed models, custom ground textures, custom GSX config, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.13, requiring at least 598.17 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2hsh</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Henderson Executive Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2hsh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a7e14755a206e0a80a8e76_hnd1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1132888"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Henderson Executive Airport (KHND) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use government airport in Henderson, Nevada, categorized as a reliever airport by the FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems.   It was founded in 1967, and built on 912 acres purchased from the city of Henderson, opening three years later as Sky Harbor Airport. It was bought out by Clark County in 1996 and given its current name.  According to 2015 data, the airport had 71,323 operations, with 86% corresponding to general aviation traffic, 14% air taxi, and less than 1% military.   The airport’s IATA (HSH) differs from its ICAO because of Tokyo Haneda (HND), forcing it to be one of the few North American airports whose IATA doesn’t correspond to the last three digits of its ICAO.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with PBR texturing, full-detail buildings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, high-detail airport vehicles, performance-friendly optimization, custom vegetation, and optional static aircraft.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.25, requiring at least 37.31 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t2goia</id>
    <title>Taxi2Gate Updates Orlando International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t2goia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647749b784a7d531f0620a1f_mco1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3708726"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taxi2Gate has recently released an update to their rendition of Orlando International Airport (KMCO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing the now non-existent requirement of having the photogrammetry disabled and more.  The new update adds full compatibility with photogrammetry, terminal C improvements, more details on the construction site, the removal of default Asobo buildings, the addition of the JetBlue University buildings and the B52 at the memorial park, auxiliary lines at airside four, the removal of trees around train rails, and other minor fixes.  From this update onwards, users can remove the default (hand-crafted) KMCO that was once required for some absent buildings.   The scenery is available on SimMarket for roughly $26.15, requiring at least 2.34 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jffrdc</id>
    <title>JustFlight Fokker F28 Release Date Confirmed</title>
    <updated>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jffrdc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a842f6d5adcf02639dc058_347631094_654973770002877_7813962146158986907_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="174872"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After much anticipation, the wait is finally over. JustFlight, a leading developer in the industry, has officially announced that their highly awaited F28 Professional aircraft add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS) will be released next week for $69.99 / 52.49 GBP / 64.95 EUROS. Mark your calendars for Wednesday 12th july. In the days leading up to the release, JustFlight has promised a treat for the community. They will be showcasing the F28 Professional through a series of preview streams and in-house videos, giving us all a sneak peek into the aircraft's features and capabilities. Already, preview videos have started appearing on popular platforms like YouTube and Twitch, offering a glimpse of what's to come. Keep an eye out for more content in the coming days as well. Similar to the previously released 146 Professional, the F28 Professional is a complex and sophisticated aircraft from a bygone era. JustFlight's team has invested extensive time and effort into conducting in-depth research, coding, testing, and fine-tuning to ensure an exceptional and true-to-life simulation experience. They extend their gratitude to the community for their patience throughout the development process and assure users that the F28 Professional will be another vintage aircraft masterpiece, meticulously crafted in every department. To assist users in getting acquainted with the aircraft, JustFlight will provide comprehensive tutorials, a comprehensive manual, and a plethora of customization options. This will enable virtual pilots to fully immerse themselves in the F28 Professional's intricacies and explore its capabilities. The excitement is building as the release date approaches. All the necessary product details and manuals can be found on the dedicated F28 Professional product page. In the meantime, JustFlight has treated the community to a selection of screenshots. Feel free to take a peek at our previous article on the F28 for some more information ! ‍ Threshold will keep you informed with future updates and the release !</summary>
    <published>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsytn</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Townsville International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsytn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a875c85efc029c67ce8aec_ybtl1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="631318"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Townsville International Airport (YBTL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Townsville in Northern Australia with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  The airport was inaugurated in 1939, featuring two grass runways. Not long after that, it was chosen by the Department of Defence to become a military air base for World War 2. The initial plan was to house three squadrons, but they eventually settled with just one, and the base was built alongside the airport in early 1940.  After the war, commercial services flourished, with a steady increase in passenger numbers and aircraft movements as time went on, especially in the mid-60s. The 1970s saw its consolidation as a regional hub for Ansett and TAA.  A decade later, the airport benefitted from a petition started by the new owners of Ansett for international flights to begin in some regional airports, with the inaugural flight departing in April 1980 to Singapore. Later that year, they were granted 13 million dollars to build a state-of-the-art international terminal.   Townsville became the first regional airport in Australia to offer direct long-distance international flights. The list of direct service airlines was Qantas, Ansett, Air Niugini, Continental Micronesia, Garuda Indonesia, Air New Zealand, Cathay Pacific, and Japan Airlines.  The international terminal was expanded in 1987 to comport domestic traffic, followed by a huge crisis (1989-1991) that ceased most domestic operations in the country for nearly two years.  With Ansett’s liquidation in 2001, 40% of the airport’s traffic vanished into thin air, starting an era of uncertainty followed by a happy surprise: Virgin Blue (now Virgin Australia) began flying to Townsville, increasing the traffic by a respectable 25%, followed by Qantas expanding their service to make up for the gap left by Ansett’s bankruptcy.  Airnorth, Alliance Airlines, Bonza, Jetstar, Qantas, QantasLink, Rex Airlines, Virgin Australia, and West Wing Aviation currently serve it.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an updated ground layout, custom ground textures, custom jetways, AI traffic compatibility, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.71, requiring at least 61.38 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teinub</id>
    <title>Teikof Studio Releases La Nubia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teinub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a87da5c867465cd3d20aa1_nubia1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="587733"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Teikof Studio has recently released La Nubia Airport (SKMZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Manizales in Colombia with a yearly average of 200,000 passengers.  The airport was built on a former dairy farm in 1956, whose name was also “La Nubia.” The original runway was only 800 meters long, initially served by Aero Caldas and Aerolineas Centrales de Colombia.   The short runway quickly became an issue, with the expansion approval coming in 1978, lengthening the runway from 800 meters to 1,480. Construction work only started in 1982.   Despite the length not longer being a limitation that could prevent jetliners from operating there, there’s a weight restriction (13,000 kg), which only makes it compatible with small regional aircraft.  The limitations go further than that: aircraft can’t land on runway 28 or take off from runway ten for safety reasons (and an urban area). It also doesn’t have many aids such as ILS, with most approaches being entirely visual and the weather dictating when the airport operates.   EasyFly serves it with flights to Bogotá, Cartagena, and Medellín.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality textures and models, animated objects, custom ground markings with wear and tear, a high-fidelity terminal representation, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.08, requiring at least 393.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orksmf</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Sacramento International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orksmf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649fa70fa27e0134453aa45f_s4.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="644588"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Sacramento International Airport (KSMF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, among the busiest airports in California with a yearly average of 12 million passengers.  The first purpose-built public-use airport west of the Mississippi was inaugurated as Sacramento Municipal Airport in 1967.  In 1998, a new terminal - Terminal A - was built, followed by its subsequent renaming to Sacramento International Airport. The first international flight happened in 2002 when Mexicana started a nonstop route from Guadalajara.   There are plans to expand the airport with more gates or a new terminal in the near future.  The current layout consists of two terminals with 32 gates in total. Air Canada, American, Delta, and United operate out of Terminal A, and Aeromexico, Alaska, Frontier, Hawaiian, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, and Volaris operate out of Terminal B.  Developed by Matteo Veneziani, an independent developer, the scenery features detailed ground markings and textures, animated jetways, dynamic airport lighting, custom ground clutter, custom ground service equipment, custom taxiway signage, an animated train, basic terminal interiors, and orthoimagery of the airport area.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.06, requiring at least 2.86 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
