<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-09-22T18:31:33.477431+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thru20</id>
    <title>Thranda Designs Previews Cessna U206G Stationair</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thru20" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325c78a56d6f1dc9d15b4b3_xp12-thranda-u206g-stationair-aug20-2022-08.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="231412"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Designs’ recently announced, Cessna U206 Stationair has got its first video preview, where it’s shown performing a visual approach into Powwatka Ridge, Oregon.  ‍ Thranda Designs has published a short video, where their recently announced Cessna U206G Stationair for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12 can be seen in action from inside the cockpit, landing into 03R Powwatka Ridge in Troy, Oregon.  ‍ To learn more about the upcoming aircraft, check out our previous post. Stay tuned to Threshold for further information on the matter. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shxa12</id>
    <title>SimHeaven Release X-World America For XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shxa12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325ca6078d241e1048b702d_simheaven.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="449911"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimHeaven have released their popular X-World America scenery for XP12.  The package download is 7.4 GB, extracted to 13.8 GB. Announcing it in a post on their website they have said;  The free scenery can be installed here</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csc510</id>
    <title>Cockspur releases new C510 Mustang Trailer </title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csc510" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325f2a7e87e89277cb389e4_C510_Promo_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="970411"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A very cool corporate jet is on its way! Cockspur, an FS2020 developer of the A22 Foxbat and the SG38 Schulgleiter, has posted a recent trailer of its C510 Mustang. The project has been under development and is making significant progress. The trailer shows an accurate rendition of the Citation Mustang, a light business jet capable of seating up to four passengers with a range of about 1,100 nautical miles.   Cockspur's trailer also shows interior details, as well as an air ambulance variant still in beta. Navigation options include the NXi or FS2020’s stock G1000. Interactive features include an iDevice for controlling various aircraft components, controllable doors, window blinds, and more. Check out the official trailer here on Youtube. Check out Cockspur's official Discord here.  Expect more updates and info soon here at Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12ea</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 now out on Steam!</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12ea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325f73fea9e2c7687a7c0c0_header.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="23198"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The long-awaited flight simulator by Laminar Research is finally available on Steam for $59.99, where customers will be able to test the platform as it progresses through the early access phase.  According to Laminar, it should be under early access from 3 to 5 months, where developers plan to improve the volumetric clouds, tweak the lightning system, implement a fully customized Airbus MCDU, and brand new third-party interfaces for add-on developers. To read the complete feature list, please refer to this post. ‍ ‍ It’s important to note that X-Plane 12 is also available directly via their website for the same price and with identical features. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flfxvj</id>
    <title>Exclusive Update, The FlightFX Vision Jet</title>
    <updated>2022-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flfxvj" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632716c7c0173f70bc7b1fa7_1_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2165690"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In an exclusive progress update, FlightFX has provided the following update to us here at threshold on the progress of their latest project, the stunning Vision jet. Members of the FlightFX discord will have been kept in the loop with the development process in the form of photos through various stages but just today we spoke to Nick from FlightFX who gives us a more detailed look at what has been done so far, and what is still to go.  “The product is currently about to go to Beta.  Right now we are cleaning and polishing a few things.  Once in Beta, we will give them a dedicated feedback form on what we are looking to have them concentrate on.  The Alpha team has been mostly concentrating on performance and handling as that group is aligned with some of our Owner/Operators.”  Nick goes on to further expand;  “Our Beta team will focus on the quality of life, visual modelling etc.  We expect them to break the aircraft.  Through each Beta round, we will connect and fix any remaining issues that we expect to roll out.” Addressing FlightFX fan's eager enthusiasm and interest to know a release date, Nick has wisely said; “We have a launch date and price point known internally. We will make an announcement on those things once we are about halfway through the Beta process. We know people are excited and are very appreciative of the support. Just want to make sure we can clearly see the roadmap in front of us. Our policy has been to not state firm dates until the unknowns are off the table.” ‍ Our thanks to Nick and the team at FlightFX. The Vision Jet is going to be fantastic no doubt and we will keep you all updated, here at Threshold.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fly2hi</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Wroclaw Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fly2hi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632718d11d07978f0237755f_MhZsMYR.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2334615"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly 2 High has just released their rendition of Wroclaw Airport (EPWR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring a fully modelled 3D terminal, enhanced city lighting, PBR materials on the airport buildings and ground, custom animated vehicle traffic and animated humans. It’s said to be their most optimized work to date, a direct result of their experience gained from developing and updating their previous airports. The scenery is available on FlightSim.to for $16.00 (excluding VAT) or SimMarket for €15.99. At least 2 GB of free disk space is recommended to install the product. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sbbrbg</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Brasília International Airport for MSFS.</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sbbrbg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6327f9d57d27dae6bc143278_NT0AqQo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2258477"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍Brazil Land Games shared work-in-progress images of their upcoming Brasília International Airport (SBBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Brasilia International Airport is the second busiest airport in Brazil, providing service to more than 10 million passengers in 2021. Brasília International has been under development since November 2021, featuring a fully modeled terminal with animated moving walkways, updated ground layout, and custom jetways. The project is still under development, see more images on BLG's official Facebook here. Pricing and release information to be announced. Stay tuned to Threshold for more updates! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nmmkai</id>
    <title>No Money Mondays: Hong Kong Kai Tak MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nmmkai" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632842b3cd6b9928a6e4d323_UZ6LrSF.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2255990"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Although it's been 24 years since the last time an airplane landed on the infamous runway 13,Kai Tak is still widely adored by flight enthusiasts all around the globe. Like the closure of Meigs Field, it marked the end of an era. It’s impossible to talk about challenging approaches without mentioning the tricky checkerboard arrival, where a pilot had to fly low, slow, and close to apartment buildings. Pilots were also required to perform a flawless turn towards the runway, managing vertical speed and aiming for the runway threshold; simultaneously. Historically, Kai Tak's runway 13 was one of the most challenging approaches in aviation. One of the most enjoyable perks of flight simulation is the ability to bring once existing airports back virtually, providing the opportunity to experience the thrill of landing in Hong Kong as it was in the 1990s. What if I told you you could experience Kai Tak for no charge in Microsoft Flight Simulator? Scenery developer ali501 shared his rendition on flights.to so that we can all go back in time to simpler days when Avgas and Jet-A guzzling airplanes were not much of a concern. An era long left behind, now to be revived in all its glory. With a fully modeled terminal, era-accurate static vehicles, and advertisements, it’s quite a throwback. ali501's Kai Tak is the perfect blend of No Money Mondays and throwback Tuesdays! It’s hard not to feel transported back to 1998 when you spot things like the Flight Simulator 98 advertisement or the Motorola flip phone that screams late 90s nostalgia. A trip down memory lane for older folks; and a glimpse into the past for younger people. Ready to take on the Kai Tak challenge? Download it here; at least 2.04 GB of free disk space is recommended to install the product. Installation is as simple as it could possibly be: drag the ali501-kaitak folder into your MSFS Community folder, and that's it! Stay tuned to Threshold for more freeware recommendations. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x-plane-to-now-live</id>
    <title>X-Plane.to Now Live</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x-plane-to-now-live" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632864353ea41e39bb24537c_XPTO.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="166781"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ‍ For those flight simmers using Microsoft Flight Simulator, chances are you’re no stranger to the popular mods and add-ons site ‘flightsim.to’. Newly released from the same team behind the aforementioned site, comes X-Plane.to. Browsing either of these sites will give you access to great freeware sceneries, liveries, etc. X-Plane.to will grow with time and community support, as time passes, it is certain that more freeware add-ons for X-Plane 12 will surface. But for now, you can expect a very similar layout as X-Plane.to’s predecessor. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniscene-ksat-development-update</id>
    <title>IniScene KSAT Development Update </title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniscene-ksat-development-update" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632873085d24b0381aea5023_KSAT4.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="655758"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ‍ ‍ Optimization efforts are well underway from IniScene and their Microsoft Flight Simulator payware scenery, San Antonio (KSAT). The developer’s update, posted on both the Discord server and the IniBuilds forum mentions that they have dissolved photogrammetry in the immediate area surrounding the airport and that in and of itself has provided “more than substantial increase in optimization,” according to the developer. Since the release of the scenery, some users have experienced stuttering issues, but the developer is hopeful that this update (releasing sometime this week-according to IniScene) will remediate any stuttering issues for users. ‍ ‍ Along with optimizing the scenery, IniScene has also modeled much more of the surrounding architecture in the vicinity. ‍ ‍ If you’re interested in picking up the KSAT scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator you can buy it directly from the Ini store, here or you can buy it from Simmarket. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/the-secret-studio-releases-miri-airport-for-msfs</id>
    <title>The Secret Studio Releases Miri Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/the-secret-studio-releases-miri-airport-for-msfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63287bdc841378f1013eb07f_QVqe4xc.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4100463"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Secret Studio has released their rendition of Miri Airport (WBGR), Malaysia’s sixth busiest airport with a yearly average of 2 million passengers (pre-pandemic). Its strategic location makes it a hub for rural air services by MASWings and Awan Inspirasi. Despite not being an international airport, it does get international flights regularly.  ‍ ‍ The feature list includes a fully recreated passenger terminal with retail booths and stores, and a custom-made VDGS (Visual Docking Guidance System) that works with default and custom aircraft without any further configuration required. ‍ ‍ The scenery can be purchased on either FlightSim.to or SimMarket for $16.00. At least 482 MB of free disk space is required to install the product. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thranda-releases-cessna-u206g-stationair-for-x-plane</id>
    <title>Thranda Releases Cessna U206G Stationair for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thranda-releases-cessna-u206g-stationair-for-x-plane" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6328aa24bc6c083772d46a9c_Screen%20Shot%202022-09-19%20at%2012.42.47%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2917157"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Designs has just released their rendition of the Cessna U206G Stationair, the “sport vehicle of the air” that is popular among bush pilots and skydivers. Introduced in 1962, over 8509 units had been built as of 2006 and the plane is still in production to this very day! Undeniably a gem for general aviation enthusiasts, it’s now ready to join your virtual fleet. ‍ As part of Thranda’s “Dynamic Generation Series”, the U206G’s liveries, gauges and aircraft configuration can be changed on the fly without reloading the simulator. It will also feature high fidelity flight dynamics and an ultra-realistic sound environment. ‍ The full feature list as follows: Feature-rich elegant fly-out menu with the following features: Flight dynamics and systems: Advanced FMOD-based sound system: To add the U206G to your virtual hangar, head over to the X-Plane.org store where it can be yours for $39.95.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffnuxp</id>
    <title>Flight Factor Releases Update for Boeing 767 and 757</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffnuxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6328c52c2caaa41d3a49581e_o5s3nao.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="217267"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has updated their current Boeing 757 and 767, including many fixes and improvements ‍ ‍ Aircraft Developer FlightFactor have further developed on their Boeing fleet to improve any imperfections during its new beta stage for X-Plane 12. The team at FlightFactor are working hard to complete other tasks which will enhance your experience when flying these wonderful machines. ‍ Sadly, no further news on the Airbus fleet or the Boeing 787 they have announced. ‍ The updates are available now to use with the current standing Boeing fleet of 767 and 757 aircraft. This update is free to the current owners of the 757 V2 Professional and 767 ER Professional. ‍ ‍ Below, you will find the Changelog for the current update: ‍ FlightFactor 757 - 2.6.2 - added glow effect to the FPDS displays (xp12) - fixed camera position for 753 (xp12) - fixed 3d reflections in displays (xp12) - fixed various issues with lamps (xp12) - fixed hovering gear (xp12) - fixed possible steering issue (xp12) - improved AT SPD mode behaviour (xp12) - updated billboard effect for external lights (xp12) ‍ FlightFactor 767 - 1.6.2 - added glow effect to the FPDS displays (xp12) - fixed 3d reflections in displays (xp12) - fixed various issues with lamps (xp12) - fixed tiller animation (xp12) - fixed possible steering issue (xp12) - fixed dome light issue in cold&amp;dark - improved AT SPD mode behaviour (xp12) - updated billboard effect for external lights (xp12) - made chart light knob as override knob (400) ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mtnfly</id>
    <title>MtnFly Simulations freeware Learjet-35A progress Update </title>
    <updated>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mtnfly" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632a05b9889cd711b0e93059_Screenshot_2021-09-29_170109.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="278400"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MtnFly Simulations have been developing a freeware Learjet-25A and have recently released a substantial progress update, outlining what has to be done, what is complete and even showcasing a full flight of the aircraft on their youtube channel.  Their update log outlining what has been done is as follows:  - NAV and COM radios are fully functional and will now work with the Garmin GPS even though there is no concept of a true standby frequency in the early model 35's radios. - The yaw damper has been modelled and is now functioning. - The three AC to DC power inverters are now modelled and functioning. - The FC-200 autopilot is now working as expected. - Improvements have been made to the side audio panels. - All four batteries are now connected to their respective power busses and function  - The captain's flight instruments are close to being fully functional. - The emergency brake lever has been modelled and now functions. - The cabin temperature indicator will now display a "cold-soaked" temperature on start-up. It will react to the user's set temperature setting once the engines are running and the passenger air conditioning system is turned on. - Improvements have been made to tying electrical circuits to their respective circuit breakers. - The RCA WXD weather radar has been modelled for those that prefer to fly "old school" without any GPS. - Panel lighting has been added. - Exterior Lighting has been added. - There have been many improvements to emissive lighting throughout the aircraft. - The wing to fuselage fairing has been added. - There have been numerous modelling updates. ‍ At Threshold we will keep you updated while this project progresses. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfs10</id>
    <title>MSFS Sim Update 10 Launches Sept 21st</title>
    <updated>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfs10" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632a08295954ea3cea5b3bd2_FdHkgcKX0AAK9h4.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="199970"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator have just confirmed that the long-awaited Sim Update 10 will be released tomorrow, September 21st 2022. The update will release at 8:00 AM PDT which is 1500 zulu time.  To see the official announcement you can head over to the MSFS Twitter account. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxor</id>
    <title>Orbx Introduces New Reward System</title>
    <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxor" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632b4b1a2011e902f3364e3f_5NH7H7a.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1194465"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently announced the introduction of Orbs, their brand new in-game currency that is earnable through purchases on the Orbx Store or Volanta (by purchasing a subscription, exploring aerocaches, or completing challenges). Users can spend their coins on the Orbs Store, which offers a list of redeemable sceneries for X-Plane 11, Prepar3d, FSX, and Microsoft Flight Simulator.  It’s important to highlight that Orbx has added a temporary multiplier to the Orbs reward system, granting twice as many coins for purchases on Orbx Direct and Volanta. The offer ends on the 3rd of October, at 01:00 UTC.  Read more about the Orbs here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
