<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-06-22T18:30:59.349009+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vskboi</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Announces Boise for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vskboi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1ced70fb718609759fdbf_287024476_4807808412656800_2786903833022319994_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="161459"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Boise’s relatively small airfield makes headlines for the second time this week with another developer announcing they’re bringing Gowen Field to Microsoft Flight Simulator. This time, the creator is Verticalsim. The scenery-maker has previously covered KBOI in X-Plane and in-line with previous releases, is now working on bringing their extensive catalogue of products for Laminar’s sim over to Microsoft Flight Simulator. Verticalsim published the following feature list with the announcement: Though a release date has not been mentioned, users likely won’t have to wait long for Boise to launch as based on previous releases Verticalsim tends to have a very short turnaround. Threshold will keep you posted.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ausham</id>
    <title>AUscene Teases Hamilton Island Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ausham" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1d4302cfb6ba96ea3783d_284513968_514946167039563_5900949890880924501_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="218117"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Australian tourist destination Hamilton Island and its airport, YBHM, has received more attention today in the form of a new development update from AUscene. The airfield is one of two projects the developer currently has underway for Microsoft Flight Simulator. On release, Hamilton Island will move alongside the developer’s ‘Reefworld’ area scenery covering the Great Barrier Reef. The two will be offered as a bundle pack due to their proximity. Today’s development update focused on the terminal’s interior, which the developer initially debated whether to include at all. “After much consideration we decided to add the Terminal Interior and are excited to finally be able to share some previews with you all! Hamilton Island will be our most extensive product with plenty of details for you to discover at the Airport, Marina, Resort and Dent Island.” See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdsrr</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Releases Sedona Red Rocks for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdsrr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a40727f36d7d0ea90ba84a_Screen%20Shot%202022-06-10%20at%2011.08.20%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2179245"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, X-Codr Designs released Sedona Red Rocks for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery, which comes with detailed models/textures and custom orthoimagery, will provide users with an immersive flight in the stunning Sedona region of Arizona, allowing them to experience the area’s famous geological wonders. According to the developers, an array of different rock formations ranging from Cathedral Rock to Capitol Butte are hand modeled and textured after their real life counterparts in Sedona.  ‍ Additionally, NAIP orthoimagery has beenused to “cover up glaring shadows” while performance has been optimized to minimize the scenery’s impact on the users’ computers. Finally, Sedona Airport (default or X-Codr’s upcoming rendition) has been seamlessly blended into this product. For a complete list of features,, visit the developer’s website. Currently, the Sedona Red Rocks by X-Codr Designs can be purchased in the MSFS MarketPlace for $14.99 USD. For other Microsoft Flight Simulator news, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lmmelb</id>
    <title>Landmarks Melbourne by Orbx Now Available</title>
    <updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lmmelb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a523d5c1fdbb460479f0d5_629-da56ab81442ca2bd8215be740378f006.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1383373"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Home to the Australian Open, the Australian Grand Prix, and Orbx's Australian Headquarters, Melbourne is the group's latest destination in the Landmarks series and was made available yesterday. The product boasts another 200 points of interest over the simulator's default skyline from World Update 7 -- which Orbx also had a hand in creating. "Welcome to the cultural and sports capital of Australia and the hometown of Orbx!" reads the product description. "With about a third of its current five million residents born outside of Australia, Melbourne’s skyline mirrors its inhabitants’ diversity, from Gold Rush and Victorian architecture to ultra-modern skyscrapers." The feature list reads: Landmarks Melbourne is available for $17.89 AUD (US$12.62 | €11,99 | £10.24) from OrbxDirect. To see more images, check out a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrpro</id>
    <title>FSRealistic Pro Released</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrpro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a52b4474c14f14cf317a77_unknown%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3111061"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Effects management system FSRealistic 'Core' has now been available for seven months, having been initially released in November 2021. In the time since, rkApps have taken to improving upon the work seen in that product with the new FSRealistic Pro. The 'Pro' version builds upon the effects included in 'Core', with the developer proclaiming a "growing list of 28" different interactions. Speaking to Threshold, the developer explains the leap forward that the 'Pro' version has made:  "After a long period of time that Asobo didn't support camera movements, it has recently released a partial support and we have now finally managed to make a breakthrough with amazing real camera effects to create a more-than-ever realistic flight experience." "We are proud to be the first company to offer such level of realism and excited to offer you [the chance] to join the ride!" FSRealistic Pro is available for EUR 28.00 from simMarket here. Users of 'Core' are able to upgrade at a discounted price of EUR 5.60. Threshold is giving away two copies of FSRealistic Pro to readers of this article. To enter, simply write a comment below this article. The winners will be drawn in 24 hours.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a31fre</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Microsoft Flight Simulator Partnership: A310 to be Free</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a31fre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a63d7a1f699a875c0cbca1_image.png.b0f3905239211c26c17332f5436020b6.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="700074"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds' aircraft development branch have shared perhaps the most significant development update in their history this evening with news that a partnership has been struck between themselves and Microsoft Flight Simulator. Users will benefit from a free copy of the group's A310 aircraft for the platform, which outside of Microsoft Flight Simulator currently retails for £69.99 GBP. In a post on the iniBuilds forum, chief executive Ubaid Mussa explains what's to look forward to with the shortest Airbus wide-body: "The aircraft introduced a two-crew glass cockpit and is truly a versatile aircraft perfect for short-long haul operations (up to 10 hrs!). It existed in many variations and iterations; our aircraft on initial release will be the A310-304 powered by General Electric CF6-80 engines, passenger variant only." The iniBuilds team have reportedly re-modelled a number of 'significant areas' about the aircraft as well as having undergone a complete re-texturing since the last set of previews, which you can check out here. Additionally, a real A310 has been used in development of the audio environment. "Moving onto systems: we have completely re-written our code base for the Microsoft Flight Simulator version, enhancing and improving our A310 systems in all areas from the previous iteration of this product." "Significant parts of aircraft have greater levels of dynamic behaviour and reliance for example in our electrical system; each item within the aircraft has an impact on the power drawn from the generators, even individual fuel pumps, which will cause realistic electrical system demand changes. "The FMS (flight management system) which is an essential component for the navigation of the aircraft, has been completely re-written from the ground up allowing for more realistic operations on day-day flying, along with new features not previously seen on iniBuilds products. The FMS will allow for full lateral and vertical guidance modes including RNAV approaches and overlay NDB VOR approaches." The largest news of the announcement in fact comes right at the end: iniBuilds' A310 for Microsoft Flight Simulator will be available for free as part of the 40th Anniversary Update in November 2022. Mussa calls this a fantastic step for the industry in the ability to provide high quality aircraft simulations. See more at the announcement of the A310 for Microsoft Flight Simulator in a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msf40t</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator 40th Anniversary: Helicopters, Gliders, DHC-2, DC-3 &amp; Many More New Aircraft</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msf40t" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a6467cb373dc45d0ec24ce_6.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3366894"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The 40th Anniversary of Microsoft's longest running franchise (that's right, Microsoft Flight Simulator) is fast approaching. Today, at the Xbox &amp; Bethesda Games Showcase, the team have showcased what is in store for an update coming in November. It will also mark the first time they've collaborated with an aircraft developer for a simulator update, with iniBuilds teasing that their A310 will come free with the 40th Anniversary edition in November. To the guts of the announcement: news today centres around a trailer released on the Xbox YouTube channel. It shows a number of new aircraft and indeed categories of aircraft coming soon. The team start vintage with the first chronologically appearing to be a Wright Flier II - this is followed in quick succession by the Spirit of St. Louis (which carried Charles Lindbergh on his non-stop transatlantic flight in 1927). A relic of Flight Simulators past, the Douglas DC-3 will also make its way to Microsoft Flight Simulator, appearing here in an Emerald Harbor Air livery. Similarly, the DHC-2 Beaver is also showcased. The Granville Gee Bee Z Super Sportster also makes an appearance, adding another aerobatic aircraft to the platforms current selection. Sliding into shot with aptly orchestral music, it was revealed that gliders will shortly be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator too. The model seems to be a Glaser-Dirks DG-808. Having left rotorheads waiting since the release of the simulator, the developer also showed off helicopters for the first time. A Bell Jetranger and a Cabri G2 look to be the default additions and the video also showcases a number of helipads in the sim. Finally, right at the end of the video and even after the credits, the developer teased the UNSC Pelican -- an aircraft from Microsoft's Halo franchise -- which will also be making an appearance in the update. Microsoft Flight Simulator's 40th Anniversary Update will be available in November to all users.  See the source video for this article here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxpde</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Shares X-Plane Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxpde" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a72a0bb912a76ea62fecdc_278391652_516087066594252_1002473650932431623_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="101607"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has taken to the X-Plane.org Forum today to share a 'comprehensive' development update covering two of their in-development aircraft as well as four other products which have already been released. The brand's leader Ramzzess says that the 'time is right' for a holistic overview of the group's projects given the short time until X-Plane 12 becomes available. No images were shared in this post, however, we've included screenshots from previous teasers which have been published over the past couple of months. Addressing the 777v2 and 787 first, Ramzzess says that "the models being built [are] more complicated than anything that we have developed before, to the point of insanity." The Flight Management System, EFB, maintenance, and sound systems all remain 'in progress' at various stages of completion.  A CPDLC system will be included with both aircraft, which at this stage is being integrated with some third party addons.  Failures will be completed on release, but at this stage FlightFactor believe that most things covered in real-world sim training are implemented. There are currently over 1000 individual failures, with 'more stuff' to be added after release.  Another unique aspect of these Boeing widebodies will be a multi-crew simulation. Ramzzess describes this as an 'enormous undertaking'. Interactions between the captain, first officer, cabin crew and ground staff will be covered, with more to be added post-release. The first officer will be able to assist in all standard procedures on release, similar to the likes of FS2Crew products for ESP-platforms.  FlightFactor list the following as being 'basically ready for release:' Turning attention to the A320, Ramzzess applauds the work of the Airbus team for the release of v1.3.0, which has improved FPS counts by a reported 20-50%. Before the end of the X-Plane 11 run, the team want to bring back the web browser, integrate a new weather radar and correct a number of small issues. With X-Plane 12, however, FlightFactor plan some more significant changes, these include: The final topic covered in the development update today are the group's other three models, the Boeing 757, 767 and Airbus A350.  These will be compatible with X-Plane 12 from the outset and will see extended support and updates through the end of version 12 or if a new version of the aircraft is rolled out -- there are no specific plans for this as yet. A 767-400 variant is also being worked on and will be added to the various 767 packages available right now.  "It is in all respects a continuation of that line. Not a standalone model," says Ramzzess. See the source post for this article on the X-Plane.org Forum.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aphdhc</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Partner with Microsoft for DC-3 &amp; Debut Standalone DHC-1 Chipmunk</title>
    <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aphdhc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a6472acf79f600ffd92934_3.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="880498"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A second developer has now gone public on a deal struck with Microsoft for Flight Simulator's 40th Anniversary Update, this being Aeroplane Heaven and the aircraft in development the legendary DC-3. Similar to iniBuilds, the other developer signed on with Microsoft for the update, the developer has been under NDA on all news surrounding the project. Speaking on Facebook, the developer maintains that "the package will be the self-same one as we would release ourselves with other advantages yet to come." "The sounds have now been completed by the best in the business and a new flight model is also now complete, authored by another top FM coder." "As part of the Anniversary celebrations we will be bringing you all the liveries we have shown you, in a special add-on package absolutely free. We will now be able to bring you updates both here and with Microsoft, as the package progresses to release in November." Later in the day, the developer also showcased another aircraft which will shortly be added to their range: the DHC-1 Chipmunk. The deHavilland craft was teased in a single image posted on Facebook, proclaiming its 'very' soon arrival. The so-called 'poor man's Spitfire' does not appear to be part of the 40th Anniversary Update and thus will be a payware product. See both of these items on Aeroplane Heaven's Facebook page. Alternatively, check out the large number of aircraft coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator with the 40th Anniversary Update in a dedicated article here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drzewiecki-design-released-rzeszow-jasionka-airport-eprz-for-microsoft-flight-simulator</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Released Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport (EPRZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drzewiecki-design-released-rzeszow-jasionka-airport-eprz-for-microsoft-flight-simulator" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a7c836f0923513c0157793_297387_EPRZ_MSFS_11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1796359"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Drzewiecki Design released Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport (EPRZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The product, an accurate rendition of the southeastern Polish airport, features high quality textures/models and serves as the gateway for pilots looking to venture into eastern Europe. According to the developers, the airport is created based on the latest layout of its real life counterpart. The scenery features high definition PBR textures and mesh, as well as detailed models, custom night lighting, and terminal interiors. Additionally, the airport has been optimized for performance and is FPS-friendly without sacrificing any realism. Finally, the scenery also includes Rzeszów City landmarks scattered in the region around the airport in order to further increase the users’ immersion. For a full list of features, visit the developer’s website. Currently, the scenery can be purchased on simMarket for EUR 15 or USD 15.87. The developers recommend users to have at least 1.6GB of free space on their hard drives in order to successfully install the product. For information on other Drzewiecki Design products, checkout another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ppegaa</id>
    <title>PYREEGUE Dev Co. Previews Belfast Airport (EGAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ppegaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ab9f64b1aa9917b4774100_Screenshot_3.thumb.png.e4f8bdd13e4a90635c1ccabb5b7db807.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="577474"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer PYREEGUE published a short update on its upcoming Belfast/Aldergrove International Airport (EGAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. In the update, the team previews the modeling, texturing, and lighting of the airport through a series of short videos, demonstrating their progress and the new technologies being implemented on the scenery. Based on the videos, it can be concluded that the airport's terminal has been mostly completed. As the plane taxied toward the gate, we can see that the overall building, signage, small objects (ground vehicles, AC units, etc), and lighting are almost fully modeled and textured. Additionally, we can see through the building’s window into the terminal interior where everything from chairs, vending machines, and walking passengers have been modeled/animated. According to the developers, what is being shown in the videos only represent a small portion of “new crazy things” that Belfast Airport will feature. The team also hinted that the new features brought to Belfast will come to “great stuff” featured in EGAA will eventually be integrated into its other airports, starting with EGPH before moving to EGPF, EGNX and EGPD. Currently, the developers are yet to announce a release date and pricing for Belfast airport, though they did indicate that they “are not far from release”. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. For more information on the scenery, check out a previous Threshold article.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflb23</id>
    <title>AirfoilLabs Launches First Microsoft Flight Simulator Aircraft: the Bristell B23</title>
    <updated>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflb23" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ad5addf9f79bf5a4e2876c_288675244_2240065689482813_6265946275129304151_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="760363"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Traditionally an aircraft-maker for X-Plane, AirfoilLabs have made a stunning leap into the Microsoft Flight Simulator market today with the announcement and release of the Bristell B23, a light sport aircraft from the Czech Republic. Sharing the news on Facebook, the developer raved about the relatively unknown LSA brand saying that the group have flown with their B23's real world counterparts. "Today, we have a pretty different announcement to make. For over a year and a half, we have been cooperating with an LSA Aircraft manufacturer, the BRISTELL." "Airfoillabs has heard the requests many of you have been asking for and, for the first time, introduces an aircraft model for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020." The aircraft was released at the same time as the announcement was made and is available on the Microsoft Marketplace for $24.99 USD. In the comments of the social media post, community users peppered questions regarding the developer's commitment to X-Plane 11 and 12 -- to which the developer remained steadfast. "This aircraft [the Bristell B23] will not be available for X-Plane, at least not yet. But we’re working on airplanes for X-Plane 12. We will be releasing the C172 NG digital once X-Plane 12 is available to the public, as well as the NG analogue version." The steam-gauge version of the group's C172 will be exclusively available on X-Plane 12. Difficulty surrounding porting to v11 and maintaining two versions is cited as the primary reasons behind this decision. See AirfoilLabs on Facebook here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/73pmdg</id>
    <title> PMDG Publishes Development Blog for MSFS 737 Series</title>
    <updated>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/73pmdg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62760542fbf0175a9b61a988_image_15258.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712230"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, PMDG published a lengthy development blog on its website where the developers shared the future plans for their popular 737-700 and 737-600 aircrafts for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Starting off the blog, the developer indicated that the current update cycle for the -700 will only carry bug fixes and small tweaks as the team focuses on improving visual features and animations within the cockpit to improve both user experience and the plane’s overall performance. Additionally, efforts are being diverted to repair the aircraft’s trim wheel animation whose code has been “accidentally reverted” to that of the original 737nGX for P3D. This means that the part has to be completely rebuilt and retested before the update can be pushed out, a process the team hopes to complete by the middle of next week. As for the -600, the developers confirmed the beta team will soon receive the new version carrying the “new PMDG Lateral Flight Path Model (LFPM) that has been under development for two years”. The LFPM will give a far more accurate, more true-to-life lateral flight path model”, improving realism and reducing errors. The new model will be first introduced in the -600 before being implemented onto the -700. The developers have indicated that they plan to implement the LFPM into all their existing P3D aircrafts. Due to the LFPM, the team is expecting the launch of the -600 to be delayed by a few weeks and will share more information on a potential release sometime next week after the new version has been tested. Finally, the team addressed the question of when will the aircrafts be made available in the MarketPlace. Currently, the -700 are being withheld from the MarketPlace due to concern of “incompatibility between [the] product and gamepad/twist grip/dual rudder axis controllers”. The developers are hoping to resolve this issue in the next update cycle and will provide more information soon. As for the -600, there will likely be a much shorter delay between its launch on the PMDG web store and MarketPlace. 	Currently, the -700 variant can be purchased for a reduced price of $69.99. As for the -600 variant, the developers are yet to announce an exact release date and pricing. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Credits to Cristian Ionescu from the Threshold Discord for the news scoop.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsdev</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Issues Lengthy Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsdev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ad6832c576e30f5be465f2_288647332_4779790138793825_2497002483118359383_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="500377"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios are planning to hit the second half of 2022 hard and bring three more aircraft to Microsoft Flight Simulator by the end of the year, according to a new development update issued today. Firstly, addressing an aircraft that's already available for the simulator, the developer discusses work on an Amphibian variant of the Kodiak 100. "The exterior and interior models have been completed. A significant amount of time has gone in re-engineering the interior of the aircraft so that it is compatible with Asobo's submodel and attachment system." The Kodiak's interior has seen similar treatment with new support for the platform's 'submodel' feature. The developer explains that this will alow a more efficient cockpit model -- this will also find its way into the other, wheeled, Kodiak currently available. SimWorks Studios' Vans RV-14 will also see some new content in the near future, with a GNS530 radio stack being made ready for rollout on PC and Xbox.  Onto the three in-development aircraft: the RV-10, Airvan and PC-12. The four-seat cousin of the RV-14, the Vans RV-10 is said to be making 'solid progress'. The developer says that the exterior model is undergoing review at the moment, with images to come in 'the next couple of weeks'. "Regarding the PC-12, we have our WIP exterior in the simulator and are dialing in the basic geometry, electrical and engine parameters. We are nitpicking at the exterior still, as some details of the aircraft were hard to come by.  "However, thanks to Pilatus and our pilots, we have everything we need and can soon dash to the finish line and focus on the cockpit!" Finally, the Gippsland Airvan -- according to this development update, the aircraft will come equipped with steam gauges and a GNS530 plus a Bendix-King unit to comprise the radio stack. As with the Kodiak, the instrument panel will be 'moldable', allowing for user customisation. See the full development update on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rksiup</id>
    <title>Pacific Islands Simulations Posts Development Updates on Incheon/Songdo Airport (RKSI)</title>
    <updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rksiup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b14d8ab1b014932dd68bf5_289440864_3126141987634129_7456268730579559754_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="514219"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pacific Islands Simulations has recently published on its Facebook page a short update on its upcoming Incheon/Songdo Airport (RKSI) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, informing the community on the team’s progress over the past few weeks and showcasing a few new previews. According to the developers, the terminal interiors have mostly been completed. From the pictures, we can see that the team has modeled and textured everything from the escalator, the glass doom, and shops such as Dunkin Donuts in great detail.  In addition to work on the interior, the taxiways, parking lots, drainage systems, and traffic tunnels have also been added - progress that is very much evident on the previews posted. Though the team has yet to set a firm release date for the product, they teased that development has entered the “final phases” for the airport. Currently, the developers are yet to announce the pricing of the product. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. For now, check out another Threshold article. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jffk70</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Fokker 100 &amp; 70 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jffk70" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b22ba377fb9d1a175969fa_287512483_10162001953168499_8760778841413427502_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="646260"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight have added a new aircraft to their list of in development products today in the form of the Fokker 100 (and the shortened 70 variant) for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  It is the second Fokker aircraft they've got on the go at the moment, with the F28 Fellowship also in the works. Learn more about that product here. "Just like in real-life, we will be following development of our Fokker F28 Fellowship for MSFS with its younger brother, the Fokker 100 and shortened Fokker 70," the developers said on Facebook. "Built with incredible detail to take full advantage of the MSFS platform, the exterior and cockpit modelling and texturing work is progressing very well, and we are aiming for a 2023 release." The developers maintain that the aircraft is still in the early stages, saying that the 3D model and textures have a decent headstart on the code and systems for the aircraft.  We can expect the Fokker 100/70 to be added to the group's website in the near future. In the meantime. 'enjoy these initial shots,' they say.  See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
