<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-11-13T18:28:04.648244+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inixp12</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Free A300V2 Compatibility Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inixp12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635e12ec8fb6acc2d668856b_A300-v2-Store_14.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="179896"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, developer iniBuilds has announced their plans of bringing their existing aircrafts to X-Plane 12, focusing exclusively on their much-popular A300. According to the developers, the A300V2 will soon receive an update that makes the plane compatible with X-Plane 12. All existing owners of the aircraft will be able to update free of charge. In addition, a significant reduction in price for the entire family is planned, though the developer didn’t offer any details regarding this planned price change. However, the developers have decided to not provide a release date for the compatibility update, though they hinted that it is expected to come in early 2023. Though the date seems far in the future, the developers reasoned that their current focus is to improve and polish the A300.  Currently, the A300V2 is on sale and can be purchased on iniBuilds webstore for £34.99 GBP, or $40.5 USD. Threshold will keep you updated on future iniBuild news.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/adpfkm</id>
    <title>Aero Dynamics Previews Freeware KC-10/DC-10 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/adpfkm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63604ca24006b960ce3f1ba3_dc-10-4.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1972447"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Aero Dynamics team has published a new quarterly drop on their Discord server, showcasing the current state of their freeware KC-10/DC-10 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with extensive focus on their 3D scanned cockpit. It is said to feature swappable instruments to provide both the OG experience and a modern flight suite, along with an EFB that will allow users to customize the cockpit settings, handle ground services, checklists, Navigraph and SimBrief integration, and OSM maps.   Regarding displays and systems, they have managed to integrate the fuel gauges into the aircraft, with upgrades to the font accuracy coming in the near future. Further progress with the electrical system has made viable work on a more advanced fuel system and the APU, with pneumatic and hydraulic systems to follow. They have also showcased two new models, the DC-10-30F (freighter) and the 10 Tanker. The 10F is their first DC-10 variant, featuring nine liveries, including FedEx (old and new), Aeroflot, and United. The latter is a tanker, capable of dropping fire retardant with the press of a button! ‍ Credits to AllNaturalBlue for the news scoop.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2022-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssroha</id>
    <title>Sierrasim Simulation Releases Olaya Herrera Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssroha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6362de304b448c610d1f9133_skmd1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2113931"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Sierrasim Simulation has recently released their rendition of Olaya Herrera Airport (SKMD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the region of Medellín with domestic and international flights. With a yearly average of 1 million passengers, it’s the main regional airport in Colombia due to its high volume of domestic traffic in comparison with José María Córdova International (SKRG), which has been the de facto international airport since 1985.  It’s visited by airlines such as Avianca Express, EasyFly, Pacífica de Aviación, Satena, and Searca, with a route network that covers most of the country. The scenery features custom ground imagery, photorealistic PBR textures for buildings and vehicles, airport objects, texture and model improvements, terminal interiors, performance optimization, and custom night lighting.  It’s available on Flightsim.to for $9.99, requiring at least 1 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pu7lfm</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pu7lfm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636349b4011f85502d5b5cb8_737-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3567645"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their current 737 lineup (600/700/800) to version 3.00.0044 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, marking the 10th update since the original release in early May, an average of one update every 18 days. The update focuses on control law and stability, ensuring proper management of atmospheric instabilities that may occur mid-flight. The complete changelog follows down below: 0011898: [Systems - Hydraulic] EDP Low Pressure lights come on to late in start (rsrandazzo) 0012029: [AFDS - Pitch Modes] Level change down : provision for FS atmoshpere "bursts" pumping pitch up/down (emvaos) 0012002: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] VC Clipping and assorted finds (vscimone) 0010744: [FMS - Route/Legs Pages] Wrapping ETA and time differences around 0000z (emvaos) 0012006: [FMS/AFDS - VNAV] CRZ phase revival even within geometric descent (emvaos) 0011655: [AFDS - Thrust Modes] Provisions and refinement of A/T speed mode in SU10+ turbulence (emvaos) 0010628: [AFDS - Thrust Modes] New AT SPD mode system (emvaos) 0012005: [External Model - Geometry] Cabin lighting tone down needed after SU10? (jbrown) 0011992: [External Model - Geometry] Pilots not shown on extenral view (jbrown) 0011993: [AFDS - Pitch Modes] Oscilattions when using V/S for descent. (emvaos) 0011996: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Small fap on the ceiling of VC, (vscimone) 0011976: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] VC Vertices cleanup (vscimone)​ additiona: provisions for stability with known SU11 changes. ‍ On the update announcement thread, Robert Randazzo from PMDG  mentioned they were progressing further into the -900 development, which should enter testing a week from Friday. The long-awaited tablet enters testing next week.  The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Pictures are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/agrvam</id>
    <title>AG Sim Releases Varna Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/agrvam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63657e365fa9f6771d7413a3_varna1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2829251"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AG Sim has just released their rendition of Varna Airport (LBWN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third largest airport in Bulgaria, averaging 2 million passengers per year (pre-pandemic). It serves Varna and the northeastern part of the country.  It’s the hub for BH Air, Bulgaria Air, European Air Charter, Voyage Air, and WizzAir, and visited by Austrian, easyJet, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Volotea, and Turkish.   The scenery features high-detail 3D buildings, PBR texturing, improved ground textures, custom vegetation, animated radar and windsock, accurate runway slope, night lighting, and accurate ground markings.   It’s available on FlightSim.to for $14.99, requiring at least 3.98 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xplr12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Announces Full XP12 Release </title>
    <updated>2022-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xplr12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6368422df99d0defe6c5a9e0_hj8r7lqrzwm21-3988564165.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="822964"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The team at Laminar Research has formally announced that the full release of X-Plane 12 will occur sometime in December. This announcement comes as a shock to many as the alpha phase of XP12 has only been in session for only a couple of months. The team at Laminar Research is confident in pushing the release of XP12 to other medians such as DVD disks, though the release of a disk will be available in early 2023. Many people are looking forward to an improved Airbus A330 with a custom MCDU instead of the default XP FMS. Laminar did provide screenshots of the MCDU to attendees, showcasing what has been worked on. Many are excited for Laminar to release the next-gen simulator fully, whilst some believe that it is a very optimistic decision on Laminar’s part. Though, it was disclosed that work will continue on the alpha version before the final release. ‍ Threshold will keep you updated on further developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsuafm</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsuafm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63692e9dddc6233d6ba2e46a_fnx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2024438"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently released an update to their A320 add-on, addressing crashes, QoL stuff, brake temperature issues with the GSX pushback, and sound tweaks (including the addition of seat movement sounds!). They have recently mentioned on their Discord that work on SU11 compatibility is underway, ensuring proper behavior with the new weather system.  The complete changelog follows down below: A320 v1.0.6.146 ‍ [SYSTEM] ‍ - Fixed TOO STEEP PATH ‍ - Fixed TCAS ‍ - Fixed several crashes/exceptions ‍ - LOC Capture in HDG mode improved ‍ - Added more variables for which brake temperature modelling is disabled during GSX pushbacks ‍ - Screen brightness set to MAX for cold and dark ‍ - Minor VNAV calculation error fixed ‍ [ART&amp;SOUND] ‍ - Minor fixes and adjustments ‍ - Particle FX reworked for improved performance ‍ - Refactored cockpit wind further so a more noticeable change can be heard below 280knots ‍ - Increased volume of brake fans ‍ - N2 volume on approach increased and improved ‍ - Cockpit wind now tied to "environment sounds" slider in MSFS, leaving it at 100% will give the most accurate experience to the real A320 ‍ - Added seat movement sounds ‍ - Cabin lights are now dimmed when set to OFF The update is available on their website for registered customers.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xdroca</id>
    <title>Xometry Design Releases Oklahoma City Airport for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2022-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xdroca" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636b00c74ff68363bc41ad73_kock1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1768262"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry Design has just released their rendition of Oklahoma City Will Rogers Airport (KOKC) for X-Plane 11 and 12, a civil-military airport with a yearly average of 3.5 million passengers. It’s also known as Will Rogers World Airport, named after a local comedian that died in 1935.  It’s served by Alaska, Allegiant, American Airlines (and Eagle), Delta Airlines (and Connection), Frontier, Southwest, and United (and Express), encompassing most of the USA. Cargo-wise, it’s visited by FedEx, Martinaire, and UPS.  The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, custom SAM jetways and marshallers, disassembled aircraft parts, realistic wear and tear, and accurately placed custom buildings and clutter. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $21.72, requiring at least 4.32 GB of free disk space to install, and compatible with X-Plane 11.50+ or X-Plane 12.00+. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrbwim</id>
    <title>LatinVFR Releases Baltimore-Washington International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrbwim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636dd346c1bbc346693029d1_bwi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="674449"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LatinVFR has recently released their rendition of Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport (KBWI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With an average of 20 million passengers every year, BWI is the 22nd busiest airport in the United States and the busiest in the metropolitan area of Baltimore-Washington.  It’s a hub for the low-cost carrier Southwest Airlines, with 71% of the market share between April 2021 and March 2022, with roughly 13 million passengers. Spirit, Delta, American, and United make for the rest of the traffic. LCCs comprehend 80% of the yearly average. The scenery features PBR ground markings and textures, realistic terminals and cargo buildings, realistic lighting, custom jetways, and an airport layout in accordance with real-world data. It’s available on LatinVFR’s Shop for $16.99, and owners of the P3D BWI can get a discount with the following promotional code: KBWIMSFS. At least 1.3 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rreetm</id>
    <title>RPSimulations Releases EMB-312 Embraer Tucano for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rreetm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636dd9a6c1bbc3157c34933a_fab1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2063413"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RPSimulations has recently released their rendition of the EMB-312 Embraer Tucano for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a low-wing single-turboprop basic trainer aircraft developed in Brazil by Embraer in partnership with the Brazilian Air Force (sponsorship). Designed in 1979, it took off for the first time in August 1980, and got its first production units in 1983. With a production span of 16 years, 664 units were built in total, operated by the Air Forces of Argentina, Brazil and Egypt. It was Embraer’s first international success. It features a highly detailed cockpit with PBR textures, an animated canopy, in-sim checklist, smoke effects, custom liveries, animated pilots, dimmable interior lights, and freedom to use either of the seats. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available on FlightSim.to for $19.90, requiring at least 2.2 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oadmaf</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Detroit Metropolitan Airport for X-Plane 12 and MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oadmaf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636e0378385263770baab23d_dtw1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2149364"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has just announced their latest project: Detroit Metropolitan Airport (KDTW) for X-Plane 12 and Microsoft Flight Simulator, with the XP version to come first. According to their announcement post, it’s developed by a group of independent developers, using real-world drawings and exclusive access to the airport as reference.  With a yearly average of 35 million passengers, DTW  is among the busiest airports in the United States, serving the city of Detroit, Toledo (Ohio), and part of Ontario in Canada. It’s a hub for Delta Airlines, with over 50% of the market share, followed by Endeavor Air and Spirit Airlines, with 12.95% and 11.69%, respectively. It’s DAL’s gateway to Asia for the eastern US, with frequent flights to Shanghai, Seoul, and Tokyo. Popular routes to Europe include Amsterdam, Paris and Frankfurt.  The complete feature list follows down below: They have also stated the intent to develop a Detroit City Pack and Coleman A. Young International Airport as a complement for the Microsoft Flight Simulator version.  There is no information on a potential release date or pricing, but we’ll keep you updated.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrbfm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Baden for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrbfm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636e6d2b8b7123cd5515064d_edsb_11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="380753"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has just released their newest scenery Karlsruhe/Baden-Baden airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Known as the international airport for Karlsruhe, Baden is a focus airport for Ryanair which operates routes over the majority of Spain and some other destinations within Europe. The airport was initially a military aerodrome in 1951 and then closed in 1994 to be turned into a regional airport as well as a business park. In 2001, the first commercial flights took place to destinations Ibiza and Palma De Mallorca by a former airline, Hapag-Lloyd Flug (now TUI fly Deutschland.) Below, you will find a list of key features Aerosoft have included in their newest scenery.   This scenery is available for purchase on the Aerosoft website and will cost €15.08. You will also need roughly 5GB of storage for the scenery to be installed.  Let us know your thoughts and keep your eyes peeled for future news!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mr4aeu</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases 40th Anniversary Edition Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mr4aeu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636eace77326516cd172c5aa_a1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2507698"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has just released the long-awaited 40th Anniversary Edition update (SU11) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing twelve new aircraft, four classic commercial airports, fourteen heliports and twenty-four classic missions. It is the most substantial update to date in terms of new content. ‍The aircraft list includes seven classics (1903 Wright Flyer, 1915 Curtiss JN-4 Jenny, 1927 Ryan NYP Spirit of St. Louis, 1935 Douglas DC-3, 1937 Grumman G-21 Goose, 1947 Havilland DHC-2 Beaver, 1947 Hughes H-4 Hercules), two helicopters (Guimbal Cabri G2, Bell 407), two sailplanes/gliders (DG Aviation LS8-18, DG-1001E neo) and a true-to-life airliner (A310-300).  ‍Airport-wise, we have the addition of Hong Kong Kai Tak, Chicago Meigs Field, Princess Juliana International (St. Maarten), and First Flight Airport in Kitty Hawk. The update also includes VRAM management improvements to the DX12 version, along with the addition of AMD FSR2 and Nvidia DLSS 3 (including frame generator). ‍ The complete feature list follows down below: 7 classic aircraft: 2 sailplanes/gliders: 1 true-to-life airliner: 4 iconic airports: 24 classic activities from previous Flight Simulator titles: 7 new tutorial missions for Gliders: New features The new update is available right now on the Microsoft Store and Steam, requiring at least 41 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssraia</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Akureyri International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssraia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636f18f3ecd52d6a68d41b1e_aku1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2039387"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently released their rendition of Akureyri International Airport (BIAR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a northern Icelandic airport with nearly 100 years of scheduled air travel history. It’s a hub for Niceair and Norlandair, with a significant domestic network. It’s also frequently visited by Icelandair, with daily flights to Reykjavik. The total yearly average is around 220.000 passengers.  It is home to the Icelandic Aviation Museum, founded in May 1999 and opened mid-2000, in a purpose-built hangar with 2,200 square meters of space. The collection includes classics like the Douglas DC-3, a Fokker F-27, and a Waco YKS-7, among others.   The scenery features an accurate model of the terminal, up-to-date apron and runway data, the Icelandic Aviation Museum hangar, custom static aircraft, high-detail textures, PBR materials, realistic taxiway markings, custom environment objects, and intensive terraforming work.   It’s available on FlightSim.to for $10.99, requiring at least 1.08GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/urtram</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Telluride Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/urtram" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/636f21310710dedd803ff66d_tex2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2482311"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has just released their rendition of Telluride Regional Airport (KTEX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the highest commercial airport in the United States, and the second highest overall in the country, only behind Leadville Airport. The yearly passenger figures are around 17.000, with Denver being the most popular destination in terms of sheer volume.   The airport is famous for providing a challenging approach because of the surrounding geography, runway length, and steep glide path angle (3.55 on 9 and 4.0 on 27). The 2167 meters of runway feel a lot shorter because of the elevation.   The scenery features high-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, night effects, FPS-oriented optimization, custom vegetation, PBR materials, both tower and terminal with a modeled interior, and optional static aircraft.  It’s available on FlightSim.to for $9.99 and on their website for £9.99, requiring at least 105 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdrbfx</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Releases Bucharest for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdrbfx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/637067d70a791e53e63f04b8_31-600x338.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="62954"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Chudoba Design have recently released their version of Bucharest Henri Coandă International Airport for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Known as Romania’s busiest international airport, Otopeni is located North of the highly populated Bucharest city which offers a major tourist attraction to tourists all around the world due to its iconic landmarks. The airport has seen well over 14 million passengers back in 2019. However, In 2020 the airport had seen almost a 60% decrease in total passengers for that year due to the COVID pandemic. Bucharest Henri Coandă International Airport offers a choice of numerous airlines that fly all around Europe and some parts of Middle-East Asia. There are two runways available at Otopeni International which are parallel to each other and are of the same length of 3500m. Below, is a list of key features this scenery contains: ‍ ‍ This airport scenery is available to purchase on SimMarket for $16.99 and will require at least 2GB of free space to be installed into X-Plane.    Keep your eyes peeled for future news from Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2022-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
