<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-11-26T18:32:27.662268+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jet111</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Updates E-Jets for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jet111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67361a028366088a0243d02d_E-JETS_FAMILY_BY_X-CRAFTS_E170_016.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts has recently issued a new update to their E-Jets lineup for X-Plane, bringing ILS autotune compatibility improvements, pitch attitude tweaks, and more. They have also announced their biggest Black Friday sale yet, with discounts ranging from 30 to 50%.  Update v1.1.1 focuses on improving what had been implemented in 1.1.0, which added automatic speed management, ILS autotune, steep approach capabilities on compatible aircraft, and next-gen pop-up displays. The changelog follows below: As previously mentioned, they have also announced their biggest Black Friday discounts yet. The E170 will be a record 50% off, and the other E-Jets will get a 30% discount. X-Crafts also plans to add an upgrade discount for users wanting the full lineup. Refer to their official blog post for further information. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mu24cd</id>
    <title>Microsoft Provides Update on FS24 Collector's Edition Delay</title>
    <updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mu24cd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67377c6b80ea609535670160_IMG_3422.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In an announcement made on their website Wednesday, Microsoft addressed the delay in shipping the Limited Collector’s Edition of the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, as well as outlining their plan to make sure customers are able to access FS24 on release, in just four days. For context, Aerosoft, the vendor for the Limited Collector’s Edition, sent out an email to customers on Nov. 5, announcing that people who have pre-ordered the Limited Collector’s Edition outside of the US before Nov. 6 can expect delays in shipping and delivery. However, U.S. customers will not be affected. You can read more about that here. Microsoft begins by thanking customers who pre-ordered the Limited Collector’s Edition, and apologising, saying that they are “heartbroken that our shipping solution for regions outside of the United States have suffered an unexpected delay”.They also confirm that Limited Collector’s Edition pre-order customers outside of the U.S. can expect deliveries to start in the first week of December. To address these delays, Microsoft has announced a plan to ensure affected customers are able to play on release day, which is as follows: Additionally, when customers receive their Limited Collector’s Edition package, they will have to redeem the code on the physical token provided for the Aviator’s Edition of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 to keep access to the sim. According to Microsoft, “As long as you sign in with the same account when redeeming the token, then all your progress in the simulator will remain”. They also posted a FAQ addressing inquiries from the community. As of the time of publication, pre-orders for the Limited Collector’s Edition are still available on the Aerosoft Store for $259.99 USD. ‍ If you’re wondering when FS24 will be available for you, check out our article covering release times for FS24. Us on the Threshold team are excited for the imminent release of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and we will keep you updated on all of the newest developments regarding the new sim, so stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwpir</id>
    <title>BMWorld Accused of Piracy; Products Removed From Multiple Vendors </title>
    <updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwpir"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6737ada669f0a65e71498fad_eba5cc_cb8bea2af25441ce8bf155e7619752d1~mv2.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a bombshell statement published on Wednesday, Amir Salehi, owner of Flightbeam Studios accused fellow scenery developer Alexey Unishkov, better known as Beautiful Model of the World (BMWorld), of distributing pirated addons from multiple developers, including Flightbeam themselves. This comes on the heels of BMWorld/AmSim's release of Washington Dulles.  As of the time of publication, multiple flight sim product vendors have pulled BMWorld’s products from their stores, including his products developed in collaboration with Pavel of AmSim. ‍ Salehi details how he became suspicious of Unishkov, initially due to BMWorld/AmSim developing the same airports as Flightbeam, at around the same time. Then, a user on the AVSIM forums, going by the username of “Peter113” caught their attention, having few posts, with most of them being critical of Flightbeam’s products. Peter113 also posted screenshots comparing the BMWorld/AmSim rendition of KSFO to Flightbeam’s teasers of their rendition of the same airport. Threshold asked Salehi for comment on the identity of Peter113, and we were provided with a screenshot of the display name history for that user on AVSIM, which seems to indicate Peter113 was actually Pavel, frequent collaborator with Unishkov. Salehi continues on to his main point, saying that in September 2020, they identified and banned a user for distributing pirated files, specifically Flightbeam’s KPDX. Flightbeam achieved this by using a “tag” unique to the user’s scenery files, and checking it against the pirated files. That user was, according to Salehi, none other than Unishkov. They confirmed that it really was Unishkov by matching the email he put up on his website in his earlier days of flight sim development. Salehi says that they “discovered this information in July 2024, [and] we patiently awaited the developers’ decision to move on, hoping that the situation would dissipate”, but they are “now confronted with an egregious display of unprofessionalism and toxicity”. Umberto Colapicchioni, owner of FSDreamTeam, corroborated Salehi’s claims in a post on AVSIM, saying that Unishkov pirated products from them as well. Lars, founder of Contrail, added in the same forum thread that Unishkov was banned from Contrail for sharing a pirated copy of LatinVFR’s KMIA. ‍ Unishkov took to the AVSIM forums on Thursday to respond to these allegations, saying “I GUARANTEE THAT I HAVE NO RELATIONSHIP WITH THE PIRATE COMMUNITY AND HAVE NEVER HAD ANY RELATIONSHIP WITH THE PIRATE COMMUNITY!!!” He continues by decrying the actions of Salehi and others, claiming that they are “illegal accusations”, “defame[d] my honor and dignity”, and they “posted my personal data online without my consent, which is also illegal”. Unishkov ends his statement by defending his work, stating “I put my soul into every airport!!!”, and “I ask the author of the accusations to go to court to prove my guilt or to delete posts that contradict the law, contain slander, insults, and also to delete my personal data”.  Pavel (AmSim) also posted a response on his Facebook page defending Unishkov, claiming “the incident 4 years ago is not evidence of BMW's [Unishkov’s] involvement in the pirate community”. He also attacks the developers making the accusations, saying they “are trying to use dishonest methods of struggle [competition] against us”, and that the situation is “not at all about piracy (which does not really exist), but about the desire of competitors to kill our company”. ‍ In response to the claims made by Salehi, Lars, and Colapicchioni, multiple vendors of flight sim products pulled BMWorld and AmSim’s sceneries from their storefronts, including iniBuilds, Orbx, and SIMMARKET. iniBuilds announced on their forums and Discord server Thursday that they have pulled BMWorld’s products from their store temporarily, until “the situation is fully clarified and a definitive resolution is reached”, and that “these allegations,…touch on issues we take very seriously”. Orbx CEO Anna Cicognani stated in a forum post that “Orbx has decided to remove all BMW and BMW+AmSim products from its platforms due to a data protection breach”, and they are “actively communicating with the developer”. SIMMARKET posted on their Instagram announcing they have “temporarily suspended sales of all products from BMWorld”, due to “activities involving alleged intellectual property infringement”. All three said that existing BMWorld/AmSim customers will retain access to their products. ‍ This situation is still evolving, and Threshold is committed to keeping you up to date with all the latest developments, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pm2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Statement on MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pm2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67394c53db7a44e176e6bc13_1250410_20231128215337_1-88398891.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a statement on their Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 plans, including potential upgrade fees, the upcoming 777F, and future products. They claim to have been given access to the new platform, stating it’s a “spectacular platform” with a visual quality never seen before, which gets them excited about what is to come. While singing high praises for MSFS 2024, they are unsure how long it will take to convert their product lineup, let alone gauge the amount of work required. Hiccups with the new platform are expected, as they have faced with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, and they will be “forgotten in no time once the fixes roll out.” “The team at Asobo has incredible depth of skill and energy and they will come through”, concluded Randazzo. ‍ Most of their development team is already running the new simulator. However, they have been unable to prove cross-compatibility with their MSFS2020 lineup, which is said not to be a surprise to them, nor unexpected. In other words, they do not yet have a clear picture of the state of their products against the new platform. ‍ Compatibility-wise, Microsoft has been contacting PMDG to address minor issues with their 737 lineup, which Randazzo assumes has to do with their testing effort to ensure near-flawless cross-compatibility between the two platforms. ‍ From the release of MSFS 2024 onwards, their products will fall into three categories: MSFS2020 only, MSFS2020/24, and MSFS 2024 only. The former means the product won’t function in 2024, the middle will mean it will load in the new simulator, albeit without any 2024-specific features, and the latter means it will only work in the new platform (747-400 and 747 Classic Whale, for example). ‍ On whether their current product lineup will be updated to include MSFS 2024 features, Randazzo has said they plan on it, but they are still evaluating the SDK and how much work will need to be carried on for that to happen reasonably.  ‍ Their provided list sheds some light on which of their add-ons will get special treatment: the 737, 77W, and all future products. The DC-6, on the other hand, might not get upgraded at all.  ‍ While the 77W feature upgrade will be charged, Randazzo promises a small fee or none at all. The 737 lineup will get a modest upgrade charge, as it’s said to be receiving a significant upgrade. ‍The 777F, rumored to be released in late October, is waiting on MSFS 2024 for compatibility testing. Their current plan is to release it for both platforms at no extra charge, but the “option is on the table” to not release it for 2020 at all in exchange for greater features—and increased development time—and platform singularity. ‍ They will continue to support their MSFS 2020 product lineup, but their long-term strategy is to move all new development to the new simulator, meaning MSFS 2020 might not see any new releases. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on PMDG.com, ranging from $34.99 to $74.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrfs24</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrfs24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673bddf79fe0f69194d99625_MSFS2024_JPG-9de6e8972db1e3f8fc95-scaled.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Today is the day flight simmers around the world have been waiting for months to arrive. Microsoft has released its highly-anticipated follow up to their longest running, critically acclaimed franchise, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Developed in collaboration with French developer Asobo Studio, the new simulator includes many gamechanging features, and highly-requested community fixes from the previous version, in what Microsoft is calling “The Most Ambitious Flight Sim Ever”.  Headlining features include the all-new Career system, 3D ground textures, first-person mode, overhauled weather and physics engines, and more, adding realism to their “digital twin”. Microsoft also claims that they have drastically reduced install size for this release, which was a widespread complaint about MSFS 2020, to around 30 gigabytes, compared to MSFS 2020’s gargantuan 300 gigabyte install with all World Updates installed. This has been enabled through Microsoft’s full embrace of cloud streaming through their Azure servers, putting most of the simulator in the cloud, including the entire in-sim Marketplace. With FS24, Microsoft and Asobo have broken new ground by collaborating with many developers who previously were primarily third-party developers, such as Orbx and iniBuilds. Nowhere is this more apparent than in the aircraft category, with 14 different development teams working on base aircraft for the simulator. However, it’s not just aircraft that are getting all the love, base systems have also gotten new features with every vertical obstacle being added in, as well as an Electronic Flight Bag with Charts, being developed by Orbx and Working Title respectively. Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is available for purchase on both Steam and the MS Store, in four different editions, with Standard Edition on the low end, and Aviator Edition on the high end. The main differentiator between each edition is how many planes and handcrafted airports come as default, with the Standard Edition containing 70 default aircraft and 150 handcrafted airports, while the Aviator Edition contains 125 aircraft and 160 airports. (For a full breakdown, see our previous article about what each edition contains.) Standard Edition - $69.99 - Steam - MS Store Deluxe Edition - $99.99 - Steam - MS Store Premium Deluxe Edition - $139.99 - Steam - MS Store Aviator Edition - $199.99 - Steam - MS Store This release marks the turning of a new chapter in the flight simulation genre. With MSFS 2020 amassing 15 million players and with nearly 5,000 Marketplace creations over its lifetime, expectations are high for the new sim. The Threshold team are very excited about this new entrant into MSFS history and we will be sure to keep you all up to date with the latest news and high-quality reviews throughout this next chapter, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mamldi</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Video Addressing MSFS 2024 Launch Day Issues</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mamldi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673d4cab13e6f471151dafa2_Screenshot%202024-11-19%20at%208.21.31%E2%80%AFPM.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a video posted to their YouTube channel, Microsoft has released a launch day development update regarding the situation of the recently released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Hosted by Head of Microsoft Flight Simulator Jorg Neumann, Asobo CEO Sebastian Wloch, and Xbox Senior Community Manager Jayne Reynolds, the update comes as a response to many users who are experiencing issues while downloading the sim, such as software crashes, long download times, and missing default aircraft. Neumann starts off by stating that they “are really proud in what [sic] we’ve accomplished with the sim” and they knew “the excitement was high for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024”, but he acknowledges that they underestimated the extent of the excitement for the new sim and that it “has overwhelmed our infrastructure”. Wloch says that they “have been struggling for a few hours with one of our services” and explains that the root cause of the issues has been a cache overflow in their servers. He goes further into detail, saying when “they [Players] start, they are…asking a server for some data, and that server is going to catch [sic] it in a database…and that database is currently getting saturated”.  Wloch then describes what they have done to address the issue: “We’ve tried to restart the services, we’ve taken measures to throttle the number of people who can come in [download],...and it worked well during [sic] maybe half an hour or so and then all of a sudden, the cache collapsed again so we’re restarting…[and] trying to investigate”. ‍ Neumann continues by reassuring the community, acknowledging that they know “a lot of people are frustrated” but they “want to be as transparent and open as possible”, and adds that “the team is on it”. Finally, Reynolds concludes by thanking the community for all their feedback and that “We appreciate each and every one of you, and we’ll see you in the skies soon”. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777f24</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Status Update on MSFS 2024 Product Compatibility </title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777f24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67007455f9c93f4f4c4607ef_randy4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently provided a brief update on the compatibility of their product line with the newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and what to expect next from their projects. As they mentioned during the previous development update from a few days ago, PMDG ran into issues when testing their product lineup on the Developer Alpha build of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 that had been provided to them, leading to more questions than answers.  With the simulator now in everyone’s hands, PMDG is still unable to thoroughly verify the compatibility or lack thereof due to stability issues and access problems with the platform (which affected most day one/two players). They have reached a few conclusions: the 777 will not work in MSFS 2024 without an update, as changes were made to the simulator’s communications API, leading to memory allocation corruption and eventual instability. The 737 also ran into similar issues, albeit to a lesser extent due to its simplicity as far as communication APIs go. As of earlier today, both products are still under evaluation, but they have not achieved sufficient platform stability to do so efficiently. The DC-6, though, appears to work just fine when pasted into MSFS 2024’s community folder. While their original plan was to provide compatibility in time for the weekend, it appears that expectation is unrealistic, given all the issues they had properly evaluating compatibility. The new timeframe is now “some weeks” from now. There is even a level of uncertainty regarding whether they will be able to make it compatible at all, as they are unaware of the amount of work that will be required to make it a reality. The upcoming 777F will be released for MSFS 2020 after all, as the compatibility assessment has proven to be more of a hurdle than initially imagined. Yet, they are cautious because Asobo and not PMDG themselves promised straightforward compatibility between both simulators and so far, they have been unable to gauge that accurately. They must be sure of that compatibility before they launch the product under such expectations. Furthermore, PMDG judges it to be too early to determine when and if native 2024 features will be implemented in the 737 and 777, as they are still undergoing their evaluation process. PMDG’s aircraft lineup is available on their website, with products ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2she</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Sherburn-in-Elmet Airfield for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2she"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673f949e180b0aad8e876e0c_sher1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Sherburn-in-Elmet Airfield (EGCJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This airfield serves the town of Sherburn in Elmet in North Yorkshire, United Kingdom. The airfield dates back to the 1920s when the Yorkshire Aeroplane Club was established there. It attracted a substantial number of young folk from the region who would gather to watch airplanes take off and land.  A few years later, Sherburn Airfield became Airspeed Ltd's testing grounds for their first aircraft: a glider, the "Tern," launched by a car pulling a steel cable. It became an RAF station during World War 2, housing a naval torpedo aircraft factory.  In mid-42, the Airborne Forces Experimental Establishment was moved from RAF Ringway (near Manchester) to Sherburn and charged with developing the means to deploy allied airborne forces and supplies during operations. After the war, private pilots and aero clubs have used it for training and leisure. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airfield, with full-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR materials, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $8.44, requiring at least 19.44 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/savxpl</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/savxpl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673f99503343107741dffd02_hilton1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Fly2High has recently released its rendition of Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport (KSAV) for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. The airport serves Savannah, Georgia, and Hilton Head Island, South Carolina, with a yearly average of 3.9 million passengers. The airport was built in the early 1940s on a 600-acre piece of land near Cherokee Hill, with three 3600-foot runways covering all possible wind options. The US Army Air Corps soon took it over as a bomber and training base for B-24 bombers and fighter aircraft. It was temporarily named Chatham Airfield, and its infrastructure significantly improved during that short period. Post WW2, it was turned over to the Georgia Air National Guard and renamed Travis Field after a late local Brigadier General, victim of a fatal B-29 accident in California. A new airline terminal was built in 1958, and runway extension work followed in 1962, preparing the airport for the jet age. A brand new terminal was built in 1994, with eight gates and expansion possibilities. Five departure gates were dutifully added in 2007.  It won #1 Best Domestic Airport two years in a row (2021 and 2022) in Travel+Leisure World’s Best Awards. The method was a survey among the readers that took accessibility, shopping, check-in, restaurants, cleanliness, and many other factors into account. The airport’s domestic popularity was also reinforced by Condé Nast Traveler, which ranked it the best in the United States for three years in a row. It’s an operating base for Allegiant Air and served by American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed ground markings, custom taxiway signage, performance-friendly optimization, custom HDR lighting, PBR textures, custom 3D models, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.89, requiring at least 2.40 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gsxp24</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Updates GSX Pro with MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gsxp24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673f9d79fedbb7413cbe45e2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDreamTeam has recently launched an update for its GSX Pro add-on, ensuring compatibility with the newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This update introduces a range of new features and fixes, with the most significant improvement being its compatibility with MSFS 2024. Along with compatibility for the new simulator, the update introduces seated passengers for the FlyByWire A380, but currently only on the main deck. Additionally, it features a few fixes and new handling and catering operators. The updated GSX Pro can be installed via the FSDT Installer. To install it for MSFS 2024, select 2024 Steam/MS Store from the drop-down menu on the left side of the FSDT Installer. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siaban</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Bang Phra Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siaban"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673fa0e6530024a565ee4305_bang1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SiamFlight recently released their rendition of Bang Phra Airfield (VTBT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Due to its surrounding geography, this airfield is one of the most challenging in Thailand. Located about 3 kilometers east of Bang Phra, a small village in Thailand, the airfield is home to the Thai Flying Club, the country's first and oldest club. The club is highly committed to developing and promoting General Aviation in the area. With a mountain on one end and power lines obstructing the approach on the opposite end, Bang Phra is known as one of the trickiest airfields in Thailand. It requires great dexterity with airplane controls. The scenery accurately depicts the airfield, with custom ground textures, hangars, village landmarks, a custom windsock, custom night lighting, a sloped runway, high power tension lines, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $7.38, requiring at least 7.12 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf2024</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Update on MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673fe163ad892655e82bbbe2_jr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight recently updated the community regarding their plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and eventual upgrades to include the new features made possible with the newly released platform.  Their development team has begun evaluating their in-house aircraft in the release build, with promising results in terms of visuals and performance. They plan on bringing their fleet to MSFS 2024 as soon as possible. Asobo has addressed many of the compatibility issues previously found, and they have successfully completed full flights in their newly released RJ Professional, the most complex aircraft in their fleet. However, some compatibility issues still exist and will be worked on. Considering the sheer size of their MSFS fleet, consisting of nine airplanes, the porting process might take a while to complete. Still, Just Flight will keep everyone updated through regular development updates. They also remind users that until the official compatibility update is released, they will not offer support for adventurous users trying to run their 2020 builds in 2024.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/afl737</id>
    <title>Airfoillabs Publishes 737 MAX Development Updates </title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/afl737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674068dae54a24aec3f3888e_image-1731963660340.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airfoillabs has released a couple of development updates for their upcoming 737 MAX for X-Plane, just weeks after announcing it.  ‍ The first part of the update covered the progress of 3D development. The modelling team has fully finished the texturing of the upper overhead panel, with a focus on precise geometric accuracy and mechanical detail. The developers have also implemented a custom shader, which they claim has improved visual fidelity. Meanwhile, the flight systems have also received progress, as the engine performance and aerodynamic model have been polished to match real-life behaviour (a video of the flight model in action can be found here). An interesting part of the update is the progress made on the Electronic Flight Bag (EFB). Thanks to the new Web API available for X-Plane, the developers will be able to provide a highly functional EFB.  The last part dealt with display rendering. The previously mentioned custom shaders also enhanced the instrument displays. The displays that received development were the Primary Flight Display (PFD), Navigational Display (ND) and Engine Indication System. The video of the current state of displays can be seen here. As always, Threshold will keep you updated with all development updates and progress of AFL 737 MAX! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fir321</id>
    <title>FlightSimLabs Posts First A321 Video</title>
    <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fir321"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674229141bb7f09ce4fc9e6f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightSimLabs has recently released its first video showcasing the upcoming FlightSimLabs A321 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The video highlights the appearance of icing and demonstrates the de-icing process on the new aircraft. The team has also confirmed that the A321 will be compatible with both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and will offer a free upgrade for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The video and its descriptions provide a wealth of information about the icing and de-icing features of the aircraft. It will offer realistic environmental interactions in conjunction with the weather engine from Microsoft Flight Simulator. The short video showcases some of the enhanced immersion that the upcoming aircraft will feature. The video does not provide a specific release date but mentions "coming soon," which suggests that the aircraft's arrival is hopefully imminent. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/whale1</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/whale1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67428686aadfc99ec3353245_whale1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published a lengthy two-part development update regarding their plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the upcoming Boeing 777F, and their ongoing work on the 747 Classic (with pictures). The first part is very similar to their previous statement on their plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with their plan to rebuild their product line in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s SDK and feature all the new niceties still in place:  ‍ ‍ Their position regarding pure compatibility without the 2024 niceties is still the same. The compatibility claim made by Asobo didn’t prove to be true, with the airplanes not functioning as they should in the new simulator. They have been working together with Asobo to figure out a potential fix that would allow the straightforward drag-and-drop compatibility to work. ‍ The second part concerns their upcoming products (777F, 747 Classic) and further information on their issues with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s SDK. It lists some of the “blockers” that have been making their lives slightly harder and draws a parallel with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020’s initial period and its initial lack of development tooling.  ‍ The 777F remains under beta testing in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, with the latest beta build featuring small fixes, a completed simulation of the cargo deck lighting systems, operational controls of the cargo deck door, safety nets, and “other fun features within the main deck cargo area,” in Randazzo’s words. They have also included further integration with FSDT’s GSX, allowing the software to seamlessly manage their doors, entries, cargo loading, and unloading.  ‍ Their best-case scenario plan was to release it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 only if the release went well enough, which did not happen. Thus, they are moving ahead with the release for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020.  ‍ They anticipate another beta cycle, “likely earlier next week or the early following week,” and then “she will roll out of the hangar to support your cargo hauling adventures.” PMDG will let people know when they have the release date set. ‍ The work on the upcoming 747 Classic continues to roll forward, with code-side preparation for the 747-400 reaching an advanced stage of readiness. As the code is running within MSFS 2020 for now, they are beginning mapping changes that will be required to make it MSFS 2024 compatible, making for a “truly magnificent simulation of this airliner.” ‍ ‍ On the other hand, the 747-100 Classic Whale is shaping up nicely, with feature sets mapped up that will “open this product line up to a greater swath of users.” “After all, while navigating via fixes defined by their lat/lon positions was revolutionary back in 1971, it can be intimidating and confusing for folks who don’t understand how the process works or who might not be inclined to take the time to learn it just for their weekend simming experience”, justified Randazzo. Their 747 Classic will come with the CIVA triple INS system—fully modeled to a high degree of detail—with a built-in flight engineer ready to assist the user should they struggle with its sheer complexity. Hardcore pilots will have the option to handle it all by themselves if they so desire. In addition to the CIVA INS, they will also offer a relatively more modern option: a Honeywell FMS, which equipped many 747-100s later in their service cycle. ‍ They anticipate it will be the “most detailed classic airliner yet produced for desktop flight simulation.” ‍ PMDG’s lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fuf24c</id>
    <title>Fenix Updates A320 Series for MSFS24 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fuf24c"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674369b7a42c6b89513c8803_livery_6.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Developers at Fenix Simulations have recently updated their Airbus A320 series, originally developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, to bring compatibility with the newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, among other updates. In a blog post on their website, Fenix founder and director Aamir Thacker announces the update, as well as their plans for MSFS 2024. Thacker says that this new update is “not simply the 2020 version ported”, and that they “rebuilt the package with the 2024 SDK…[and] have taken advantage of several of the new features present in 2024”. This includes adding experimental support for 4x SimRate, changes to support MSFS 2024 walkaround mode, and more. The update also brings improvements to the aircraft itself, with a rebuilt airmass temperature simulation, rewritten fuel flow and estimated fuel onboard (EFOB) math, and various improvements to the flight model. Thacker provides a disclaimer that the support for MSFS 2024 is “entirely experimental at this stage and DO NOT consider 2024 compatibility an ‘advertised’ feature” due to MSFS 2024 being unstable, and they “do not want to begin taking customers’ money on this basis while being unable to guarantee a smooth experience”. He continues to say that Fenix “will not be considering refund requests on the basis of MSFS 2024 experiences/issues”, and they “will not be accepting customer support tickets in the 2024 environment at this time”. Additionally, Thacker mentions that they know of certain issues with the aircraft in MSFS 2024, but most of them are related to simulator-level issues which are not necessarily specific to the A320 series. Finally, Thacker adds that Fenix is not yet done with MSFS 2024, stating that “Once we’ve all had more time with the new platform and a few of the bigger issues are resolved, we’ll be back to really sink our teeth into new items”. The full changelog can be found in their blog post. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews! Join our Discord and follow us on social media to never miss another article!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
