<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-04-08T18:25:05.930067+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwa380</id>
    <title>X-Works announces A380 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwa380"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660db307cb6583ed3c852670_A380_-_2024-03-28_17.05.20.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Works, a freeware development group known for mods for default A330 in X-Plane 12 announced on April 1st that they are developing A380 for X-Plane. Many were puzzled if this was just a joke or a real project, so we decided to investigate a bit… ‍ A short conversation with the main developer of this project solved this interesting April Fools’ enigma. We are glad to announce that the X-Works A380 mod is indeed - a real project! ‍ Bru_aviationspotter, one of two main developers in this project was kind enough to answer some of our questions, and provide us with more previews of A380! ‍ What is your estimation for the release date? “We have come a long way with the exterior model but we certainly have a long way ahead so don’t expect it to be released in the near future. Looking at other developers a plane is not made within a few months or a year but because it’s a complicated plane and my first time that I make a plane from scratch this will take longer.” How far has the plane progressed? “I made a little progress chart where you can see what has been done and what needs to happen or how far we are in working on that part of the plane.” What inspired you to start this project? “I wanted an A380 in XP for a long time, and when I realised that no other developer wanted to work on it, I decided to make it myself.” ‍ As you can see in the screenshots, the fuselage is nearly done, and developers are currently in the modelling phase, working on the landing gear to be precise. We wish X-Works success in further developing! As always, Threshold will keep you updated with the progress of A380. ‍ What do you think about this project? Are you excited about it? Let us know in the comments! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ricaxo</id>
    <title>Axonos Announces Richmond International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ricaxo"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660eaad9ee08b24d3635dec4_ric1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Axonos has recently announced the development and imminent release of Richmond International Airport (KRIC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Sandston, Virginia, with a yearly average of 4.7 million passengers, making it the busiest in Central Virginia and third-busiest in the state, only behind Washington Reagan and Washington Dulles. Its history dates back to 1927 when it was dedicated as Richard Evelyn Byrd Flying Field in honor of Richard E. Byrd, brother of the governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia.  A terminal building was built in 1950, designed by Marcellus Wright and Son. Expansion work, including the current passenger concourses, was conducted between 1968 and 1970. The early 2000s saw impressive growth figures, leading to a complete redesign of the terminal, which added ten gates, extra parking spaces, and a new air control tower. It also included a complete revamp of the terminal building and the construction of a central utility plant. The two-year project was concluded in 2007. It was expanded again in 2018, two years after it recorded its second highest yearly passenger volume, with the gate count going from 22 to 30. It was concluded three years later, in 2021. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, detailed 3D modeling, static aircraft (optional), custom jetways, custom ground clutter, realistic night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, and a custom GSX profile. ‍ It’s set to release on Saturday (06/04) for $14.99. Refer to their store for further information and screenshots. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ap124</id>
    <title>Flight Sim April Fools Round Up 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ap124"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660ebbcdd9f6df5eaf3c6cf6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. April Fools' Day was a few days ago, and it's a day of jokes and giggles where developers break out of their professional skin and come up with something funny for the community to enjoy. It's a day of tradition, and every year we get something fun to laugh about. Now that we’ve given enough time for the jokes to go through the system, let's recap what April Fools' Day has brought the flight simming community in 2024. IniBuilds has released the iniR24 for MSFS, a state-of-the-art Formula 1 car that can be driven around the Yas Marina Circuit. Flight simming has now turned into a racing sim, so put on your gloves and get out on track with the new iniR24. Aeroplane Heaven has announced the A/47/10 THUNDERWARTHOG, a new and interesting plane for MSFS. Although we don't have many details about it, the plane has two turboprop engines at the back, and we can't wait to soar the virtual skies with it. Parallel 42 has released the ChasePlane Professional 4K HDR for MSFS, a convincing store page with many features like custom views, cinematics, turbulence effects, and more. However, the Buy Now button reveals the truth that ChasePlane for MSFS is not yet released, and they are dependent on Microsoft to change some things before it can become a reality. FSNews has announced FSNews Australia, a new website that is friendly to Aussies and the rest of the world. The whole website is turned upside down, and it's time for Australia to log on and finally enjoy it just like the rest of the world has done for a while. FlyJSim has announced the "Too Real" update for their upcoming 727 and 732 for X-Plane 12, which includes features like Door Plug Roulette, Maintenance Mayhem, and Random Flat Tires to push the boundaries of realism in flight simming. Got Friends has released the Paddle Wheeler for MSFS, a new aquatic bike that makes it easier to explore the seas within MSFS. MK Studios has announced a drastic change in their scenery development, with new scientific data showing that customers prioritize interior over exterior within a scenery. Therefore, MK Studios has decided to no longer consider the exterior as crucial. Flight Simulator 2024's aircraft list has been announced on Facebook, including planes like the "Airsus A320neo V3" and the "Belong 717-200" for the Ultra version of the sim. SoFly has released Dinosaurs for MSFS, allowing users to experience different types of dinosaurs and race around a dino-themed rally course. Toliss has announced a new add-on for X-Plane, the Handley Page H.P.42, which boasts features such as detailed dead reckoning navigation, top-notch electro-mechanical systems, and custom sounds. Mango Studios has also announced a sound pack for the new Toliss Handley Page H.P.42. FlyByWire shows a fine-tuned wing flex system on their A380. The new system will show how the real A380 acquires lift due to the realism of the new fine-tuned system. We hope you enjoyed these April Fools’ Day entries by the flight sim community.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news (and jokes), stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsogig</id>
    <title>FSoares Announces Galeão International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsogig"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660ec874e3bafc1ab9d6a1d4_galea1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSoares has recently announced the development of Rio de Janeiro/Galeão International Airport (SBGL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main airport serving Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with a yearly average of 7.9 million passengers. ‍ It was opened in 1952 on top of a pre-existing Brazilian Air Force base that ended up being utilized by international long-haulers, which were too heavy and too large for SBRJ’s (Rio’s domestic airport) 1300m runway. With the ever-increasing international demand, they finally built a passenger terminal, which was progressively expanded until 1977. ‍ A new terminal building was opened that year, with all the scheduled passenger traffic transferred there. It’s still in use today as Terminal 1. ‍ Terminal 1 was first renovated in 1991 in preparation for the United Nations Earth Summit (held in 1992), with its annual capacity increased to 7.5 million passengers. Eight years later, Terminal 2 was opened, with 24 jetways and also being able to handle up to 7.5 million passengers yearly. ‍ With the imminence of the World Cup and the Olympic Games, in 2014 and 2016, respectively, Infraero (the airport’s former manager) unveiled a $431 million upgrade and expansion plan for Galeão, including the renovation of Terminal 1, the completion of Terminal 2, and expanding the parking lots. The new concessionary later revised the plans and decided to include a new pier with 26 jetways, a new apron for 97 aircraft, and 2640 car parking spaces. The $400 million sum quickly jumped to $800 million instead. ‍ Aerolíneas Argentinas, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, Azul, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Flybondi, Gol, Iberia, ITA Airways, JetSmart Argentina, JetSmart Chile, KLM, Latam Brasil, Latam Chile, Latam Peru, Lufthansa, Paranair, Sky Airlines, TAP, United Airlines, and Voepass serve it. ‍ There’s no information on features, pricing, or release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arw747</id>
    <title>arwasairl &amp; FSMuseum Showcase Progress on Boeing 747 Classic’s Flight Deck for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arw747"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660ecf47b7bf4cf813d76df2_7471.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSMuseum’s 747 Classic, initially meant for Flight Simulator 2004, appears to be getting a Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version instead, with a custom 3D flight deck modeled by arwasairl. The incomplete renders of the flight deck reflect a 747-200B with Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D-7R4G2 engines, FFRATS, Triple autopilot, Dial gauges, US weights with metric temperatures, and a Kollsman altimeter. Other variants are planned, including dual autopilot, taped displays, corrected engine scales, etc., and will be developed after the current variant is fully completed.  The 747 Classic project was first announced in 2020, and had been in development for six years prior, featuring a fully featured FDE with realistic damping, control, stability, and mach effects, and fine-tuned according to Boeing and NASA documents for all phases of flight. The load station data is also directly from Boeing weight and balance documents, with exact locations for MAC, LEMAC, Cargo, PAX, fuel tanks, and landing gear (including suspension).  It also features an accurate simulation of the electrical and fuel systems, working in accordance with Boeing specifications with correct loads and transfer rates.  ‍ However, it’s important to note that the feature list reflected the project for Flight Simulator 2004, meaning things could have changed since then. ‍ Refer to FSMuseum’s original thread for further information on the project. Arwasairl’s cockpit previews are available here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ltn101</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates London Luton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ltn101"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6606f1e13e5286d1e071ebf1_luton1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated their newly released rendition of London Luton Airport (EGGW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing bugs and adding a few 3D models. Update 1.0.1, the first so far, adds four new models to the scenery: Signature Flight Support’s new interior, Marriott Hotel, Hotel Ibis, a Vauxhall dealership, and the main terminal model underwent slight corrections. The list of overall fixes includes taxiway and terrain corrections, ground marking changes, fencing adjustments, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Added/updated models: Fixed: The scenery is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.91, requiring at least 5.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vpikcg</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases Cartagena Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vpikcg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660f8a153db79e2540008508_skcg1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. V Pilot Designs has recently released the upgraded version of their Rafael Nuñez Airport (SKCG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Cartagena, Colombia, with a yearly average of 7.2 million passengers. It was built in 1946 as Crespo Air Field, with TACA Colombia being the first airline to serve the city, albeit very briefly, as they went under a year later, with LANSA taking the remaining slots. ‍ By 1979, the airport averaged around 99 flights a week, which was not enough in terms of touristic volume for the local hotels, leading to pressure for an airport redevelopment in 1982: a new passenger terminal and a runway extension, allowing for bigger aircraft. It is now the fourth busiest airport in the country. It’s a hub for Avianca and served by Air Century, American Airlines, Arajet, Avianca Costa Rica, Clic, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Edelweiss Air, JetBlue, KLM, Latam Colombia, Latam Peru, Spirit, Wingo. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed models, PBR materials, custom lighting, custom POIs (points of interest), and more. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $16.99. V1 owners are eligible for a discounted rate by buying the “SKCG V1 Improvement” package.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/smvtsg</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Krabi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/smvtsg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610758b3befae569e16a4fc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released its latest project for MSFS - Krabi Airport (VTSG). The international airport serves the Thai city of Krabi and accommodates over 2.3 million passengers annually.  Located in southern Thailand, the airport was opened in 1999 and has witnessed a steady increase in passenger traffic since then. In 2016, the airport received funding for expanding its facilities, including a new terminal and renovating existing infrastructure. Although a further expansion was planned in 2019, it was subsequently cancelled due to space constraints and the city's expansion. Instead, a new alternative airport has been proposed. Located 11.5 km (roughly 7.15 mi) from the city center, Krabi Airport is the operating base for Thai AirAsia and features a range of airlines such as Bangkok Airways, Flydubai, Scoot, and seasonally TUI Airways. It serves a variety of destinations, ranging from international destinations like Copenhagen or Dubai to regional destinations like Bangkok. The new scenery for Krabi Airport includes various features such as Custom Realistic Terminal Building, Realistic Parking Area, Realistic Building in Airport Area, and Custom Jetways. The scenery requires 1.4 GB of disk space and is available on SimMarket for roughly $14.77.  If you're interested in the latest flight simulation news, stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfbv2a</id>
    <title>Just Flight 146 Professional V2 Now Available</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfbv2a"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610772030b8e4f762bdf1d0_146%20V2%203.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has just released a v2 update for BAe 146 Professional. This major free update will provide a custom-coded UNS-1, a new passenger boarding and cargo loading system controlled by the EFB, new cabin models, a cabin boarding music player, interactive yoke-mounted checklists, and clipboard paper charts. Along with these new features, the update will bring three new liveries for the -200 and -300 variants, and many bug fixes and improvements.   The full changelog can be found here. ‍ Version 2 will also feature new manuals for EFB, UNS-1, and 146 Professional Operations Manual.  146 Professional is currently on Spring Sale, at a 25% discount. You can buy it here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nddaag</id>
    <title>NetDesign Releases Algiers Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nddaag"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610787fe59764d458367c79_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NetDesign has recently released its version of Houari Boumediene Airport (DAAG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport has a yearly capacity of around 12 million passengers and serves Algiers, the capital of Algeria. Located roughly 16.9 km (10.5 mi) southeast of Algiers, the international airport was opened 100 years ago in 1924. During World War II, the airport was seized by the Allies and used by the US Air Force. After the war, the airport has expanded and grown over time to become what it is today. It is the hub for Air Algérie and Tassili Airlines and is served by a variety of airlines, including British Airways, Emirates, and Transavia, offering a multitude of destinations worldwide, such as London, Beijing, Dubai, and Montreal. Additionally, Algiers Airport has a significant cargo operation with Air Algérie Cargo, Emirates SkyCargo, Swiftair, and Turkish Cargo. The scenery includes four bespoke terminals, various buildings such as train stations and hotels, high-quality static aircraft, high technical accuracy, high-resolution PBR textures, multiple layers of textures for dirt, wear and tear, interiors, AI traffic, and detailed night lighting. Moreover, the scenery comes with custom landmarks for the city of Algiers. Algiers Airport requires 3.16GB of storage and is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $25.60. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avdufr</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Publishes Frankfurt Airport Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avdufr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66107971ce8289af59130fe2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Software has shared an update about the development of the Frankfurt International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. As announced in December, the airport will be available as a free download, and the developer has been working hard to ensure that it meets the highest standards. While the community has been patiently waiting for the release, the developer has now shared further information about the project. The team has been busy adapting to the new simulator, as they are used to working with X-Plane. Although this has slowed down the pace of the project, the team has been working hard on beta testing. The beta testers have been doing an excellent job, and the team has been fixing bugs and adding new features based on their feedback.  They have shared several images that showcase the airport buildings, ground details, interior, and ground equipment. These images give a glimpse into the level of detail that the team has put into the project.  A couple of new features were added to the list, including fully functional VDGSs, fully operational jetways, more land-side vehicles, ground markings, and animations. Their libraries are also constantly being updated. ‍ At the moment, beta testing is ongoing, and the team is working hard to ensure that the airport is as polished as possible. Once the airport is ready, it will be available as a free download for the Microsoft Flight Simulator community. We will let you know once new information is available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777046</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New 737/777 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777046"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610eb3ab25734dbc3450d08_777apr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published another development update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, covering a new 737 lineup update to mitigate a camera issue and a couple of new 777 flight deck previews. The fixes are related to a mechanism within the 737 that handles the viewpoint when data is entered into the tablet. They found out that under certain conditions, the camera could get stuck during that process, making it seem as if the simulator is frozen, while it is, in fact, just the camera acting up. After a lot of research and replication, their tablet team engineered a fix and pushed the update right away, which is already available via the PMDG Operations Center. The update might take a while to appear on the marketplace as they are still completing their intake process on the previous build.  Randazzo has shared three new images of the upcoming 777-300ER flight deck, emphasizing that it does not represent the final product and is merely a work in progress.  It demonstrates some of the "wear and tear" they mentioned during the previous (Jokeless April Fools) development update, with high-touch areas being "polished" by oily fingertips after twelve years of heavy usage. ‍ While the surveyed airplane is, in fact, relatively old, it was treated with care, meaning the wear isn't as accentuated as one could imagine, being mostly natural wear that inadvertently happens regardless of the nature of the usage. ‍ They have also included dust and crumbs, which accurately represent an airplane that has been actively used for so long.  ‍ PMDG also confirms it will be possible to open the cockpit door and wander around the cabin, with dynamic sounds that will change according to your position in the airplane. Nocturnal screenshots were taken but discarded because they showed slight artifacting upon compression, according to Randazzo, which also drew an interesting parallel with taking night photos of your dog and how the picture doesn't have the same personality as they do in person. "Dark scenes in MSFS are the same way. In person they look spectacular, but in still images they often look artifacted and cloudy", concluded Robert. The movable lights on the flight deck can be moved about and pointed wherever one wants, like their 737s.  The PMDG 737 lineup is available in their store, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99. The upcoming 777-300ER's pricing and release date are yet to be revealed. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/richax</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Richmond International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/richax"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660eaaf2eb399ea2b2870b42_ric4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Axonos has recently released their rendition of Richmond International Airport (KRIC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Sandston, Virginia, and has a yearly average of 4.7 million passengers, making it the busiest in Central Virginia and third-busiest in the state, only behind Washington Reagan and Washington Dulles. Its history dates back to 1927 when it was dedicated as Richard Evelyn Byrd Flying Field in honor of Richard E. Byrd, brother of the governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia.  A terminal building designed by Marcellus Wright and Son was built in 1950. Expansion work, including the current passenger concourses, was conducted between 1968 and 1970. The early 2000s saw impressive growth figures, leading to a complete redesign of the terminal, which added ten gates, extra parking spaces, and a new air control tower. It also included a complete revamp of the terminal building and the construction of a central utility plant. The two-year project was concluded in 2007. It was expanded again in 2018, two years after it recorded its second-highest yearly passenger volume, with the gate count going from 22 to 30. It was concluded three years later, in 2021. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, detailed 3D modeling, static aircraft (optional), custom jetways, custom ground clutter, realistic night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, and a custom GSX profile. ‍ It’s available in their store and OrbxDirect for $14.99 and $16.45, respectively. To install the scenery, you need at least 1.04 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phehle</id>
    <title>Papa Hotel Releases Lelystad Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phehle"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6612158bb42c8a2c3c32c4d0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Papa Hotel has recently released Lelystad Airport (EHLE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the Dutch province of Flevoland, Lelystad Airport is the second busiest airport in terms of flight movements in the Netherlands with an average of 80,000 aircraft movements per year, which also makes it the busiest General Aviation airport in the country. Lelystad Airport was originally established in 1973 to cater to General Aviation. The runway was paved in 1981 and extended in 1993. In 2015, the airport was given the green light to adapt for holiday and leisure air traffic, with a completion date initially set for 2018. However, the opening of the airport for commercial traffic has been delayed multiple times by the Dutch cabinet in The Hague. Despite not being open for commercial traffic, Lelystad Airport is still being utilized by several flight schools and clubs. Moreover, it is also home to the Luchtvaartmuseum Aviodrome, which hosts the famous FSWeekend. The scenery features a high-quality and accurate rendering of Lelystad Airport, high-resolution PBR textures, ortho imagery, a detailed rendition of Aviodrome and its exhibitions, a custom car pack, custom 3D animated objects, and much more. The airport requires 6.84GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for $16.22USD. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdivj</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases Capitán Vicente Almandos Almonacid Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdivj"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66121f6326eb03e88c579344_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Colombian Virtual Design has recently released its version of Capitán Vicente Almandos Almonacid Airport (SANL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This airport, located in the Argentinian city of La Rioja, serves around 63,000 people annually. The airport of La Rioja opened in 1948, and its first terminal was built three years later, in 1951. In 1969, the airport's grass runway was replaced with a new asphalt runway, which is still in use today. In 1978, a new passenger terminal and car parking were added, and the terminal had air conditioning installed in 1990. The airport has two domestic destinations, San Fernando del Valle de Catama and the capital of Argentina, Buenos Aires, operated by the airline Aerolineas Argentinas. The scenery includes various features, such as an accurate rendition of the airport, a custom terminal, and a realistic ground layout, and it is performance-friendly for the simulator. The airport requires 55MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for $7.58USD. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsa064</id>
    <title>FSA Releases FlightSimExpo 2024’s Schedule &amp; Activities</title>
    <updated>2024-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsa064"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6613b4df36f307518a6852df_2019_6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Flight Simulation Association (FSA) recently released the schedule and activities for FlightSimExpo 2024, which will take place between June 21 and 23 in Las Vegas. The event will feature developer announcements, panel discussions, community-inspired seminars, and more. The event kicks off on Friday (June 21) with #FSExpoFriday, consisting of a series of announcements and new product reveals, with more than fifteen presentations from developers. Then, the weekend seminar series will cover RNAV approaches, scenery design, online networks, combat and helicopter simulation, a live PC build on stage, and more. The seminars were sourced from the community and selected by the vote of the attendees. They will take place in Rio Las Vegas’ Brasilia room and on the FSElite stage in the exhibit hall. The organizer - Evan Reiter - ensures there’s absolutely something for everyone in their 2024 seminar schedule, regardless of their level of experience with flight simulation. The list of paid and free activities includes a tour of the Las Vegas Air Traffic Control Tower, museum visits, a night out on the town, on-site workshops, and live shows at the Rio. Further information about the activities can be found here. ‍ Twelve new partners were confirmed since the initial reveal in late March: Beta Technologies, The Pilot Club, Hyperion Sim, Thrustmaster, Redbird Flight Simulations, BeyondATC, Vyral LLC, Yawman, National STOL Series, Somnium Space, FlyVirtual.net, and FlyInside. Prospective exhibitors can visit this page for further info. Registration is available online at their official website. Attendees are encouraged to book discounted hotel rooms before they sell out. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
