<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-08-06T18:39:54.980675+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxbfu</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases “Big Fenix Update” for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxbfu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6887a3b2db6f22ef4f786a4f_videoframe_356352%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations today released the long‑anticipated, aptly nicknamed “Big Fenix Update”, a sweeping overhaul of the entire A320 family, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. The update delivers full MSFS 2024 support, major flight-model enhancements, and a range of system, livery, art, and EFB improvements. The update introduces full FS2024‑native modular SimObject support and rendering updates, along with new engine models, as well as the new A319 Sharklet variant, with custom performance data. The flight deck has been remodelled and retextured for MSFS 2024, complete with reworked display rendering, new soundsets, and a revamped livery manager featuring dozens of new liveries. Landing dynamics and fly‑by‑wire responsiveness have been retuned, with ground law, elevator deflection, AoA protection and αMAX handling improved across all variants. Flex temp unlatching logic, OP CLB/DES behaviour, and Flight Director pitch response in normal flight have all been refined. Performance has also been improved through reduced CPU load and optimised display rendering. A new LOD-system has also been implemented for all models, bringing further optimization. Flight model enhancements focus on improved ground‑law behaviour, AoA protection, and refined handling characteristics across all variants. Autopilot pitch response, flex temp logic, and Open Climb/Descent behaviour have also been reworked. Furthermore, Wingflex has also seen further improvement. The update introduces full support for MSFS 2024’s walkaround mode, with interactive cargo doors, chocks, power panels, engine fanblades and refuelling controls. Automatic connection of stairs and door opening on spawn-in has been added. New configuration options in the EFB allow control over ADIRS type, ACP style and ISIS display preferences. The update also brings support for the MSFS weather-radar, which is now fully implemented, within simulator limitations. Furthermore, the update includes various visual upgrades such as new cabin lighting, a new native iridescent windshield material, microscratches and refined glass decals for MSFS 2024. New sounds have been added to doors, cooling fans and avionics contactors, amongst others. A completely new IAE engine sound set is also included, with windmilling effects.  Walkaround mode now supports inside‑outside sound transitions and even avatar walking noises, though collisions may still cause occasional jitter. A brand‑new native EFB chart app is featured, with LIDO support and an option to switch between simulator and Navigraph sources. Pilot Brief PDF viewing, custom refuelling rates, take‑off performance tools with ACT count, chart annotations and automatic switching of weight units when importing from SimBrief are included. The EFB also now works in walkaround-mode.  For a further deep dive into flight model and fly‑by‑wire behaviour, an unlisted video on Fenix’s official YouTube channel offers detailed insight into control input processing and control surface responses.  You can watch it here. The full changelog for the update follows below: Avionics and Systems Art and Sound EFB Flight and Engine Models For all the latest in flight simulation news, stay up to date on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fslneo310</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo &amp; neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fslneo310"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68540e8ed866ddc50457ee02_fslneo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs recently issued a new experimental update to their A321ceo and ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update focuses on increasing stability, improving visual performance, and improving the braking distance, among other things. Update v11.0.1.310 is a small interim update that brings further improvements to performance, improves stability by mitigating a problem with the TCAS that causes CTDs, and fixes a typographical error in the aircraft.cfg that would allow the plane to be used as AI traffic, hindering performance. They have also made further tweaks to the handling, fine-tuned the autobrake distance, and prevented the brakes from “grabbing” on touchdown under some specific circumstances. Furthermore, the update also extends compatibility with hardware such as overheads, pedestals, and more that can be used with Mobiflight. ‍ The complete changelog follows below: FMGC: BSCU: Systems Improvements: The developers have also announced they will improve the thrust and drag models for the LEAP engines. They will bring a more accurate thrust output across altitude and mach ranges and refined drag behavior to better reflect real-world figures in terms of overall performance and fuel burn. These improvements are based on deeper performance data analysis and internal validation work they have been doing for the past couple of weeks. The new changes are expected to roll out in an interim update next week. The A321ceo and neo are available in their store for $69.95 each. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2acomanche165</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2acomanche165"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665ba18298e4f651ac834e3a_comanche.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently rolled out an update to their Accu-Sim Piper Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, correcting “a few niggles that have crept in”. Update 1.6.5 swaps the Pilot and Co-Pilot, fixes broken 3rd party GPS units when additional liveries are selected, wind direction is reported in relation to the true north on the tablet, and the GTN 750 configuration was changed to prevent runaway trim situations. They had to hold back sending the previous update to other storefronts until this issue was fixed. With that out of the way, they have now submitted it to all third parties for intake. The add-on is available in their store for $37.49 (discounted price).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilca</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilca"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688a7a3e6e25861a4677a97b_videoframe_18336.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has announced its upcoming scenery release of Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024. The product aims to provide a comprehensive and performance-optimised recreation of Cyprus’s busiest airport, featuring an up-to-date recreation of the popular holiday destination. Located on the island’s southern coast, Larnaca Airport functions as a key gateway for both regional and international travel. The scenery features hand-made ground textures, dynamic lighting, a fully modelled terminal building, with interior detailing, and a complete set of custom buildings and airport signage. The layout represents the real-world operation as of 2025. Key features of the scenery include high-resolution textures in PBR, bespoke jetways, accurate foliage placement, and clutter models, to reflect the airport's current operational atmosphere. The package also comes with a custom GSX profile. The scenery uses Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s updated SDK and includes optimised LODs to ensure broad hardware compatibility. The product will be available for purchase soon through iniBuilds at £9.99, excluding sales tax. Be sure to stay updated on Threshold for all the latest in flight simulation! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwpnc1</id>
    <title>RW Profiles Releases Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwpnc1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688a81f555f9e6f2f1e79a82_videoframe_110467%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. RW Profiles has released its rendition of Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020 and 2024, following the developer’s announcement last week.  Located in the northeast of England, Newcastle International Airport handled over five million passengers in 2024, with connections to more than 80 destinations across Europe, North America, and the Middle East.  The package includes hand-crafted ground textures, a fully modelled terminal with interior, and an up-to-date airfield layout. Landside areas have also been recreated in high fidelity, alongside custom signage, static aircraft, accurate clutter and ground service equipment. Further features include animated jetways, a custom GSX profile, and dynamic lighting for runways, taxiways, and the apron. The general aviation area is fully modelled, with a detailed FBO interior. You can also customise performance through included configuration options that allow for disabling specific scenery elements, such as the terminal interior. The full feature list follows below: Newcastle International Airport is available now through RW Profiles, for £12.99, excluding sales tax. Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for all the latest in flight simulation! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a096</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a096"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688acadadc666ae7a637df33_gps600.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing multiple fixes, new GPS options, and more. Update v0.9.6 brings more fixes to their early access airplane, cross-fill support for multiple GPS layouts, a new dirt layer (dust), and more. The complete changelog follows below: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrebhx2024</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases Birmingham Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrebhx2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688cb3c6813a386cef7a159b_bhx1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently released their rendition of Birmingham Airport (EGBB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the West Midlands in the United Kingdom and has a yearly average of 12.8 million passengers, making it the seventh busiest in the Country. The idea for an airport in Birmingham was first conceived in 1928, and a committee was created shortly after to research possible locations to start building. After much deliberation, Elmdon was deemed the best of the bunch, but the project soon went back to the drawing board due to the Great Depression. It wasn’t until 1933 that works resumed, with a new committee formed to oversee its construction. Before taking any steps, though, the newly formed committee went on a research trip to multiple successful airports in Europe, such as Schiphol (Amsterdam), Berlin (Tempelhof), Paris (Orly), Brussels, and London.  By January 1935, they had finally approached a company—Norman and Dawbarn—to advise on the construction and help design the airport as lead architects. Groundwork started in 1936, after the government allowed the airport’s development. ‍ A year later, in 1937, Norman and Dawbarn were authorized to begin drawing the airport’s project, the undertaking of which took 6 months to reach completion. It was not until October 1937 that the construction of the airport’s buildings would start, costing around 360,000 pounds. Prime Minister Neville Chamberlain opened the airport in July 1939 as Elmdon Airport. The terminal featured a modern (for late 30s standards) art deco design with an integrated control tower and was the airport’s main terminal until 1984.  ‍ The airport was requisitioned by the Air Ministry to be used by both the Royal Air Force and the Royal Navy as RAF Elmdon during World War 2. The military “occupation” replaced the original grass runways with two hard runways, 753 meters in length and 1,271 meters in length, respectively.  It was used as a testbed for Avro Lancasters and Stirling bombers manufactured in northeast Worcestershire. These bombers were transported via land to Elmdon because their local airport didn’t have a long enough runway. ‍ On July 8, 1946, the airport, which was celebrating its 7th anniversary, was reopened for civilian use, albeit still government-controlled. ‍ Scheduled services started in 1949 with British European Airways, flying passengers to Paris. Over the years, the airline eventually expanded its network to Zürich, Düsseldorf, Palma, Amsterdam, and Barcelona. In the early 1960s, they built a new terminal to handle international traffic and extended the main runway to 2.2 km, allowing the airport to handle larger turboprop aircraft and jetliners. ‍ By the beginning of the 1970s, Birmingham Airport was already reaching a million passengers per year, significantly congesting their subpar terminal infrastructure. In the 1980s, BHX became home to the world’s first commercial maglev system, a train levitated by magnets. This system ran for nearly 10 years but eventually faced discontinuation due to unreliability. It was replaced by a cable-hauled system in 2003. ‍ In late 2007, the airport’s administration devised a development plan for Birmingham called “Towards 2030: Planning a Sustainable Future for Air Transport in the Midlands.” The plan included changes to the terminals, alterations to the airfield layout, and infrastructure improvements. Unexpectedly, environmentalists and locals complained, as they didn’t want the construction of a second parallel runway.  The original plan—now canceled—could have created up to 250,000 jobs in the area, made the airport handle up to 70 million passengers annually, and led to around 500,000 aircraft movements in total. ‍ In 2008, the shorter runway (06/24) was decommissioned due to its length and noise impact. Instead, it became a taxiway, allowing the expansion of the apron.  ‍ Construction work on the new 3-storey International Pier kicked off in June of that same year, taking a bit more than a year to complete. Now, Birmingham Airport was fully compatible with the Airbus A380, which visited the airport during its 70th birthday. It was the first commercial service of the A380 in the United Kingdom that was not bound to London Heathrow. ‍ In 2010, it was announced that they would merge Terminal 1 and 2 into a single building and change the name from Birmingham International Airport to Birmingham Airport. They figured this could help create a new corporate identity that would better reflect their current position in the market and attract more people to fly from it. Research showed that while 8 million people lived within an hour of the airport, only 40% of them used it.  ‍ A new control tower was built in 2011, ultimately replacing the original one built in 1939. The plans for extending the main runway, originally submitted in 2008, were approved a year later, but the work was only completed in 2014, two years after their original target, which was the 2012 London Olympics.  ‍ In late 2016, 100 million pounds were invested in building a new baggage handling system and two new car parks. ‍ It’s an operating base for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways, and served by Aer Lingus, Air France, Air India, Aurigny, Brussels Airlines, Corendon Airlines, Emirates, Eurowings, KLM, Loganair, Lufthansa, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, SunExpress, Swiss International Air Lines, Turkish Airlines, Vueling, and WizzAir. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout representing its finished status in 2026, 25,000 square meters of explorable interiors (2024-only), custom terraforming, animated people, a custom GSX profile, an animated monorail, and much more. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $22.78, requiring at least 3.42 GB of free hard disk space to install. You can read our product review here. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniegcc</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Manchester International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniegcc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688d737c2fd634e6fa1ecb48_manchesterr.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently announced their intent to develop a rendition of Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the third busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 23.3 million passengers. ‍ Construction work began in 1935, and the airport was partially operating by 1937 (the official conclusion happened a year later). KLM was the first airline to launch scheduled commercial flights to the newly opened airport in 1938. ‍ It was converted into an RAF base during WW2 and played an essential role in military aircraft production and parachutist training. ‍ The post-war period saw its return as a commercial airport, with rapid growth during the 50s and 60s, where it eventually managed to be Britain's second busiest airport after London Heathrow. ‍ The airport was heavily expanded in the 1980s and 90s to keep up with the exponential growth figures, eventually leading to the millionth passenger in a month mark in 1987. Plans for a new terminal were put in place, and Princess Diana opened it as Terminal A in 1989.  ‍ From 1997 to 2001, a second runway was built, leading to many protests from locals because natural habitats were disturbed and listed buildings had to be demolished, but they didn't have another option. ‍ New expansion work started in 2019 to keep up with the ever-growing passenger traffic figures. ‍ EasyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways have operating bases in Manchester. Many airlines from around the Globe serve it, including Air Canada, Air France, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad, Finnair, KLM, Kuwait Airways, Lufthansa, Qatar, Scandinavian Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish, Virgin Atlantic, and more. ‍ iniBuilds says they are heading back to the UK as British sceneries have been reaching new heights as of late, and they also want to be a part of it, delivering an accurate rendition of Manchester. ‍ Currently, they are looking for locals who happen to work at the airport to help them with data so they can craft an exquisite rendition of the airport. If you fit the bill, reach out to management@inibuilds.com. ‍ There's no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. Stay tuned! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini340</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Officially Announces Airbus A340 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini340"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688e2e8aa044ded0a0c14d6c_A340D-AIGUL.png.12c16eca56296cb3be00a21eaadc547e.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently provided an exciting update on aircraft development in their forum, announcing the official launch of the Airbus A340, which was teased earlier this summer. The A340 model in question is the A340-313 variant, powered by four CFM56-5C4 engines. IniBuilds says that the aircraft will feature a diverse selection of real-world liveries, custom cabins, a comprehensive failure system, and complete EFB (Electronic Flight Bag) integration. Additionally, IniBuilds is collaborating with Echo19 Audio to enhance the audio experience. Three variants will be included in one purchase: the passenger variant, the ACJ variant (luxury configuration), and the passenger-to-freighter converted variant. IniBuilds states that they intend to release it simultaneously on both PC and Xbox, while also confirming that the aircraft will be exclusive to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The development update primarily focused on A340, but we also received information that the A380 is very much still in active development and is making steady progress in the background.  ‍ Additionally, work is ongoing on the A350, which had its initial release earlier this year. iniBuilds is continuing to resolve bugs and making progress towards an Xbox release on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. ‍ For more details on the A340 and other iniBuilds news, check out their development update here. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx2070</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx2070"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68915cbb040a4ad97614834a_bfu01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has issued a hotfix for their newly released “Big Fenix Update” for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update brings improvements to the VRAM usage in MSFS 24, multiple fixes, and more. Update 2.4.0.2070 is the first update since the advent of the Big Fenix Update, which was their biggest patch to date, with over half a petabyte of download traffic (including livery downloads). The hotfix aims to lower the VRAM usage in 2024 by a significant margin, allowing a bit of breathing room so that stutters don’t happen.  Furthermore, the update resolves several CTDs and freezes, brings multiple sound fixes reported by the community, improves differential braking, improves overall stability, adjusts cabin and cockpit wind, and more. The complete changelog follows below: Avionics and Systems ‍ ‍ Art and Sound ‍ ‍ EFB ‍ ‍ Launcher ‍ ‍ Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (full bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sbct104</id>
    <title>flyt Updates Afonso Pena International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sbct104"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689160d8df0bfef535a4be21_bct1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt Simulations has recently issued a new update to their rendition of Afonso Pena International Airport (SBCT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024, bringing a series of fixes, performance improvements, and a ground layout update. Update 1.0.4 brings the long-awaited ground layout update, including the new apron area, expanded parking positions, and new jetways on gate 1 and 2. They have also improved the terminals' LODs and reduced VRAM usage, along with minor QoL fixes. The scenery is available in the MSFS Marketplace for $12.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mtmh60</id>
    <title>Miltech and Blackbird Release MH-60 and Mission Hub for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mtmh60"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689281e3d85baab125137a8a_20_f315e054-3dcc-4a8b-ad01-43d418f61db0.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Miltech Simulations, in collaboration with Blackbird Simulations, has recently released the MH-60 helicopter package for MSFS 2020 and 2024. The product includes three major variants of the MH-60 family, also accompanied by the new “Mission Hub” platform. The MH-60 is a multi-role, maritime helicopter designed for operations such as search and rescue, anti-submarine warfare, medevac, and special operations support. The release features the MH-60R, MH-60S, and MH-60T variants, with a total of 39 liveries, representing a range of real-world operators. The helicopter’s systems are modelled in detail, including a customised autopilot and stability augmentation functions, semi-functional weapons, and mission equipment, such as sling loads and acoustic elements. Blackbird Simulations contributed the 3D modelling for the package, which includes a highly detailed cockpit, functional displays, and mission-specific systems. The soundscape was produced by Echo19, using actual recordings of the GE T700-GE-401 engine. The package also includes four mini-scenery areas for mission execution, including CGAS San Diego, CGAS Kodiak, Garden Island in Australia, and Peñón de Vélez de la Gomera in Spain. The Mission Hub, released alongside the MH-60, provides a mission and campaign system, adding multiple objective types, dynamic triggers, and an in-sim editor. Missions can be created using a modular system and executed with any aircraft. Pre-built missions are available for immediate use with the MH-60, and new mission content is planned for future updates. The full feature list of the Miltech Simulations MH-60 follows below: Ultra-Detailed 3D ModelHand-crafted with high-resolution detail, based on real-world survey imagery and references. Three Variants, 39 LiveriesIncludes the MH-60S (Sierra), MH-60R (Romeo), and MH-60T (Tango) models, each with their own role-specific equipment and liveries. Custom Flight Model and Stability SystemsRealistic flight dynamics validated by MH-60 pilots. Includes a fully custom AFCS and SAS, supporting all documented autopilot modes. The MH-60 is priced at $37.99, and the Mission Hub at a standalone price or discounted bundle when purchased together. Both are available via the iniBuilds, Miltech Simulations, and Blackbird Simulations stores, with a release on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace to follow. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay updated on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilc1</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilc1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6892896b9862bc4b3681943e_FlightSimulator2024_YDm5vAPbHV_4472x.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following its initial announcement in July, iniBuilds has now released Larnaca International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The scenery provides a detailed and performance-optimised representation of Cyprus’s busiest airport, based on the current real-world layout as of 2025. Larnaca Airport is located on the southern coast of Cyprus and serves as a hub for both regional and international flights. The scenery includes hand-crafted ground textures, HD jetways, and a fully modelled terminal building, with interior detailing. More than 180 custom models and structures are included across the airside and landside areas, complete with accurate signposts, vegetation, and dynamic lighting. The product features high-resolution PBR textures and comes with its own GSX profile. LOD’s are applied across all assets to ensure optimised performance on a wide range of systems. Built using the latest Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 software development kit, this scenery is now only available for the newer simulator. Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024 is available now through the iniBuilds store for £9.99, excluding taxes. For all the latest news and updates in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cfsydt</id>
    <title>Canadian Flight Sim Studios Releases Boundary Bay Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cfsydt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68928eef34e4b6bb8b7c32bb_688a25ae1fd88.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Canadian Flight Sim Studios has released its rendition of Boundary Bay Airport for X-Plane 12. The scenery aims to provide a realistic and detailed general aviation environment at one of Canada’s busiest airports. Located in British Columbia, Boundary Bay Airport is a leading centre for flight training and private aviation in the Vancouver area. The scenery features accurately modelled terminals in high detail, hangars, and fixed-base operators, with designs tailored for business jet and light aircraft operations. Animated hangar doors have also been included at key general aviation facilities. Taxiway and apron layouts are built to match current charts, with custom markings and lighting throughout. The environment has extensive detail across all airport structures to mirror the real-world location closely.  Boundary Bay Airport is available now through the Orbx Store for $12.29, excluding sales tax. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar098</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar098"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently issued a new patch for their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which brings many improvements and tweaks. Update v0.9.8, also known as “Scott’s list update” brings a significant amount of changes to the product, including new beacon lights, tinted glass, windshield texture improvements, the addition of the Davtron 307FCI cabin temperature indicator, a working cabin temperature gauge, the landing gear’s got extra weathering, new sounds were added, and more. The changelog follows below: v0.9.8 Changelog Highlights: - New Beacon Lights - Added fan sound files - Added jacks - Added pitot tube cover - Air vents sound reduced - Ammeter no longer shows battery charging amps - Autopilot: Alt hold more resilient to sim stutter - Autopilot: Tweaked interaction between pitch and trim servo - Bug in aux hydraulic pump sound where it would keep playing fixed - Cabin fan hi/low sounds added - Cabin heat now draws slight electricity but requires the cabin fan to be on - Compass correction card. - Defroster blower sounds added - Flap and gear sound physics rumble tuned - Flaps pressure damage physics tuned - Fuel booster pump sounds reduced - Fuel selector servo sounds play properly with electricity on or off - Fuel will now drain out of the fuselage tank when fuel selectors are off - Individual cabin lights now draw current - Nose steering moves to center a bit faster - Nosewheel steering dash switch sounds - Opening door creates stronger air flow exchange - Prop feathering issues fixed, including an issue feathering the right engine - Right engine not feathering bug fixed - Slightly faster starter cranking speed, starter cranking physics sent into the airframe - Throttle, mixture and prop end sounds - Tinted glass - Windshield texture details - Yoke anim range fixed - Yoke trim knob sounds - [Tablet] Disabling / enabling jacks, heaters and pitot cover controls - Improved Active Pause &amp; Photo Mode handling - Fixed Landing Lights check in walkaround + using new .fx not the defaults - Added Davtron 307FCI cabin temp indicator - Fixed high speed buffet from magnetic compass - Working cabin temperature gauge - Improved handling of mixture events which may help FSUIPC users - Tablet moved to not cover ASI as much - Fixed tablet colliding with right sun visor - Updated baggage door textures - Fixed reg numbers clipping - Increased tail area reg number - Added some extra weathering to landing gear The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/20su26</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 16 for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/20su26"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68936c78301a9fdd93dac9fd_MFS-40th_Evergreen_KeyArt_Horizontal_9600x5400_RGB%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Microsoft has released Sim Update 16 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The update, version 1.39.9.0, introduces a broad range of improvements across avionics, aircraft, navigation, scenery, and system stability. Among the most notable updates are stability fixes targeting specific crash conditions, such as the Pecs TV Tower in Hungary, and improved memory management on Xbox Series S and Xbox Series X. The update also includes refinements to timezone accuracy and improved coastline and border data within the world environment. Other enhancements include updated Bing Maps data, to the 2024 standard, improved terraforming, and water body rendering. In terms of aircraft, the Boeing 787-10 Dreamliner, Cessna Citation Longitude, and Daher TBM 930 each received targeted fixes and feature improvements. These have been updated with changes to spoiler behaviour, thrust reverser behaviour, updated cockpit annunciators and autopilot logic. Updates to the Cessna Citation Longitude include new flight director modes, FMS initialisation, and pressurisation controls. Avionics platforms, including the G1000 NXi, G3000, G3X Touch, Primus Epic 2.0, and UNS-1Ew, have also been improved, addressing both performance and functionality. Navigation logic has been improved, especially in cases involving runways not present in the base simulator.  Peripheral support now includes the Honeycomb Aeronautical Alpha Lite, and Sim Update 16 also addresses infinite loading issues in specific activity scenarios. Developers also gain new tools, with 3ds Max 2024 support added to the simulator’s SDK exporter. You can view the full changelog below: For all the latest in flight simulation, be sure to stay updated on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
