<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-08T18:22:25.417014+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fetdal</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Dallas Love Field for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fetdal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c98aafa8fe50b3f8f063f1_dal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="246802"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Dallas Love Field (KDAL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Dallas-Fort Worth metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.  It opened 105 years ago as a training camp for World War 1 pilots and then converted into a storage facility for surplus aircraft after the war, with traffic reducing massively through that period.  It was purchased by the city of Dallas in 1928 and opened for civilian use, with its first set of paved runways coming four years after its grand reopening.  The first passenger terminal was built in 1940, serving over 21 weekday departures from American, Braniff, and Delta.  World War 2 saw the airport become a training school for army pilots, returning to its civil applications after the war.  The increased demand for air travel in the 1950s led to an expansion, with a new terminal (T3) designed by Donald S. Nelson, sporting three concourses, 26 gates, and the world’s first moving walkways.  Currently, the airport has a single terminal with 20 gates, with Alaska and Delta Air Lines having one each and Southwest Airlines having full control over the remaining 18. Unsurprisingly, Southwest has 95.3% of the passenger market share, while Delta and Alaska have 2.2% and 1.7%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly-detailed PBR models, custom ground poly, custom ground textures, custom animated jetways, custom night lighting, and an updated AFCAD.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.11, requiring at least 715.23 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slcrvu</id>
    <title>Self-Loading Cargo Receives version 1.6 update</title>
    <updated>2023-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slcrvu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cacca7ab0820e15e89cc5b_covere02.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="197655"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Popular cabin interaction app Self-Loading Cargo has been updated to version 1.6 or what Lanilogic Technologies is calling "The Interactivity Update". The update comes nearly 3 years after the last update which was released in August of 2020. Self-Loading Cargo aims to add another layer of realism for users who are looking for a more airline-focused experience in their chosen simulator. The name is based on what some pilots jokingly give their passengers. The app was extremely popular when it was first released in August of 2019 and received many updates during its first year of release. Lanilogic stated the reason for the lack of updates or announcements in the last three years is due to personal reasons and was very apologetic while promising to have more open communication about updates to his product moving forward.  Version 1.6 brings a ton of new features including voice commands and ground crew simulation. The ground crew integration includes interaction at both departure and arrival airports, a completely regionalized sound pack, and a completely integrated pushback system that includes support for both 'hotel' and single-engine taxi modes. Ground crew interactions can be initiated by either voice commands or through the updated UI. Along with the update, many existing features have also been updated including a complete rework of the pilot scoring and passenger satisfaction systems. The developer states that now instead of passenger satisfaction being rated by a simple percentage, you'll receive updates both in real-time and as an overall opinion of the flight based on things like the smoothness of the flight as well as the timing of announcements. Additionally, both the flight crew and cabin sound packs have been completely reworked to include new sounds as well as the ability to use different languages. The update also comes with a small price increase from £12.99 to £16.99. The developer states the price increase is the result of rising operational costs as well as the added functionality of the software. This price increase is only applicable to new purchases though and customers with existing licences are free to download version 1.6 without any additional costs.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned as Threshold brings you the latest in flight sim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cfsnia</id>
    <title>CFSS Releases Niagara District Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cfsnia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cb06f72e6d4dc8ff3cfb27_nia.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="600144"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CanadianFlightSimStudios has recently released their rendition of Niagara District Airport (CYSN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the town of Niagara-on-the-Lake in Ontario, Canada.  The St. Catharines Flying Club initially established the airport in March 1929, although in a different location (it was relocated in 1935 to its present location). It was then heavily utilized by the RCAF (Royal Canadian Air Force) during World War II for pilot training, where they also built basic infrastructure (hangars, barracks, and a control tower).   It was then returned to civilian use after the war, growing continuously, featuring three runways, a terminal building, multiple hangars, a flight school, and an aircraft maintenance facility.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models, PBR texturing, HDR lighting, and an interior for the executive terminal.  It’s available in their official shop for roughly $9.74. Shout out to Shenherm for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwyul</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release Montréal-Trudeau International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwyul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cbfb19b531f5b60676f17d_bmw1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="694189"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Montréal-Trudeau International Airport (CYUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving greater Montréal and eastern Ontario with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.  It was opened in 1941 to replace Saint-Hubert Airport  - Montréal’s former main airport -considered inadequately small for the city’s size and needs, on a former race track known for good weather throughout the year, rarely fogging up.  In the 70s, the government made huge plans to replace it with a new, much larger airport - Montréal Mirabel -, which would become the largest airport in the world when built in terms of total land area and fully expansible if there was ever a need to add a new runway or terminals. On the other hand, YUL was repurposed as a domestic airport during that period, while Mirabel’s expected traffic figures never came to fruition, eventually leading to its partial shutdown in the early 2000s (it has ceased passenger operations).  During Mirabel’s final commercial breaths, Montréal-Trudeau saw the resumption of its international traffic in 1997 and charter flights in 2004, while Mirabel saw nothing but the demolition of its passenger terminal in the last 20 years. The maintenance costs were far too high for something not in use, leading the administration to adopt such an extreme measure.  It’s a hub for Air Canada (Barcelona, Bogotá, Brussels, Calgary, Casablanca, Delhi, Denver, Edmonton, Fort-de-France, Frankfurt, Geneva, Halifax, Houston–Intercontinental, Lisbon, London–Heathrow, Los Angeles, Lyon, Mexico City, Miami, Milan–Malpensa, Paris–Charles de Gaulle, Pointe-à-Pitre, Providenciales, Rome–Fiumicino, San Francisco, San José de Costa Rica–Juan Santamaría, São Paulo–Guarulhos, Tampa, Tokyo–Narita, Toronto–Pearson, Toulouse, Vancouver, Winnipeg), Air Transat (Cancún, Cayo Coco, Fort Lauderdale, Holguín, Lisbon, London–Gatwick, Lyon, Málaga, Marseille, Miami, Montego Bay, Orlando, Paris–Charles de Gaulle, Port-au-Prince, Puerto Plata, Puerto Vallarta, Punta Cana, Samaná, Santa Clara, Toronto–Pearson, Varadero), and OWG (Cayo Coco, Holguín, Santa Clara, Varadero), flying passengers all over the globe.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal area, animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution texturing, landside buildings, custom runway guard lights, parallax windows, and more.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.66, requiring at least 2.73 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksmol</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Montréal-Trudeau International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksmol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cbfecbc6174b9107622d68_yul1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="520801"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released another update to their rendition of Montréal-Trudeau International Airport (CYUL), adding features requested by the community and more.  Update v1.0.2 removes the HSBC logos from the jetways (it was also removed in real life), adds the missing logo on the Air Canada hangar, fixes the brightness and opacity on the terminal glass, improves performance with LOD tweaks, and more. The complete changelog follows down below: - Removed HSBC logos (up to date with the real airport), - Added missing logo on Air Canada hangar, - Terminal glass brightness and opacity fix, - Added Montreal sign lights at night, - Better LOD setup to improve performance, - RAM usage reduction, - Static vehicles placement fixes to allow more space for GSX to operate, - General improvements around the airport.  They have also mentioned a potential new update (1.0.3) coming in a week, with more fixes and improvements.  The scenery is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.29, requiring at least 3.75 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdukv</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases United Kingdom VORs for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdukv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cc1ee519452178f29cdb92_VOR01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2875810"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Burning Blue Design has recently released a package with 50 VORs (VHF Omnidirectional Ranges) scattered across the entire United Kingdom for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  A VOR station is a short-range navigation system for aircraft, allowing planes to determine their position by receiving a signal from a fixed ground station. They are being decommissioned as of late thanks to the advent and popularization of GPS units, which are way more accessible now than they once used to be and easily found on all sorts of aircraft these days. While GPSes don’t require maintenance per se, VORs cost money to maintain, which has made some countries start phasing them out as they fail. The United States, for example, went from over 3000 VORs in the early 2000s to less than 1000 nowadays. The UK also plans to phase out their VORs gradually and cut them down to 20.  Burning Blue Design’s package depicts every one of the 50 fixed-ground VOR stations in the United Kingdom, made with PBR texturing and looking as close as possible to their real counterparts. The complete feature list follows below:  It’s available on their official store for roughly $11.38. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/550v2x</id>
    <title>AKD Studios Releases GLF550 V2 for X-Plane 11/12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/550v2x" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd25ea7137f7778fac5371_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3340400"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AKD Studio has recently released version 2 of their popular GLF550 business jet for X-Plane 11/12 almost a year after the release of version 1. The update brings various new features from custom MCDU to FMOD sounds, as well as an array of bug fixes. 	According to the developers, the plane’s modeling has been “completely overhauled”. Accompanying the new model are a brand new custom MCDU, new textures, custom RNAV support, and a FMOD customized by Mango Studios. In addition, the new version also brings improved systems and a tuned flight model. For a full list of new features, tweaks, and bug fixes that come with V2, visit the aircraft’s store page. Currently, the GLF550 V2 can be purchased on X-Plane.org for $41.95 USD, a $10 increase from V1. The developers recommend users to have at least 920 MB of free disk space to install the aircraft.</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbv2rt</id>
    <title>Fenix Begins V2 Rollout</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbv2rt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd3b62a03f0b2cfaf47241_v2header.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="520714"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. This is the first part of a two part announcement by Fenix. You can read the second announcement here. The rollout of the highly anticipated V2 commences. Over the next few days, Fenix plans to initiate this process by pushing a "staging" build. This rollout strategy involves releasing the modules of V2 in two distinct blocks. An exciting milestone has been reached with V2, where certain modules are ready for deployment, independent of any dependencies still under development. In the initial block, referred to as V2 Block 1, the offerings will include FBWv2, FMv2, and the first of the new displays, (ISIS). Additional smaller displays will be introduced later. Users can look forward to all code-side performance optimisations, including the innovative display render technology. Furthermore, a substantial portion of non-dependent avionics improvements across the aircraft, including the brand new VNAV, and a host of bug fixes, will be included. The full changelog will be provided upon rollout. This sets the stage for the second phase of the V2 delivery, projected to conclude by the end of September. Block 2 will comprise the new visual model, IAE and external engine model, further avionics fixes, EFBv2, and any additional revisions or improvements deemed necessary for Block 1.The rationale behind the decision to divide the rollout into two blocks is multifaceted. Block 2 requires additional refinement before it's ready for its prime-time debut. However, Fenix believes that the substantial improvements Block 1 brings to the user experience cannot be held back, especially since the development teams have completed their work on it. Fenix also encourages community feedback on Block 1's features to refine and enhance Block 2, aiming for an optimal overall user experience when V2 is fully delivered. In appreciation for users' patience, Fenix will be releasing some screenshots next week, giving a sneak peek of what they aim to achieve with Block 2, particularly the visual model. The entire aircraft has undergone a painstaking rebuilding process. This endeavor not only raises the bar from what was achieved with the first version but also demonstrates Fenix's commitment to delivering a high-quality product at no additional cost. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/faaams</id>
    <title>Fenix Announces A321 and A319 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/faaams" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd3cbd00081cedd6d21b20_fenix_back.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1303835"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. This is the second part of a two part announcement from Fenix, you can see the other announcement here. ‍In the world of flight simulation, secrets are hard to keep. Speculations have been brewing, and the big reveal is finally here. While working on revamping the A320 with V2, Fenix has simultaneously been developing the A321 and A319. The improvements made with the rollout of V2 have laid a robust foundation upon which these new aircraft models have been built. Fenix has announced plans to release these new models by the end of the year as a single expansion package, priced at £39.99. As with the A320, sharklets will follow at no additional cost to the customers. With the release of Block 2 scheduled for September, the end of the year will witness the debut of the A321 and A319. As Fenix moves into 2024, it plans to update all its product lines with sharklets for free. Timelines are often tricky and met with apprehension. Nevertheless, Fenix believes in the importance of transparency with their customers. It is crucial for them to provide a clear roadmap of their plans and timelines, alleviating the anxiety that can come with uncertainty.A question that might arise is why the A321 and A319 are prioritized over the A320 sharklets. Fenix said the simple answer is financial stability. The new aircraft models' release will ensure the company's steady financial standing, crucial to support continued product line development and future offerings. For the time being, customers are encouraged to enjoy the revised displays, enhanced performance, and improved handling and behaviour of the aircraft. While the next month might seem like a long wait, the company assures its customers that they are diligently preparing the rest of V2. Over the weekend, Fenix will share performance benchmarks for V2 Block 1, detailing the improvements over the .146 version. In a few days, they will provide a changelog and a new build, continuing to keep their customers in the loop of this exciting journey. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssyul</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Teases Progress on Montréal-Trudeau International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssyul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd74ac80d7f92f46f479a5_yul1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="210510"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently teased the development progress of their Montréal-Trudeau International Airport (CYUL) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which appears to be nearing completion. The developers claim it’s set to become their best product yet, emphasizing detail and quality (and custom interiors!). They have been working with locals to get the best fidelity on signs, boards, etc. There is no release date yet, but they expect it to be around the end of August/beginning of September. Upon release, Customers who own at least two FSimStudios products will also get a copy of Mont Tremblant Airport (CYFJ). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/coc162</id>
    <title>Cockspur Releases Cessna C162 Skycatcher for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/coc162" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cf72d041ee40d8682214bc_cock1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="221142"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur has recently released their C162 Skycatcher for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a high-wing tricycle gear light-sport aircraft designed and produced by Cessna between 2009 and 2013.  Its design was unveiled in 2006 during EAA AirVenture Oshkosh, back when they were testing the waters of the commercial feasibility of a light sport aircraft. The development program was launched a year later, kickstarting the development of a production version.  After carrying out all the required testing and passing the ASTM Light Sport Aircraft requirements with flying colors, it was ready to roll out of the factory. In December 2009, the first production Skycatcher had finally been delivered, and the order list was sitting at a thousand units by then.  The plans for 2010 included a 300-400 unit production rate which never came to be, with only 30 deliveries that year, followed by many cancellations in the subsequent years because the aircraft was deemed too expensive for what it was. By 2014, the sales had been halted, and unsold units were scrapped for parts.  Reviews criticized the aircraft’s high empty weight, fragility, and lack of tall-friendliness, feeling even more cramped than a little 152. Many considered it a failed attempt at creating a Light Sport Aircraft, yielding nothing but a miniaturized 152.  Cockspur’s rendition aims to deliver an accurate rendition of the Skycatcher, developed in close connection with real-world pilots. It includes a full glass cockpit, twelve liveries, and more.  It’s available on Cockspur’s website for $22.04 and on the MSFS Marketplace for $19.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fenben</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Publishes V2 Stage 1's Performance Benchmark Figures</title>
    <updated>2023-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fenben" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cf7a05368d5eeb7c4eabb7_perf1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="184238"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently announced their gradual V2 rollout, with stage one bringing a new fly-by-wire, an improved flight model, new display rendering technology, and code optimizations that would increase the add-on’s performance. It made people wonder: how much does it improve it? Their latest blog post is all about that. ‍ They have been working hard at making the software run more efficiently, investing over a thousand hours of manhours into rebuilding their display render pipeline, auditing the 3D model and overall code to make it perform great, and balancing VRAM usage.  ‍  Then, they showcase a series of benchmarks, showing the before and after of the framerate, system specs, and resolution while comparing them with V1 and other popular aircraft add-ons. ‍ ‍  Fenix finishes with a sneak peek at the Navigraph moving map integration and the new 180-pax layout accompanying V2’s first rollout. ‍  The aircraft is available for roughly $63.73 on Fenix Simulations’ official website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nsssit</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Sitka Rocky Gutierrez Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nsssit" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d0b8c2a13cc26ac3844311_sitka.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="576832"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Northern Sky Studio has recently released their rendition of Sitka Rocky Gutierrez Airport (PASI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Sitka in Alaska with a yearly average of 38,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1942 as a military airfield during World War 2, then turned over to the city of Sitka right after it was over and converted into a civilian airport. Scheduled airline service only started a decade later with Pacific Northern Airlines. ‍ The jet age only arrived at Sitka in March 1967, when an Alaska Airlines Boeing 727-90C Golden Nugget touched its then gravel runway with 70 passengers. Gravel runway operations were still brand new to jet operators, and the 727 required a specific FAA certification before such a feat.  ‍ Historical records say the “whole” city came to the airport to watch the landing, including the mayor, governor, and even a high school marching band. One of the employees shot an 8mm film of the landing that the local historical society preserved afterward. ‍ The airport currently has a single terminal with a single jetway, operated mainly by Alaska Airlines, which serves the airport all year long with routes to Juneau and Ketchikan. Delta Connection runs a seasonal leg to Seattle-Tacoma. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed replica of its buildings and vehicles, full PBR materials, texture baking effects on all buildings, high-resolution textures, and custom orthophoto for the airport and surroundings. ‍ ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.00, requiring at least 1.47 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mldtim</id>
    <title>MLD Scenery Releases Timisoara International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mldtim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d0c6b5a25e7c26e512795d_timi.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4107280"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MLD Scenery has recently released their rendition of Timișoara Traian Vuia International Airport (LRTR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Romania with a yearly average of 1.1 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1942 on a 91-hectare plot of land, originally sporting a 1,200x600m runway, a 9x5m plank cabin with offices, and a 20x8m shed.   A decade later, the airport received several upgrades to fit the needs of the Romanian Army, including a runway extension, bringing its length from 1,200 to 2,000 meters.   In the 60s, with Timisoara’s growth becoming more and more evident and transforming the city into an economic center, the government decided to build a proper civil airport on its location, with a big passenger terminal and a 2,500m runway.  It was then modernized in the mid-1970s to meet the new demand for passenger traffic while also getting yet another runway extension. Arad International Airport took all of the Timisoara traffic during the works from 1977 to late 1979 as it only had one runway.  A new terminal for international arrivals was built between 2019 and 2021, further increasing the airport’s passenger handling capabilities.  AirConnect, Corendon Airlines, Eurowings, HiSky, Lufthansa, Sky Express, TAROM, and WizzAir serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom ground polygons, an up-to-date layout, custom night lighting, and a custom GSX profile. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.32, requiring at least 1.21 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inippd</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Ponta Delgada - João Paulo II Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inippd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d0f22877068fbd7a300fc8_inippd.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1345317"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of Ponta Delgada - João Paulo II Airport (LPPD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the municipality of Ponta Delgada on São Miguel Island in the Archipelago of the Azores with a yearly average of 2 million passengers. The airport's construction started in 1963, with the official inauguration only happening six years later in 1969 by President Américo Tomás. Its primary purpose was serving inter-island connections and Europe, with regular flights to Lisbon beginning a year later. A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1995 when the airport also got its current name after the Pope's visit to the Azores four years prior. ‍ The following decade post-new terminal brought massive growth in passenger traffic, which has been steadily growing, connecting the Azores to the world.  It's also the most important cargo airport in the Azores, handling over 10,000 tonnes yearly. Azores Airlines, Binter Canarias, British Airways, Edelweiss Air, Iberia, Lufthansa, Ryanair, SATA Air Açores, Smartwings, Swiss, TAP, Transavia, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Netherlands, and United Airlines all serve it, with most of them only offering their services during summer. iniBuilds' rendition is said to bring exceptional detail and immersion, with full interiors, points of interest, and more. They have also announced the "Summer Surprises" event, starting later this month with new product launches and announcements.  There's no information on the pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/silkun</id>
    <title>Silvercrest Creations Releases Kumasi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/silkun" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d1e6dc477a92b0d753132a_kum.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3095999"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Silvercrest Creations has recently released their rendition of Kumasi International Airport (DGSI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Kumasi in Ghana with a yearly average of 500,000 passengers.  The Royal Air Force built the airport in the early 1940s to serve as a military air base, becoming a civilian airport two years after the conflict was over upon authorization granted by the British Empire.  ‍ A decade later, the airport underwent major redevelopment work on the runway and infrastructure, ensuring proper viability for commercial operations. The runway was improved again twenty years later with lights for nocturnal operations. ‍ A new terminal was built in 1993 - commissioned by President Jerry John Rawlings -.Then, in 1999, it was changed from a military and commercial hybrid into a commercial airport only. ‍ New terminal improvements came in 2008 for the African Cup of Nations and between 2014 and 2022, including a full expansion with the construction of a new 7,000 square meter terminal with VIP lounges, restaurants, commercial areas, three boarding gates, a central screening system, and an IATA compliant baggage handling system.  ‍ The airport is currently served by Africa World Airlines and Passion Air, with flights to Accra and Wa. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D model of the passenger terminal, custom objects, a terminal interior, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.87, requiring at least 432.56 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
