<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-10-04T18:30:40.300742+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1233</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.3.0 Beta </title>
    <updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1233"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d8140c3a9e95f077741b44_553686471_1345164110337120_4493339418293256017_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. EDIT: As of 26.09.2025, the Beta build 3 has been recalled due to the issues experienced by Mac users. ‍ Laminar Research has published a new beta build with weather radar improvements, bug fixes and improvements for the default aircraft, implementation of new debug tools for developers, and the fix for the users who experienced black boxes in the sky. Currently, there are two known issues: the update to Beta build 3 for users on macOS will fail unless the X-Plane.app file is deleted beforehand, and the weather radar output may be inaccurate for some 3rd party aircraft. ‍ This build brought in many improvements and fixes, with some of them being the improved TrackIR movement, a new debug tool for capturing graphic data, fixed synchronising between sim and UTC time, improved colors of the VFR map and the Synthetic Vision, improved crash handling on systems using Windows, and many more. For the aircraft side of the update, the close-range weather radar detection has been significantly improved, as in the previous versions, the radar could miss the clouds due to the width of the beam. The rest of the improvements are for the Beechcraft Baron 58, where the fuel tank selector could cause some levers to get stuck, Boeing 737-800, where the wind condensation particles have been corrected, and lastly, the PROG page on the Cessna Citation X on the second FMS is now fixed, and the destination airport is displayed there as well. ‍ The full change log is as follows: ‍ General Aircraft General Beechcraft Baron 58 Boeing B737-800 Cessna Citation X Graphics ‍ The Beta 3 is available for download for all users who have chosen the public beta. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdgdevupd279</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdgdevupd279"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6731bf52e0c3783d31cd6eb3_1250410_20240628201837_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a development update justifying their recent "silence" of sorts. An illness got in the way, and part of the team was on vacation, but that doesn't mean their work stopped: there's progress on the 777 lineup update, new information on the 737NG, and two previews from the upcoming 747 Classic! Their 777 lineup has been updated to build 121 on MSFS 2020/2024 (Marketplace), with 2024 taking a bit longer to be on build 121 due to an issue with texture streaming. On the other hand, the website customers are already on build 130. A new build will be released sometime next week, with the Marketplace version to follow soon after the intake process. The aforementioned texture issue still hasn't been fully mitigated, but PMDG and Microsoft are investigating the cause to try and come up with a solution. It manifests by randomly displaying odd textures on the wings and "other places." The only way to fix it is by going on the tablet and replacing the tires. They are not exactly sure why it fixes it, but they suspect it's because MSFS 2024 does not like the methods they use to reflect tire wear. The long-awaited sound update for the 777 fleet is in its final approval stages. It will completely rebuild and upgrade the airplane's sound environment based on hundreds of new recordings, code magic, and audio engineering wizardry. Although some roadblocks were encountered during the development process, they have been overcome, and they think the wait will be worth it. ‍ Furthermore, in Randazzo's words, the new sound environment "sounds like it sounds on the airplane", "not simply serving as a mimic the high-frequency-distorted sound you hear in most YouTube videos". "If you have an opportunity to sit on the flight deck in flight, the audio environment is far more broad-spectrum than what can be picked up by the average consumer grade electret microphones, so we not only had to make a heavy investment in studio grade equipment, we had to then make the investment in studio grade processing and expertise in order to ensure the sound sampling and mixing was done in such a way that you will experience the entire broad spectrum of sound as if you were sitting in the airplane". ‍ The 737NG's port for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 has progressed into fitness and cleanup, and they are already looking at the calendar to plan a release date, albeit cautiously, as they are still not entirely happy with the product's state. ‍ Once the 737-800 goes into final testing, they will shift their attention to the -700, then the -900, and -600, respectively. ‍ They have also shared an image of the upcoming 747 Classic, which still isn't quite ready for previewing. For the time being, they have shifted their development focus to the 737NG for 2024. They have also not clarified whether it's the 747-100 or the 747-400, leaving it to the audience to find out. PMDG's product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nss707fd</id>
    <title>Nimbus Simulation Studios Teases 707's Flight Deck</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nss707fd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68da27498661e97e0cbfbbb9_nimbu1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has recently shared a few screenshots of the cockpit progress on their Boeing 707 for X-Plane, which was first announced during last year’s FSExpo. The new previews showcase the cockpit work under different lighting conditions, highlighting their intricate attention to overall detail, with wear and tear to boot, as you’d expect from such an old airplane. The 707 was Boeing’s first jet, directly contributing to the history of modern travel by being the first commercially successful jet. It truly inaugurated the so-called “jet age,” transforming long-distance air travel into a fast, reliable, and somewhat affordable means of mass travel.  Its revolutionary design was centered around speed and efficiency, cruising higher than most airliners at the time, avoiding turbulence and reducing drag, often cutting transatlantic travel times in half. Its impact was much more than just the noticeably faster speed; it was also cultural and economic, forever changing the landscape of airline travel. There’s still no release date or pricing information, but Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwumth</id>
    <title>Winwing Opens Pre-Orders for URSA Minor 32 Throttle Metal and 32 PAC Metal</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwumth"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68dacdedb1ee281adbd76c21_QmPsfhcLLV8grXLWaFNoFYNkwhy3UhtnS8AZdY9JoDcs3p.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Winwing has opened pre-orders for its Airbus-style URSA Minor 32 Throttle Metal, alongside the matching 32 PAC Metal add-on. Limited units are shipping via the Winwings global store, with regional sites offering pre-order only for now.  The throttle features a full-metal core, contactless Hall sensors, six detents (IDLE, CL, FLX/MCT, TO/GA, REV IDLE), and a reverse latching mechanism. Real-time, sim-synced backlighting, dual lever vibration, adjustable damping, and a quick switch between detented and non-detented modes round out the hardware. The engine master switches have lift-to-unlock guards, and SimAppPro support is included, providing plug-and-play support and broad aircraft profiles. The 32 PAC Metal panel add-on adds metal flaps and speed brake levers with authentic gates, a parking brake with pull-and-turn functionality, and integrated rudder trim with a live indicator. The main throttle is required to function. Both units support desk and profile mounting, built for airliner operations. The URSA Minor 32 Throttle Metal and 32 PAC Metal are available on Winwing's website, both standalone, as well as in a bundle deal for $267.52.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fpsfnx</id>
    <title>Flight Panels Releases 2025 Fenix Stream Deck Profile For MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fpsfnx"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68dadab8f96a9e9c09bddbc2_Home1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flight Panels has released its 2025 Edition Stream Deck profile for the Fenix A319, A320, and A321 in MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. The package spans 33 pages, includes 750+ custom buttons, with three-state displays, and aims for near total cockpit coverage, from routine flows to deeper systems. A new “QSTART” feature groups key checklist items for cockpit prep, pre-flight, before start, and after start, streamlining the jump from cold and dark to ready for departure. Beyond switches and selectors, the profile adds ground services, performance readouts, ATIS access, walk-around aids, doors and seating controls, camera presets, refuelling, and GPU management. The profile supports Stream Deck XL, Stream Deck MK.2, Stream Deck Mobile, and Xeneon Edge. It is available now on the Flight Panels website for $33.59, and you can save 20% if you already own the 2023 edition, until October 7th 2025. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fscj6a</id>
    <title>UHI Products Releases CJ-6A Primary Trainer for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fscj6a"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68dae901ac70329e5d02b0e5_uhi-cj-6a-primary-trainer_8_ss_l_250904141702.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UHI Products has recently released its CJ-6A Primary Trainer for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, via the Just Flight store. Modelled on an early variant of the Chinese Nanchang CJ-6A, the two-seat trainer arrives with more than 15 liveries, dual-seat operation from front and rear cockpits, and support for aerobatic manoeuvres, including smoke effects. The package features a compressed-air engine start, working emergency cold-air system, gravity-fed tanks, attitude-indicator drift, and a left-turning constant-speed, variable-pitch propeller.  Cockpit labels can be toggled between Chinese and English, gauges can switch between metric and imperial, and an optional modern GPS (via the free PMS530 plugin) is supported.  Flight dynamics are based on manual data, with feedback from real-world pilots, while sounds were recorded from the aircraft itself. Other touches include ground differential braking, multi-level LOD for smoother online flying, and manuals in Chinese and English.  The CJ-6A is available now through JustFlight, for $18.99, with a 436MB download. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfpodp</id>
    <title>RowsFire Opens Pre-Orders for the A105 and A107 V3, and Shares Development Update</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfpodp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68dbe3ccbd4f7944d30182ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. RowsFire has just announced that pre-orders for their A105 radio and frequency panel and A107 overhead panel are now live. Both Airbus-styled panels are estimated to ship between October 15th and 30th. Additionally, the team has provided a development update, which includes the announcement of a Boeing 737 overhead panel.  The A105 features a combined RMP (Radio Management Panel) and ATC (Air Traffic Control) panel, equipped with backlit buttons and toggle switches. This panel is compatible with the Airbus A320 family by Fenix, FBW, and iniBuilds in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The price of the A105 is $249.99, and it can be pre-ordered from their website. Customers can use the discount code rowsfire15N to receive a 15% discount on their pre-order.  The A107 has been upgraded to version 3 (V3), incorporating several improvements over the previous model. The upgraded A107 V3 features stronger buttons to address issues found in the earlier version. Additionally, the panel thickness has been increased, the toggle switches have been enhanced, and the USB port has been relocated to the back of the unit instead of the side. There are also various other improvements.  ‍ Similar to the A105, the A107 V3 is compatible with the Airbus A320 family, specifically from Fenix, FBW, and iniBuilds, in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The new A107 is priced at $379.99 and is available for pre-order from their website. Customers can receive a 15% discount on their pre-order by using the discount code rowsfire15N.  It's worth noticing that customers who have purchased a previous version of the A107 from RowsFire and whose orders have not yet shipped are eligible for a free upgrade to the new V3 model. If you wish to upgrade to V3 instead of receiving the V2, you must inform customer service within three days. Please be aware that if you choose to upgrade to V3, shipping will be delayed until after October 15th.  ‍ If you do not notify the team of your desire to upgrade within three days, you will receive the V2 model. Additionally, all customers who own the A107 V1 or V2, whether purchased directly from RowsFire or elsewhere, are eligible for a 20% discount on the new V3. To take advantage of this discount, the team asks customers to contact their customer service.  Along with the announcement that both panels are now available for pre-order, the team has also shared a development update on their ongoing plans. The A101, A103, A105, A107, and A109 models have all been upgraded to V3. This version introduces light synchronization, which aligns the hardware lighting with the aircraft lighting in the simulator. Additionally, V3 includes various other enhancements for each model, which are all listed in the full development update.  ‍ Furthermore, the A108 is set to receive upgrades by October 15th, including improvements to the shell, screen, and functionality of the panel.  ‍ Lastly, the team has announced that they are developing an overhead panel for the Boeing 737, which is expected to be completed in November. The design drawings for the new overhead panel have already been finalized. You can find the complete development update and details about all hardware upgrades here.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!  ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctpcnc</id>
    <title>VATSIM Cancels Cross the Pond Eastbound 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctpcnc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68dc2ffd1c3ff29e54647d52_M9SDSfIVHfX2wzq1Xmq2CpwSH2vgCJZr6CWEJtb7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The online network VATSIM has today put forward a statement, confirming that the upcoming Cross the Pond (CTP) Eastbound event, scheduled for later this year, will officially not proceed, after consultation with partners. In their statement, the Cross the Pond Planning Team explained that Cross the Pond has continued to grow in scale with every edition, prompting the need for a “temporary break”, to review how the event is managed.  The team said the goal is to ensure a better overall experience for everyone involved, including vACC and division staff, pilots, and, importantly, controllers. They added that the intention is to return in spring 2026, with a new edition of the event, with further details expected in the first quarter of that year. ‍ The full statement reads: ‍ "Dear Members, With every event, Cross the Pond grows more and more. After some discussions with our partners, we’ve collectively decided to take a temporary break to determine the future of CTP, keeping everyone’s enjoyment of the event front and center. We hope to be back next spring with a new edition of the event. We will take this opportunity to revise some aspects of how we create and manage the event, to lead to a better experience for all those involved - Division/vACC staff, pilots, and very importantly, ATCOs. We understand that this might cause some frustration, and believe us, this was not an easy decision. We hope to count on your support and understanding. More news will follow in the 1st quarter of 2026, where we aim to host the next edition of Cross the Pond! Thank you, On behalf of the Planning Team" Cross the Pond, often referred to simply as CTP, is one of VATSIM’s flagship events. Held twice a year, it offers thousands of virtual pilots the chance to fly across the Atlantic, with full, end-to-end Air Traffic Control coverage. Slots for participation are typically booked in advance and remain in high demand, making it one of the most popular gatherings on the network. For now, attention turns to 2026, when the Planning Team hopes to bring the event back in refreshed form. Threshold will keep you updated. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lvlup737v2</id>
    <title>LevelUp Announces 737NG V2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lvlup737v2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68de00a6730b08e9bc28e442_V2-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. LevelUp recently announced the 737NG V2, which wholly revamps the visuals and sounds for X-Plane 12. The new platform’s rendering capabilities help push the overall fidelity even higher. The polygonal resolution across major external features was doubled, and cylindrical elements of the visual model, such as engine cowlings, fuselage, and gear tyres, were upscaled to look substantially smoother. Furthermore, the scimitar and non-winglet wingtips got a makeover to look better. The texture department has also seen major upgrades, with 8K textures for the landing gear, fuselage, and tail, improving the model’s overall consistency. The cabin didn’t escape the refurbishment either. Brand new modeling and 8K textures throughout allowed LevelUp to properly reflect how most modern cabins look. The sound department saw a major revamp. It now uses FMOD 2.0, brings sounds with much more detail than before, and plays more sounds at once since X-Plane 12 doesn’t suffer from the same limitation that X-Plane 11 did, which limited the number of sounds you could play at the same time. The interior sounds also have their own sound set, greatly increasing the experience. The deployment will happen in two stages, with the first stage bringing the new visuals and sounds, and the second stage bringing the new cockpit model and textures. They are not yet ready to reveal the progress on the flight deck, but “it’ll be worth the wait.” There’s no release date yet, but they hope to have it out by the fourth quarter of this year. They also hint that their V2 gives them a solid foundation for the 737MAX development since the visuals would meet the expected standards.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostarelease</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations’ Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 Out of Early Access</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostarelease"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68de04d1efd8a75e3cb03bb6_aerostarnew1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently released version 1.0 of their Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, marking the end of its early access cycle. Furthermore, they have also delineated their plans, including a version for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Update v1.0 adds the Collins ANS-351 RNAV unit, engine electric heaters, addresses bugs, animation improvements, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: - Added Collins ANS-351 RNAV unit - Added engine electric heaters - Cabin fresh air lever tooltip fixed - Fixed VOR2 TO/FROM flags - Fixed propeller rotation angle for LOD01+ - Fixed rare freeze when switching EDM modes - Fixes to the oil on the dipstick - Mapped fuel selectors to MSFS bindings (FUEL SELECTOR 1 OFF/LEFT MAIN/CROSSFEED, FEUL SELECTOR 2 OFF/RIGHT MAIN/CROSSFEED) - Smoother oil, fuel caps and doors animation - Tuned elevator authority - [Tablet] Checklist correction - [Tablet] Options rearranged - Autopilot NAV mode does not disengage on signal loss - Fixed bug with icing causing higher rumbling and shaking than it should A2A has also shared their post-release work list for the Aerostar, which is comprised of:  Due to popular demand, A2A has also decided to backport the Aerostar to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, albeit with some limitations: no walkaround and no dynamic wear/dirt visuals. Other than that, it will include the full Accu-Sim fidelity and systems depth. It will be included for free with the MSFS 2024 product download for all existing customers, and development is already underway. They might use a light early access model for this version, similar to what they did with the MSFS 2024 version. Other plans include a livery pack for Xbox pilots and - maybe - a second Comanche Livery pack. Once the Aerostar is deemed complete, they will move on to their next aircraft. They hinted that they have never modeled it before for other platforms, meaning it’s a brand new project. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw777pack</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Announces 777 Sound Pack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw777pack"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67007455f9c93f4f4c4607ef_randy4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works recently announced the development and imminent release of a sound pack for PMDG's 777 lineup—encompassing every engine variant (GE, PW, and RR)—in collaboration with Dave from Fenix Simulations.  In a seven-minute video, Boris previews some of the new sounds, including start-up, cabin &amp; flight deck sounds, buttons, and more. A more in-depth showcase will be out soon. Curiously enough, PMDG has recently claimed (in a development update) to be nearly completing their sound upgrade for the 777 lineup, but it won't encompass every engine variant. While there's no release date yet (although it's said to be coming this month), Boris has announced a $15 price tag for the whole bundle or $8 per engine pack. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rkafsrplus</id>
    <title>RkApps Announces FSRealistic+ for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rkafsrplus"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68de12bf6d46d162b81386db_fsr.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. RkApps recently announced FSRealistic+ for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 (the latter will depend on ChasePlane's eventual compatibility), rebuilt from the ground up to ensure the utmost realism, bringing new effects, a significant sound redesign, and realistic camera motions by integrating with Parallel 42's ChasePlane. Combining FSRealistic+'s most advanced camera and sound effects with ChasePlane's powerful camera engine, the plugin delivers "realism like never before", enhancing every phase of flight. ‍ Among the effects, engine vibration now translates into natural cockpit motion, rattling and vibrating as it would in real life; Applying reverse thrust now makes the camera react accordingly. Furthermore, passengers can now react to adverse conditions such as pronounced turbulence and rough landings.  ‍ Users can create and share custom sound profiles straightforwardly, fostering creativity and potentially improving the app's longevity. ‍ Due to how much FSRealistic+ depends on ChasePlane for the realistic camera effects to work, the latter is a requirement. Users who don't own ChasePlane might have to settle with FSRealistic Pro instead, a cheaper - and less feature-rich - solution. ‍ The product is already in an advanced stage of development, and it will launch once the developers deem it ready. Pricing is yet to be defined, but FSRealistic Pro owners will be eligible for a discount. Threshold will keep you covered! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini340soon</id>
    <title>iniBuilds A340 “Coming Sooner Than You Think”, says CEO</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini340soon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68de17076393fea8f74bacac_3401.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Officially announced in early August, iniBuilds’ newest airliner—the mighty A340—is said to be “coming sooner than you think,” as said by their CEO, Ubaid Mussa.  When questioned on their Discord about whether the A340 would be released this month, Ubaid responded with “yes” and “it’s coming sooner than you think”. The NDA lift for screenshots further reinforces its imminence. Their rendition of the A340-313 with its four CFM56-5C4 engines will feature a diverse list of liveries from multiple carriers worldwide, custom cabins, a comprehensive failure system, a feature-rich EFB, and high-quality audio.  The exact release date and pricing have not yet been revealed, but Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pricgh196</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Updates Congonhas Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pricgh196"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68de1a7e3f1f48c46cd8b62a_1250410_20250904221155_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Paulo Ricardo recently issued an update to their rendition of Congonhas Airport (SBSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The update focuses on performance improvement and general adjustments to further improve the product’s quality. It does not apply to the MSFS 2020 version. Update 1.9.6 improves LOD (level of detail), lowers VRAM usage, and makes a series of adjustments to enhance the scenery’s overall performance in the new platform. As previously mentioned, the update does not apply to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which remains on 1.9.5 for now. ‍ It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for roughly $16.99, requiring at least 6 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini340mp24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Publishes Video Introduction to A340; Initial Release to Be Marketplace-only </title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini340mp24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68de170e6d46d162b8155846_3402.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently published an in-depth video showcasing the intricacies of their upcoming Airbus A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The aircraft is set to release sometime this month exclusively—albeit temporarily—in the Marketplace. The 56-minute-long video encompasses the A340’s history, the power plant characteristics, the central landing gear, an in-depth external walkaround, tire and hatch details, engine details, GSX integration, wear and tear, a complete cabin walkthrough, the flight deck and the EIS1 screens, further flight deck details and functionality, taxi and flight model, take-off and climb performance, the EIS1 terrain radar, night lighting and differences between EIS 1 and 2, handling characteristics on approach and landing, EIS2 displays and features, a walkaround of the cargo version, an overview of the electronic flight bag, CPDLC integration, ACARS/CPDLC and its integration with Air Traffic Control, their custom code for flaps and slats, further handling characteristics, and information regarding its availability. The add-on will initially only be available via the in-game Marketplace, but it will eventually reach the iniManager. Furthermore, marketplace version owners will be able to request a license transfer once that happens. There is no information regarding pricing and its eventual release date just yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350116</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350116"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e04f57d6416b8bcce3aab7_A350116.2.png.9f313bcbbacf47b06dbbf5568e147938.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released version 1.1.6 of its A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with the update focusing heavily on bug fixes, refinements, and system improvements. Among the most notable fixes are the resolution of WASM-related errors, corrections to the cabin vertical speed display, refinements to ND and HUD/ECAM warnings, and improvements to ATC and navigation calculations. Failures such as emergency battery and TCAS behaviours have also been addressed. On the visual side, the update ensures proper decal placement on the engines, adjusts strobe light sequencing, and fixes dome lighting issues. Sound has also received attention, with tweaks to reverse thrust, flap operation, RA callouts, and low-frequency engine rumble. iniBuilds has also added a deeper cabin condition simulation and increased the refresh rate of the electronic displays. They also noted that the new sound package, developed in partnership with Echo19, is in testing and planned for a future release. As always, here's the full changelog: V1.1.6SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED WASM errorsFIXED Cabin VS constantly fluctuatingFIXED DIR TO via ND goes to some random waypoint not selected LL positionFIXED HUD ECAM warnings and advisoriesFIXED NAVMode Heading IndicationsFIXED Deselect FLS not working / SLS not workingFIXED Runway change causes weather info from APPR page to be removedFIXED Selecting AUTO for XDDR, puts TCAS straight into TA/RAFIXED Fuel values removed when page manipulated (see desc)FIXED Waypoint radial information doesn't clearFIXED ENG Out Acceleration Altitude not being used when ENG FAIL triggered belowFIXED Overlapping text on ATC COM screenFIXED Changing sim time erroneous ETA calculationsFIXED Issues with CMSFIXED Issues with overlapping text with fix pagesFIXED ATC COM  CONNECT PAGE  Notification Text overlaps with BEYOND ATC optionFIXED Instant descent (wobbly descent)FIXED FIX INFO cannot use NDBs as reference pointFIXED ELEC BAT FAULTS failing to trigger ECAM or overhead FAULT lightsFIXED PFD: AFS target alt displaced to the rightFIXED Alpha lock in direct lawFIXED Mach remains boxed if cruising at 290FIXED Emergency battery 1 and 2 failures don't workADDED Deeper cabin condition simulationADDED Increase ED refresh rate ART 🎨FIXED 900 LS Engine cover missing "350" decalADDED Strobe flashing sequenceADDED Dome light not working in 2020 SOUNDS 🔊FIXED Reverse thrust is too instant, no gradual/realistic increaseFIXED 350 Flap sounds not "as accurate as can be"FIXED RA Callouts different tonalityFIXED Engine growling/rumble should coincide with fuel flow as EGT is increasing The update can be downloaded now through the iniManager. New customers can purchase the A350 through the iniBuilds store, for $81.03. Stay tuned on Threshold for all the latest! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
