<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-11-01T18:31:28.524229+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/facbyo</id>
    <title>FlyingArt Updates Cabby AI Plugin for MSFS and X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/facbyo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffad9aa454e0bdd40d4e55_maxresdefault%20(3).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FlyingArt has rolled out an update for their Cabby, AI Cabin Crew software, adding a dynamic Passenger Satisfaction Simulation, networked boarding screens, and 3D spatial audio.  Every flight now generates a unique manifest with individual profiles and fear-of-flying levels, so smooth landings and fewer delays keep your virtual cabin happy, while rough rides do not. The new Boarding Screen feature mirrors a real gate setup on a TV, tablet, or second monitor, with four layouts and simple network access.  3D spatial audio is also implemented, with announcements in realistic positions around the cabin, working with headphones, 5.1, or 7.1 setups, for a more convincing soundstage. Rounding things off are AI flight summaries, landing feedback, and a flight history map.  You can read more about Cabby and try it out on the FlyingArt website. Prices range from $12.00 to $22.00, with several plans available. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfbrso</id>
    <title>SoFly Teases Bristol Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfbrso"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffb2624e3410f359972f65_571115643_1411194024345331_391040262126603842_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly has shared a fresh update of its upcoming Bristol Airport (EGGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, confirming that the scenery has now entered beta testing.  The team previously stated their focus is on detail and authenticity, with a carefully modelled terminal interior, inspired by real reference material. While not every area will be perfectly true to life, SoFly promises a close and convincing recreation, capturing the atmosphere of one of the UK’s busiest regional airports. The first beta testing round is nearly complete, with a second build already underway, meaning release could be just around the corner. We’ll keep you updated. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brsaa1</id>
    <title>BRSimDesigns Releases AA-5B Tiger G1000 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brsaa1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffbb0985c5542599d0b4ce_557530637_1404745094986421_9076242823794646352_n%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. BRSimDesigns has recently rolled out a refreshed version of its AA-5B Tiger for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, now including a full Garmin G1000 suite. The package includes a dual-screen WT-G1000 with autopilot, custom flight dynamics, an authentic Wwise sound set, and an EFB for payload, panel, and ground options.  Furthermore, the aircraft features high-quality 3D modelling, a mix of 4K and 8K textures, full PBR materials, dynamic registration, and MSFS volumetric lighting.  You also get eight liveries, an openable canopy, and a castor nose wheel, among others. FEATURES The Tiger is available at simMarket for $29.08. Owners of the original AA-5B Tiger can upgrade for $13.99, excluding sales tax. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dc2921</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Updates DCS World, Including Heatblur F14A Early </title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dc2921"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffc89dd87ce2caceda3463_G38OHk8WcAAiwX0.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has recently released DCS World 2.9.21.16362, a substantial update that, among others, brings the long-requested F-14A-135-GR (Early).  This new variant captures the original fleet-defence interceptor era, powered by the quite notorious Pratt &amp; Whitney TF30-P-414A engines, and fitted with the AN/ALR-45/50 radar warning receiver, complete with its distinctive strobe display.  The RIO cockpit features new RWR panels and indicator lights, plus updated TACAN and volume panels. There is also a VF-101 Grim Reapers livery from 1978 included. Beyond the Tomcat, this update touches nearly every corner of DCS. The F-4E Phantom II, for example, has also seen an update from Heatblur, including an EFB, and the AN/APX-80A “Combat Tree” IFF interrogator.  TV-guided weapon logic has been refined, new Zuni rockets have been added, and the Jester AI now has some new IFF options and a faster interface. Moving along, Eagle Dynamics’ own aircraft have seen meaningful improvements, too. The MiG-29A has had its autopilot behaviour updated, the F-16C Viper and F/A-18C Hornet have gotten first-person visor effects and an expanded NCTR database, while the AH-64D Apache’s George AI copilot has been updated with smarter flight logic, new control modes, and expanded commands. Furthermore, Ugra Media’s Normandy 2.0 has been updated with a new winter season, additional airfields across the Channel Islands, and dozens of fresh landmarks. Some new Swedish and Norwegian airfields have been added to Orbx’s Kola map, plus environmental refinements across the region. There are numerous other changes, summed up in the full changelog below: AI (Ground, Air, Sea) ‍Dedicated Server Weapons User Interface Mission Editor Graphics / Effects 3D Models Features Launcher Currenthill Asset Pack Known Issue: Switching George AI Pilot’s altitude reference between radar and barometric when hovering at an altitude of 20 feet or less over the surface can cause a conversion error that will force George to land and may not be able to switch back to radar altitude. This has been fixed internally. DCS: A-10C II Outpost Campaign by Stone Sky DCS: AH-64D Outpost Campaign by Stone Sky DCS: F/A-18C Operation Green Line Campaign by Badger 633 DCS: F/A-18C: The Rampagers Campaign by Baltic Dragon  DCS: F/A-18C Operation Mountain Breeze Campaign by Sandman Simulations DCS P-51D Blue Nose Bastards of Bodney Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS Spitfire IX The Big Show Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS P-51D Debden Eagles Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS Bf-109K-4 Jagdflieger Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS P-47D Wolfpack II Overlord Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS Mosquito FB.VI V for Victory Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS: F/A-18C Operation Cerberus North Campaign by Ground Pounder Sims DCS: F-16C Dragon's Fury Campaign by SorelRo DCS: UH-1H The Huey Last Show Campaign by SorelRo The full changelog for DCS World 2.9.21.16362 is also available here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mtsoct</id>
    <title>Miltech Simulations Shares October Progress Update </title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mtsoct"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffd0ad544caa222d4927f3_532517991_777431868129951_528965529907888171_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Miltech Simulations has recently published its October development blog, outlining progress across several of its big projects, including updates for the MH-60, Mission Hub, and Skyraider. New details on the U-2 Spyplane and CH-53 have also been shared. Miltech confirmed plans to gradually phase out MSFS 2020 development by 2026, citing the majority of users having already moved to MSFS 2024.  The MH-60, developed in partnership with Blackbird Simulations, remains one of Miltech’s flagship aircraft, and recently joined the Marketplace’s Top-Rated Aircraft Sale.  A major v1.0.3 update is on the way, featuring an overhaul of  APU logic, improved flight model and SAS behaviour, and AFCS refinements.  The patch also introduces optional realistic INS alignment, new keybind support, and pop-out gauge functionality for multi-monitor setups.  In addition, the first Livery Pack is nearly complete, adding a nice selection of military and rescue variants from the US Navy, 160th SOAR, and other international operators. Meanwhile, the Miltech Mission Hub is preparing for its long-awaited Xbox release, with both MSFS 2020 and 2024 versions in final testing. The update introduces sling load enhancements, a distance measuring tool, new SAR scenarios, and expanded SimObjects including vehicles, ships, and rescue assets.  A Mission Builder App is also in development, allowing players to upload and share missions directly from the cloud. The upcoming Skyraider, also developed with Blackbird Simulations, has entered beta testing and is described as feature-complete for MSFS 2020, with a full conversion to the modular MSFS 2024 framework.  Miltech said that the project will include multiple variants, including the A-1H, AD-3W, AEW.1, and AD-4W, each tied to specific liveries. Pricing is expected to land in the mid-$20 USD range, covering all variants, and the aircraft will support both PC and Xbox platforms at launch. Also in active development is the U-2, a passion project that originally began in early 2023. Miltech is building both S (digital) and R (analogue) variants, with complex avionics systems, new ground equipment, and fully modelled chase cars.  The aircraft will come with five detailed airbases,  including Groom Lake (Area 51), Fairford, and Akrotiri, and will feature dynamic missions built for Mission Hub.  While no release window has been given, the developer notes that additional resources have been dedicated to bringing the project up to modern standards. Rounding out the lengthy blog, Miltech provided a brief look at the CH-53, showcasing its intricate rotor hub and configurable cabin layouts.  Both the CH-53E and MH-53E variants are in progress, leveraging MSFS 2024’s modular framework for high detail and performance efficiency.  You can read the full blog here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdsolar</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases United Kingdom &amp; Ireland Solar Farms for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdsolar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6900c3f259f9eea8304143d0_solar2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Burning Blue Design has recently released a comprehensive pack of solar farms across the United Kingdom and Ireland, allowing VFR pilots to navigate more accurately during their virtual journeys. Over 1700 distinct solar farms total 210 square kilometers of custom scenery area (larger than the city of Dublin), featuring a variety of sizes and layouts, from tiny solar farms to massive behemoths spanning over 3 square kilometers of area. The product is made with full PBR texturing to ensure it will shimmer and reflect realistically regardless of the weather conditions. Furthermore, the developers have ensured that every little detail is captured: custom-modelled solar panels, inverters, and substations, with performance-friendliness in mind (multiple levels of detail). They also ensure that it blends seamlessly with the terrain. It’s available on their website for roughly $15. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a340102</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a340102"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690142ef437d8d5400f505d6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released the second update for their A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 since its launch. This new update includes a variety of changes, fixes, and improvements that further enhance the aircraft. The latest version, 1.0.2, features improved sounds and enhanced EFB functionality, among other updates. The update includes several important fixes related to flight management, display formatting, and logic handling. Additionally, there are various enhancements to the aircraft's sounds, such as improved engine acoustics, rain sounds, and cockpit interaction effects. The EFB will also perform better during turnaround procedures and exhibit improved chart behaviour. The latest version comes with a substantial changelog, which is outlined below: ‍ V1.0.2 SYSTEMS ⚙️ FIXED Custom thrust reduction doesn't work FIXED ATC Menu Option: When Can We; appears INOP but is accessible FIXED Cannot DIR TO (via manual entry) any Pilot Stored Wpt (e.g. PBD or custom name) FIXED EIS1 FPV incorrect track shown in AH FIXED EIS1: AH heading ticks not matching HDG tape ticks at the bottom FIXED EIS2: TRK/FPA, track blue tick out of AH FIXED Time Marker logic FIXED RS5 key causing MCDU display to go dark FIXED Persistent ETP Symbol on ND Post-Flight FIXED Zero DME shown on PFD during ILS approach FIXED Auto Pitch Trim slightly incorrect FIXED Oxygen Mask test logic revised FIXED GPS position in GPS MONITOR Title FIXED IRS INIT Page formatting FIXED F-PLN B Page formatting FIXED F-PLAN A Page formatting FIXED FUEL PRED page formatting FIXED RADIO NAV Page formatting FIXED Wind Page formatting FIXED PERF GO AROUND page formatting FIXED PERF APPR page formatting FIXED PERF DES Page formatting FIXED PERF CRZ Page formatting FIXED PERF T.O. Page formatting FIXED EIS1: ROSE VOR CDI not working FIXED FCU altitude should not have managed dot in cruise FIXED EIS1, FUEL SD crossfeed line has a break FIXED MCDU: PERF TO page should change format when TO phase active FIXED LS course is true and not magnetic FIXED EIS1&amp;2: early descent VDEV displaced indication FIXED Cabin doesn't ready all of the time FIXED Various systems working without electrical power FIXED AOC RCVD MSGS page logic FIXED INIT A page format feedback FIXED EIS2-FUEL FLOW: values clipping/total is cycling quickly FIXED ELEC ECAMs not working for most failures FIXED IRS Simulation and Page(s) logic FIXED PROG Page logic FIXED DIR TO Page (ADIRU not aligned) logic FIXED A/C STATUS Page logic FIXED EIS2 Terrain heights inverted FIXED DECELERATE Message should appear as soon as TOD reached without descending FIXED FMGS - Unable to delete Step Alts through their PSEUDO Waypoint FIXED FMGS predictions coloring - White, should be Magenta FIXED Can't select RETURN on SELECTED NAVAIDS Page FIXED MCDU menu - ATSU (currently ACARS) should bring up the ATSU MENU FIXED MCDU menu - "ACARS" should actually read "ATSU" FIXED ACP Light Test FIXED Missing Secondary Engine Indication with FADEC unpowered FIXED Hydraulic Panel Pushbuttons FIXED GND CTL pushbutton should be spring loaded momentary FIXED CVR TEST FIXED GND CLTR SPRS Switch logic FIXED Cold and Dark panel state adjustments FIXED MCDU missed approach format FIXED MCDU: missed approach altitude &amp; speed should be magenta FIXED Maintenance "Stow Rat" engages animation only; systems still show RAT deployed and sound plays FIXED Engine out ceilings and display pages in MCDU FIXED FLT CTL Computer Guards missing FIXED MCDU PERF page EO CLR format FIXED MCDU PERF page should auto display if engine failure FIXED EIS1: ND ETP formatting FIXED ADR off/failure should also lead to ALT indication lost FIXED ADR3 is feeding FO ISO ADR2 FIXED ETP MCDU page FIXED EIS1: ND speed limit magenta dot off route FIXED EIS2 PFD green dot offset FIXED EIS2 ND LS G/S diamond shown too far out FIXED EIS2 ND DME distance position FIXED EIS2 PFD yellow square offset FIXED EIS2 WHEEL SD FIXED EIS1 &amp; 2 APU SD page FIXED DTO and FPLN behavior FIXED DDRMI should not have leading 0s FIXED PERF CLB: PRED TO value behavior when reached FIXED ICE IND &amp; STBY compass light missing FIXED MCDU MENU lights would not go off when in MCDU FIXED DCDU stuck in recall mode FIXED Fuel System logic - Secondary pumps and totalizer in low quantities FIXED EIS2: ALT red ribbon incorrect FIXED EIS1 and EIS2: PFD ALT target incorrect position FIXED DDRMI should only show decimals below 20nm FIXED EIS1: ND DME should only show decimal below 20nm FIXED Incorrect inop systems in STS on ground FIXED FMS Approach didn't re-sequence correctly on go-around FIXED Step climb advisory logic FIXED Revised FADEC power-up timing FIXED DIR LAW revision on DU FIXED Autotrim advisory revised FIXED Selected ALT on FCU must equal CRZ ALT from FMS to display PRESET mach FIXED ALT and GS positions FIXED When in FPA mode missing V/S protection logic FIXED Autothrottle FMA logic revision FIXED Managed mode speed preselect logic revised FIXED When overspeed is gone, FD should not come back automatically FIXED DIR TO doesn't accept airport as FIX FIXED CLB Mode logic revision FIXED CRZ PRESEL input format corrected FIXED When in NORTH REF, bearings should have a T on lateral pages FIXED NAV BACKUP retains ILS FREQ after reset FIXED vls visible under vaprot (should not be visible) ADDED Lavatory flush logic tied to AC Bus ‍ ART 🎨 FIXED TURB DAMP shouldn't be guarded FIXED GND CNTL switch correct animation but logic needs updating FIXED Iberia missing engine "Iberia" decals FIXED KAM Air emblems on engine nacelles z-fighting FIXED RAT animation tied to sounds state FIXED ICE IND light too bright and tied to WING LT switch FIXED Lufthansa new liveries - white streaks on tail when moving away FIXED Iberia minor z-fighting on starboard horizontal stab plate FIXED Olympic livery door labels not correctly paired to animation FIXED DCDU brightness increased FIXED Adjusted Dome light splash area FIXED Ground power panel lighting FIXED Reverse sunshade triggers FIXED Smaller clickspot for window handles FIXED APU no heat haze ‍ EFB💻 FIXED EFB turnaround not clearing TO PERF FIXED EFB: PVI ON not showing on initial load (should show PVI: OFF) FIXED LIDO charts showing even if invalid ‍ SOUNDS🔊 FIXED Outside engine sounds too quiet vs windmill sound FIXED SUGT: be able to listen to cabin announcements if PA ACP knob is out FIXED PA ACP now allows audible cabin announcements FIXED Engine windmill mix when starting engines FIXED Various avionics sounds audible with no power FIXED Issues with walkaround sounds ADDED Missing pedestal sounds ADDED More noise to cargo hold ADDED Noise when ACU connected ADDED SPD/MACH &amp; HDG/VS knob sounds ADDED Sound for 10/1000 knob ADDED Sun visor sounds ADDED Rain sounds ADDED Improvements to overall engine mix ADDED Increased default internal engine volume ADDED Improvements to exterior engine mix ADDED Adjusted and improved whine and buzzsaw tone, pitch and volume The latest update is available for all current owners or can be purchased exclusively in the Marketplace for $59.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx2656</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx2656"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f14fa969afcc22cfd797fa_a319_a321_3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations recently updated their A320 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, addressing various issues and improving overall stability. Update v2.4.0.2656 addresses an issue where the thrust lever null zone would not save with uncalibrated thrust levers, fixes the elevators and ailerons not drooping fully down when unpowered, mitigates a potential CPDLC handover crash, among other things. The complete changelog follows below: 2.4.0.2656  Avionics and Systems EFB Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (full bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blcbundbon</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Beechcraft Baron &amp; Bonanza Bundle for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blcbundbon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69025efe10a5a0a6dfa70b45_bundle1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has recently released an aircraft bundle with the Beechcraft Baron and Bonanza for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Unlike their earlier steam gauge overhaul add-ons, this bundle features its own 3D models and custom sounds.  The bundle brings one of the most technically advanced simulations for Microsoft Flight Simulator (according to the developer), with an intricate reciprocating engine simulation, over a hundred possible failures, 12 hot-swappable radio configurations, and a custom turbocharger, pressurization, and cabin temperature simulation.  Furthermore, Black Square’s new Electronic Flight Bag allows you to configure the aircraft, manage payload and failures, monitor engines, electric schematics, and more. On top of that, the custom failure system features persistent wear, MTBF, and scheduled failures for nearly every component in the aircraft, and the tridimensional gauges are subject to the laws of physics, meaning they can become stuck and require tapping on the glass to become unstuck again. In the navigation department, there are multiple navigation suites to choose from, ranging from various eras of both planes’ long history: from a humble no-GPS Bendix-King RNAV system to a modern Garmin GTN 650/750 (PMS or TDS), a slightly humbler GNS 530/430 combo, or the classic KLN 90-B. It also features the KFC 150 autopilot, the RDR1150XL weather radar, and more. The Beechcraft Baron set includes three distinct airframes: the normally aspirated B58, the B58TC, and the B58P. The latter is from the early 2000s, and the former two are from the 1980s. It also accompanies six different interiors and nine different liveries. On the other hand, the Bonanza set also includes three variations: the A36, the A36TC with an aftermarket turbo-normalising package, and the B36TP turboprop conversion. Similarly, it also sports six interiors and nine liveries. Overall, the package includes an entirely custom exterior model, a custom sound pack from Boris Audio Works, higher-quality materials, fine-tuned performance tables, more avionics options, and much more. The bundle is available on the Just Flight store for roughly $64.99, requiring at least 3.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carb390</id>
    <title>Carenado Teases B390 IA for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carb390"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6902655801dc90c1d37b973b_beec.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has recently teased the development and imminent release of a B390 IA rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a light business jet designed and manufactured by Beechcraft. ‍ The Beechcraft B-390 Premier IA was an updated version of the Premier 1, which was designed in the mid-90s, first flown in 1998, and certified in 2001. The IA was like a real-life patch to fix some lingering issues with the project, such as the subpar brakes, noisy cabin, and cockpit, which many deemed below par. Said upgrade rolled out in 2006, and over 163 new Premiers were built in five years. ‍ The little jet is powered by two Williams FJ44-2A Turbofan engines. It cruises at 841 km/h, has a range of 950 miles, a service ceiling of 41,000 feet, and, depending on the configuration, can carry 6 to 7 passengers. ‍ There’s no information regarding pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vasexp</id>
    <title>VA Systems Launches "The Explorer," an App Designed to Search Real-World Flights</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vasexp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6903c4b92bbc7ec47a9e06ad_Skjermbilde%202025-10-30%20205526.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. VA Systems has just launched a new web app named “The Explorer.” This app is designed to search real-world airline schedules and, with one click, dispatch them directly with SimBrief. According to VA Systems, The Explorer provides users with quick access to their entire airline schedule database. Users can filter flights by departure and arrival airports, airline, aircraft type, time of day, and duration. These filters can be combined for more precise results. Once a flight is found, it can be sent directly to the user's SimBrief account for dispatching. Additionally, support for custom airframes from the user's SimBrief account is coming soon. The Explorer utilises a user-based pricing model, meaning a subscription is not necessary. Instead, users pay using a system of “Credits” by purchasing various credit packs. One credit is equivalent to one row of results returned. Users can set a limit on the number of results to control their spending. Accessing the Schedule view costs 20 credits. Saved searches, or “cached” searches, remain available for one hour, while schedules are stored for 24 hours. This allows users to view the same items multiple times within the time frame without incurring additional charges. ‍ Credits can be purchased in packs, with the following pricing structure: ‍ ‍ VA Systems estimates that 1,000 credits will last for 1-2 months. ‍ For more information about The Explorer, check out VA System’s website ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwumctm</id>
    <title>WinWing Announces URSA MINOR Combat Throttle Metal</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwumctm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6903cd8894914d995304c217_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. After recently opening pre-orders for its URSA MINOR 32 Throttle Metal, WinWing has just announced an all-new throttle quadrant, the URSA MINOR Combat Throttle Metal. Although information about the upcoming throttle quadrant is sparse, the team has shared some details, including the pricing. The throttle quadrant will include hall sensors and is described as having an "uncompromising performance core." Although not much additional information has been released, it is positioned as an entry-level option. The price for the throttle quadrant is set at $154.95. We will keep you informed as soon as the team provides any new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozaab6mtq</id>
    <title>MOZA Launches New AB6 FFB Flight Base and MTQ Throttle Quadrant</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozaab6mtq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6903d049f77942ead3d5e6e9_Skjermbilde%202025-10-30%20214803.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. MOZA has just updated its product line, featuring the new AB6 Force-Feedback Base and MTQ Throttle Quadrant. ‍ The AB6 FFB Base is being launched paired with the MHG Flightstick and a desk mount. The AB6 is a smaller and more affordable version of the AB9. MOZA claims that the AB6 accurately transmits all control forces, ranging from a gentle touch for trim adjustments to strong feedback during a stall buffet, delivering 6NM of direct drive torque. The MHG Flightstick features a fighter-inspired design, over 25 mappable inputs, and an integrated Hall-effect rudder axis. Additionally, it includes a two-stage trigger and hat switches. The MOZA AB6 FFB Flight Base is priced at $399 ‍ The MOZA MTQ Throttle Quadrant aims to combine military flying and civil aviation in one unit. Featuring easily interchangeable throttle handles, with users being able to switch between fighters, Boeing airliners and Airbus airliners. The MTQ Throttle Quadrant includes 10 programmable buttons, 3 rotary knobs, 3 toggle switches, and a dedicated landing gear lever. ‍ Fighter-style handles are included, with the TQA Throttle Module (Airbus) and the TQB Module (Boeing) being sold separately. The MOZA MTQ Throttle Quadrant is available for $199, and additional Throttle Modules can be purchased for $39 each. ‍ For more information about MOZA’s new offerings, check out their website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgpoa24</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Upcoming Porto Alegre Airport Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgpoa24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6904de3bb2a49e9f6a278fa7_alegre1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Brazil Land Games has recently previewed their work on updating their rendition of Porto Alegre Salgado Filho International Airport (SBPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024. It is the ninth busiest airport in the country, with nearly 8 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic). Originally called São João Federal Airport, it was just an air club, with its first flights dating back to 1923. It saw commercial action for the first time in 1932, when VARIG (the oldest Brazilian airline) replaced their seaplanes with land airplanes, adopting Porto Alegre as their hub. It took eight years to commission an actual passenger terminal. Its current name was adopted in 1952, after Joaquim Pedro Salgado Filho, a local politician who had died a year prior (air crash). It’s a focus city for Azul Brazilian Airlines, with a significant domestic network (fifteen destinations) and international legs to Punta del Este and Montevideo (Uruguay). The other two Brazilian giants, GOL Linhas Aéreas (thirteen domestic destinations) and LATAM Brasil (5 domestic destinations), are also regularly seen around POA. TAP Air Portugal is the sole European visitor, coming from Lisbon. Not much was said besides the pictures themselves and the fact that it’s still undergoing development. Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carb390pre</id>
    <title>Carenado Previews Upcoming B390 1A for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carb390pre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6902655801dc90c1d37b973b_beec.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado recently shared further previews of their upcoming Beechcraft B-390 Premier 1A for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which is said to be “on final approach” and “ coming soon.” The new previews show more of the externals, one shot of the flight deck, and a shot of the cabin.  The Beechcraft B-390 Premier IA was an updated version of the Premier 1, which was designed in the mid-90s, first flown in 1998, and certified in 2001. The IA was almost like a real-life patch to fix some lingering issues with the project, such as the subpar brakes, the noisy cabin, and the cockpit, which was deemed below par by many. The aforementioned upgrade rolled out in 2006, and over 163 new Premiers were built in five years. The little jet is powered by two Williams FJ44-2A Turbofan engines. It cruises at 841 km/h, has a range of 950 miles, a service ceiling of 41,000 feet, and, depending on the configuration, can carry 6 to 7 passengers. ‍ There’s no information regarding pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jsrafs</id>
    <title>JATSim Designs Releases Rand Airport for MSFS 2020/MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jsrafs"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69055404f1087bae1f721fc4_367589_FAGM-16.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. JATSim Designs has recently released its rendition of Rand Airport (FAGM) for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing one of South Africa’s most historic airfields to the simulator. Located in Germiston, near Johannesburg, Rand Airport first opened in 1931, and quickly became one of the most advanced facilities in the Southern Hemisphere. It served as the region’s main international gateway, and operated as a hub for Imperial Airways, later South African Airways. During the Second World War, the airport played a crucial role in supporting military operations and training. With the opening of Jan Smuts Airport (now OR Tambo International) in 1952, Rand transitioned to a general aviation field. Today, it remains active as a centre for flight training, maintenance, and airshows, retaining much of its heritage and historical infrastructure. The scenery is available on simMarket for $14,50, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
