<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-09-04T18:26:00.663128+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tla339</id>
    <title>ToLiss Previews Upcoming Airbus A330-900 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tla339"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d04e14300f7a9c1e98e55e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In April, ToLiss announced that their next aircraft type will be an A330-XXX. They have now revealed that the new aircraft will be the Airbus A330-900, which is part of the A330neo family. ToLiss has also provided some previews and a progress update. ToLiss has announced that the upcoming aircraft will be released in 2024. The aircraft will come equipped with a head-up display, new DRAIMS radio panels, and more. Most of the work on the aircraft has been completed, and the team is now focusing on the final texturing. ToLiss has not yet announced a release date or pricing, but the team has stated that they will provide an exact date soon. We will make sure to keep you informed once the release date and more information become available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/feu29m</id>
    <title>Fenix Updates A321 and A319 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/feu29m"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d086a33d3636fdcf344912_a319_a321_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations' latest aircraft package was released 10 days ago, today it received an update to squash bugs and adjust parameters. The two aircraft have been popular addon, following their high-detail A320. The update brought fixes to the Avionics and Systems, Art and Sounds, EFB, Flight Model, Livery Manager and Installer. The full changelog can be found below:‍ ‍2.2.0.334 Avionics &amp; Systems Art and Sound EFB FM Livery Manager Installer The update is available from the Fenix Installer. In the meantime, make sure to keep tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and stay up to date by joining our Discord server!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbligh</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Preview Exterior Lighting on Upcoming 757</title>
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbligh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d200c5eded5217a808cdc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BlueBird Simulations announced the development of their 757 back in February 2022, since then the team have been hard at work creating a highly detailed rendition of the aircraft. Today they released a video on their Discord server showcasing their work on the exterior wing and strobe lighting on the aircraft.  A key feature of the exterior lighting is the ‘shadow casting’. As the light shines onto the engine, a shadow forms behind the engine and wing that can be seen at night. This is a key feature that adds to the realism of the aircraft during night operations.  To keep updated on further development of this aircraft, and more, make sure to stay tuned to Threshold and join our Discord server. </summary>
    <published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfegff</id>
    <title>SoFly Releases Cardiff for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfegff"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d203ae2c1ad3372f178df4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Heading to the Welsh capital city, SoFly has released its debut scenery, Cardiff Airport, developed for SoFly by SkyHigh Studios. Having previously released add-ons such as Animals for MSFS, SoFly decided to head to the sunny city of Cardiff for their next project.  Cardiff Airport offers a gateway for Welsh travellers to venture to Southern Europe but also plays a key role in British Airways Maintenance. British Airways has a maintenance hangar that looks after a lot of their fleet. The team at SkyHigh Studios have animated the moving doors to this hangar, allowing users to take aircraft in and out of the hangar. Some of the key features included with the scenery are a realistic rendition of the airport, high-quality textures, dynamic lighting, terminal interior, custom AFCAD, custom GSX profile, and much more. SoFly Cardiff is available from the iniBuilds Store for $15.88 (excluding tax) ‍ To keep up to date on future releases, be sure to stay tuned to Threshold and join our Discord server.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777v2i</id>
    <title>FightFactor Announces Imminent Public Release for its 777v2</title>
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777v2i"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d213e5f638dc83a87296ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has announced that the public release of their highly anticipated 777v2 aircraft for X-Plane is imminent. The team mentioned that the public beta will be released on the 12th anniversary of the model. Along with the release statement, a trailer of the aircraft, created by Thomas Rasmussen, has been posted. The trailer showcases the aircraft and its features. The aircraft's store page has been up for a while after the aircraft was in beta pre-release for invited members. The page includes a detailed description of the aircraft and plenty of screenshots. The 777v2 will come with a range of features, including an accurate flight model, 3D modelling, accurately simulated systems, ground services, custom sounds, failure model, EFB, and much more. When this imminent release will occur has not been shared yet, but the fact that it is coming exactly on the 12th anniversary might be a hint. Once the aircraft is released, we will make sure to let you know. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/int-33</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases T-33 Jet Trainer for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/int-33"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d22835d306d0990731e3c3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released its newest aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the T-33 Jet Trainer. In collaboration with SimWorks Studios and Ace Maker Aviation, the team has brought the aircraft to the virtual skies. The aircraft is equipped with a range of features, including detailed canopy covers, toggleable chocks, toggleable entry ladder, engine plugs, pitot covers, high-resolution liveries, forward and rear cockpits, authentic classic steam-gauge and modern glass cockpit, and much more. The aircraft requires 6.05 GB of storage space and is currently available for $26.41 on the iniBuilds Store.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a300ov</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes New A300B4 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a300ov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d25607a14a1366c7bad0d6_airbus1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a new development update concerning their progress on the upcoming Airbus A300B4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing their work on the overhead panel. Like most modern airliners, the overhead panel houses the controls for some of the most complex systems, albeit not in the same way: the A300B4 still had a flight engineer panel. Still, it paved the way for the two-pilot cockpit philosophy, which was present in every other Airbus from there on. That transitional period becomes quite evident when there’s a mixture of awfully familiar switches and a plethora of annunciator lights, switches, and knobs that are no longer commonly seen in modern airplanes (replaced by automation or simplified). But even so, there are already glimpses of the contemporary Airbus philosophy that would dictate the future of their planes.  Panels are clearly and accurately labeled, annunciator lights are color-coded, and every rotating drum, knob, and switch is 3D modeled rather than a flat bidimensional texture. Every object has been texturized to look as realistically worn out as possible, as you would expect from an old airplane. They will showcase the engineer’s panel next, and there is still no information regarding the release date or pricing.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/surtha</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Surat Thani International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/surtha"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d25ac8433627d94db59f76_thani1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Surat Thani International Airport (VTSB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Surat Thani, Thailand, and has a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers. It was initially built as an airfield during World War 2 and left aside for many years after due to the existence of Donnok Airport, Surat Thani’s former main airport. Although a development plan for the decrepit airfield was proposed in the early 1970s, the government decided to drop it and focus its financial resources elsewhere (Phuket International Airport). Two years later, the population pushed for a reconsideration, and the Ministry of Defence also embraced it. Development finally started in 1978, and the airport was officially opened in 1981.  Plans are underway to expand the airport’s apron and passenger terminal, doubling its passenger handling capabilities. Nok Air, Thai AirAsia, Thai Lion Air, and Thai VietJet Air serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom night lighting, a custom-made terminal interior, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.29, requiring at least 818.17 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsfyon</id>
    <title>FSFORMOSA Releases Yonaguni Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsfyon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d26191e45f5974c7c9459a_yona1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSFORMOSA has recently released their rendition of Yonaguni Airport (ROYN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the city of Yonaguni in Okinawa Prefecture, Japan, with a yearly average of 100,000 passengers. It was constructed by the Japanese Army in 1943, being a vital airbase for their war strategy due to its location (awfully close to Taiwan). The post-war period led to abandonment, and its transformation into a civilian airport was only to happen over a decade later, in 1957. The airport's initial operations were modest, with small aircraft providing essential transportation links. As time passed, the airport's facilities were gradually upgraded to accommodate larger planes and growing passenger numbers. International service started in 2007, with flights to Taiwan operated by Uni Air. That helped consolidate the airport as a gateway to the island. It's currently served by Ryukyu Air Commuter, with routes to Ishigaki and Naha. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR texturing, custom ground textures, custom POIs, performance-friendly optimization, custom vegetation, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $15.41, requiring at least 1.09 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rexatm</id>
    <title>REX Simulations Announce REX Atmos</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rexatm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d32f6a576a46d8e93a759f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The popular plugin developers REX Simulations have announced their latest project, REX Atmos, a shader plugin for MSFS. The plugin will allow users to custom-tweak the weather, environment and atmosphere. Once tweaked they can generate a preset and will be able to share it with other REX Atmos users.  ‍ A picture was shared to show the effects that can be expected on release. The shot showcased the difference between default MSFS and REX Weather Force with REX Atmos. Changes seen include sky colour changes, added true rayleigh scattering, altered environment colouring, and corrected cloud lighting and ozone.  At this point, we do not know any more information about the product, release date or price. However, make sure to keep tuned to Threshold for any further updates and join our Discord server.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmeddg</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Münster Osnabrück Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmeddg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d340e08b5356f704fffa23_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations has recently released Münster Osnabrück Airport (EDDG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the two German cities of Münster and Osnabrück and is considered a minor international airport. It welcomed just under 1 million passengers last year and offers flights to various leisure destinations and European cities. The airport was established in 1966 and has since undergone various developments, including upgrades and new constructions. Currently, it serves airlines like Eurowings, Ryanair, and Sundair, offering flights to destinations such as Palma de Mallorca, Rhodes, and Tenerife, among others. The airport accommodates nearly 1 million passengers annually and consists of one terminal building, which is divided into separate sections for arrivals and departures. The latest release of Münster Osnabrück Airport includes several features such as custom night lighting, parking positions, surroundings, people and animated objects, PBR materials, and more. The add-on requires 2.28 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx for $18.94. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukbear</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Big Bear Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukbear"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d396a4ca30c3b7fe75706b_bear1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Big Bear City Airport (L35) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Big Bear City and San Bernardino, California, and has an average of 30,000 aircraft operations per year. The first airstrip in the area was established in the early 1920s. It was mainly utilized for private pilots and airmail service. The overall structure was precarious for its first two decades, and the runway was not paved.  The US Army Corps of Engineers constructed a new runway at the airport in the 1940s, allowing it to be used as a training airfield during World War 2. Following the war, Big Bear City Airport continued to expand. New hangars were built, and the airport's facilities were upgraded to accommodate the growing number of private aircraft and commercial flights. The airport's strategic location in the mountains made it a popular destination for pilots seeking scenic flights and challenging flying conditions. The region's ever-increasing popularity led to increased growth in traffic figures, which forced the administration to implement measures to manage the congestion in a safe - and less disruptive to the residents - manner: specific arrival and departure procedures and noise abatement rules.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, custom ground textures, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR materials, custom static aircraft, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.29, requiring at least 23.45 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftmcca</id>
    <title>FOX TWO MODELS Releases Cherry Capital Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftmcca"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d3a10dcc95ecdebc75d83a_fox1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FOX TWO MODELS has recently released their rendition of Cherry Capital Airport (KTVC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Traverse City, Michigan, with a yearly average of 602,000 passengers, making it the third busiest in the state. It was opened in 1936 as Traverse City Airport, replacing Ransom Field. A decade later, it was moved to the Coast Guard Air Station and has been operational since. In 2004, a new terminal was opened, wholly replacing the old one, which had been demolished. The runways were also reconfigured, with the third diagonal runway removed. It won the Balchen/Post awards for three seasons in a row for outstanding snow and ice control achievement in the small commercial airport category.  The east-west runway was extended in 2017 to accommodate larger aircraft, attempting an international status promotion (not granted yet). Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom night lighting, handcrafted models, custom taxi lines and ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.30, requiring at least 70.63 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsskar</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Skardu International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsskar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d5068ffd6f966d1f9a058e_skardu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Skardu International Airport (OPSD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a civilian/military airport serving Skardu in Pakistan, with a yearly average of 127,124 passengers. Initially built as a Pakistani Air Force airbase in 1949, following their independence, it was later converted into a domestic airport for civilian use, albeit still serving as a forward operating base for the Pakistani Air Force.  In late 2021, the airport was designated and re-inaugurated as an international airport after undergoing several upgrades to its infrastructure to comply with the required standards. It’s served by airblue (Islamabad) and Pakistan International Airlines (Dubai, Islamabad, Karachi, Lahore). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models, an up-to-date ground layout, custom dynamic lighting, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.08, requiring at least 119.62 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fratrai</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Launches Mega Airport Frankfurt Trailer for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fratrai"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d66345018e269f48d96e9b_trailer3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft, in collaboration with AviationLads, has recently launched the official trailer for their upcoming Frankfurt Airport (EDDF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which will be released on Thursday (05/09). Developed by Jo Erlend Sund and his team, Mega Airport Frankfurt promises a highly accurate rendition of Germany’s busiest airport. It features custom ground textures, custom jetways,  custom ground service equipment, terminal interiors, custom terraforming, and much more. The final minute of the trailer also provides details on the launch party, which is set to start at 1800Z on the 5th of September, with the presence of Jo Erlend and Lukas Vezyroglou (the lead developers), LondonController (a Twitch Streamer), and Calum (FSElite). IVAO and VATSIM will be fully staffed for the night, warranting a busy release night. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfssha</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studio Releases Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfssha"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d79c55b11a90ad9c3a4fce_shanghai1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WF Scenery Studio recently released their rendition of Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport (ZSSS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Shanghai, the largest city in China, with a yearly average of 33.2 million passengers. Construction started more than a century ago, in 1921, and opened for mixed civilian use in 1923.  It was occupied by the Japanese during the Second Sino-Japanese War and used as an air force base. Even after being handed over to the Chinese government, it remained used for military purposes, only being fully converted into a civilian airport between 1963 and 1964. Two major expansions followed in 1984 and 1988, significantly increasing the airport’s passenger handling capabilities. Since the early 2000s, the airport has mainly operated domestic routes, with most international routes being transferred to Shanghai Pudong. The only exceptions to this rule are a couple of international flights to Taipei, Seoul, Hong Kong, and Tokyo.  It was expanded in 2010 for the Shanghai Expo, which included a new runway and a new terminal capable of handling up to 40 million passengers a year. It’s four times the size of Terminal 1, inaugurated in 1964. It houses 80% of the domestic airlines at the airport. Terminal 1 underwent a major renovation at the end of 2014, bringing it up to modern standards. The renovation was done in two phases, with the final phase reaching completion in 2018. It’s a hub for China Eastern Airlines, Juneyao Air, and Shanghai Airlines. Air China, Air Macau, All Nippon Airways, Asiana Airlines, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Southern Airlines, China United Airlines, EVA Air, Hainan Airlines, Hebei Airlines, Hong Kong Airlines, Japan Airlines, Korean Air, Lucky Air, OTT Airlines, Shandong Airlines, Shenzhen Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tianjin Airlines, Tibet Airlines, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, realistic ground markings, a detailed terminal interior, custom jetways, animated vehicles, and more. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $23.99. Shout out to aca343 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
