<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-12-05T18:35:29.678192+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xomcrw</id>
    <title>Xometry Releases West Virginia Yeager Airport for X-Plane 11/12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xomcrw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69232f568d1326d94bf6cce4_CRW_30.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry have recently released their rendition of West Virginia International Yeager Airport (KCRW) for both X-Plane 11 and 12. Located in Kanawha County, it serves the capital of West Virginia, Charleston (not to be confused with Charleston, South Carolina, known for the assembly facility for B787), with more than 400,000 passenger operations per year. Opened in 1947, the Kanawha Airport served as a replacement for the old Charleston airport - Wertz Field, as it had to be closed due to the factory that had blocked the approach paths. American Airlines was the first airline to start operating flights from the new airport. Three years later, the airport received its first terminal.  In 1985, the airport was renamed to West Virginia International Yeager Airport, in honour of the legendary Chuck Yeager, the first man in the history of mankind to break the sound barrier, while flying a Bell X-1. The Yeager Airport is currently served by four airlines: American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Connection and United Express, to 6 destinations, along with a seasonal route to Myrtle Beach, operated by Breeze. The Xometry’s rendition of West Virginia International Yeager Airport features high-resolution ground textures, detailed buildings, custom high-res mesh, SAM jetways and marshallers, custom night lighting, realistic vegetation and a high-resolution colour-corrected Ortho4XP patch. The scenery is available on the iniBuilds store for roughly $14.39, and requires at least 2.27GB of free disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkshel201</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Helsinki-Vantaa Airport V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkshel201"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691759cf8e315639349f692b_hel1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently issued an update to their newly released Helsinki-Vantaa Airport (EFHK) V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing a series of fixes and improvements. Update v2.0.1 - the first since its release - introduces animated ground service equipment vehicles, jetway improvements, fixes missing materials at the terminal, and more. The complete changelog follows below: It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.91, requiring at least 4.10 GB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners get a 30% discount. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inimantrailer</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Launches Manchester Airport Trailer for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inimantrailer"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6924e75205c33f97b68441ce_sco1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently launched the first trailer for their upcoming Manchester Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which is set to be released soon in their store. Their next addition to the British lineup is nearing completion, built with extreme attention to detail using thousands of reference photos and textures. They also gained insight into their daily operations, future expansion plans, and design updates, which helped them further increase overall accuracy. Furthermore, they have also gained access to Terminal 2, which is still under construction, photographing every detail to ensure the scenery is as accurate as possible. The scenery will feature hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life landside recreation, dynamic airport lighting, custom jetways, over 180 hand-crafted models, a full HD ground poly, an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimisation, and much more. There’s no release date or pricing yet, but iniBuilds says it’s “coming soon” to their store.  A huge thank you to SCOTSGOD for the images! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg73824new</id>
    <title>PMDG Teases 737-800 Update for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg73824new"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6731bf31f12ae04fad8a6dea_1250410_20240201232924_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently shared two screenshots of the upcoming 737-800 upgrade for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with “even more” previews to come soon. In an unusual manner for PMDG, the post does not contain a developer update alongside the screenshots, but rather a single sentence stating that it’s progressing nicely. Although they have responded to some of the questions made by their customers, shedding some light on what we might expect from the upgrade: ​ There is no other information to be shared at the moment, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inimanrel24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Manchester Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inimanrel24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69276d4caaa895bf78ea910c_chester1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Manchester Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Greater Manchester, in the United Kingdom, with a yearly average of 30.9 million passengers, making it the third-busiest airport in the country. It officially opened as Ringway Airport in 1938, and later, during World War II, it became RAF Ringway, serving as a Royal Air Force base that trained parachutists and provided grounds for military aircraft production. Post-war, it reverted to its civilian duties, rapidly becoming Britain’s second-busiest airport after London Heathrow. The buildings that once belonged to the RAF were replaced by a passenger terminal in 1962, featuring a modern departures hall (the first covered passenger piers in Europe). The airport underwent significant expansion during the 1980s and 1990s to meet the ever-growing passenger demands. By 1987, the airport was handling a million passengers per month. Terminal A, now part of Terminal 3, was inaugurated in 1989, followed by Terminal 2 in 1992, along with the opening of the Manchester Airport Station. The main terminal became Terminal 1. In the late 1990s, the second runway was constructed, causing massive protests in Cheshire, where people had to be relocated to make space for the runway. In 2019, they inaugurated the first phase of Terminal 2’s expansion project, and the second phase was completed two years later, in 2021. It’s a hub for Aer Lingus UK, easyJet, Jet2, TUI Airways, Ryanair, and Virgin Atlantic. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air France, Air Transat, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia Express, Icelandair, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Royal Jordanian, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. Their next addition to the British lineup was meticulously crafted, utilising thousands of reference photos and textures. They also gained insight into their daily operations, future expansion plans, and design updates, which helped them further increase overall accuracy. The scenery features hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life landside recreation, dynamic airport lighting, custom jetways, over 180 hand-crafted models, a full HD ground poly, an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimisation, and much more. ​ It’s available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $23.56, requiring at least 4.74 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfl14624out</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases 146 Professional v2.4 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfl14624out"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/692890386068bd37c0c7eb33_ba1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently released the long-awaited 2.4 update for their 146 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, and now it is also compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It’s their most substantial upgrade yet to the 146, bringing it up to pair feature-wise with the RJ Professional. There are over 200 items on the changelog, alongside the long-awaited native compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024: The add-on is currently discounted by 30% as part of a Black Friday sale, and previous owners will receive the update for free.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxnov</id>
    <title>Fenix Postpones A320neo Beyond 2025, VNAV Overhaul Coming</title>
    <updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxnov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/692b6969f014edab0a286449_watch_vXCCarfZd8UU.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has just published a new development update, confirming that its A320neo expansion will not arrive before the end of 2025, as the team has shifted attention to the current A320 lineup for now. After what Fenix describes as intense, very direct feedback from users and support tickets, three problem areas have been pushed to the front of the queue, these being VNAV, state saving, and an ageing ECAM framework. As for the VNAV, this will see a full rewrite. Fenix openly admits that the existing system sits on very old, generalised code, which has led to oddities in vertical path building, deceleration placement, and performance figures.  The new VNAV is built from the ground up, including more accurate handling of pressurisation segments and decel points, and the team says it has captured behaviour it previously only saw in the real aircraft or full-fidelity level-D simulators. Underneath that, a brand-new ECAM infrastructure is replacing the legacy system. Both the revised VNAV and the new ECAM framework have entered limited internal testing, with small groups of subject matter experts focusing on each system, before a wider beta follows.  Fenix says the NEOs are already in a position to move into testing once the VNAV and ECAM update has been released to existing customers. Alongside this, work on proper state saving continues in the background. The team plans to share dedicated media showcasing the new VNAV and ECAM closer to release, and only then will the spotlight fully swing back to the A320neo and the experimental features being lined up for its eventual debut. A small taste of what’s to come was, however, shared, which you can take a look at here: For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmenvn</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Previews Harstad/Narvik For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmenvn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/692b7269b5c0b8d1309142cd_586411909_1171549235189099_2004527111642859920_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has shared a batch of night-time previews from its upcoming rendition of Harstad / Narvik Airport (ENEV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  The new screenshots focus on the atmosphere after sunset, with apron and terminal lighting, detailed tower work, and updated building textures all on display.  Located in Evenes, Harstad/Narvik serves as an important gateway to northern Norway and the wider Hålogaland region, making it a nice base for both domestic journeys and adventures further out towards Lofoten and Vesterålen. MM Simulations signs off by saying that more previews are on the way, so those keen to add another Norwegian stop to their route network should not have to wait too long before seeing more of ENEV in action. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbypphrel</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Perth International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbypphrel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cb176e5167ea141d458f3_ypph1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Perth International Airport (YPPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the 4th busiest airport in Australia, with a yearly average of 17 million passengers. The airport was built in the late 1930s to replace the city’s former main airport, Maylands Aerodrome. Maylands had become too small for the larger airplanes of that era and was impossible to expand. With the advent of World War 2, the Royal Australian Air Force redesigned the new facility for military purposes. Civil operations started mid-war in 1944 with Qantas Empire Airways and Australian National Airways. This happened despite protests from military authorities, who were against it due to it “undermining” their defense and camouflage needs. The government ignored the protest and authorized the airlines to move from Maylands to the new airport. They wanted to operate larger aircraft, which were too large for the older airport. Perth was granted its International status in 1952, despite not yet having a proper passenger terminal. They were using an adapted hangar as the passenger terminal was still under construction. The jet age made Perth a strategic stopover for flights to Asia. This increased its passenger figures dramatically, forcing the administration to expand the infrastructure as demand grew. A new terminal opened in the early 1960s to replace the adapted hangar terminals, finally bringing the airport into the modern era. In the 1980s, the project for a new international terminal was approved, featuring a modern design that would facilitate easy expansion whenever necessary. Construction work began in 1984, and the facility was officially opened in 1986. The international terminal was expanded from 2003 to 2004. The project added extra floor space, introduced new duty-free facilities, and modernized the infrastructure. In 2012, the airport was rated as the worst in Australia. This changed with the modernization and expansion that occurred in the years that followed. It eventually became the best airport in Australia six years later. As of 2025, they are expanding Terminal 2 again. The goal is to double its passenger handling capabilities by 2027. ​ It’s a hub for Qantas, Virgin Australia, and Virgin Australia Regional, and an operating base for Alliance Airlines, Jetstar, National Jet Express, Network Aviation, and Skippers Aviation. AirAsia, Air New Zealand, All Nippon Airways, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Southern Airlines, Emirates, Singapore Airlines, Thai Airways International, and VietJet also serve it. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout reflecting the latest changes, a highly detailed skybridge and T1 International Terminal, PBR materials, Dynamic Lighting, custom ground poly, custom jetways, high-resolution aerial imagery, and much more. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.59 (2020/2024), requiring at least 11.95 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navacm</id>
    <title>Navigraph Launches Navigraph Academy</title>
    <updated>2025-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navacm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/692c82a14440b217ad2394b7_1A40mEzrmSA-HD.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has launched Navigraph Academy, a new free training platform for those seeking more resources to sim like a real-world pilot.  Front and centre is the Virtual Private Pilot Licence (VPPL) course, which lets you practise core general aviation procedures. The VPPL course includes video lessons, written theory, quizzes, and in-sim exercises, mirroring the structure of real-world PPL training.  Students work through topics such as basic aerodynamics, aircraft handling, navigation, airspace, and standard operating procedures, with each lesson including a practical flying component that immediately applies the knowledge in the simulator. According to Navigraph, the material has been developed with real pilots and instructors to keep the syllabus as close as reasonably possible to actual aviation training while remaining accessible to newcomers.  Progress is tracked within the platform, and those who complete the full programme receive a digital certificate to mark their achievement. Navigraph Academy is free to use and does not require an active Navigraph subscription; only a standard account is required. The VPPL is the first of several planned courses, with instrument flying and instrument approaches already teased as “coming soon”.  With the trailer now live and the first course available, Navigraph Academy looks to become an interesting starting point for new simmers, and a more structured training path for people looking to take things a step up. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asc130</id>
    <title>Airplane Simulation Company Releases C-130J for DCS World</title>
    <updated>2025-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asc130"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/692ca0c445e7a732143a3f40_o_to3uVRigs-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Airplane Simulation Company has released its C-130J Super Hercules for DCS World, landing alongside the latest simulator update, version 2.9.22.17790. The module brings a deeply simulated, fully interactive C130. The Hercules arrives with a clickable cockpit, modern digital avionics, and a detailed simulation of the AE 2100D3 turboprop engines. A standout feature is the first-person loadmaster mode, letting you walk through the cargo bay, move around the exterior, and handle loads directly. The aircraft supports vehicle transport, airdrops, and even deployment of the enormous GBU-43/B MOAB, all enhanced by DCS’s new dynamic cargo system. Thanks to the update, the C-130J can also act as a mobile logistics hub, spawning Forward Arming and Refuelling Points from delivered cargo. Multi-crew is supported at launch, with pilot and co-pilot roles available, and a third station planned.  Airplane Simulation Company notes a few early-access limitations, including occasional visual glitches when unloading cargo, restrictions on re-loading previously unloaded vehicles, and an in-game manual that misbehaves in VR. The C-130J is available now for $63.99 via Steam, the Eagle Dynamics e-shop, and the Airplane Simulation Company website. Read the full DCS 2.9.22.17790 changelog here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ludecp</id>
    <title>More Previews of the LevelUp 737NG Series V2 </title>
    <updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ludecp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/692f2e1a1a9f4eeaae6ac0b3_December-Update%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. LevelUp has shared a new development update on the 737NG Series V2 for X-Plane, confirming that V2 Stage 1 has now entered the “Final Artwork” phase. According to the team, core development for this first stage is largely complete, and the focus has now shifted to finishing touches, ahead of release later this year. In this phase, the updated aircraft has been handed over to a group of livery artists, who are porting their work to the new 3D model and texture set, while the testing team validates systems and handling. The team notes that the schedule remains on track with the previously announced window, targeting a Stage 1 release before the end of the year. V2 itself is a major refresh of the freeware 737NG Series, bringing a comprehensive visual and audio overhaul, including new high-resolution textures, revised modelling, and an updated sound set.  Stage 1 will deliver the bulk of those visual and sound upgrades, while a second stage is planned to introduce an all-new cockpit model and additional refinements, and to lay the groundwork for a future 737 MAX line, built on the same assets. Alongside the written update, LevelUp released two new preview images, highlighting the reworked mode control panel and exterior detailing around the CFM56 engines, wing, and landing gear, giving a closer look at the improved materials and surface work that V2 brings to the aircraft. The 737NG Series remains a freeware download for X-Plane, combining LevelUp’s custom 3D and visual work with systems derived from the popular Zibo mod. Once a firm date for V2 Stage 1 is confirmed, we will share it. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgpoanew</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Shares New Porto Alegre Airport Previews for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgpoanew"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6931ccce57d66835f902e2eb_po1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Brazil Land Games has recently shared more images of their work on the Porto Alegre Salgado Filho International Airport (SBPA) update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024. It is the ninth busiest airport in the country, with nearly 8 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic). Originally called São João Federal Airport, it was just an air club, with its first flights dating back to 1923. It saw commercial action for the first time in 1932, when VARIG (the oldest Brazilian airline) replaced their seaplanes with land airplanes, adopting Porto Alegre as their hub. It took eight years to commission an actual passenger terminal. Its current name was adopted in 1952, after Joaquim Pedro Salgado Filho, a local politician who had died a year prior (air crash). It’s a focus city for Azul Brazilian Airlines, with a significant domestic network (fifteen destinations) and international legs to Punta del Este and Montevideo (Uruguay). The other two Brazilian giants, GOL Linhas Aéreas (thirteen domestic destinations) and LATAM Brasil (5 domestic destinations), are also regularly seen around POA. TAP Air Portugal is the sole European visitor, coming from Lisbon. Not much was said, except for the pictures themselves and the fact that it’s still undergoing development. Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tulxplane12</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Tulsa International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tulxplane12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6931cf55e88d9fe77d75f38f_tul1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ​Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Tulsa International Airport (KTUL) for X-Plane 11 and 12. The airport serves Tulsa, Oklahoma, and has a yearly average of 3.2 million passengers. The airport opened nearly a hundred years ago, in 1928, as Tulsa Municipal Airport. Its initial infrastructure was rather rough, with a one-story wood and tar “terminal” and landing strips and taxiways made of mown grass. It was busy enough at the time to be the “busiest airport in the World,” handling nearly 10,000 passengers a month, somehow outpacing Croydon Airport in London, Berlin Tempelhof, and Paris Le Bourget. In the early 1930s, Frederick Kershner designed a new terminal with an elegant Art Deco design, no more wood and tar. That building soldiered on until the 1950s, when the administration realized it was no longer sufficient for the traffic figures, leading to the construction of a new terminal in 1958. The new – and much bigger – terminal opened in 1961, qualifying it to become an International airport two years later. It hosted the 130th Fighter Wing in 1940 during the early stages of World War 2. Within a year of that, the War Department determined that Tulsa would become the site of an Air Force Plant, operated by Douglas Aircraft Corporation to manufacture and assemble bombers from 1942 to 1945. A year after the war, American Airlines purchased two ex-Air Force hangars to start their maintenance facilities in Tulsa, where they had nonstop routes to Los Angeles and San Francisco. In the 1960s, McDonnell Douglas still used the Air Force Plant for aircraft maintenance. The lease ended in 1996, when Boeing acquired it for aerospace manufacturing. The passenger terminal was renovated in the 2010s, designed by Gensler and Benham Companies. The ceilings were raised, passenger waiting areas were improved, and the gates were redesigned. It’s a hub for Omni Air International and Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, PBR textures, dynamic night lighting, hand-placed objects and vegetation, optional static aircraft, and much more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.99, requiring at least 8.91 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2exe</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Exeter Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2exe"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6931eee8fbc90023f2c2c058_exe1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Exeter Airport (EGTE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the counties of Devon, Cornwall, Somerset, and Dorset, with a yearly average of 382,000 passengers. It was officially opened in early 1937 as an airfield, with a tent serving as the terminal, before the construction of permanent structures would eventually follow. Shortly after its debut, the airport was used by the Royal Air Force as RAF Exeter, where the RAF Fighter Command was based and played a crucial role during the Battle of Britain. It was also used by the United States Army Air Forces Ninth Air Force as a troop transport base for D-Day. Immediately after the war, it was briefly occupied by a French air force fighter squadron serving under the RAF, which departed a year later. By 1947, it had been transferred to the Ministry of Civil Aviation for civilian use, although some RAF activity continued until the early 1950s. Scheduled services started in 1952, flying people to the Channel Islands and multiple charter destinations. A new terminal was built in the 1980s, along with a runway extension to ensure the safe operation of larger airplanes. The runway was recently resurfaced, and LED lighting was installed, resulting in a significant reduction in operating costs and maintenance. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR materials, and much more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.66, requiring at least 63.06 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbpng5</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack 5 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbpng5"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6933246f17e15f8058ce63ec_guin1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their fifth pack of Papua New Guinea Highland Bush Strips, featuring seven new airstrips (Dusin, Yomneri, Kanainj, Bank, Kombaku, Ambaluwa, Bundi). Bush airstrips in Papua New Guinea are generally the only gateway to certain remote villages, making them vital to their existence and the primary means of bringing in supplies. The weather is often harsh, the runways are often short and hand-carved, and the challenge is unparalleled. The pack leverages MSFS 2024’s powerful SDK to provide an even more immersive experience.  Each airstrip features their unique terminal buildings, infrastructure, signage, etc., and the developer (Ken Hall) plans to add more stuff in the near future. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.60, requiring at least 2.84 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
