<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-08-17T18:34:56.658832+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/madtash</id>
    <title>Middle Asia Developers Releases Tashkent International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/madtash"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6896b4ff6ac47aa8744b5bf0_tashkent1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Middle Asia Developers has recently released their rendition of Tashkent International Airport (UTTT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Tashkent, in Uzbekistan, with a yearly average of 8.7 million passengers, making it the 8th busiest in the Post-Soviet states. The airport’s first records date back to 1924, when the first passenger flight was completed on a Junkers R-13, flying the Tashkent-Pishpek-Almaty route.  It eventually evolved into a transportation hub during the Soviet era, embracing the jet age as soon as 1957 with the Tu-104. By 1967, Tashkent had routes to Leningrad (Saint Petersburg), Novosibirsk, Sverdlovsk, Chelyabinsk, Simferopol, certain cities in the Baltic states, the Caucasus, and some in the Far East. ‍ The airport underwent many changes during the post-Soviet era, struggling to cope with the passenger volume. Western construction companies helped out quite significantly during the mid-1990s. Terminal 2 was rebuilt in 2001 to serve over 2 million passengers a year. It has modern waiting lounges, VIP halls, restaurants, bars, duty-free shops, and even a pharmacy. ‍ Terminal 3 was launched a decade after Terminal 2, and it could handle 400 passengers per hour (half the capacity of Terminal 2). ‍ The airport has been expanded in recent years, going from 45,000 square meters to 65,000 square meters of terminal area, allowing it to handle even more passengers per hour. ‍ In August 2024, they finished another expansion project, renovating the airport’s facade while at it. Later that same year, they started expanding the arrivals hall by 2,500 square meters.  There are plans to merge the arrival and departure terminals by 2026. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, a basic interior, and much more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.64, requiring at least 984.50 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/implinc</id>
    <title>Impulse Simulations Releases Port Lincoln Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/implinc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6896bda9f875f3b9cd19917c_linc1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Impulse Simulations has recently released their rendition of Port Lincoln Airport (YPLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Port Lincoln, South Australia, with a yearly average of 199,546 passengers. The airport’s history dates back to World War 2, when it was established as a Royal Australian Air Force training facility for bomber crews. This laid the groundwork for the infrastructure that would eventually become a civil airport in the not-so-distant future. For nine years after the war, the airport remained closed, only reopening as a civilian airport in 1954. It then had a short grass runway and rudimentary passenger infrastructure. During that time period, Adelaide was the only scheduled destination. Eleven years later, the infrastructure saw major improvements with the sealing of the runway and the construction of a new terminal building, attracting airlines such as ASA (Airlines of South Australia) with their Fokker 27s.  The start of the 21st century led to many changes and improvements as the region saw its demand increase with its growth as a tourist destination. A new terminal was inaugurated in 2013, significantly increasing its passenger handling capabilities and bringing modern amenities. QantasLink and Rex Regional Express are the only airlines currently serving Port Lincoln. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an accurate terminal model and its respective interior, custom ground textures, custom terrain and vegetation, high-quality PBR texturing, realistic night lighting, custom orthoimagery, performance-friendly optimization, a custom GSX profile, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.91, requiring at least 996.74 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iamd8x</id>
    <title>Immersive Audio Releases Fly The MaddogX Soundpack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iamd8x"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6897a7c92ca37a0cc80079d8_6896ea4e62e78.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Immersive Audio has released its MaddogX Sound Immersion NG, a sound pack designed for the Leonardo Fly The MaddogX, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. Featuring more than 235 authentic sounds captured exclusively from the MD-80 series, Immersive Audio aims to deliver one of the most detailed and accurate audio experiences available for the type. Developed over eight months, the pack uses 48kHz field recordings to replicate the MD-80’s cockpit atmosphere and mechanical nuances. This includes the distinctive sound of the JT8D engines, switch clacks, air conditioning pack howls, rack fan hum, and subtle rattles and squeaks unique to the aircraft. The pack also features dynamic taxi and landing roll effects, authentic gear operation noises, and smaller quirks, such as FO window wind leak whistling sounds on climbout. Many of these features can be toggled on and off manually from the MD-80’s overhead audio control panel. The full feature list follows below: You can watch a preview video showcasing the sound pack here. Immersive Audio’s MaddogX Sound Immersion NG is compatible with the Leonardo MD-82, as well as the MD-83 and MD-88 expansions. It is available now via the Orbx store, for US$16.17, excluding sales tax. For all the latest news in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carb55</id>
    <title>Carenado Announces Beechcraft Baron B55 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carb55"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6898cbab679d4cb403ab59b0_527516492_1171259145041887_2804892709349720491_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following its first teaser in a Facebook post earlier this month, Carenado has announced that the Beechcraft Baron B55 will be coming to MSFS 2024. The B55 is known for its stable handling, solid performance, and flexibility for both private and business flying.  Further updates have since been shared, including a closer look at the cockpit, featuring an Aspen Avionics EFD1000 unit. The product is also set to feature Carenado’s new "RealXperience” concept, which aims to add extra depth to the flying experience by utilising some of the newer MSFS 2024 features, such as various wear and tear effects, dirt, vibrations, mud buildup, and bug splatters. The Beechcraft Baron family, including the short-body Baron 55, Baron 56, and long-body Baron 58, is a series of piston aircraft evolved from the Beechcraft Travel Air,  itself a twin-engined development of the Beechcraft Bonanza. Model 55 Barons were produced until the early 80s, with a total of 3,651 units manufactured between 1961 and 1983.  While Carenado has not confirmed a release date, more details, including avionics options and other features, are likely to be announced as the project nears completion. For all the latest news in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crzcsj</id>
    <title>CRZ Studio Releases The Aeroplane Manufactory Chinook SJ</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crzcsj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6898f50ed43f53e9af652922_Skjermbilde%202025-08-10%20213710.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Newcomers, CRZ Studio has recently released its first aircraft, the Chinook SJ from the Aeroplane Manufactory. CRZ Studio were founded in 2023 by two brothers, aiming to “bring highly authentic, handcrafted aircraft to the flight sim world”.  The Chinook SJ is an ultralight homebuilt kit aircraft available in two versions: one designed for the 4-stroke Rotax 912UL engine and the other for the 2-stroke Rotax 582UL engine. The 2-stroke version has now been recreated by CRZ Studio in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with the 4-stroke version coming at a later date. According to CRZ Studio, the Chinook SJ was developed using actual aircraft assembly manuals, ensuring unmatched accuracy and realism. The developers also claim that the Chinook SJ is the ideal aircraft for exploring remote islands, mountain valleys, and other inaccessible areas, thanks to its exceptional Short Takeoff and Landing (STOL) performance. CRZ Studio has announced a variety of upcoming updates for the Chinook SJ. The future releases will, according to the developer, include a custom sound set for the Rotax 582 and 912 engines, a new sport light DR2 variant, an optional Rotax 912 engine, a floats configuration, optional GPS units, and dynamic effects for dirt, mud, dust, and grime, among other features. A DLC expansion celebrating the record-breaking competition-ready Chinook variant, titled "Dan Reynolds Valdez Special," is also in development. ‍ The Chinook SJ Aeroplane by CRZ Studio is now available for $26.83 on CRZ Studio's website, exclusively for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csdttf</id>
    <title>CAT3DUAL Studios Releases Gafsa - Ksar International Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csdttf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6898fb0037a5644593a3eefb_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. CAT3DUAL Studios has recently released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, Gafsa - Ksar International Airport (DTTF). Situated near the cities of Gafsa and Ksar in Tunisia, the airport currently has no scheduled passenger flights. The airport features a 9,514-foot-long runway, three helipads, and two parking stands for aircraft. While there are no regular commercial flights, the Tunisian Air Force operates from the airport, primarily using helicopters. The newly released scenery is packed with features including a handcrafted passenger terminal, a handcrafted air traffic control tower, an accurate airfield wayfinder, custom apron flood lights, a custom windsock, and much more. The 2024 version of the scenery is available on SimMarket for approximately $9.31, with the 2020 version also offered on SimMarket at the same price. If you purchase the 2020 version, you can receive the 2024 version as a free upgrade. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350133</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350133"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689b8c8ac64be90cff774481_HVNa359.png.3357d569aa794db40a666ac1d4e25350.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released version 1.1.3 of its Airbus A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020 and 2024, delivering a range of fixes and improvements, across systems, visuals, and sounds. Key changes in v1.1.3 include refinements to the Flight Management System, fixing SEC/F-PLN display issues, VNAV constraint handling, and LNAV sequencing after go-arounds. HUD performance has been improved, with more accurate acceleration cues, proper minimum height indications, and better in-sim alignment. Brake to Vacate logic now responds correctly to runway exit changes, and brake thermodynamics have been adjusted, for slower, more realistic cooling rates.  System updates cover electrical, hydraulic, and pressurisation behaviour, including more accurate vent system effects, consistent GPU availability on spawn, and correct yellow electric pump ECAM alerts, on cargo door opening. Stability fixes address WASM-related crashes, tied to custom waypoints and certain procedures, while art updates have resolved cockpit LOD flicker, as well as various floating livery decals. The visibility of exterior lights in the wingtip assemblies has also been improved.  Furthermore, OIS enroute maps and Navigraph authentication should now be more reliable, and flap deployment sounds are now more audible across all configurations. In a significant announcement, iniBuilds also confirmed a partnership with Echo 19 Audio Productions, to deliver a complete sound overhaul for the A350. This update will bring richer and more detailed cockpit, engine, and environmental audio, aiming to provide a more immersive soundscape in future releases. You can view the full feature list for the update below: v1.1.3SystemsFIXED: Various EFIS and MFD related WASM crashesFIXED: WASM crash after inserting custom waypoint into next waypointFIXED: Overweight landing: brake temps already decreasing during landing roll, brakes cooling down too fastFIXED: Discon, incorrect track maintainedFIXED: PFD altitude vertical profile refinementFIXED: SEC/F-PLN edits and display issuesFIXED: SEC flight plan modification now displays holds on NDFIXED: SEC index button now returns to original page if pressed twiceFIXED: VD reaction in PLAN modeFIXED: Manual aircraft time entry now acceptedFIXED: Yellow electric pump ECAM missing when cargo doors openedFIXED: Pressing return on FMS performs correct action on FMS1FIXED: Brake cooling rate reducedFIXED: Notify max uplink delay message displayed correctlyFIXED: D-ATIS header and message handlingFIXED: Position time marker and data display when IRS is not alignedFIXED: Tropopause value rounding improvedFIXED: ATC COM connect armed color displayed correctlyFIXED: VHHH Kai Tak - runway length validation improvedFIXED: BTV does not disengage properly on go aroundFIXED: BTV does not disengage when ground spoilers disarmFIXED: BTV display remains at 10kts even when braking has stoppedFIXED: Changing RWY exits does not affect ROT or Turnaround time displayed on NDFIXED: Crossing Managed SPD LIMIT Pseudo-Waypoint behavior in Selected SPDFIXED: FMS 2 submenu navigation restoredFIXED: Grid heading logic correctedFIXED: LNAV sequencing after go-around path captureFIXED: Direct-To behaviour on SIDFIXED: HUD shows "No MINIMUM" indication below minimumADDED: Backing up a non-precision approach using an ILSADDED: D-ATIS previous message behaviorFIXED: Fix info on abeam pointsFIXED: Fix info not updating EFB/OISFIXED: OIS Enroute map functionality restoredFIXED: EFB lbs readout now truncates decimal placesFIXED: GSX boarding/deboarding stutters resolvedFIXED: Navigraph token resets after 6–8 hours ARTFIXED: Odd shadows toward the front of the fuselageFIXED: Nose cone mesh precision improvedFIXED: PAX signs no longer illuminateFIXED: GPU sometimes missing on spawnFIXED: "Landing" pilot camera view better aligns with HUD viewADDED: Windshield ITO effect (indium tin oxide) - Please note: Windshield ITO effect requires "windshield effects" setting on 'High' to render. SOUNDSFIXED: Flap sounds missing or inaudibleFIXED: Gear lowering sound played even if gear not lowered ‍ If you want to read the full update post, you can do so on the iniBuilds forums. The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for approximately $76.16 and requires at least 10.63 gigabytes of free storage to install. The v1.1.3 update is available now, and can be downloaded through the iniManager. ‍ For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdrkevv</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Library and KEVV Scenery Receive Free Updates</title>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdrkevv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689bc19c6316e0b87879192f_11897a_d1ace438d0804814bd0cbb79e6491ee9~mv2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr Designs has recently announced extensive updates for both their Scenery Library and Evansville Regional Airport (KEVV) scenery. ‍ Evansville Regional Airport (KEVV) Owners of X-Codr Designs’ Evansville Regional Airport can now upgrade to the new V2 version at no cost. According to the developer, the scenery has undergone extensive work aimed at enhancing both usability and visuals. These updates feature a complete rework of the ground textures, a nearly fully remodelled and retextured terminal with a custom interior, and new custom jetways that utilise X-Plane’s built-in jetway animation system. ‍ Living Scenery Technology Updates The key improvements to KEVV include significant updates to the "Living Scenery Technology." The updates now enable the scenery to interact better with moving objects. For example, according to the developers, doors will automatically open and close as people enter the terminal, and cars will stop to avoid colliding with pedestrians.  ‍ X-Codr Designs Library V2.0 The X-Codr Designs Library offers a unified collection of assets used across various sceneries. Therefore, any updates made to the design library will also affect other airports. For instance, new 3D people have been introduced with enhanced animations. ‍ A full changelog can be found below: Evansville Regional Airport V2 is available for new users now for $21.95 on the x-plane.org store, existing owners may download the update free of charge. ‍ For more details on updates made to Evansville Regional Airport, Living Scenery Technology and the X-Codr Designs Library, visit the X-Codr Website ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon. ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsla321313</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo &amp; neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsla321313"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689e9753124a2ec35bb7adce_1250410_20250810225101_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs recently updated their A321ceo and neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, further improving stability in the product line. Accessible via their experimental channel, update v11.0.1.313 addresses a stability issue that would arise when traffic add-ons inject AI traffic into the sim. The A321ceo and neo are available in their store for $69.95 each. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar099</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar099"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689e99fa36f6ed4f56b29d04_paint.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently issued another update to their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing a “healthy mix” of fixes, tweaks, visual improvements, and a set of new liveries. Update v0.9.9 brings under-the-hood changes to how the aircraft is built within Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, warranting a smoother experience overall. However, a small number of users might need to remap their controls after updating. Furthermore, the update adds a USB port to the EDM790, fixes a glitch with the yoke trim, restores the tail rope position on the ground, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ - Added three new liveries - Beacon animation is no longer affected by the time slider - EDM790 has mini usb port - Fix for dirt not acumulating sometimes - Fixed font paths in registration css - Fixed radio knobs occasionally working in opposite direction - Fixed the bad lighting on the left oil dipstick - Fixed the gap on the top left window and the frame - Fixed typo in N122PC ATC ID - Fixed yoke trim switch glitching sometimes - New initial avatar position - Restored the tail rope position on the ground - Sounds for yoke buttons and temperature gauge switch - Toe brakes are no longer depressed when loading on a parking spot The three new liveries are still work-in-progress, and one of them comes from a popular Hollywood movie involving smuggling illegal substances across the border. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shadetawau</id>
    <title>SHADESCENE Releases Tawau Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shadetawau"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689ea05e070d54ee4b675e6e_tawau1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SHADESCENE has recently released their rendition of Tawau Airport (WBKW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the Tawau Division in Malaysia and has a yearly average of 572,365 passengers. The airport was inaugurated in December 2001, replacing Tawau’s former main airport. It was small and tricky due to its very short runway (one of the shortest in Malaysia), which caused great concern overall.  The official inauguration only happened two years later, in 2003.  Its passenger terminal has one and a half stories, with two jetways and the ability to accommodate up to 8 airplanes simultaneously. ‍ Before COVID-19, the airport was operating above maximum capacity, reaching 1.8 million passengers yearly, significantly exceeding its intended 1.4 million passenger capacity. A plan was made to expand it to 2.5 million passengers and upgrade the passenger facilities and overall infrastructure. COVID put a halt to the expansion plans, and in 2022, they were still facing the same issue, constantly suffering from congestion. ‍ In 2023, the government allocated a substantial sum for an improvement program, including extra toilets, an enhanced check-in area, an expanded departure lounge, more retail spaces, and more air conditioning units. A year later, a new plan was announced, encompassing a major expansion set to begin in 2025. The expansion will bring the main terminal from 15,800 square meters to 23,500, add eight new check-in counters, and more. The new capacity would remain aligned with the previous project at 2.5 million passengers annually. ‍ AirAsia, Batik Air Malaysia, Firefly, Malaysia Airlines, and MASwings serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.02, requiring at least 345.46 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/frav11</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Updates Mega Airport Frankfurt to Version 1.1</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/frav11"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689f8fee1c68a008364b25f6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has just released an update for Mega Airport Frankfurt for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. While the changelog is brief, this update introduces optimisations that significantly decrease VRAM usage and enhance overall performance. The latest update introduces optimisations for all models, textures, LOD settings, and more. This has allowed for a reduction in VRAM usage of up to 1.6 GB, though most users can expect a slightly smaller decrease. Some users reported performance drops when facing Terminal 2. This issue was caused by the large forest north of the terminal, but it has now been resolved. The team has noted a bug with blurry textures in the scenery, and they are currently working on a patch that is expected to be released by early next week. The updated version of Mega Airport Frankfurt is now available at Aerosoft on sale for $18.41. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ifl158</id>
    <title>iFly Outlines Future Plans, Confirms MSFS 2024 Focus and MAX 9</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ifl158"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689f9451173cd50793952942_PIC02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iFly has via Discord released an official development update for its 737 MAX product, outlining planned features for the Service Pack 1 update, as well as its plans for the MSFS 2024 platform. The team made it clear that the SP1 content is still in active development, and that the update will not be released within the next three months. Amongst the changes in SP1 are a more “tablet-style” electronic flight bag (EFB), rather than the current Boeing OEM unit, accompanied by CPDLC integration via the Hoppie API, with support for online networks, as well as BATC and SayIntentions, also under review. Other planned features include cabin announcements (with and without GSX), the MAX 8-200 variant, with the type’s Mid-Cabin Emergency Doors modelled, a visual APU model, an expanded main wheel well model, and an updated fuselage model, rivets and other details.  Cabin materials will be redrawn with more texture detail, multiple seating layouts will be offered, and cockpit materials will be refined for better surface type distinction. Landing gear textures will be overhauled, LNAV behaviour will see targeted adjustments, and numerous smaller fixes will be implemented before release. The update also marks a shift in development priorities. SP1 will be the final major release to support MSFS 2020, with all future development moving to MSFS 2024, due to substantial platform differences between the two. Post-SP1 plans include a native MSFS 2024 version of the MAX 9, with the MAX 10 and MAX 7 also under consideration, only after official certification and service entry of those types. While small patches may still arrive for the current MAX 8 for 2020 after SP1, iFly’s primary focus will be advancing the series for the newer simulator. You can read the full development update on iFly's official Discord server.  For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfd148</id>
    <title>TFDi Design Shares Previews of MD-11 Art Update for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfd148"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689fa2dd315e966de6b0a662_jk6Y1LsPToAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. TFDi Design has shared a fresh set of previews on its official Discord server, showcasing the upcoming MD-11 art update. The team stated the overhaul is nearing completion, with the landing gear still undergoing final adjustments. The upcoming update, previously detailed by TFDi in early July, will be free for all existing MSFS 2020 owners. This work focuses on refining the aircraft’s exterior model, with updated textures and detailing. Among the new images is a close-up look at the MD-11’s tail-mounted no.2 engine, a signature characteristic of the MD-11 trijet. This is joined by a view of the left-hand engine and wing assembly, highlighting improvements to panel lines and rivet work. Additional shots showcase the trailing-edge flaps, as well as fuselage riveting. We also got a preview of the aft cargo door in its open position.  TFDi Design previously stated in their July update that they expected a release within 60 days, which, at the time of writing, would be in September. For all the latest flight simulation stories, Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b55rel</id>
    <title>Carenado Releases Beechcraft Baron B55 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b55rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68a1fa821d7f61f24f4eab6c_B55_FS2024_11.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has released its Beechcraft Baron B55 for MSFS 2024, available exclusively through the in-sim Marketplace. The light twin-engine aircraft arrives as the latest addition to the developer’s growing MSFS 2024 catalogue. The Baron B55 is a light twin, first introduced in 1961, as part of Beechcraft’s Baron family, which evolved from the earlier Travel Air. Production of the 55 series continued until 1983, with 3,651 units built. Powered by two Continental IO-470-L engines, producing 260 horsepower each, the aircraft is capable of cruising at around 190 knots, with a range of more than 900 nautical miles. Its six-seat layout and twin-engine configuration made it a popular choice for both private and training operations. Carenado’s rendition of the type for MSFS 2024 includes avionics options such as Aspen Avionics’ EFD1000, or traditional steam gauges, Garmin GNS530 and GNS430 units, with GTN750/650 compatibility, and the Bendix King KFC 225 autopilot. The package also features eight liveries, plus a paint kit, and an EFB with 2024 interfacing, for switching between avionics configurations. Additional systems modelled include a Garmin GMA 340 audio panel, Garmin GTX 330 transponder, weather radar, and fuel flow indicators. The aircraft is also compatible with MSFS 2024’s Career mode out of the box, with support for missions such as ferry flights and charter services. You can read the full feature list of the product below: Features The Carenado Beechcraft Baron B55 is available for purchase now through the MSFS 2024 Marketplace for $24.99. For all the latest news in flight simulation, Threshold will keep you updated. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atlprv</id>
    <title>Orbx Previews Hartsfield–Jackson Atlanta Scenery for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atlprv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68a205d1d21c9655244a663e_107-fe18cad19434a794853a40954d08fd8d%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has shared an update of its highly anticipated Hartsfield–Jackson Atlanta International Airport (KATL) for MSFS 2020 and 2024. The update was posted on its community forum earlier this week. Developed by Matteo Veneziani, this is the third and final planned preview before release. The previews highlight the Delta TechOps area and the airport’s control tower, amongst others. Delta TechOps, also known as Delta TOC, is the largest airline maintenance, repair, and overhaul facility in North America, and has been recreated in the scenery, with 1:1 accuracy. Veneziani stated that “every pipe, air-conditioning unit, and rooftop element” was individually modelled, based on real-world references. While the developer showcased the maintenance complex, he noted that the airside portion of the airport is not yet ready for display, as the ground polygon is still in progress. Remaining work includes cargo buildings on both the north and south sides, taxiway signage, approach lighting, and tunnel detailing, as well as general finishing touches. According to Veneziani, the goal is to release the scenery before Christmas. He noted that development has been underway for nearly two years, with a continued emphasis on quality over timelines. Hartsfield–Jackson Atlanta International Airport is the world’s busiest by passenger traffic and aircraft movements, serving as Delta Air Lines’ primary hub. We'll keep you updated on its release. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
