<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-09-11T18:21:49.030800+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/idscom</id>
    <title>IDS Comanche nearing completion - Threshold Exclusive </title>
    <updated>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/idscom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f1085792dfe0e5b926c39e_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="204253"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. InDepthSimulations Piper Comanche for XP11 &amp; XP12 is nearing completion; the developer has disclosed to Threshold in a recent update that the aircraft is rapidly approaching touchdown, where Piper fans can enjoy the iconic aircraft in X-Plane.  Threshold has exclusive access to the latest development updates to share with the public! We can reveal the aircraft's price will be $20.00, but the stores that will supply the aircraft are still in consideration and will be revealed later.  The PA24 is around 85% done, according to the project's lead developer; all that remains are some artwork items, some sound implementation and GPS screen integration. This has been a sticking point in the project's development to date. InDepthSimulations are looking for an experienced programmer to join the team and help them with the closing stages of the development.  We are delighted to be able to share with you some of the latest development previews of the aircraft, exclusively at Threshold!  Enjoy! </summary>
    <published>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sxasai</id>
    <title>SXAD Releases San Antonio International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sxasai" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f1e6b353915e7d5e1414c3_sai1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="575598"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SXAD has recently released their rendition of San Antonio International Airport (KSAT) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving Greater San Antonio with a yearly average of 9.4 million passengers, placing it among the busiest airports in Texas.  The airport was inaugurated in 1941, built on 490 ha of undeveloped land that was quickly taken by the US Army for training during WW2, then named Alamo Field. It hosted the 77th Reconnaissance Group, training personnel for overseas operations.  The end of the war saw its return to the city of San Antonio, followed by the construction of a second terminal in the early 1950s, along with a control tower and a baggage claim area. Then, in the late 60s, a new concourse was built with eight jet bridge gates.  In the mid 70s, a master plan was put into action to further develop the airport, with a new 33,000 square meters terminal and a larger parking garage, bringing the airport from eight to twenty seven gates.  Twenty years later, it was once again upgraded with a new parking garage that only reached completion in 2007.  In 2010, the old second terminal was closed, replaced by a brand new terminal with eight gates, designed by Corgan Associates, Inc. and 3D/International.   Aeroméxico Connect, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, VivaAerobus, and Volaris currently serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom seasonal orthoimagery, custom PBR ground textures, baked night lighting and ambient occlusion, custom airport surroundings, and more.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $19.99, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdd73</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdd73" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f3e693f93202d1f37245ff_1250410_20230902204337_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1840663"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published another development update concerning the progress on the UFT, pending 737 marketplace updates, and their upcoming 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  Randazzo begins with a note on how their Universal Flight Tablet is progressing, claiming “things are getting exciting,” with weekly updates being pushed to the beta team to ensure it’s appropriately polished. While they do not have a release date yet, it’s said to be getting closer. Their testers are currently testing the performance calculators while PMDG refines the EFB’s functionality based on their feedback.  The tablet has also been fitted into the 777, and the testing of that plane will be simultaneous with its normal beta testing, meaning it will be there from day one. The airplane, on the other hand, is still under development, and they claim it’s bringing a tremendous improvement in performance, resource utilization, and visual quality and is fairly more integrated with the simulator.  The marketplace updates are running six weeks behind because Microsoft has made some changes to their intake and approval process, dragging on for a little longer than it used to, to no fault of their own (according to their claims).  Their 737 Lineup is available on their website and the MSFS Marketplace, ranging from $34.99 to $69.99 depending on variant. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdhgh</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Hurghada International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdhgh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f5c72c07608b20b1f7bf0b_hurgha1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2228616"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Hurghada International Airport (HEGN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Egypt, serving the coastal city of Hurghada.  It was inaugurated in 1988, quickly becoming a gateway to the Red Sea Riviera. Expansions were made in the 90s and 2000s to keep up with the ever-increasing passenger figures. It played a pivotal role in transforming Hurghada into one of the busiest tourist destinations in Egypt because of its strategic location, close to the Red Sea, offering many summer activities.  The airport is served by Air Cairo, Brussels Airlines, Chair Airlines, Condor, Corendon, easyJet, Edelweiss Air, Egyptair, FlyArna, Luxair, Marabu, Pegasus Airlines, Smartwings, Sundair, TUI Airways, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Deutschland, TUI fly Netherlands, Turkish Airlines, and WizzAir. The list does not include the many seasonal charters serving the airport during summer. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom landside, updated ground layout, dynamic lighting, custom ground textures, and custom clutter, and it also includes the El Gouna private airport (HEGO). ‍ It’s available on the FSDG Store for roughly $27.00. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lesdv2</id>
    <title>Leading Edge Simulations’ DC-3 v2 Releasing on Thursday</title>
    <updated>2023-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lesdv2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f6b8fd0277c01fb6696813_dc31.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1340988"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Leading Edge Simulations’ Douglas DC-3 v2 store page is up on X-Aviation with a release date, features, and official documentation.   ‍ Releasing on Thursday, the DC-3 v2 for X-Plane 12 will feature two different variations: classic and modern, with the first one replicating the early production layouts from the 1930s and 1940s and the latter sporting modern instruments and avionics, fully developed custom systems with accurately simulated electric logic, two autopilot options, simulated engines, hydraulics, and fuel system; custom fmod sounds, particle system effects, and a maintenance system where every aircraft operation is tracked and logged. ‍ ‍ ‍  It will accompany a modern user interface with airframe information, maintenance, customization options, loadsheet control, and a checklist.  ‍ ‍ The developers also disclaim a list of things that will not be available right on release: the hydraulic system has correct indications, but X-Plane does not allow for deep interaction with it; the anti-ice systems are present yet not fully simulated; hardware support is said to be “basic” for the time being; the Sperry autopilot on the “Classic” variant doesn’t have heading mode, only the basic operations. ‍  The add-on will be available next Thursday on X-Aviation for $49.95.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nvfaoc</id>
    <title>Navigraph Adds Flight Telemetry, ATIS, OFP Reader to Charts</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nvfaoc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f7ca91ff86b086f5dd1599_AITS-Blog-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="512566"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has released an update adding three brand new features to their popular Charts software. ‍ The main feature within this update is the addition of digital ATIS. Users can now go to the “Weather” section within any airport on the map view, and view that airport’s current ATIS, along with live METAR and TAF information. The data for the ATIS can come from multiple different sources, including VATSIM, IVAO, and PilotEdge. At many larger airports within the United States, the ability to pull real-world digital ATIS information is also possible.  Navigraph has also added Flight Telemetry monitoring. This feature allows users to pull current aircraft information from the simulator, such as airspeed, altitude, ground speed, estimated time to destination, and much more. This feature can be personalized within the app, with the ability to pick and choose what information is displayed, or it can be completely turned off if desired. Finally, the team has added the ability to display Operational Flight Plans from SimBrief. This feature allows users to, according to Navigraph, make their flight planning process smoother and more efficient. This feature even more closely integrates Navigraph’s Charts product with the very popular SimBrief, after being acquired by Navigraph in 2021. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbycg</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases Gold Coast Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbycg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8dd18a74389714384d810_ycg1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="941327"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has published a teaser thread on their forums showcasing Matteo Veneziani’s work on their upcoming rendition of Gold Coast Airport (YBCG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the seventh busiest airport in Australia. It was initially built as an airstrip (Coolangatta Airstrip) in the 1930s, being heavily used by the Australian Royal Air Force during World War 2. Post-war saw its return to civilian use, progressively expanding to meet the ever-growing demands for passenger traffic in the region, especially in the 50s and 60s. International status was granted in the 1980s after they had built its current terminal (Eric Robinson Building), inaugurated by acting Prime Minister Douglas Anthony. The airport was serving up to 650,000 passengers yearly at that point. The main terminal was expanded to 27,000 square meters in 2010, doubling its size, adding 40 check-in desks, and incorporating domestic and international operations. It houses Qantas, Jetstar, Virgin Australia, Rex, Air New Zealand, and Scoot. There’s no information about the pricing or a potential release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mximyt</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Mytilene International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mximyt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8e1085669e617adb325d5_myt1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="611725"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has recently released their rendition of Mytilene International Airport (LGMT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Lesbos with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers.  Even though the airport was built in the 1940s, charter operations only started 40 years later and continue to this day regularly during summer (only Aegean and Sky Express offer a fixed year-long schedule). ‍ It was privatized in December 2015, with an agreement between Fraport/Copelouzos and the state privatization fund. They will operate 14 airports in Greece for 40 years as of 11 April 2017. ‍ Upon takeover, Fraport had a list of immediate actions to be taken on the airport, which included improved lighting, a general clean-up, sanitary facilities upgrade, service enhancement, and fire safety improvements.  ‍ Their long-term plan includes a new terminal, a new fire station, a new apron, a 185% terminal size increase, and a 29% increase in check-in counters.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom buildings, a basic terminal interior, PBR models, custom parking positions matching real life, 3D passengers, animated flags, and custom surrounding models. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.72, requiring at least 1.71 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siloei</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Loei Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siloei" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8e5ceef5670526e3cff31_loei1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2834825"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Loei Airport (VTUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Thailandese city of Loei with a yearly average of 212,000 passengers. ‍ It was opened in December 1954, approximately eight kilometers southwest of Loei, after 12 years of planning that started with Governor Thian Kerdperch’s wish to move Loei’s airport from its temporary location within the city to the outskirts.  ‍ The airport was expanded in 1968 and 1972 after the government purchased additional land, building a fire department, a larger apron, and installing navigation aids. ‍ The administration has recently purchased more land to build a larger passenger terminal. ‍ Thai Airways, Air Andaman, Nok Air, Happy Air, Solar Air, and Thai Smile Airways currently serve it. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom terminal interior, true-to-life parking spots, custom ground markings, custom night lighting, accurate light positioning, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.73, requiring at least 306.84 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflten</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Tenerife North Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflten" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8eb2de06c5ee3b1d19973_tenerife.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="267570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently released their rendition of Tenerife North-Ciudad de La Laguna Airport (GCXO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Santa Cruz de Tenerife in Tenerife - the largest and most populous island in the canaries = with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  After five years of fund gathering, the airport was built in the late 30s to improve a spot where flights were already happening regularly ten years prior with C.L.A.S.S.A. ‍ Commercial operations on the newly built airport started in 1941 with Iberia’s fleet of DH89A’s. Five years after its first proper commercial flight, the airport already had a couple of hangars, a passenger terminal, and a paved runway while also opening for domestic and international traffic—multiple runway expansions followed during the subsequent decades. ‍ The most significant runway expansion happened in 1964, when the runway was stretched to 3000 m to accommodate the DC-8, along with new navigation aids and an apron expansion. An ILS system was installed seven years later, in 1971.  ‍ That decade marked the inauguration of Tenerife South, which only came to be because Tenerife North often suffered with thick fog, the main contributor to the Tenerife tragedy of 1977 involving two Boeing 747s, still the deadliest accident in aviation history. ‍ A new terminal was inaugurated in 2002 with a four-story terminal building, 12 gates, and its international reopening after 24 years of domestic-only operations.  ‍ Air Europa, Binter Canarias, CanaryFly, Iberia, IberiaExpress, Plus Ultra Líneas Aéreas, Ryanair, and Vueling currently serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures and objects, animated jetways, animated custom vehicles, a modeled interior, realistic ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.38, requiring at least 1.99 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/codden</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Denver International Airport for X-Plane 11 and 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/codden" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64f8eef27f242211ccbf4c02_den1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1740086"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr Designs has recently released a major update to their rendition of Denver International Airport (KDEN) for X-Plane 11 and 12, delivering the culmination of two years of development time with a load of new features and improvements. ‍ Version 2.0 - free to owners of the previous version - brings a high-quality rendition of the airport as of 2023, with an up-to-date ground layout, realistic terminal interiors with multiple points of interest, animated escalators, animated people (with varying density according to the time of day), windows on buildings that mimic the optics of real glass, PBR texturing, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It uses their Living Scenery Technology plugin that warrants animated people, animated vehicles traveling at realistic speeds, animated electronic display boards on concourse B displaying time and temperature, variable AC fan blade speeds depending on temperature, and more. ‍  The complete list of features follows down below:  ‍ The scenery is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $29.95, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. As previously mentioned, owners of the previous version are entitled to a free upgrade. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2ac13</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2ac13" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64fb668b716c5dba1711f94f_cuman1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1159834"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 to version 1.3, including multiple bug fixes and two new features. ‍ The third update since its release brings the ability to switch off trim acceleration, an option to set metric air temperature and pressure units independently of each other and regional settings within the simulator, and a substantial changelog with seventeen fixes, which follows down below:  ‍ The add-on is available on their store for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lesdx2</id>
    <title>Leading Edge Simulations Releases DC-3 v2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lesdx2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64fb6ad1257527f71ebf8ae4_dc32.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="406637"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Leading Edge Simulations has recently released the v2 of their Douglas DC-3 for X-Plane 12, bringing two cockpit variants, custom-coded systems, and more. ‍ Their newly released DC-3 features an accurately modeled Douglas DC-3 with heavy use of PBR materials, ensuring great visual acuity. There are two cockpit options, ranging from the classic layout from the 1930s-1940s and a modern style with modern instrumentation and avionics.   ‍ The custom systems bring a deeply simulated electric system, two autopilot options, multiple navigation tools (VOR and ADF radios, GPS unit compatibility), a simulated hydraulic system, engines with fully simulated mixture control, a custom auto-feather mechanism, and realistic oil consumption figures depending on the engine’s health.  ‍ It also features an airframe system where every livery is individually persistent, with individual options, maintenance logs, and states, which can be controlled through a user interface. ‍ The developers also disclaim a list of things that will not be available right on release: the hydraulic system has correct indications, but X-Plane does not allow for deep interaction with it; the anti-ice systems are present yet not fully simulated; hardware support is said to be “basic” for the time being; the Sperry autopilot on the “Classic” variant doesn’t have heading mode, only the basic operations. ‍  It’s available on X-Aviation for $49.95 and is only compatible with X-Plane 12. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsasa</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Asahikawa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsasa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64fcf29998a948242f08db7d_asahi.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="552429"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Asahikawa Airport (RJEC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Asahikawa in Hokkaido, with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  ‍ After half a decade of planning, the airport was inaugurated in 1966, with scheduled service beginning that same year with Japan Domestic Airlines, flying a NAMC YS-11 to Tokyo Haneda via Okadama. It was primarily seasonal until 1970 when there was finally a year-round flight to Tokyo.  Nearly twenty years later, the airport was briefly closed for expansion work, with its sole runway being extended from 1,200 meters to 1,640 in February 1982 and then to 2,000 meters in November 1982, allowing the operation of larger jet aircraft like the DC-9, the MD-80, and the Airbus A300. ‍ In 2016, the administration made plans to build a new international terminal to the south of the old one, with 5,700 square meters of constructed area, targeting 500,000 international passengers yearly by 2030. It opened in November 2018. ‍ The airport is served by Air Do, All Nippon Airways (seasonally), Asiana Airlines, Japan Airlines, Tigerair Taiwan, and T’way Air. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom ground textures, AI traffic compatibility, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.38, requiring at least 31.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsvva</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Verona Villafranca Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsvva" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ff03f777f82a249650edbd_verona.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2889827"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Verona Villafranca Airport (LIPX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Italian city of Verona with a yearly average of 3.5 million passengers. ‍ Built as an air base in the early 1900s and heavily used during World War I, it opened to civil air traffic not long after the conflict with daily connections to Rome and multiple charter flight destinations in northern Europe. ‍ A passenger terminal was built in the late 1970s by the Province of Verona, the Commune of Verona, and the Local Chamber of Commerce. A managing society was formed shortly after, sharing the ownership between provincial governments from Veneto, Lombardy, Trentino, and Alto Adige. ‍ With healthy growth figures in the late 90s and early 2000s, the administration decided to expand the airport by constructing a new arrivals terminal, inaugurated in 2006. ‍ Aer Lingus, Air Albania, AirBaltic (seasonally), Air Dolomiti, Albawings, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings (seasonally), Finnair (seasonally), FlyOne, Jet2 (seasonally), Neos, Norwegian Air Shuttle (seasonally), Play (seasonally), Ryanair, Transavia (seasonally), TUI Airways, Volotea, and WizzAir serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, custom ground vehicles, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.06, requiring at least 374.60 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lepiap</id>
    <title>Low-End Pc Studios Releases Iquitos Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lepiap" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ff09637816a5dcf38a329e_iqutios.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1647987"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Low-End Pc Studios has recently released their rendition of Coronel FAP Francisco Secada Vignetta International Airport (SPQT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Peruvian city of Iquitos with a yearly average of 1 million passengers. ‍ It was built in the late 1920s as a gravel airstrip for military purposes, eventually evolving into a commercial airport over the following decades, along with several infrastructural upgrades and expansions.  ‍ Its current name was adopted in 1973 after a local Peruvian Air Force pilot who had fought in the war with Colombia between 1932 and 1933. ‍ The airport is of great importance to the city’s economy because it’s only accessible by air or river, meaning every urgent logistical operation has to go through the airport, which also justifies the relatively high passenger figures in comparison with the city’s population (1 million passengers yearly, and the city has less than half a million inhabitants). Said figures make it the fourth busiest airport in Peru. ‍ LATAM Peru, SAETA Peru, Sky Airline Peru, and Star Peru serve the airport year-round.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom ground mesh, PBR textures, terminal interior modeling, custom runway elevation profile, animated objects, and a performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.16, requiring at least 150.09 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
