<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-03-09T18:19:32.842138+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini109</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini109"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65dfb70fbfdc6dd323f94dbd_a300-slide4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing the spoiler arming code, numbers cutting off on VOR frequencies, and general system stability improvements. v1.0.9, the eight so far, brings a relatively modest changelog, which follows below: ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmmanc</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Manchester International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmmanc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e10409b0847eef65753e36_manchester1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 23.3 million passengers. Construction work began in 1935, and the airport was partially operating by 1937 (the official conclusion happened a year later). KLM was the first airline to launch scheduled commercial flights to the newly opened airport in 1938. It was converted into an RAF base during WW2 and played an essential role in military aircraft production and parachutist training. The post-war period saw its return as a commercial airport, with rapid growth during the 50s and 60s, where it eventually managed to be Britain's second busiest airport after London Heathrow. The airport was heavily expanded in the 80s and 90s to keep up with the exponential growth figures, eventually leading to the millionth passenger in a month mark in 1987. Plans for a new terminal were put in place, and it was opened by Princess Diana as Terminal A in 1989.  From 1997 to 2001, a second runway was built, leading to many protests from locals because natural habitats were disturbed and listed buildings had to be demolished, but they didn't have another option. New expansion work started in 2019 to keep up with the ever-growing passenger traffic figures. ‍ EasyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways have operating bases in Manchester. Many airlines from around the Globe serve it, including Air Canada, Air France, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad, Finnair, KLM, Kuwait Airways, Lufthansa, Qatar, Scandinavian Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish, Virgin Atlantic, and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, realistic lighting, custom jetways, performance-friendly optimization, realistic terminals, and custom ground textures. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $20.85, requiring at least 1.68 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdgtnp</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Releases GTNXi Pro with Full Navigraph Data Support for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdgtnp"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e10a649702b430b57a5395_tds1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TDS Sim Software has recently introduced the GTNXi Pro navigation suite for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring full compatibility with Navigraph’s navigation database and charts instead of only accepting the - rather expensive - official Garmin navdata.  The developers claim there are no setbacks or limitations from using the Navigraph database instead, with the overall experience being indistinguishably similar. The main difference, though, is the pricing: while one can subscribe to Navigraph for as little as $27 (navdata only), Garmin’s subscription plan can easily go past the four-digit mark for the worldwide database ($1869/year for the database and charts), which can be a bit steep for flight simulation usage. They have been developing this integration for two years, and it’s said to be their most challenging project yet. It’s the first time in history that a Garmin-trainer-based GTN was made compatible with Navigraph data.  The feature set is the same as the standard GTNXi, delivering an authentic replica of the real GTN 750Xi/650Xi with advanced navigation features, great levels of customization per the real unit, and high-resolution displays with great clarity. The Navigraph integration also features geo-referenced data where available, providing real-time aircraft positioning overlaid on the Jeppesen charts for extra situational awareness. Their data also allows for LPV (Localiser Performance with Vertical Guidance) approaches, RF (radius-to-fix) legs, and much more.  ‍ The GTNXi Pro subscription is available as an upgrade from the standard GTNXi for $26.95 or standalone for $70.15 on their official website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkbcn1</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkbcn1"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3a76961aaa3b024644a92_bcn1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Spain's second-largest and second-busiest airport with a yearly average of 49.9 million passengers. El Prat was Barcelona's second airport, built in 1918, after their previous airport (El Remolar) couldn't be expanded any further. It was a base for the Spanish Navy's Zeppelin fleet and was the headquarters of the Aeroclub of Catalonia. Regularly scheduled commercial service started in 1927 with Iberia. Following the end of World War 2, they built its first paved runway, making way for the first scheduled international flight in its history: a Pan American Airways Lockheed Constellation that would come over from New York regularly.  The subsequent years brought its first passenger terminal, taxiways, and a second runway, allowing the airport to keep growing. It would handle a million passengers annually within a decade of that construction effort. The airport's growth had halted after the 1970s, and the imminence of the 1992 Summer Olympic Games led to an urgent makeover: two more terminals were built, and jetways were finally introduced. It's a hub for Iberia, Level, Air Nostrum, and Vueling and a focus city for EasyJet and Ryanair. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air Transat, airBaltic, Avianca, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, ITA Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, VDGS, custom satellite imagery, elevation data based on LiDAR scans, custom ground poly, realistic night lighting, and more. It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $14.61, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bougpk</id>
    <title>Boundless Announces Glasgow Prestwick Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bougpk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3aaf22d46a53d71486979_egpk.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently announced the development of Glasgow Prestwick Airport (EGPK) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the second busiest airport in Glasgow (Scotland), with a yearly average of 445,211 passengers. It was officially opened in 1935 despite operating as an airfield for longer (since the early 1910s). Passenger facilities were added in 1938 and remained untouched until the government made them compatible with jet aircraft. ‍ The RAF used Prestwick to control trans-Atlantic flights during World War 2 as a gateway for US Army personnel and a training base for RAF pilots. ‍ Its commercial duties started right after the war, with a transatlantic flight between Prestwick and New York. ‍ The main runway was expanded in 1960 from the original 2,100 meters to 3,000 meters, which is still its current length. ‍ During the early 1990s, Prestwick was in shambles, desperately needing “rescue,” which came in the form of a takeover from a Canadian entrepreneur (Matthew Hudson), who constructed a railway station beside it, making it the first Scottish airport with its own railway station. To this day, Matthew’s rescue effort is unanimously recognized as heroic. ‍ Ryanair embraced Prestwick in 1994, with a route from Dublin and a second route a year later to London Stansted. A third one followed suit in 1998, taking passengers to Paris-Beauvais. ‍ 1998 also marks the ownership transfer from Matthew Hudson to the Stagecoach Group, a transport group based in Perth, primarily focused on buses, trams, and train services. They sold it three years later for 33 million pounds. ‍ Infratil, a Kiwi company, was the new owner from 2001 onwards, responsible for revamping the main terminal in 2005 and redecorating most of it with very controversial touches. ‍ After over a decade of ownership, Infratil called it a day and passed it on to a new owner, which was no less than the Scottish government. They paid an incredible sum of 1 pound for it. ‍ It’s currently served by Ryanair, with flights to Alicante, Faro, Lanzarote, Málaga, and Tenerife-South. ‍ There’s no release date, pricing, or feature information, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerbar</id>
    <title>Aerosoft/sim-wings Release Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerbar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e63e8cfc4a16127d18690b_LEBL_116.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft/sim-wings have recently released their rendition of Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Spain's second-largest and second-busiest airport with a yearly average of 49.9 million passengers. El Prat was Barcelona's second airport, built in 1918, after their previous airport (El Remolar) couldn't be expanded any further. It was a base for the Spanish Navy's Zeppelin fleet and was the headquarters of the Aeroclub of Catalonia. Regularly scheduled commercial service started in 1927 with Iberia. Following the end of World War 2, they built its first paved runway, making way for the first scheduled international flight in its history: a Pan American Airways Lockheed Constellation that would come over from New York regularly.  The subsequent years brought its first passenger terminal, taxiways, and a second runway, allowing the airport to keep growing. It would handle a million passengers annually within a decade of that construction effort. The airport's growth had halted after the 1970s, and the imminence of the 1992 Summer Olympic Games led to an urgent makeover: two more terminals were built, and jetways were finally introduced. It's a hub for Iberia, Level, Air Nostrum, and Vueling and a focus city for EasyJet and Ryanair. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air Transat, airBaltic, Avianca, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, ITA Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with realistic 3D terrain made from DEM data, custom interiors, sloped runways, custom aerial imagery, custom ground textures, VDGS, custom animated jetways, an up-to-date layout, realistic night lighting, and more. It's available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $23.99, requiring at least 3.7 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkbarc</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkbarc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3a79e20bf83fad30d0730_bcn7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently issued an update to their newly released rendition of Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL)  for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing a list of issues based on user feedback. The scenery’s first update sports extra optimization on the terminals, AFCAD airline code adjustments, correct gate numbers on terminal 2, light color tweaks, and more. The changelog follows below:  They also stated it has already been sent to the vendors and should be available on all platforms soon. MK’s Barcelona can be yours for roughly $14.55 (on sale) on OrbxDirect, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/axvarn</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Varna Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/axvarn"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e64521e9dcf7f105ea8558_varna1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos has recently released their rendition of Varna Airport (LBWN) for X-Plane 12, the third largest airport in Bulgaria, averaging 2 million passengers per year (pre-pandemic), serving Varna and the northeastern part of the country. It was built in the 1940s to replace Varna’s former main airport - Tihina Airport - which was deemed too primitive for the demands of a modern city. It was enthusiastically built with the help of residents, with constant improvement work being done over the decades to keep it current, with the most notable changes being a new terminal in 1972 and a new runway in 1974. A new passenger terminal was built 11 years ago, replacing the former from the 1970s and significantly increasing passenger handling capabilities with an area of 18,000 square meters.  It’s a hub for BH Air, Bulgaria Air, European Air Charter, Voyage Air, and WizzAir and is visited by Austrian, easyJet, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Volotea, and Turkish.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom night lighting, 3D vegetation, animated marshallers, an accurate ground layout, custom 3D buildings, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.37, requiring at least 3.91 GB of free hard disk space to install. X-Plane 11 owners might e-mail Axonos for a XP11 compatible version. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samsan</id>
    <title>SamScene Releases Sanya Phoenix International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samsan"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e649eb1df8f9b1c98e781c_sanya1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SamScene has recently released their rendition of Sanya Phoenix International Airport (ZJSY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Sanya in South Central China, with a yearly average of 16.6 million passengers. The airport was opened in 1994, covering an area of 7,000 acres, with a combined terminal area of 85,000 square meters after its last expansion in 2011.  It’s currently undergoing further expansion work, scheduled to reach completion in 2025, adding another 15,000 square meters of terminal area and 78 stands, bringing the passenger handling capabilities to 25 million a year. It’s the 20th busiest airport in China as of 2017, served by 9 Air, Aeroflot, Air Busan, Air China, Beijing Capital Airlines, Cambodia Airways, Chengdu Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, China United Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Hebei Airlines, Hong Kong Airlines, Loong Air, MIAT, SCAT Airlines, Tibet Airlines, XiamenAir, and more. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, detailed terminals, animated custom jetways, detailed surroundings, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.08, requiring at least 3.98 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mestxp</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Queen Tamar Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mestxp"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e7a7614b86a8772d427ca7_mestia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Skyline Simulations has recently released their rendition of Queen Tamar Airport (UGSM) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving Mestia in Georgia, with a yearly average of 9,300 passengers as of 2022. Mestia Airport was part of Georgia’s plan to increase regional tourist figures. It was built in 2010 with a GEL 8 million investment, with an architectural project that boasts a modern glassy style that contrasts with the natural surroundings and does not impact the environment. Designed and created by Jurgen Mayer-Hermann, the BBC considers the airport one of the world’s most beautiful.  With a 1,158-meter runway at 1,456 meters above sea level, the range of aircraft that can fly into this airport is limited. It’s currently only served by Vanilla Sky with their Let L-410 UVP-Es, taking passengers to Kutaisi, where passengers can connect with the rest of Europe. The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom OSM data, PBR materials, custom 3D vegetation, custom 3D objects, high-resolution buildings, animated flags, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.65, requiring at least 4.49 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pksmel</id>
    <title>PKSIM Releases Melilla Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pksmel"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e7adfb73d0eca37319f930_mel1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PKSIM has recently released their rendition of Melilla Airport (GEML) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Melilla, an autonomous city of Spain in North Africa with a yearly average of 500,000 passengers.  ‍ It was opened in 1969, and beforehand, tourists had to visit Melilla through Nador International Airport, then called Tauima Aerodrome, in Morocco (both before and after its independence).  Sporting a 1,433-meter-long runway, it’s mostly suitable for small regional aircraft such as the ATR, Dash 8s, etc. While theoretically, an A320/B738 and their smaller variants could land somewhat safely, the maximum fuel range (they can’t fill it up entirely because the runway is very short) is not enough to reach most countries in central Europe, making it infeasible. It’s served by Air Nostrum (Iberia Regional), the only airline connecting Melilla to the World as of 2024. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR textures, GSX compatibility, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.35, requiring at least 389.42 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flbsfo</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Previews San Francisco International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flbsfo"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e9645d1ed8b7e8943d957c_sanfran1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam Studios has recently previewed their work on San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator and launched their Discord server for future product previews, support, and more. San Francisco International is the second-busiest airport in California, with a yearly average of 57 million passengers, only behind Los Angeles International.  It’s a hub for United Airlines (44% of the market share) and Alaska Airlines (10.66% of the market share) and is visited by multiple international carriers such as Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air New Zealand, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, and WestJet. According to Flightbeam, the upcoming scenery will be their most detailed work yet, sitting high above their previous releases regarding visual complexity, quality, and performance, hence the “Captain’s Edition” title.  ‍ It’s said to be inching closer to completion, with a potential release happening before summer if things go according to plan. The pictures shared cover International Terminal A and its surroundings, and further previews will be shared closer to release. All the terminals have been revamped from the inside out. There’s no price or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aswmad</id>
    <title>Aerosoft/sim-wings Update Madrid Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aswmad"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e96e4fba3cad57f21c7279_AS_LEMD_Madrid_XP12%20(33).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft/sim-wings have recently updated their rendition of Adolfo Suárez Madrid-Barajas Airport (LEMD) for X-Plane 12, bringing SAM improvements, airport functionality tweaks, and more. It was constructed in 1927 and opened in 1931, with commercial operations starting two years after the official inauguration. It was initially unpaved, and the paving process only began in 1940.  The National Terminal, now T2, was inaugurated in 1954 after mere months of construction. It was considered a first-class international airport in 1957. Terminal 1 was constructed in the 1970s during the air travel boom, which was a direct consequence of the advent of the Boeing 747. It reached 4 million passengers yearly during the period that led to its construction. In the 1990s, the terminals saw further expansion, which happened again with the construction of Terminal 4 in 2004, significantly increasing its passenger handling capabilities. With a yearly average of 61 million passengers, it’s the busiest airport in Spain and the 5th busiest in Europe. It’s a hub for Air Europa, Iberia, Iberia Express, Iberia Regional, Plus Ultra Líneas Aéreas, and World 2 Fly, and an operating base for Iberojet, Ryanair, and Wamos Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Aeroméxico, Air Arabia, Air China, Air France, Air Transat, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Finnair, Korean, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Chile, LATAM Perú, Lufthansa, Transavia, Turkish, United Airlines, and WizzAir also serve it. Update 1.1.0 brings a hefty changelog, which follows below: ‍ The scenery is available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $25.60, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inj120</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates John F. Kennedy International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inj120"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65eb7b99fbec3392f350d7a8_inijfk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated their rendition of John F. Kennedy International Airport (KJFK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, focusing on improving its performance with model optimization, LOD tweaks, and more. ‍ The busiest international gateway to the United States is served and visited by over 90 airlines, covering all the inhabited continents around the globe. JetBlue tops the market share chart, with 28.8% or 15,624,961 passengers, followed by Delta Air Lines and American Airlines, with 28.4% (15,390,437) and 14.5% (7,870,971), respectively. From foreign operators, Air France leads the way with 1.9% of the total market share or 1,025,339 passengers. Update 1.2.0 adds the option to completely disable interiors and replace them with parallax windows and brings LOD value adjustments, performance-friendly material resolutions, LODed jetways, model tweaks, etc. The changelog follows below: The scenery is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.21, requiring at least 4.47 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bcn102</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bcn102"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3a7937f6e7835f7124d50_bcn5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has released another update to their rendition of Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing more issues brought up by the community. Update 1.0.2, claimed to be their biggest and quickest update ever, adds extra interior details on Terminal 1, improves detailing on Terminal 2, fixes some textures, brings better ground service equipment positioning, and more. The changelog follows below: ‍ ‍ MK’s Barcelona can be yours for roughly $14.55 (on sale) on OrbxDirect, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inu211</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A300-600 and BelugaST for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inu211"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65eb8deb5a3e794e89ad96d6_beluga1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniBuilds has recently updated their X-Plane 12 fleet (Airbus A300-600R and BelugaST) with a comprehensive list of fixes, improvements, and flight model tweaks. The updates (v2.1.1 on the A300 and v1.1.4 on the BelugaST) address the nose landing gear light not working, flight model improvements, engine fixes, system freeze mitigations, and more. Both changelogs follow below: ‍  The A300 and the BelugaST are available on the iniBuilds Store for $67.49 and $43.38 (on sale), respectively. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
