<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-09-26T18:32:07.798658+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t320ra</id>
    <title>ToLiss Announces Airbus A320ceo Release Date</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t320ra"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cd9c4b874d424ab014fe5b_TOPOST---a320-2025-09-1910_09%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After releasing the A320neo for X-Plane in 2023, ToLiss has announced that the much-loved A320ceo will soon join the line-up, coming for X-Plane 12 next Friday, as an expansion package. First launched in the mid-1980s and entering service with Air France in 1988, the A320ceo was revolutionary for introducing all-digital, fly-by-wire controls to the airliner market. The family grew to include the A318, A319, and A321, and became a workhorse for airlines across the globe. The ToLiss A320ceo will come with both the CFM56-5B4 and IAE V2527-A5 powerplants, and will require the ToLiss A320neo base package to run. ToLiss has confirmed that pre-release copies of the A320ceo expansion will be going out to streamers and reviewers very soon, so expect full previews, walkthroughs, and performance showcases in the coming days. ToLiss hasn’t confirmed which platforms it will release on just yet, but going by past launches, you can expect to see it available through the X-Plane.org Store, Aerosoft , and Simmarket. For the full post, visit this link. The ToLiss A320ceo is releasing Friday, Sep. 26. The expansion will be priced at $29.95.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inifact</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Cape Town International Airport Scenery for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inifact"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cdc146dee8977f5bff03da_5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently announced its latest scenery pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, Cape Town International Airport. iniBuilds aims to provide an accurate representation of the airport, along with a detailed 12-meter Digital Elevation Model that captures the stunning landscapes surrounding Cape Town, including the iconic slopes of Table Mountain, and even its cable car. iniBuilds states that the airport will provide “unparalleled” accuracy while also striving for the “best performance possible,” achieved through Level of Detail (LOD) optimisation, the latest MSFS SDK features, and full configurability via iniManager. Furthermore, the scenery will include handcrafted ground textures, unique texture sets, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, objects, and surroundings, custom taxi signage, dynamic airport lighting, an official GSX profile, and more. The scenery will be available soon for $20 (excluding VAT) and has been “built from the ground up” for MSFS 2024. For more on Cape Town International Airport, check out iniBuild’s press release. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teikofskbq</id>
    <title>TEIKOF Studio Releases Ernesto Cortissoz International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teikofskbq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cdca3d122bf85099764ec5_548507515_784219594368128_4366000255631816655_n%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TEIKOF Studio has just released Ernesto Cortissoz International Airport (SKBQ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Ernesto Cortissoz International Airport serves Barranquilla, the capital of the Atlántico department in Colombia. It was originally opened in 1981 and is named after Ernesto Cortissoz, a pioneer of Colombian aviation. Today, it is a focus city for both Avianca and the somewhat controversial airline, Aeroscure. With just under 3 million passenger movements per year, the airport can accommodate widebody aircraft, including the Boeing 747, with its 3-kilometre-long single runway. TEIKOF Studio's virtual recreation of Ernesto Cortissoz features accurately modelled airport facilities, high-resolution PBR textures, custom ground markings, immersive night lighting, and more. The Airport is available for PC and Xbox on the in-game Marketplace for $16.99, and is compatible with both MSFS 2020 and 2024. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/azdarafdevu</id>
    <title>AzurPoly Shares New Development Update on the Upcoming Dassault Rafale</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/azdarafdevu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cdd1666df993b87ab0db1e_xz24i6weelfbqjmhonde.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. AzurPoly has just shared a new development update on their upcoming officially licensed Dassault Rafale for Microsoft Flight Simulator. AzurPoly states that the majority of the remaining work involves developing the unique systems for the Rafale. These systems have been entirely created from scratch due to their specificity. We didn't receive a significant update about the exterior model; however, AzurPoly noted that they are "really happy with how it's turning out." They also stated that the level of detail for the Rafale has been enhanced even further than what they achieved with the Jaguar. Cockpit modelling and texturing have progressed significantly since the last development update. As a result, AzurPoly has begun sharing interior screenshots. However, AzurPoly states that things may be subject to change. MSFS 2020 compatibility remains uncertain, with AzurPoly noting that MSFS 2024 presents significantly better options overall, including enhanced visuals and performance. Nonetheless, a port for MSFS 2020 is still a possibility. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdsgtn1303</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Updates GTNXi Suite for MSFS and X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdsgtn1303"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ce1bdbff86b55acc489a53_r66.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. TDS Sim Software has issued an update to their GTNXi Suite (750Xi and 650Xi) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 &amp; 2024 and X-Plane, bringing bug fixes, addressing a METAR server issue, and featuring internal changes for an upcoming feature. ‍ The MSFS version has been updated to version 1.3.0.3 and addresses the METAR requests not working anymore due to a file format change, the Working Title G3X integration not sending procedure turn legs, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Furthermore, the default Robinson R66 Turbine now features the GTN750Xi integration.  ‍ On the other hand, the X-Plane version has been updated to version 1.0.0.7, which also fixes the METAR requests that are not working due to a file format change and a couple of bug fixes. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ ‍ The TDS GTNXi add-on can be purchased on their official website for $76 each (MSFS/X-Plane). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/at98ib</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Wolf’s Fang for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/at98ib"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d00d4f6aed88b4e5e497d5_FlightSimulator2024_CQYyv0wXUT.png.51ef8f4b82c91cc0d96964ba72cecc80.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has announced the infamous Wolf’s Fang Runway (AT98) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a recreation of the private Antarctic ice strip, operated by White Desert. The scenery is planned as freeware, with a release marked as “coming soon”. The package focuses on the site’s distinctive blue-ice runway and expedition outpost. iniBuilds says the team has produced a bespoke texture set for ice and snow, custom lighting suited to the environment, and hand-placed clutter, such as tents, vehicles, and static aircraft. The airport layout reflects the current real-world position. Level of detail optimisation is applied across models, and the scenery uses the latest MSFS SDK features for performance. Wolf’s Fang also ties into long-range operations from Cape Town International. Each season, Hi Fly’s Airbus A340-300 and other types connect Cape Town to Wolf’s Fang, over roughly 2,600 nautical miles. iniBuilds highlights that the route can be recreated in MSFS 2024, alongside its Cape Town (FACT) scenery and forthcoming A340 airliner. ‍Scenery Features We’ll keep you updated on Wolf’s Fang and its release. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inifact245</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Cape Town International Airport (FACT) for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inifact245"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d3f63798e106fe93acc246_fact1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Cape Town International Airport (FACT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves the city of Cape Town, South Africa, and has a yearly average of 10 million passengers. It opened in 1954, replacing the city’s previous airport, Wingfield Aerodrome. From humble beginnings as a domestic airport, it quickly reached international status with the introduction of a direct flight to Britain. In the early 1990s, the airport’s ownership was transferred from the state to a private company (Airports Company South Africa), and it was renamed a politically neutral “Cape Town International Airport” instead of the pre-apartheid “D. F. Malan Airport.” Growth skyrocketed at the beginning of the twenty-first century, from 6.2 million annually in 2005 to 8.4 million between 2007 and 2008.  The airport underwent its first major expansion in 2010 in preparation for the World Cup. This expansion consisted of developing a central terminal building linking the domestic and international terminals and greatly expanding its passenger handling capabilities. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life airport landside, custom night lighting, 180+ handcrafted models, custom high-definition jetways, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $20.23, requiring at least 6.59 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a300105</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A300-600R Airliner Premium for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a300105"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d3f89d03e7c7d81a86c2e7_cargoo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued an update to their A300-600R Airliner Premium for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, fixing a wide range of issues, including stutter mitigation, animation fixes, and more. Update v1.0.5 mitigates a stutter with lights on, fixes the cargo door animation, restores the standby compass, and addresses several other minor bugs and visual glitches. Furthermore, they have also added the official LIDO charts accompanying the new platform. The complete changelog follows below: v1.0.5 Fixed - Stutters and freezing when beacon or strobe lights are turned on (multiple user reports) Fixed - CWS and CMD both active simultaneously Fixed - Constraint mode enabled by default Fixed - FO side DH button does nothing when clicked  Fixed - TCAS STBY ECAM should appear when transponder is set to XPDR Fixed - Blue arrow drawn on curved path even when curved path option is disabled Fixed - TOD is drawn based on curved path regardless of settings Fixed - Altitude intercept point shown on curved path instead of straight path Fixed - All EFB checklists were categorized as “Preflight” Fixed - Strobe lights not working as intended Fixed - Clouds bleeding through virtual cockpit Fixed - FLEX TEMP pushbutton sound missing Fixed - Typos in standby compass labels Fixed - No dome light splash in cabin (Pax GE) Fixed - Navigation lights too large Fixed - Landing elevation display half-dark at night Fixed - Landing elevation flickering Fixed - Wind data input order incorrect on DES forecast page Fixed - DES forecast winds not importing correctly Fixed - INIT B page: ALTN and FINAL fuel values cannot be edited during refuel Fixed - Missing ground roll and reverse thrust sounds Fixed - Elevator stuck in full down position Fixed - Landing light artifacts visible under wings Fixed - Floating light orb on main deck cargo Fixed - Cargo door animation and logic issues Fixed - V2 calculated lower than Vls Fixed - Missing copilot model in cockpit (GE Pax) Fixed - Standby compass lighting missing Fixed - Single chime for master caution stops after fire test Fixed - CPT TERR terrain display rendering incorrectly (solid green) Fixed - Vertical guidance symbols drawing off-track Fixed - Charts A/C symbol not pointing in flight direction Fixed - DME resolution too low Fixed - Missing tooltip for standby compass Fixed - Missing tooltip for captain and FO yoke show/hide switches Fixed - Charts page not refreshing departure/destination airports after SB input Fixed - TCAS showing INOP status Added - LIDO charts Added - Option to disable “Engine Covers On by Default” for Cold &amp; Dark spawns Added - Functional standby compass The add-on is available at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $60.71, requiring at least 3.61 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-set-to-arrive-on-playstation-5-on-december-3rd</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 Set to Arrive on PlayStation 5 on December 3rd</title>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-set-to-arrive-on-playstation-5-on-december-3rd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673bddf79fe0f69194d99625_MSFS2024_JPG-9de6e8972db1e3f8fc95-scaled.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. For the first time in over 30 years, Microsoft Flight Simulator is being released on a non-Microsoft platform. Microsoft and Sony have announced that Microsoft Flight Simulator will be available on PlayStation 5 starting December 8th of this year. Players who pre-order either the deluxe or premium deluxe editions will receive early access on December 3rd. Support for PS VR2 will also be added in 2026 through a free update. Additionally, Sony has confirmed that the DualSense controller, along with its adaptive triggers, will respond to different speeds and surface types on the ground while providing varying resistance in the air. ATC communication will also be transmitted through the controller's speaker. Preorders have already begun, and those who preorder will receive the Northrop T-38A Talon. For everyone else, the Boom Supersonic XB-1 demonstrator will also be released concurrently. For the full press release, check out PlayStation’s blog. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmshhn</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Announces Frankfurt–Hahn for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmshhn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d534324c9d0860eac94ed1_550589517_1118884870455536_1681818681889143084_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has unveiled its next airport project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Frankfurt–Hahn (EDFH). The team shared a first look via Facebook, showing sneak peeks of the airport’s ATC tower. Frankfurt–Hahn comes with an interesting history. Once a United States Air Force base during the Cold War, Hahn was home to F-16 squadrons and more than 13,000 personnel. After the base closed in 1993, the German government converted it into a civilian airport.  By the early 2000s, low-cost carriers, most notably Ryanair, had established a strong presence, marketing the airport as a more affordable alternative to Frankfurt Airport. With a 3,800-metre runway, it is capable of handling wide-body aircraft and serves as a base for a range of low-cost and cargo carriers. MM Simulations has yet to share a feature list, release date, or pricing, but with development already showing detailed tower modelling, a full reveal does not seem far off. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inipcr</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Impulse 100 “Pocket Rocket” for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inipcr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d550de67ce0e4e06216ca3_FlightSimulator2024_oRffQs6kZ4_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released the Impulse 100, also known as the “Pocket Rocket”, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The aircraft is a single-engine, experimental design, known for its nimbleness and performance, and powered by a 450 shp Allison turbine. Thanks to being wrapped in lightweight, carbon-honeycomb composite materials, the Impulse 100 has a thrust-to-weight ratio, that’s unusual for a two-seat prop aircraft. iniBuilds describes the aircraft as having been developed with “careful attention to detail,” featuring custom-tuned flight dynamics, intended to replicate its nimble, high-performance nature.  Beyond handling, the model includes a detailed electrical and fuel system, complete with functional circuit breakers, and a turbine engine simulation that accounts for hot starts, ITT behaviour, and failure conditions. The cockpit comes fitted with Working Title’s G1000 NXi suite, with custom engine and system pages, as well as annunciation support. A variety of animations, from gear flex to canopy operation, are included, alongside rain, icing, exhaust heat, and smoke effects. Six liveries are provided by default, each paired with a distinct interior. The full feature list can be read here: Aircraft Features: For the full details, you can read iniBuilds' Blog Post here. The Impulse 100 Pocket Rocket is now available for both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024 via the iniBuilds Store, priced at $16.22 (excluding taxes). For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mswu20</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update 20: Japan for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mswu20"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d55862028e824592b538f9_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has released its latest world update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is the twentieth world update, and like the very first one, the team has returned to Japan to enhance the country further. This update includes updated areas and cities, new points of interest, handcrafted airports, and more. Microsoft has updated several cities, including Hiroshima, Kyoto, Osaka, Sapporo, and Tokyo. By using advanced photogrammetry and TIN surface texturing, Microsoft collaborated with Bing Maps, Gaya, and Asobo to enhance the representation of these cities. The new world update features 67 points of interest (POIs) located throughout Japan. These include famous landmarks such as Osaka Castle and Fukuoka Tower. Additionally, the update includes five handcrafted airports created by Gaya: Hokkaido Spaceport, Kitakyushu Airport, Rishiri Airport, Sado Airport, and Satsuma Iōjima Airport. The new world update is now available for free in the in-Sim Marketplace for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssq3u</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Provides Q3 Update, Updates 727</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssq3u"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d569c8447617c919325db2_Q3-header.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlightSim Studio has provided a roundup of its current projects following the summer break, released 727 Super27 expansion, as well as given some updates, on the newly confirmed 727-100, the E-Jets closed beta, and native MSFS 2024 Tecnam updates. The 727 Super27 expansion has now released, and FSS also provided two posts that detailed visual refreshes and system work. The headline change is an EFIS fit, paired with a new autopilot, that adds VNAV modes and RNAV approaches. The 727 has now also been updated to v1.1.3. Documentation is already available, and creators should have access to preview content. As a reminder, Super27 is an expansion that requires a base 727 installation (passenger or freighter).  The EFIS and new autopilot operate with the GNS-XLS and remain optional, while the digital VSI with TCAS can be used in the base 727 when Super27 is installed. Alongside that, the studio has formally begun work on the 727-100. The plan covers a dedicated freighter and a dedicated passenger variant; convertible models are not currently planned. A Super27 treatment for the -100 is under consideration for later, but the immediate priority is to bring the variant fully into the sim first. On the E-Jets side, closed beta testing continues, with a focus on LNAV/VNAV, performance prediction, and autopilot behaviour. Issues highlighted by testers include waypoint skipping on the lateral path, intermittent drops on the vertical profile, autothrottle oscillation during step climbs, take-off Flight Director sequencing, and unreliable fuel and time estimates.  Two departure-routing bugs have been resolved internally, though other items remain. The team is also integrating Navigraph data into the new MCDU to replace problematic stock data. This work has slowed some bug-fixing, but is expected to reduce nav-data-related reports once complete. VNAV logic already follows generated vertical profiles, handles step climbs and pre-TOD descents, and can fly RNAV approaches; however, VNAV is not enabled in the current closed beta, as stability and path generation are being improved first. Finally, the Tecnam P2006T and P2012 are being prepared as native Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 releases. The P2006T is set to receive an enhanced 3D model, new textures, improved flight dynamics, a new FS24 EFB, and a native walkaround.  The P2012 is due for improved sounds, an FS24 EFB, and a native walkaround. Flight Sim Studios has not provided release windows for these aircraft, noting that timelines depend on parallel work elsewhere. For the full details, you can read the official update on FSS' website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msll22</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Local Legend 22: The NAMC YS-11 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msll22"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d5819e7982c57e719b6271_MSFS_NAMC_NoSnipe_NoLogo_NoText.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has, in conjunction with World Update 20, released Local Legend 22, bringing Japan’s post-war NAMC YS-11 airliner to both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024.  Developed by the Nihon Aircraft Manufacturing Corporation in the late 1950s, the YS-11 first flew in 1962 and entered service three years later. A straightforward, robust design, low wing, pressurised cabin, and tricycle gear helped it find work with civil and military operators worldwide.  Power comes from a pair of Rolls-Royce Dart Mk. 542-12K turboprops, driving four-blade, constant-speed propellers, giving the YS-11 plenty of short-field capability. In the simulator, the YS-11 is offered in two variants, Passenger and VIP Charter, and comes with a set of period-appropriate liveries. Performance figures presented with the release include a service ceiling of 23,000 feet, a maximum range of 1,485 miles, and a typical cruise speed of nearly 294 mph.  The YS-11 also boasts impressive take-off and landing distances of 3,642 feet and 2,165 feet, respectively. For the full read, you can find Microsoft's blog post here. Local Legend 22 is now available via the in-sim marketplace for $19.99, with rental options including a seven-day pass for $9.99, a three-day pass for $6.99, and a one-day free trial. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ahdhlm</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Teases de Havilland Mosquito for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ahdhlm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d6b53c08c6063f0da56c19_553754326_1472243147602593_3308607875618847901_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aeroplane Heaven has recently taken to Facebook to tease yet another project, providing a set of work-in-progress screenshots that reveal the legendary de Havilland DH.98 Mosquito. This reveal lands days after the developer officially announced its B-25J Mitchell, meaning Aeroplane Heaven now has two iconic World War II bombers for MSFS in the pipeline.  Nicknamed the “Wooden Wonder” (or simply the “Mossie”), the Mosquito was one of the most versatile combat aircraft of the Second World War. It had a plywood construction, twin Rolls-Royce Merlin engines, and was a fast, agile, and adaptable aircraft, serving as a bomber, night fighter, pathfinder, and reconnaissance platform.  It even carried out some of the war’s most daring precision strikes, like the famous Amiens Prison raid. The early screenshots showcase a nicely detailed cockpit, complete with scuffed paint, weathered fittings, and authentic wartime instrumentation.  It’s a world of chunky levers, green-painted panels, and exposed wiring, showing off what Aeroplane Heaven is well known for. Externals also make an appearance, giving us a peek at the landing gear and fuselage lines, that defined the Mosquito’s unmistakable profile. Aeroplane Heaven has kept specifics close to its chest. We don’t yet know which Mosquito variants will be modelled, or what the release timeline will be. From the look of things, the 3D modelling phase is well underway, but the larger details are still under wraps.  We’ll keep you updated on the Aeroplane Heaven Mosquito! For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniwfr</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Wolf’s Fang Runway for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniwfr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68d6c4ea83cfaced5d66d888_FlightSimulator2024_Q7uKv5REQ9_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just released their Wolf’s Fang Runway (AT98) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing an Antarctic blue-ice strip to the sim as free scenery. The airfield, used seasonally by operations in Queen Maud Land, is represented with a bespoke texture set for ice and snow, custom environment-specific lighting, and detailed camp assets, vehicles, and static aircraft. The layout reflects the current site, and iniBuilds has done some level-of-detail work to ensure satisfying performance. Wolf’s Fang is modelled as a long, true-course runway, cut into glacial terrain, notable for its distinctive surface and remote setting.  Accompanying the release is a brief navigation guide, covering route suggestions from Cape Town, basic procedures, and waypoint tips, for sim briefings and FMS entry. The feature list of Wolf's Fang follows below: iniBuilds’ Wolf’s Fang Runway scenery is available for free on the iniBuilds store. The download weighs in at roughly 230 MB, with an installed size of about 498 MB. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
