<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-02-12T18:23:05.068393+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simpps</id>
    <title>Simport Team Releases Porto Santo Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simpps" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e0126fba8407e1029446fb_sim1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3285822"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simport Team has recently released their rendition of Porto Santo Airport (LPPS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the oldest and first airport in the Madeira Islands, inaugurated in 1959.   With a yearly average of 180,000 passengers, most of the scheduled flights operate on a seasonal basis, with offerings from AlbaStar, Binter Canarias, easyJet, Eurowings Discover, TAP Air Portugal, and TUI Airways. Porto Santo has a single 3,000-meter-long runway, long enough for most airliners, and a modern terminal completed in 1995. The airport is shared with the Portuguese Air Force, with permanent detachments of Squadrons 502 and 751, whose main focus is search and rescue operations.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with 8K baked textures, custom 3d models, custom lights, accurate terrain elevation and runway profiles, realistic night lighting, custom ground textures, detailed markings, and custom satellite imagery. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.67, requiring at least 205 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spiint</id>
    <title>Spinoza Releases Interlaken Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spiint" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e022ca7571b7a5b060084b_inter1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1866816"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Spinoza has recently released their rendition of Interlaken Airport (LSMI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a former military airbase dating back to WW2.  Built by the Swiss Army Military in 1940, it originally had two runways, with the first one made of concrete and 600m of total length, made operational in 1942. The second one, 900 meters long, was completed a year later. After the war, it was converted into a Jet Maintenance Base for the De Havilland Vampire, with an eventual runway expansion to accommodate the fighter (the original runway was extended to 920 meters), along with the construction of a control tower. Further lengthening happened in the following decades, where it ended up at 1656 meters.  Commercial service took place for the first time in 1964, with Globe-Air flying from Interlaken to London thrice a week until 1967.  The base was closed in 2003, now hosting REGA 10, a Swiss Air-Rescue service responsible for more than 1100 mountain rescue operations annually.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the former airport as it stands, with the military hangars, a 3D model of the Jungfrau Park, and the REGA 10 - Wilderswil base.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.11, requiring at least 223 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avmsfs</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Avro Vulcan as Next MSFS Project</title>
    <updated>2023-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avmsfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e0a35e2c0da73570befac2_328984399_653392803205798_2471093560067383555_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="346707"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer Just Flight has announced its latest project for MSFS - the Avro Vulcan. The team is working hard to bring this iconic British bomber to the community, utilizing the latest technologies the simulator has to offer. Just Flight has previously released a version of the bomber for X-Plane, P3D, and FSX, and is currently working to improve the plane and “bring it up to the very latest MSFS standards”. At this stage, however, it is unclear how much of the plane will be inherited from these older versions and how much of it will be built from the ground up. Alongside the announcement, a few preview photos of the plane have also been released to showcase its detailed modeling and texturing. According to the developers, the Vulcan’s basic flight model and systems are already complete and the plane is just entering an early testing phase. Though the team is quite optimistic about the bomber’s development, they stressed that their main focus is currently directed at other projects such as the F28 and RJ series. Currently, there is little information on the release date or pricing of the product. However, the developers did hint that the aircraft will also come to Xbox, provided that Microsoft fixes “the current WASM issues”. Threshold will keep you updated on the progress of the Vulcan. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slhmag</id>
    <title>SLH Sim Designs Releases Marie-Galante Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slhmag" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e2c818944e76412912e488_gal1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3759632"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SLH Sim Designs has recently released their rendition of Marie-Galante Airport (TFFM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Marie-Galante in Guadeloupe. Marie-Galante was the first island of the Guadeloupe archipelago to be reached by Christopher Columbus during his second expedition, back in November 1493. The island is named after his flagship, Maria Galanda. The Carib Indians called it “Aichi” and the Arawaks would refer to it as “Toloukaera.” The Mills, one of the island's highlights, were built in 1664 when Madame de Boisseret handed over her rights to the Company of the West Indies, which built their first oxen-powered mills. By 1830, the island had a total of 105 mills. Nowadays, only 72 remain. The scenery features 4K PBR textures, accurate terraforming and runway slope, dynamic night lighting, and a true-to-life landside recreation. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $6.47, requiring at least 127 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pbo739</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Boeing 737-900 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pbo739" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e2d0f3b3073e56151bcb22_739-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="469888"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently released their rendition of the Boeing 737-900 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding to the other - already released - three variants of their 737 lineup.   The 737-900 is the longest 737 variant to date, with 42.11m of total length, seating up to 189 people in a high-density layout, or 177 on two-class, whilst keeping the same MTOW and fuel capacity as of the -800. It was first flown in 2001 with Alaska Airlines. The 737-900ER, on the other hand, can seat up to 220 passengers with a single-class configuration or 180 with two classes, along with an increased range (as implied by the name), around 3,280nm (the normal -900 only has 2,800nm). Due to its limited carrying capacity and range, the -900 was unsuccessful, with only 52 orders in total. The ER variant has accumulated over 500 orders recently.  PMDG’s rendition features a fully customized system simulation for all major and minor aircraft system components, a highly sophisticated logical simulation of onboard information systems and aircraft management, a customized flight model with enhanced physics augmentation, rigid body physics for wing and tail surfaces, fully customized flight control systems, accurate resolution cockpit displays, interchangeable equipment options for cockpit instrumentation, numerous user-configurable options, native datalink simulation compatible with SimBrief, a driveable pushback tug, a custom sound package, a highly-detailed tridimensional cockpit, advanced animations, and a complete tutorial for 737 beginners.   The developer has also listed some features that are to come in future updates, including the custom EFB, high-resolution cabin models and gear bay interiors for the entire 737 lineup, and Asobo-dependant updates such as the weather radar, which they mention as an example.   The -900 ($49.99) and the rest of the lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini108</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Bf108 Taifun for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini108" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e3447e5680465b9e1efed0_taifun1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1467218"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced the second addition to their classic lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the Bf108 Taifun, a single-engine sport aircraft developed by Bayerische Flugzeugwerke in the early 1930s, with 885 units built in total. The Taifun was designed to compete in the 4th Challenge International de Tourisme, the fourth and last International Tourist Plane Contest held by the FAI (Fédération aéronautique internationale), taking place in Warsaw, Poland. It was a major aviation event in pre-war Europe, held from 1929 to 1934. The prototype, then called M34, was powered by a 247 hp Hirth HM 8U V8 engine, did not win the competition, more so, was outperformed by many other aircraft, yet managed to impress with a low fuel consumption rate, good handling, and take-off/landing characteristics. The Bf108a variant took off for the first time in 1934, powered by three different engines: the original Hirth HM 8U, the Argus As 17B with 217 hp, and later units had a Siemens-Halske Sh 14 radial, with 158hp. The Bf108b was a revised version whose prototype had a Siemens-Halske Sh 14a radial, but the production model sported an Argus As 10C instead, delivering 237 hp, or the Argus AS 10E with 266 hp.  iniBuilds’ rendition makes use of the latest CFD technology on all primary and control flight surfaces, as well as the propeller, and with specifically modeled unique characteristics of the real-life counterpart like the capability of landing as slow as 45 knots thanks to its leading edge slats. The inclusion of such details enables a realistic STOL performance.  With the help of Microsoft Flight Simulator’s modern fuel system, the developers managed to model an authentic fuel system that closely matches the real-world behavior of the Argus As10 engine. The airplane features interactable elements that range from foldable wings to doors and storage compartments, and many EFB-controlled features such as customizable rain covers, language, units, curtain visibility, etc. On that language note, they mention it will come with two sets of gauges and panel text, with German or English texts, and either metric or imperial units.  The complete feature list follows down below: There is no information on the release date or price yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t2gffr</id>
    <title>Taxi2gate Announces Pointe-à-Pitre International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t2gffr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e34af90031d556c2d4d273_tffr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="387992"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taxi2gate has recently announced their first scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator: Pointe-à-Pitre International Airport (TFFR), serving the city of Pointe-à-Pitre on the island of Grand-Terre in Guadeloupe, boasting a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers, making it the second busiest airport in the Lesser Antilles region. It is the main airport of the French West Indies and a hub for Air Caraïbes, sporting a single terminal building with modern facilities and services, including shops, restaurants, lounges, and car rental. It offers direct flights to destinations across Europe, North America, and the Caribbean, connecting Guadeloupe to the rest of the world and playing a vital role in the region's tourism industry and economic development. Nothing has been revealed in terms of features but there’s a chance it could be similar to their Prepar3d v5 version (released in mid-2022), which features custom ground textures, custom photoscenery, carefully detailed 3d objects, realistic ground markings, night lighting, PBR textures, and a 3D terminal interior. They have also claimed to be working on Orlando (KMCO) and Paris Charles de Gaulle (LFPG), to come later. Pointe-à-Pitre, on the other hand, is said to be coming soon. There’s no information on the release date or price yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flsloc</id>
    <title>FlyLogicSoftware Releases Locarno Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flsloc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e3ed13f8223f3c0922ea56_loca1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1181112"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyLogicSoftware has recently released their rendition of Locarno Airport (LSZL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a mixed civilian and military airport serving the city of Locarno in Switzerland. ‍ Opened in 1939, it was utilized by the Swiss Air Force throughout WW2 for flight training due to its generally acceptable weather conditions. Post-WW2, Locarno was among five airports in the country that underwent modernization to become regional airports.  Nowadays, the airport has three runways: a paved one and two made of grass. Most of its traffic consists of private aircraft, student pilots, or Swiss Air Force operations (mostly training). It also hosts Eliticino, a helicopter charter company, and a local glider club that makes exclusive use of the two grass runways. For nearly a decade, between 1999 and 2007, the airport underwent a major renovation plan, with a large new solar-powered hangar and a private taxiway to runway 26R.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with lifelike lighting effects, an animated clock on the large hangar (which shows the correct time), an animated quad radar system, static airplanes and vehicles, animated people and windsocks, precise collision detection at the buildings, performance-friendly optimization, and an instruction manual in German and English. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.27, requiring at least 93 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skycvg</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Cincinnati International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skycvg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e51a0a878bcc3b752680c7_cvg1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="439703"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyline Simulations has recently released their rendition of Cincinnati International Airport (KCVG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, located in Hebron (Kentucky) and serving the Cincinnati tri-state area, averaging 9 million passengers yearly. Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky International boasts a passenger service network with over 50 destinations in North America and Europe, but its specialty is cargo: it is a global hub for Amazon Air, Atlas Air, ABX Air, Kalitta Air, and DHL Aviation. The 7th place in cargo traffic doesn’t come as a surprise, and it features among the fastest-growing cargo airports in America. The airport’s roots date back to the early 1940s when Franklin Delano Roosevelt wanted to establish multiple training facilities across the country for World War 2. The congress provided 2 million USD for the construction, and Kenton County bought the 7,700 acres of land that were offered by Boone County officials as a suitable site. 2 years later, in August 1944, it was finally training B-17 bombers, even if shortly, as the war was rapidly approaching its end. By 1946, they had already built a small terminal building for passengers. As a curious fact, KCVG used to rank among the most expensive major airports in the country up until 2015, when Delta downsized their operations and more low-cost carriers showed up. Delta still leads the market share as of recent, with 24.44% of the passengers (1,735,000), followed by Allegiant with 14.52% (1,030,000), and Frontier Airlines with 11.92% (846,000). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with 4K custom textures, PBR ground and decals, detailed 3D models, PBR materials on buildings, thousands of custom static objects, detailed night lighting and texturing, accurate city using OpenStreetMap data, ground traffic, animated custom jetways and radar. It’s available on Skyline Simulations’ Website for $21.33, requiring at least 1.02 GB of free disk space to install.Shout out to Tomcat_22 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/akdg55</id>
    <title>AKD G550 Updated to V1.10 </title>
    <updated>2023-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/akdg55" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e53f970a6f9ed17a081a9a_E3EA0446-11B3-484E-8094-A9A368472F2A.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3816292"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AK Designs have released a massive update for their Gulfstream G550. The latest update to the G550 brings a host of new features and improvements that have been long awaited.  ‍ The changelog included the following:  New features: -Added NEW Ground Handling(3D Model,Textures)(XP11/XP12) -Added 3D Cargo Door(Animations/3D  Model)(XP11/XP12) -Added new Baggage Compartment 3D Model(XP11/XP12) -Added Custom HUD(XP11/XP12) -Added DC GPU(XP12/XP11) -Added WingFlex animations(XP11/XP12) -Added SmartCopilot config(XP12/XP11) -Added new external lights(XP12) -Updated SASL to 3.15.0(XP12/XP11) Bugs fixes include: -Fixed NavSource on Display Controller(XP11/XP12) -Fixed squawk page in FMS3 radio panel(XP11/XP12) -Fixed checklist for G450 instead of G550(XP11/XP12) -Fixed Loadsheet prints in kg even when lbs is selected as unit measure in EFB settings (XP12/XP11) -Fixed SASL crash “can't load component Capt_radio_alt_test”(XP11/XP12) -Improved external lights(XP12) -Improved Baggage Compartment Textures(XP11/XP12) -Removed Menu with pop-out windows(XP12/XP11) -Fixed Minor bugs(XP12/XP11) If you don’t already own the AKD G550 you can pick it up at the Xplane.org store ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xsipiu</id>
    <title>XSimulations Releases Guillermo Concha Iberico International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xsipiu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e5d069b5aaa7c5c9fe1e6c_piu1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1889256"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XSimulations has recently released their rendition of PAF Captain Guillermo Concha Iberico International (SPUR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Piura in Peru.   It has a rich and dynamic history dating back several decades. The airport was built in the 1950s as a small regional airfield, serving primarily as a hub for domestic flights. In the following decades, as the region experienced significant economic growth, the airport underwent many renovations and upgrades to accommodate the increasing demand for air travel, including the addition of modern terminals, runways, and air traffic control systems, as well as the expansion of the airport's passenger and cargo facilities. Today, the airport is a gateway to the northwestern region of Peru, connecting travelers to major destinations both within the country and abroad. With its modern facilities and growing passenger traffic, the airport continues to play a critical role in regional economic development, poised for continued growth. It’s served by JetSmart Perú, LATAM Perú, and Sky Airline Peru, with legs to Lima and Arequipa (JetSmart only), with a yearly average of 860,000 passengers in total. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with PBR texturing, a modeled terminal interior, and military static aircraft. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.61, requiring at least 1.67 GB of free disk space.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbucs</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Helipads LA Medical for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbucs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e69a0edb4612a72eed8e2b_ucs1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2444221"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released another addition to their Helipads LA lineup: nineteen medical helipads all over downtown Los Angeles and its surrounding areas, with meticulously created models and five liveries for the Bell 407 helicopter (part of base Microsoft Flight Simulator).  The complete list of helipads and their respective description follows down below: ‍   The pack is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.93, requiring at least 1.99 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrfte</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Make E175 &amp; E195 Freeware</title>
    <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrfte" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e7aa1d441a2dadeb736b71_EMBRAER-E-JETS-E175-E195-X-PLANE-FREE-DOWNLOAD-main.jpg.fc7f1fec6d09d76829c5048f2ddbc0da.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="150160"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts first released their E175 and E195 to the X-plane market many years ago now and they have long been a popular product among virtual pilots. The development team have taken to the X-Plane.org Forums to announce that their original E range (175 &amp; 195) would now be free, for everyone to enjoy!  X-Crafts have said:  ‍ You can download the aircraft on the X–Plane.org Forums now!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff7772</id>
    <title>FlightFactor tease 777 v2 Engines</title>
    <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff7772" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6210dcef7048187164424ef4_FLWXwyUXsAUWBtr.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="85056"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor tease 777 v2 engines  The much anticipated 777 V2 from FlightFactor have recently been increasing their output of teaser content for their upcoming aircraft! In a recent post, FlightFactor has taken to Twitter to tease the different engine sounds of the incredible GE90 engines both during spool up on the ground and in the air!  A brief background on the GE90:  The GE90 is a high bypass turbofan engine that has been designed and developed by GE Aviation primarily for the 777 aircraft family. It outputs thrust ratings anywhere from 81,000 to 115,000 lbf which is absolutely incredible. The GE90 first entered service with British Airways mounted on the 777 in November of 1995. The FlightFactor 777 V2 sure looks as though it's going to be one of the most accurate representations of both the 777 and GE90 for any flight sim to date. </summary>
    <published>2023-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfr500</id>
    <title>Got Friends Releases Mini-500 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfr500" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e8412b195579e079584ddc_got1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1932425"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Got Friends has recently released their rendition of the Revolution Mini-500 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-seat light helicopter from the 90s sold as a kit for homebuilding by Revolution Helicopter Corporation.   Designed to resemble a mini Hughes 500, the Mini-500 is powered by a Rotax 582 engine that produces around 64 horsepower, with a range of 225 miles and a maximum speed of 115 mph. The fuselage is made of tubular steel with a cabin made of foam and structured with glass fiber.   It first flew in 1992, with its official introduction in 1994, and a total of 500 kits sold until production ceased about six years later. The kits were sold for around $24,500, including the engine, the fiberglass enclosure, instruments (the basic pack), the electric starter, landing lights, and navigation lights. As most of the parts came pre-assembled at the factory, the total build time was around 40 hours.   The MSFS counterpart features custom MGL avionics, multiple visual effects (including downwash, combustion, heat, rain, and icing), a native flight model using the Helicopter SDK, interchangeable avionics (GTR-220 radio or GNS-530), and many custom liveries.  It’s available on the Got Friends Shop for $15.00.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbche</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Chester Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbche" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e89333228647d8209b4b65_che1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1660895"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Chester Airport (KSNC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use airport serving the city of Chester, Connecticut.    Categorized by the FAA as a general aviation airport, KSNC is privately owned by Whelen Aviation and features a single runway layout with 782 meters of length. 80% of its yearly traffic (2000 data) comprises general aviation aircraft and 20% of air taxi operations, with a total of 20,800 aircraft movements.   As a curious fact, Chester does not have an IATA identifier as ‘SNC’ conflicts with General Ulpiano Paez Airport in Ecuador.    Developed by Matteo Veneziani, an indie, the scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, including custom groundpoly with sloped runways and taxiways, conditional display of objects depending on weather and time of the day, and 4K textures with PBR.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.68, requiring at least 2.36 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
