<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-02-19T18:29:17.559291+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kra024</id>
    <title>FlyDesign Releases Krakow-Balice Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kra024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a1d90118932095932e524d_kra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyDesign has recently released their rendition of John Paul International Krakow-Balice Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Kraków, Poland, with a yearly average of 11 million passengers.  Its construction started in 1964, opening for civil aviation three years later, in 1967. A passenger terminal was only built four years after its civil opening. The 1970s brought further development work to accommodate larger aircraft: a longer runway, new taxiways, and high-intensity runway lights. A new terminal was inaugurated in the late 1980s after the authorities deemed the actual capacity to be subpar compared to the projected traffic figures for the upcoming decade. Thus, it was inaugurated in 1993, followed by apron upgrades in 1995. New modernization work was carried out in 2002, focusing on improving the international passenger experience. Such effort was not in vain, and international routes increased in the following years. A separate domestic terminal (Terminal 2) was opened in 2007, and at the time, plans were underway to build an entirely new terminal in addition to Terminal 2. Ryanair opened their second Polish base in Kraków in 2012, basing two 737-800 aircraft there and connecting Kraków to many destinations across Europe.  Krakow-Balice became the first regional airport in Poland to reach over 9 million passengers yearly in 2023.  ‍ ‍ Due to the recent increase in traffic, the authorities have announced an upgrade plan to build a new terminal. The current terminal is not large enough to meet the projected demand for the future. ‍ It’s a focus city for Buzz Air (Ryanair Poland), Wizz Air, and LOT Polish Airlines. Aegean Airlines, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, hand-placed vegetation, fully dynamic lighting, high-definition buildings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.00, requiring at least 924.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sflphu</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Phuket International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sflphu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a1df1c67b05e122e6a0820_phu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SiamFlight recently released their rendition of Phuket International Airport (VTSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves the island of Phuket, Thailand, and has a yearly average of 17.2 million passengers, making it the third busiest airport in Thailand. Built in 1988 to accommodate only 6.5 million passengers yearly, it operated nearly at capacity for almost 30 years, until a new expansion project brought the figures to 20 million passengers per year (12.5 million passengers on the new terminal, 6.5 on the old one). It currently has three terminals: Terminal 2 handles international flights, Terminal 3 handles domestic operations, and Terminal X exclusively handles charters. Due to space constraints, Phuket has reached its capacity limit, which led the authorities to consider a rail link to Krabi International Airport for traffic alleviation in the near – or distant – future. In addition to the link, there’s a plan to build an entirely new airport elsewhere to serve Phang Nga, Phuket, and Krabi. It was supposed to be a multi-phase project, with phase one to start in 2022 and reach completion by 2025, but everything was indefinitely put on hold.  It’s a focus city for Thai Airways International and an operating base for Bangkok Airways, Thai Lion Air, and Thai AirAsia. Aeroflot, Air Arabia,  Air China, Air India, Azur Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Condor, Emirates, HK Express, IndiGo, Jetstar, Korean Air, Mahan Air, Nok Air, Qatar Airways, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, TUI, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terminals with an interior, custom ground textures, custom jetways, landside buildings, hand-placed taxiway guidance signs, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.38, requiring at least 196.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwa350</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces the Release Window and Price Range for their A350</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwa350"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a4dbf809e49f35e64e9429_471422468_1095337999269447_6998084516673360667_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IniBuilds recently announced the release window and price range for their highly anticipated A350, during a recent livestream event. While a replay of the stream is not available, highlights will be uploaded to their YouTube channel. IniBuilds aims to release the product by the end of February, with a price set at under $83 (Excl. VAT). Both the -900 and -1000 variants will be available at launch for MSFS 2020 and 2024. Customers will receive both variants through a single purchase.  ‍ Initially, the aircraft will be available on PC through the IniManager software, with a marketplace release planned for a later date. IniBuilds also emphasized that MSFS 2024 for PC is their primary development platform, which may result in some features being unavailable on MSFS 2020 or the Xbox versions. The iniBuilds A350 has been one of the most anticipated addon aircraft for MSFS, since its announcement in late 2023, with iniBuilds aiming to develop the first study-level A350 aircraft for MSFS. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxerj</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces Embraer 145 as Next Project</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxerj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a5282ddeffbd513d5f49da_0E145_flyer.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightFX has announced their next project to be the Embraer E145 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This announcement coincides with the release of their long-awaited Piaggio P180. The Embraer E145 is the largest member in the Embraer ERJ family. It first flew in August of 1995 and entered service two years later with Continental Express. The aircraft seats 50 passengers, has a maximum range of 1,550 nautical miles, and has a service ceiling of 37,000 feet. The aircraft is most commonly seen in North America with airlines such as American Eagle and JSX being prolific operators of the type. FlightFX announced their new project on the same day that they released their long-awaited Piaggio P180 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The developer is currently working on the Bombardier Challenger 350 and the Cessna 750 Citation. According to FlightFX CEO Nick Sdoucos, during a stream with flight simulation streamer twotonemurphyt, the Cessna 750 Citation is expected to be released in late March or early April, and its price will be $29.99. The aircraft is set to be the first high-fidelity regional jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The team at FlightFX currently plan to release the E145 and the E145XR. Its release is expected in the fourth quarter of 2025. Stay tuned to Threshold for all of the latest flight simulation news and updates!  ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbatl</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Atlanta International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbatl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a5bdb3d847fb25daeab4e2_jac1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx recently announced the development of Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport (KATL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves the Atlanta metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 104.6 million passengers, making it the world’s busiest airport. Developed by Matteo Veneziani, the creator of Sacramento Airport (KSMF)—previously reviewed on Threshold –, Burbank, and Olbia (also reviewed by us), Orbx’s Atlanta promises a highly detailed and fully up-to-date rendition of the airport, including the very recent Concourse T extension. Due to its single-creator nature, it claims to boast remarkable consistency across the board, with top-tier optimization and unparalleled realism. The unveiled feature list includes a fully up-to-date ground layout as of 2025, accurate ground elevation, detailed interior modeling, high-quality photorealistic textures, custom ground service equipment vehicles, and more. There is no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon. ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/afsc25</id>
    <title>Date and Location for the FS Conference 2025 Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/afsc25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a6206487d2fefed3f23e15_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The FS Conference 2025 will be the 20th edition of the event. The date and location have just been announced: it will take place on November 15th at the terminal of Paderborn Lippstadt Airport in Germany. The German flight simulator event aims to showcase the latest developments in the flight simulation community, including both hardware and software. This event also provides visitors with the opportunity to meet and interact with industry professionals. The very first FS Conference took place in 2002, and since then, the event has been held at various airports across Germany. Last year, our very own Magnus attended the FS Conference. If you are interested in learning about his experience at the event, be sure to check out his travelogue. For more information about the upcoming event, visit the official website.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/c/thresholdx</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl293</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl293"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de3df1ae2d10ada9d7bc_labsup2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs recently issued a new experimental update to their A321ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which includes a series of fixes and improvements. Update v11.0.1.293 –  the fifth since its release – includes a fix for a memory leak issue when the weather radar is active, a new way to set up Thrust Lever detents via their MCDU options page, and several other fixes which were observed and thoroughly reported by the community. The full changelog follows below: The add-on is available on their website for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/omdb24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Enhanced 2024 Version of Dubai Scenery</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/omdb24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a66d895be20c00df82a27d_KDyHgLtf9WQ-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released a trailer for the Enhanced 2024 version of their Dubai Airport (OMDB) scenery, and its surrounding area, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. IniBuilds stated “The new scenery brings a host of changes to the already impressive scenery”. These changes include an integrated Dubai landmarks pack, with the ability to be toggled on and off, a new terminal interior for Concourse A, and optimized Level of Detail (LOD) work for smoother performance.  The new version will build upon the previous MSFS 2020 version of iniBuilds' Dubai scenery. It currently features detailed ground textures, realistic airport landside elements, accurate dynamic lighting, intricately designed airport building models, and custom taxi signage. Dubai International Airport (OMDB) is one of the largest airports in the world, offering connections to over 260 destinations as of January 2024. It serves as the primary hub for Emirates, opening up for numerous routes to be flown with the upcoming iniBuilds A350. Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbemd</id>
    <title>Orbx Release Emerald Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbemd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a7ca88e52dd7ce05062a2a_Skjermbilde%202025-02-08%20221803.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has released Emerald Airport (YEML), developed by Rob Byrne, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. Emerald Airport is situated in the Central Highlands region of Queensland, Australia, approximately 6 km south of Emerald, the main town it serves. QantasLink, Virgin Australia Regional, and Alliance Airlines operate an average of 54 return flights to Brisbane every week. The area is sparsely populated, with fewer than two inhabitants per square kilometre. Additionally, it experiences very little rainfall, averaging around 830 millimetres of precipitation per year. Orbx says Emerald Airport for MSFS offers detailed exteriors and interiors of its terminals. The airport features subtle terraforming, with night lighting for both the terminal and aprons, as well as custom ground markings. There is also custom lighting on the runway, taxiway, and aprons. ‍ In addition, the airport includes a detailed helicopter hangar, general aviation hangars, fuel facilities, and functioning anemometers that respond to changes in wind speed. ‍ A full feature list follows: The scenery can be purchased for $16.36 at the Orbx store and is compatible with both MSFS 2020 and 2024. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon</summary>
    <published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prifer</id>
    <title> PhotoRico Releases Fernando Luis Ribas Dominicci Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prifer"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67aa3e2cb61abb5ebf52e943_fer1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PhotoRico has recently released their rendition of Fernando Luis Ribas Dominicci Airport (TJIG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024. The airport serves the municipality of San Juan in Puerto Rico and has a yearly average of 37,000 passengers. Constructed by the US Navy in 1929 as Naval Station Isla Grande, it served as Puerto Rico’s main international gateway until 1954, when it was ultimately replaced by Isla Verde International Airport. All international airlines moved there shortly after. The airport’s future was questioned a few times in the early 2000s, but a definitive—favorable—decision was eventually reached in 2006 due to its key function as a primary reliever for Puerto Rico’s main airport. In early 2011, the airport’s future went through another scare: the FAA wanted to close the airport’s control tower because they operated it themselves and intended to cut costs. Air Flamenco, Fly the Whale, M&amp;N Aviation, and Vieques Air Link regularly serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail buildings, custom ground textures, detailed landside, real static GA aircraft, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.70, requiring at least 873.59 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsaw25</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Awards 2025 at FSWeekend Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsaw25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ab94377fd2a9c99ad186bd_16_9_static.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Threshold, cruiselevel, and FSElite are excited to announce the Flight Sim Awards, taking place at FSWeekend 2025! The Flight Sim Awards aim to celebrate the developers, creators, and innovators who make our enjoyment of flight simulation possible. The jury, selected from members of the Threshold, cruiselevel, and FSElite teams have reviewed all product releases from 2024.  After careful deliberation, the nominees have been narrowed down to a select few finalists in each category. In MSFS and X-Plane, there are three categories: airliners, aircraft and scenery. Additionally, the best add-on for DCS has its own category, along with the best tools, hardware, and freeware for the entire flight sim genre. To conclude, there is a special Content Creator category where you, along with thousands of other fans, determine the winner! ‍ Members of the jury are not the only ones who have a say in the decision. Starting this Friday, February 14, you can vote for your favourites! The final result will be determined by a 50/50 split between the jury and the public votes. Categories will be scored using a point system. Award five points to your favourite, four points to your second favourite, three points to your third favourite, and so on for your top five. Juries will follow the same scoring system. The entry with the most combined points at the end will be declared the winner! ‍ The flight simulation community has no shortage of great content creators. The Flight Sim Awards aim to recognize your favourites, and this category will truly showcase who your top choice is, as 100 percent of the points are determined by the public. ‍ The 2025 Flight Sim Awards will take place on Friday, March 14, the eve before FSWeekend in Lelystad at the Captain's Dinner. For those who cannot attend the event in person, a live stream will be available. ‍ As we celebrate this year’s achievements, we also look ahead to the future. The jury is eager to hear your thoughts and feedback to make the 2026 Flight Sim Awards even better! ‍If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbsan</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Sandane Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbsan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b179b7fc990e8699d30e42_sandane1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their rendition of Sandane Airport (ENSD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves the village of Sandane in Norway and has a yearly average of 37,000 passengers.  The airport was built in the early 1970s and opened in 1975, then the only airport serving the district of Nordfjord. Due to its geography and low regularity, its initial years were plagued by severe turbulence, which was eventually partially mitigated in the following decades by a terminal expansion and a runway extension. The regularity issue was addressed relatively recently by installing navigation systems, ultimately reducing the canceled flights to a mere 5% in 2022. Its pre-ILS days were rather grim, with airplanes often dealing with low visibility, extreme winds, and insufficient runway. It’s served by Widerøe, which has obligatory public service flights to Bergen, Oslo, and Sogndal, flown with Dash 8-100 airplanes. The Norwegian government subsidizes all of the routes. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 2K PBR textures, custom ground decals, crisp orthoimagery, custom approach lighting and ground equipment, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $11.97, requiring at least 842.51 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/salbgn</id>
    <title>Salvuz Releases Bergen Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/salbgn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b22a23c1e0ca1d9b332a9c_bgn1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Salvuz recently released their rendition of Bergen Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It is the second busiest airport in Norway, with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. Dating back to the early 1950s, Bergen Airport was partially funded by the municipalities of Bergen and Fana with 4 million Norwegian kroner, securing the construction of a terminal and a 1,460-meter-long runway. NATO funded an expansion in 1953, warranting a 2,440-meter-long runway instead. When the first flight landed at the airport in mid-1954, only 800 meters were complete. It was a chartered flight from Bergen to Oslo, transporting a local football team. It’s a hub for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe, with an extensive domestic and intra-European network. According to 2014 data, Scandinavian Airlines had 46% of the market share for domestic flights, Norwegian had 38%, and Widerøe 15%. Internationally, Norway led the way with 36%, SAS with 23%, and KLM with 18% (with a single route to Amsterdam).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed buildings, high-resolution PBR textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date layout (as of 2024), and it also supports MSFS 24’s new lighting and LOD system. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.85, requiring at least 1.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd216</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd216"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67007455f9c93f4f4c4607ef_randy4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published a new development update concerning the status of their product lines for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, including further information on the upcoming 777-200ER and the 747 Classic project. The upcoming 777-200ER’s beta testing phase has finally started. The plane will feature all three engine variants (GE, RR, and PW) with their correct performance figures, indications, and sounds.  ‍ While there is no timeline for the beta testing phase to end, Randazzo suspects they will have a better feel for the qualitative state of the product in the next 7-10 days. ‍ Like the 777F, the 777-200ER will be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 first, with a 2024 version to be released later. ‍ PMDG has also announced a new Operations Center (3.0), which is currently under beta testing as well and will eventually replace their current Operations Center, sporting a fresh new look, the ability to manage all product installations from within it, update management, rollbacks, and multiple channels (stable, experimental, beta, streamer builds). It will also handle activation and install rights and significantly improve PMDG’s ability to diagnose and resolve any problems that might occur with their products at hand.  Furthermore, the new Operations Center will eliminate the need for installers, which used to be one of their biggest choke points during product releases. ‍ It’s scheduled to roll out soon and coexist with 2.0 until they are wholly comfortable with the new methods. ‍ Regarding the status of the 777’s conversion to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, PMDG has managed to build its lineup inside the new platform with great success, but some stability issues were found that would ultimately break the experience.  Despite the slightly underwhelming results, PMDG remains optimistic that their “relationship” with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will improve as Asobo updates the platform. ‍ On the other hand, the DC–6— which they assumed would be an easy conversion—has proven to be one of the trickiest, with numerous problems with the animations (including cockpit controls, levers, buttons, and other items). They have been unable to determine what is causing the problem so far. ‍ They have reported the issue in Asobo’s dev community forums, but it appears to have not caught their attention yet, and no other developer has encountered anything similar. In light of this, PMDG has provided no ETA for its eventual conversion to the new platform. ‍ 737NG-wise, they have not yet evaluated it in the new platform, as they are using the 777 as a testbed to learn the ropes. As for the upgrade pricing, PMDG’s position remains the same: while they ideally do not want to charge, they might have to charge depending on the amount of work required (they haven’t fully gauged how much effort will be necessary yet). ‍ Work on the 747 fleet has been accelerating while everything else remains relatively stagnant due to the compatibility stalemate. Randazzo reiterates that things are still moving, though slowly.  ‍ While the 747-400 doesn’t have any images yet, they have shared two pictures of the flight deck work on the 747-100, showcasing the newly started labeling work, custom weathering, etc.  Coding is also progressing nicely, with PMDG taking full advantage of the “stalemate” to move developers on and off the 747. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their official website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99 If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse26v</id>
    <title>Vote Now: Dates and Location for FlightSimExpo 2026</title>
    <updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse26v"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b3be5532cc84d8a9e2e6da_2023_20.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The Flight Simulation Association has recently released a survey to decide the venue and dates for FSExpo 2026. FSExpo is North America’s largest flight simulation conference, drawing thousands of attendees each year and featuring exhibitors from across the industry, from developers to content creators, and more! “As North America’s community-driven flight sim convention, attendee and partner feedback is a key input to where and when we host the show”, says FSA’s Evan Reiter, a volunteer air traffic controller on VATSIM and an organizer of the show. “Three of the options on our survey were suggested to me in Discord DMs or comments from attendees at FSExpo—keep them coming!” ‍ ‍Click here to vote and influence one of flight simulation’s largest events! ‍ As for this year’s expo, Registration is open for FSExpo 2025 in Providence, RI from June 27 to 29 at the Rhode Island Convention Center. ‍ While Expo organizers are already looking ahead to next year’s event, FSExpo 2025 is just a few months away, and Threshold will be there on site covering all the latest from the event! However, we would not be able to do this without the support of our amazing community, so consider supporting us on Patreon, and joining our vibrant Discord community!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42dee</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes Deep Dive Video on Upcoming ChasePlane for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42dee"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67980a55024e3305b1018fc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently published a video on their YouTube channel showcasing ChasePlane’s onboarding tutorial. The video walks you through setting up all the necessary items to get the best experience and provides further information on the optional community access. The 10-minute video covers the entirety of the introductory steps, walking you through removing your bindings in Microsoft Flight Simulator (ChasePlane “kidnaps” the camera system), configuring your bindings, setting up different camera presets, enabling cinematics, and sharing views with the community. ‍ It’s important to note that—unlike Flow, one of their best-selling products for MSFS—cloud storage can’t be provided for free, as it takes significantly more space. Therefore, they have chosen to make the cost optional, lowering the product’s final price tag and allowing customers to decide whether they want to pay extra for community access. The prices for community access range from 5 dollars for the yearly subscription to 20 dollars for a lifetime.  ‍ P42 also reiterates that community access is NOT needed to share camera views, as they have built powerful importing and exporting methods that allow you to share camera views via any platform outside of their community ecosystem. ‍ Refer to this blog post for further information on the optional community access system. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
