<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-06-02T18:24:37.435568+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fadsrs</id>
    <title>Final Approach Design Studios Releases Sylhet Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fadsrs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6650edf8a96d290c6005f2d8_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Final Approach Design Studios recently released their version of Sylhet Airport (VGSY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Officially known as Osmani International Airport, the airport serves the Bangladeshi city of Sylhet. The airport is the third busiest in the country and is located around 5 miles from the city centre. It serves an average of just under 650.000 passengers annually. Osmani International Airport was built during the period of 1944-1945. It was constructed during World War II with the purpose of controlling Japanese aggression from Burma. Initially opened as Sylhet Civil Airport, it started as a domestic airport. In 1986, a terminal building, navigational aids, new runway pavement, taxiways, and aprons were constructed. The airport saw its first international flight in 2002 and has since undergone further expansion and upgrades. Today, the airport is operated by airlines such as Biman Bangladesh Airlines and Novoair, offering flights to destinations such as Dhaka, London, and Dubai. The recently released version of Sylhet Airport features 4K PBR textures, highly detailed ground poly, detailed 3D buildings, ground service equipment, animated jetways, terminal interiors, and more. The add-on requires a total of 1.40GB of storage space and is available on iniBuilds for roughly $14.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/denm24</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Announces Denver International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/denm24"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6651c99d344734cfdb5f9191_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. X-Codr Designs has announced the development of Denver International Airport (KDEN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This comes after the successful creation of the airport for X-Plane. The team is currently in the final stages of development and testing for the Microsoft Flight Simulator version. The scenery package will include highly detailed models, high-resolution textures, custom jetways, an accurate and up-to-date layout, performance optimisation, ortho imagery, and more. The announcement was made on the developer's website, and as the airport is nearing completion, the release of the scenery might be right around the corn ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stsmaa</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Announces Maastricht-Aachen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stsmaa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66526f799454c6a0685fbedf_maa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently announced the development and imminent release of Maastricht-Aachen Airport (EHBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Maastricht, in the Netherlands, and Aachen, in Germany, with a yearly average of 97.000 passengers. It was built by the Allies as a temporary airfield during World War 2, later transferred to the Dutch government and named Beek Airfield. It saw lots of traffic during its initial months because most roads in the country had been bombed and/or heavily damaged. As the repairs progressed, the traffic figures died down. The first semi-permanent terminal was built in 1947, followed by runway paving work in 1949 and 1950. Further expansion work was carried on from 1951 and beyond after an agreement between the airport and the Dutch Air Force. The airport underwent expansion work in the early 1970s to handle bigger aircraft, which included runway lengthening, taxiway widening, and apron enlargement. A decade later, a new passenger terminal was built, replacing the old one from the 40s. Corendon Dutch Airlines, Pegasus Airlines, and Ryanair serve it. ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, custom taxiway signage, custom objects, PBR texturing, a realistic runway profile, and more. Refer to their website for further information. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msesmx</id>
    <title>SkyHigh Studios Releases Växjö Småland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msesmx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665450683649913b944ef8c4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SkyHigh Studios has just released their rendition of Växjö Småland Airport (ESMX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Swedish city of Växjö and sees just under 150.000 passengers yearly. It offers both regional and international destinations for the city. The city of Växjö received its first scheduled flights in 1960, operating to and from the Uråsa airbase at that time. With increasing demand, a larger airport, Växjö Småland Airport, was constructed and opened in 1975. Initially, the airport only offered flights to Stockholm, but in 2007, international flights began. Airlines such as Ryanair and Wizzair began operating out of the airport, and over the years, the popularity of charter flights to the Canary Islands and Southern Europe increased. Presently, the airport offers year-round flights to Stockholm Bromma Airport through Braathens Regional Airlines. Additionally, airlines like Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Sunclass Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic operate seasonal routes to destinations such as Alicante, Rhodes, and Gran Canaria. The airport sees around 4000 aircraft movements annually. The scenery package is filled with features, such as PBR 4K ground polygons, custom AFCAD, fully modelled interior, authentic assets, dynamic night lighting, and more. The newly released Växjö Småland Airport is now available on Orbx for approximately $14.10 and requires 2.64 GB of storage space. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carplc</id>
    <title>Cloudsurf Asia Releases Clark International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carplc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6654974903838761a186deb1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cloudsurf Asia has recently released its version of Clark International Airport (RPLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located 50 miles northwest of Manila and serves both the Central Luzon and Northern Luzon regions, welcoming just under 1.9 million passengers annually. In 1902, after the United States Cavalry established Fort Stotsenberg, part of it was converted into an airfield, which was later renamed Clark Air Field in 1919. In 1991, the Philippine government took over Clark Air Field, and it wasn't until 1996 that the airport opened for commercial operations. Over the years, the airport has undergone various expansions and developments. Today, the airport features an 889.000 square feet terminal, opened in 2022, and one runway after the former second runway was decommissioned due to its proximity to the other one. The airport handles both passenger and cargo operations and serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific, Sunlight Air, Emirates, and Qatar, offering a variety of destinations such as Cebu, Dubai, and more. The airport sees around 5.500 aircraft movements annually. The newly released version of Clark International Airport for MSFS includes many features such as fully custom objects, terminal interior, PBR textures, custom animated jetways, and much more. The add-on requires a total of 1.63 GB of storage space and is now available on Orbx for approximately $23.82. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tlcsim</id>
    <title>New Takeoff and Landing Calculations Feature in Simbrief</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tlcsim"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66573f9a2926d7ca819c4f8c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. SimBrief has recently been updated to include takeoff and landing calculations in the flight planning application. A new tab within the SimBrief dispatch system provides performance calculations based on flight and aircraft data, making it easy to view and use the calculations. The new SimBrief Performance Tool will automatically calculate all relevant speeds and limitations, eliminating the need for manual calculations. The SimBrief Performance Tool offers a variety of options to choose from, including engine bleed, flaps, brake options, and more. If this seems complicated, you can allow the tool to decide the best options for you. The new takeoff and landing calculations feature is available for free to all SimBrief users on the SimBrief website. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mscuec</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update 7: European Cities II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mscuec"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665743a1e159616e5d1a3ed6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released its latest city update, City Update 7: European Cities II. The new update includes a total of six cities. The cities included in the update are Stockholm, Nice, Monaco, Porto, Barcelona, and Madrid. The cities have been significantly improved using high-resolution aerial imagery and high-fidelity TIN surface modelling. Thanks to the new update, simmers are able to explore everything from the Spanish Coast to the French Riviera and the capital of Sweden. The new city update is available for free on the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msll16</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Local Legend 16: Short SC.7 Skyvan for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msll16"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6657496c65366b270530d6df_Banner_Image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently launched the Short SC.7 Skyvan for Microsoft Flight Simulator, marking it as Local Legend number 16. The aircraft was developed by iniBuilds for Microsoft. The Short SC.7 Skyvan is a British turboprop aircraft manufactured by Short Brothers. First flown in 1963, it has been primarily used for short-haul freight and skydiving. The aircraft is commonly known as the "Flying Shoebox" and has been utilized by various operators including Olympic Air, Skydive Spaceland, and Ryan Air Services. The new add-on includes sixteen liveries with themes such as airliner, military, skydiving, and surveyor. Additionally, the aircraft offers various features to explore. The add-on requires 7.88GB of storage space and is available on the in-sim Marketplace for $14.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/29lgsr</id>
    <title>29Palms Releases Santorini Airport &amp; Island for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/29lgsr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6658a034d1db87bede1ba9d6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. 29Palms has just released its version of Santorini Airport (LGSR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery package includes a highly realistic version of Santorini Airport, as well as the entire island of Santorini. The airport welcomes around 2.7 million passengers to the Greek island annually. The airport was first used in 1972 for military purposes and began commercial operations in the early 1980s. In 2015, a joint venture of Fraport AG/Copelouzos Group and the state privatisation fund took over the airport, with plans to operate it for 40 years. A major renovation in 2021 included numerous upgrades and refurbishments. Currently, the airport offers year-round flights to Athens and Thessaloniki, with seasonal operations to destinations such as Oslo, London, and Paris. Airlines like Aegean Airlines, Jet2.com, and Ryanair ensure that Santorini receives around 2.7 million passengers and 24.000 aircraft movements annually. The new scenery package by 29Palms includes custom buildings, interior, updated layout, and dynamic lights for the airport, as well as mesh terrain in 3m/pixel resolution, vegetation, villages, ports, points of interest, animations, and AI vessel traffic for the island. The add-on requires 2.58GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for $19.85. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hsav</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hsav"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6658ddbe42ac22c1098ab61b_sav1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released its rendition of Savannah/Hilton Head International Airport (KSAV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Savannah, Georgia, and Hilton Head Island, South Carolina, and as of 2023, it had a yearly average of 3.9 million passengers. The airport was built in the early 1940s on a 600-acre piece of land near Cherokee Hill, with three 3600-foot runways covering all possible wind options. The US Army Air Corps soon took it over as a bomber and training base for B-24 bombers and fighter aircraft. It was temporarily named Chatham Airfield, and its infrastructure greatly improved during that short period. Post WW2, it was turned over to the Georgia Air National Guard and renamed Travis Field after a late local Brigadier General, victim of a fatal B-29 accident in California. ‍ ‍ A new airline terminal was built in 1958, and runway extension work followed in 1962, preparing the airport for the jet age. In 1994, a brand new terminal was built, with eight gates and expansion possibilities. Five departure gates were dutifully added in 2007.  It won #1 Best Domestic Airport two years in a row (2021 and 2022) in Travel+Leisure World’s Best Awards. The method was a survey among the readers that took accessibility, shopping, check-in, restaurants, cleanliness, and many other factors into account. The airport’s domestic popularity was also reinforced by Condé Nast Traveler, which ranked it the best in the United States for three years in a row. It’s an operating base for Allegiant Air and served by American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, custom jetways, and more. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.15, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/g1sris</id>
    <title>Gate15Scenery Releases Rishiri Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/g1sris"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6658e3c10bd509d63ee2c191_ris1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Gate15Scenery has recently released the second version of its Rishiri Airport (RJER) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the entirety of Rishiri Island in Hokkaido Prefecture and has a yearly average of 38.000 passengers. The airport was built in the late 1960s when air travel was gaining momentum in Japan, and connecting remote islands became a priority. Initially, the airport served a limited number of flights, primarily connecting Rishiri to the nearby Wakkanai Airport on the mainland. However, its presence proved crucial in boosting tourism and facilitating the transportation of goods and services. The airport also became a vital link for emergency medical services, ensuring timely access to specialized care for the island's residents. Over the years, Rishiri Airport has witnessed steady growth. The runway was extended in 1990 to accommodate larger aircraft, allowing for more direct flights and increased passenger capacity. Today, the airport serves several domestic destinations, including Sapporo and Tokyo, making travel to and from the island more convenient. Beyond its role in transportation, Rishiri Airport has become a symbol of the island's connection to the broader world. It serves as a gateway for visitors to experience the island's natural beauty, from the majestic Mount Rishiri to its diverse marine life. It's currently only served by ANA Wings and Hokkaido Air System, with flights to Sapporo (Chitose and Okadama). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. Owners of the previous version are eligible for a free upgrade. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $14.38, requiring at least 298.89 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fltjer</id>
    <title>FLYT Simulations Releases Comte. Ariston Pessoa Regional Airport for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fltjer"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665a3246f2755381fa1dad35_jer1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FLYT Simulations has recently released their rendition of Comandante Ariston Pessoa Regional Airport (SBJE), serving Jijoca de Jericoacoara, Brazil, with a yearly average of 102,000 passengers as of 2023. ‍ Funded by a government plan to develop regional aviation in Brazil, construction work began in 2011 and concluded three years later. The inauguration, though, only happened in 2017 after a series of organizational mishaps. The passenger terminal, designed by Francisco Antonio Laprovitera Teixeira, consists of a single block with departure and arrivals, food kiosks, bathrooms on each extremity, and—not many—check-in desks. Its 2200m runway is long enough to accommodate an Airbus A320 and its Boeing counterpart, the 737-800. It’s served by Azul (Belo Horizonte), Azul Conecta (Fortaleza, Parnaíba), Gol Transportes Aéreos (São Paulo - Guarulhos), and LATAM Brasil (São Paulo - Guarulhos). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, a high-detail terminal interior, custom ground service equipment, custom ground clutter, and more. It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for $9.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avij14</id>
    <title>Aviotek Software’s Frankfurt Airport to Release in mid-June</title>
    <updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avij14"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665a397a34d8cd44fd5aec91_fraport1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Simulation Software has published a new development update covering the progress on their free Frankfurt International Airport (EDDF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which is set to be released in mid-June. ‍ They apologize for taking so long with the project, justifying it with their decision to add new features, fix bugs, and remake some objects and buildings to improve the overall experience further. The scenery will feature a full rendition of Terminals 1 and 2, including all concourses, remote stands, cargo areas, etc. It will be fleshed out with fully animated jetways, detailed aprons, custom vehicles, custom ground service equipment, terminal interiors (toggleable), a custom ground profile, an up-to-date taxiway layout, custom HDR lighting, and more. ‍ Aviotek will continue to update the scenery post-release, covering all the areas that haven’t received “enough love” yet, including the brand-new, yet-to-be-finished Terminal 3. It’s set to release on June 14, sneakily revealed by one of the WIP screenshots accompanying their publication.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xraw139</id>
    <title>X-Rotors Releases AW139 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xraw139"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665aef524f8157df3202f7fe_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Rotors have released their rendition of the AgustaWestland AW139 for X-Plane 12. This helicopter is used in various roles, in both civilian and military sectors. Designed by Agusta and Bell Company in the late 90s, the AB139 had its first flight in February 2001. After Bell left the project, the helicopter was redesignated as the AW139. After entering service in 2003, the AgustaWestland AW139 proved to be a commercial success, as more than 1100 were built as of January 2021. It has found many customers in the civilian sector, such as CHC Helicopters, Gulf Helicopters, and Weststar Aviation. There also was a variety of customers in the military sector, as more than 27 Air Forces around the globe still operate this helicopter to date. Powered by two Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6C-67C turboshaft engines, the AW139 can cruise at speeds of 310km/h with a range of 1061km. The new X-Plane 12 version features a complete model rebuild, including a new cabin, landing gear and panels. The new version also comes with new animations for both rotors, Epic Primus 7 avionics, with fully functional PFD and MFD, improved Flight Director, new textures, liveries, functional audio panel, winch, wire-cutters, inlet filters and float additions (which can be managed from inside the cockpit). An overhauled flight model, improved autopilot and a quick reference guide are also included. Version 5.01 for X-Plane 11 is still available, however, it has been discontinued and will not receive any more updates. The AW139 is available at the X-Rotors store for roughly $43.36. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/otegbc</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases TrueEarth Great Britain Central for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/otegbc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665af9d2d6fdb9b5e55f51f6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently released their final TrueEarth Great Britain region for X-Plane 12. Following the recent release of Great Britain South, Orbx has now released the last region in the series, Great Britain Central. This TrueEarth package covers a total of 22.928 square miles (59.383 km²) and comes with tons of features to explore. TrueEarth Great Britain Central covers a variety of areas, including the famous cities of Liverpool, Manchester and Newcastle. The new scenery package comes with tons of POIs to explore and has been made as realistic and performance-friendly as possible. TrueEarth Great Britain Central comes with tons of features, such as aerial imagery, 72.5 million trees, 4 million buildings, VFR landmarks, POIs, 10-meter mesh, and more. The add-on requires a total of 60.82 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx for approximately $37.53. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a161</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a161"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665ba18298e4f651ac834e3a_comanche.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding compatibility with the KLN 90B GPS mod by falcon71 and addressing a few issues. The brand-new GPS addition simulates the Bendix/King KLN 90B, an IFR approach-capable classic with a bright three-inch CRT display, moving map graphics, and more. Its rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator can be found on GitHub for free. Other than the new device, update 1.6.1 also brings ground physics tweaks, better detection of multi-position switches, JPI EDM 830 fixes, and more. The complete changelog follows below: Version 1.6.1 Changes The Accu-Sim Comanche 250 is available on their store for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
