<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-01T18:23:23.069289+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lga101</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates LaGuardia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lga101"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662687f3664455587651f087_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has updated their recently released LaGuardia Airport (KLGA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new update brings various features and improvements making the scenery more realistic. The new update for LaGuardia, v1.0.1, includes various improvements, fixes, and enhancements. See the full changelog below: ‍ Changelog v1.0.1: - VDGS textures improved, - PAPI light fixes, - TDZ lights added to RWY04, - GS double antennas fixed, - Jetway fixes, - Snowplows added, - Terminal fixes, - Improved stadium area, - Parkings added to AFCAD, - Some A parking removed from AFCAD, - Fixed AA Hangar LOD. The updated version of LaGuardia is available on Contrail for approximately $16.21 and requires a total storage space of 1.93GB. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftkbos</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Boston Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftkbos"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6627a2d6d6116c4cc6818a07_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has released an update for their version of Boston Logan International Airport (KBOS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new update comes with various improvements and new features. The latest update, V1.7, for Boston Logan includes several bug fixes and enhancements. Below is the complete changelog: ‍ Changelog V1.7: New Taxiway Layout at F, T, Q and N New Hilton Hotel Model Taxiway blue edge lights now flat models like realworld Fixed bad rendering on Lipstick Terminal E Improved LODs and Performance New night lighting on American Hangar to match real world Missing PAPI added to Runway 27 Red lights added to end of 22L Misc visual tweaks and improvements The newly updated version of Boston Logan International Airport is now available on Contrail for approximately $20.27 and requires a total storage space of 2.52GB. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwpspr</id>
    <title>RW Profiles Releases Springfield-Branson National Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwpspr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66291b0bd8da09705a0b3544_springers1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RW Profiles has recently released their rendition of Springfield-Branson National Airport (KSGF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Springfield and Branson in Missouri with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers as of 2023. It opened as Springfield-Greene County Airport in July 1945, replacing their former - much smaller - main airport.  American Airlines started scheduled service to the newly built airport in that same year, only pulling out in 1963. Chicago and Southern landed in 1948, and Ozark in 1951. Ozark was also responsible for the airport’s first scheduled jet service with their brand-new DC-9s in 1966.  The airport’s current name was adopted in 1992 as the administration attempted to capitalize on Branson’s ever-growing tourist industry (even though it’s around 80 km away).  In May 2006, construction work started on a new terminal, inaugurated three years later, designed by Reynolds, Smith &amp; Hills.  Allegiant Air, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, United Express, DHL, FedEx Express, and UPS Airlines serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, accurate night lighting, a custom runway, highly detailed models, up-to-date airport layout, LOD optimization, and an official GSX profile. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.24, requiring at least 2.35 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eca777</id>
    <title>Exclusive Closed Alpha and Public Beta Announced for FlightFactor’s 777v2 Release: Invitations Rolling Out </title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eca777"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66292049518cd676100f1e79_ram1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently published a statement on their social network pages with their final decision on the release policy of their upcoming Boeing 777 v2 for X-Plane, including an exclusive non-public alpha program and a public beta later down the line. A previous statement made by Ramzzess on X-Plane.Org Forums stirred quite a bit of drama from the community as it mentioned their ponderation of a beta release without any vertical guidance at all, which led to a poll and their decision to feature a non-public alpha program first, where a select few would be chosen to purchase and test the product after signing a non-disclosure agreement.  Later, a public beta will roll out with all the major features (except CPDLC). Therefore, once that is out, the public beta testers will not have to experience the 777 without a working VNAV. Invitations for the closed alpha have been rolling out since yesterday (23/04). The purchased keys will be permanent and grant access to future updates. They also made sure to highlight that there are no applications for the closed alpha, and invitees will be chosen by themselves. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsb244</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsb244"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662928fab802dffb292ad1cc_brazila1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has shared more previews of their upcoming Brasília - President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR), the third busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. A proper terminal building was inaugurated in 1971, designed by Tércio Fontana Pacheco, a Brazilian Air Force architect. The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more. It was divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The upcoming scenery is said to feature animated moving walkways, an up-to-date ground layout, terminal interiors, custom jetways with detailed interior, detailed landside, and more. There’s no release date yet, but it’s said to be coming soon. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfr938</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Piper PA-38 Tomahawk for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfr938"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a5c81faf849cd7243da28_tom1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight recently released their rendition of the Piper PA-38 Tomahawk for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This two-seat fixed tricycle gear general aviation plane was designed for flight training, touring, and personal use. Introduced in 1978, the Tomahawk was designed from the get-go to be an affordable trainer aircraft with flight characteristics that would allow instructors to push the envelope a little further in comparison with the Cessna 152, which was the de facto trainer aircraft at the time: unlike its rival, the PA-38 would require specific pilot input to recover from spins. Nearly 2,500 units were produced during its relatively short production lifespan from 1978 to 1982.  Powered by a 112 hp Avco Lycoming O-235-L2C, the PA-38 can cruise at 185 km/h with a maximum range of 867 km and a service ceiling of 13,000ft.  It’s still widely used for pilot training in many countries worldwide, reflected in the add-on with its considerable set of liveries. Other than the liveries, Just Flight’s rendition offers an accurately modeled rendition of the aircraft, with PBR materials, custom ground equipment, 8K textures, a truly tridimensional virtual cockpit, realistic wear and tear, an EFB for controlling various aircraft options, and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ The add-on is available on Just Flight’s website for $41.99, requiring at least 1.6 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssda50</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Previews DA-50RG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssda50"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a6da424e97843527b0932_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyward Simulations has recently previewed its first project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the Diamond DA-50RG. The DA-50RG is a modern single-engined aircraft, powered by a 300HP turbodiesel engine. The sleek airframe is made of carbon fiber, which sets a new bar for aircraft construction. The aircraft can fly at 20,000 feet at a speed of 180 knots. Together with great fuel consumption, these features make the DA-50RG one of the best modern general aviation aircraft. According to Skyward, The DA-50RG will feature an accurate 3D model, true-to-life definition textures, Custom-coded systems, ground idle function simulation, accurate flight model, integrated WortkingTittle G1000NXI, hand-made liveries, and immersive custom sounds by Boris Audio Works.  The addon will cost around 16.12 USD, but as of the publishing of this article, the release date is yet to be announced. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a150</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a150"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a8a5b47035b5699933700_pa24.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing small improvements to the PC version of the add-on. Update 1.5.0 fixes an SU15 beta issue that would happen on engine run-ups with brakes or chocks applied, improves battery performance at very cold temperatures, adds more telemetry variables for force feedback hardware, and more. The changelog follows below: The update will also be available in the marketplace at a later date. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/haliv2</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Halifax Stanfield International Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/haliv2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a9519d18669c7d7ef9b2c_halifax1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently released their upgraded rendition of Halifax Stanfield International Airport (CYHZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Halifax Regional Municipality with a yearly average of 3.6 million passengers as of 2023. ‍ Construction started in 1955, and the airport was inaugurated five years later, costing the administration $18 million.  The first couple of years in operation were rather successful, leading to a complete renovation of the passenger terminal in 1966 and a 5,000-square-meter extension a decade later. By 1990, the airport was already averaging 2.5 million passengers a year. It was further renovated in the early 2000s, with slight expansions and improvements, which happened again between 2018 and 2019. It’s a focus city for Air Canada and Porter Airlines and served by Air Saint-Pierre, Air Transat, American Airlines, American Eagle, BermudAir, Canada Jetlines, Condor, Delta Connection, Discover Airlines, Flair Airlines, Icelandair, Sunwing Airlines, United Express, and WestJet. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout (as of March 2024), significant performance improvements, an improved interior model, new ground poly, custom taxi signs, an improved terminal model, and more. ‍ The V2 Update is available as a free upgrade for previous owners, and new owners can find it on OrbxDirect for roughly $19.19. It requires at least 5.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tekola</id>
    <title>Threshold Exclusive: Orbx Kola Map Previews</title>
    <updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tekola"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662b9980524bd60b8b0c37c3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Threshold has received exclusive screenshots for the upcoming major release of Orbx's Kola map for DCS. The release has been teased on their YouTube channel, and now Threshold is the first to share these exciting images. The Kola map is a geographical representation that spans over 550,000 km2 of land across northern Scandinavia and northwestern Russia. It also includes large sections of the Norwegian Sea and Barents Sea for naval operations. Upon release, this map will showcase various airbases such as Bodø, Bardufoss, Evenes, Rovaniemi, Luleå, Vidsel, Monchegorsk, Olenya, Severomorsk-1 and -3, and many more. Additionally, the map will feature test ranges, naval bases, radar sites, storage sites as well as a complete network of railroads and roads. The Kola map will feature various civilian points of interest, such as key buildings, bridges, hydro dams, power plants, port facilities, and vertical obstructions. The region's beautiful coastline will be enhanced by dramatic fjords, glaciers, and numerous islands. The taiga forests dotted with lakes and the arctic tundra will add to the natural beauty of this area. There will be both Summer and Winter versions of the Kola map available. Orbx collaborated with experienced DCS campaign creators Baltic Dragon and Reflected Simulations to create engaging campaigns featuring F/A-18C and F-16C at launch. The map's release is imminent, so if you want to be the first to know when it is available, register your details at Orbx's website. Currently, there is no confirmed release date, but the trailer has a hidden Morse code message that says "Coming Soon." ‍ The next previews will show more terrain, so remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brnwax</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases North Weald Airfield for XP11 and XP12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brnwax"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662bb63635fa337836882bbc_11.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has released their rendition of North Weald Airfield for X-Plane 11 and 12, a small General Aviation airfield in Essex, UK. Opened in 1916 as Royal Flying Corps Station North Weald Bassett Aerodrome by the Royal Flying Corps (predecessor to the Royal Air Force), and in 1918 it became a Royal Air Force airport. This airfield played an important role in defending British skies during WWII. Hawker Hurricanes stationed in North Weald Airfield saw action in Dunkirk and the Battle of Britain. Later on in the war, Norwegian squadrons were reassigned to this airfield. Between the 1940s and 60s, this aerodrome was used for RAF glider training. The last combat unit left North Weald in 1958, while the RAF completely withdrew in 1964, and since then this aerodrome has been classified as civilian. Today, North Weald sees over 40,000 movements on average per year and is home to a collection of vintage and veteran aircraft such as the P-51 Mustang, Hawker Hurricane, Supermarine Spitfire, Douglas Dakota, Curtiss Kittyhawk, as well as early jet aircraft such as Hawker Hunter, de Havilland Venom, de Havilland Vampire, Folland Gnat and BAC Jet Provost. North Weald Airfield will feature up-to-date orthophotos, 4K PBR airport buildings, 3D Forrest (XP12 only), 3D vegetation, 3D volumetric grass, Custom night lighting, realistic HD static aircraft, accurate ground markings including cracks and wear &amp; tear, dynamic weather effects (XP12 only) and accurate airport layout based on latest charts. You can buy this scenery on the Boundless store for $13.75 USD. It requires around 970MB when installed. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/g15mya</id>
    <title>GATE15Scenery Releases Miyako Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/g15mya"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663133f74227e68d0af480a9_miyako1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GATE15Scenery has recently released its rendition of Miyako Airport (ROMY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Miyakojima, Okinawa Prefecture, and has a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers. It opened in 1943 as an Imperial Japanese Navy airbase, and civilian operations only took place for the first time in 1956. The airport sports a single terminal building with five gates and three extra stands for mid-sized aircraft. All Nippon Airways, ANA Wings, Japan Airlines, Japan Transocean Air, and Ryukyu Air Commuter serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, a basic interior model, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.01, requiring at least 391.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skyvat</id>
    <title>Sky-Additions Releases Paris-Vatry Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skyvat"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663136e2e8954cc558351816_vatry1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Sky-Additions has recently released their rendition of Paris-Vatry Airport (LFOK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It serves the champagne region in Northeastern France and is close enough to Paris (135km) to be considered by Ryanair as one of the Parisian airports. As of 2018, the airport had a yearly average of 61,826 passengers. It was built as an air base in 1953, housing fifty fighters in three large hangars. When France withdrew from the integrated NATO structure in 1967, the Americans left the base, leading to its closure. The French Air Force then used it for training until the early 2000s, when it was sold to civil interests and converted into a civilian airport. Besides handling occasional passenger traffic, it’s also a training pilot site for many airlines, such as Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, KLM, Transavia, Transavia France, and Swiss. Airbus has also used its relatively long runway for aircraft testing. It’s served by Ryanair, with flights to Marrakech and Porto.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, a custom GSX profile, detailed environmental elements, realistic airport vehicles, custom ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.64, requiring at least 120.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vueiva</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Ivato International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vueiva"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66313a8e0cc90a5e00caa2e2_ivato1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Ivato International Airport (FMMI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Antananarivo, the capital of Madagascar, with a yearly average of 845,000 passengers. Since the 1960s, this civil and military airport has served as Antananarivo's main airport. It features two terminals, one for domestic operations and the other for international operations. It's the main hub for Air Madagascar, the nation's carrier, taking passengers to South Africa, France, China, and nearby French islands. Air Austral, Air France, Air Mauritius, Airlink, Corsair International, Ethiopian Airlines, Kenya Airways, Tsaradia, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery accurately depicts the airport, with a highly detailed main terminal and its interior, custom runway materials, accurate night lighting, LOD optimization for optimal performance, an up-to-date layout, and much more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.92, requiring at least 301.76 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftsydx</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Previews Sydney Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftsydx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66314ed3b936dadb3d37e191_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlyTampa has recently revealed its newest scenery, Sydney Airport for X-Plane 12. The team has shared screenshots on Facebook and a trailer on YouTube, and the scenery is expected to be released soon. The team has shared some of the features and previews of the upcoming Kingsford Smith Airport rendition for X-Plane 12. The airport has been fully customized with custom mesh, custom night lighting, SAM and LST integration, and an Ortho4XP patch. Additionally, there are many more features that have not yet been revealed. As the busiest airport in Australia, Kingsford Smith Airport is a highly anticipated addition to X-Plane 12. Although FlyTampa has not announced the pricing and release date, they have confirmed that the airport is coming soon. We will update you with more information as soon as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxkm</id>
    <title>Orbx Kola Map Previews and Features</title>
    <updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxkm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66321d2ea471ee5009516050_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Threshold recently received exclusive screenshots of the upcoming Kola Map for DCS, and today, we have three more exclusives to share with you. The community has highly anticipated the new Kola Map, which will cover large parts of Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia. As of now, the project is listed as "coming soon," with the release of the early access version imminent. The Kola Map will first be available for early access and will be feature-packed with a multitude of airports. There will be two airports in Finland, five in Russia, two in Norway, and three in Sweden. Additionally, early access ensures a complete base terrain, highly detailed topography for the entire map, and lots of POIs, road and railroad networks, night lighting, and many landmarks to explore. Although early access will be available first, many future features have already been planned. Winter textures are scheduled to ensure the representation of the cold and harsh climate up North. A multitude of military airfields like Bardufoss and Kirkenes and a variety of civilian airports, including Tromsø and Luleå, are also planned. Also, general improvements to landscape features have been scheduled. The official store page for the Kola Map is now available on Orbx. Be sure to check it out for more information and screenshots. ‍ We will update you with more information as soon as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
