<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-07-29T18:27:14.192629+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vstboh</id>
    <title>Velocity SkyTech Releases Bournemouth Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vstboh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66997e90f6ea520bbabe692b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Velocity SkyTech has recently released its rendition of Bournemouth Airport (EGHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located just 4 miles away from Bournemouth, England, and is an international airport that serves a variety of destinations, particularly warm and summer destinations. The airport first opened as a Royal Air Force station, called RAF Hurn, in 1941. In 1944, it was transferred to civil control and even served as London's international airport before the opening of Heathrow in 1946. Over the years, the airport has served a variety of airlines and destinations, growing to its current state. Last year, the airport served just over 950.000 passengers and had over 5000 aircraft movements. It is the focus city for Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways, and also serves airlines like easyJet, offering flights to destinations including France, Greece, and Spain. The newly released Bournemouth Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator comes with several features, such as exterior and interior 3D modeling of the terminal buildings, PBR textures, performance optimization, and more. The add-on requires 375.07 MB of storage space and is currently on sale on SimMarket for approximately $13.02. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777038</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates Entire MSFS Product Lineup</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777038"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66999818f0169fc6be3b28f7_anz1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued significant updates to all of their products for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing stability improvements, bug fixes, new textures (DC-6), and more. ‍ The newly released 777-300ER has been updated to 2.00.0039, focused once again on stability and performance improvements, mitigating new issues reported by the customers, with more to come in the near future as they are not convinced about finding all of them.  ‍ The new update also brings the possibility of updating the Navigraph navdata via the Ultimate Flight Tablet, ultimately allowing seamless data updates straight from the flight deck on both PC and Xbox (when available). A QR code within the UFT also links people to the 777 online manual. ‍ The complete changelog for 0039 follows below: Regarding the 777’s appearance on the Marketplace and Xbox, it’s set for a dual release and expected to happen within two to four weeks. The upcoming 77F is their current development focus and is nearing its beta testing stage. PMDG anticipates it to be a rather quick process, and they are already evaluating the next variant after that. A major update has also been pushed to the 737 lineup, bringing the stability and performance fixes they used on the 777. It has also been pushed to the marketplace and might take around two weeks to show up. ‍ More 737 updates are expected as they continue squashing the issues with the 777, and some of the structural changes from the Triple Seven will be back-ported, including the new navdata format, updated lateral path solving, updated autopilot roll modes, updated EFB, and more. ‍ Last but not least, the DC-6 has been updated with the new cockpit textures. It has also been rolled out to the marketplace and might take around two weeks to become available. ‍ PMDG concluded the weekly update thread with a brief note on the 747’s progress. It has been in development since January and is progressing nicely, with “unexpected and very exciting things planned for this product line.”  ‍ PMDG’s product line is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $77.73.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bai103</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Dubai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bai103"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66999b04d8d3c84361a86bb5_dubai4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated - again - their rendition of Dubai International Airport (OMDB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing the ILS/PAPI mismatch in previous versions and more. Update v1.0.3 brings a complete repositioning of the ILS beacons and PAPIs using GE coordinates to match real life, adjusted autogen building heights, and minor ground service equipment tweaks. The airport is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.11 (on sale), requiring at least 4.4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dtw105</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Detroit Metropolitan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dtw105"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66999f47a97a2a5f8a2322a9_dtw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their rendition of Detroit Metropolitan Airport (KDTW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing new ground service equipment, new car models, reworked building LODs, and more. Update v1.0.5 brings newer variants of people, cars, vegetation, and ground service equipment, new building LODs for improved performance, an overall reduction in clutter, and other minor bug fixes. The changelog follows below: v1.0.5 - Rework of building LODs - Removed SD/HD option - Replaced all GSE with new versions - Replaced vegetation models - Replaced people models - Replaced car models - Updated terrain sculpting method - North terminal LOD radius issue fixed - Added A65 parking - Significant reduction in the number of parking and hash markings (replaced with more efficient decals) - no visual change. - Overall reduction in the number of people, cars, GSE etc. - Corrected missing ILS from VFR map. - Closed fence gap The scenery is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.30 (on sale), requiring at least 4.73 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/egphv2</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases Edinburgh Airport II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/egphv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/669a826c5a9f7b377c663753_egph1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ Pyreegue Dev Co. recently released their new rendition of Edinburgh Airport (EGPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This is a major upgrade to the original release from 2021, entirely rebuilt from the ground up. It is the busiest airport in Scotland, with a yearly average of 14.7 million passengers. Over 200 scheduled flights connect Edinburgh to the world every day.  Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada (seasonally), Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, easyJet, Edelweiss Air, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, Jet2.com, JetBlue, KLM, Loganair, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and Vueling serve it. Rebuilt from the ground up to meet the ever-growing industry standard, Pyreegue’s Edinburgh II features an accurate rendition of the airport, with true-to-life terrain elevation profile, a 3D model of their drainage system, LiDAR scanned interiors and buildings, latest satellite imagery data, an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, dynamic ATC tower lights, many landside buildings, custom static GSE vehicles, dynamic gate doors and VDGS (requires GSX), and a custom-made GSX profile. It’s available on Contrail for $14.15 (Temporary launch price; regular price will be $28.22). To install it, you need at least 3.4 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ia3112</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ia3112"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/669ac52fd397ac66977bf7ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an update for their Airbus A300-600R add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The aircraft has been updated to version 1.1.2 and includes various fixes to systems, art, sound, and more. The new update has been in the works for the past 10 weeks. It has been designed to provide the aircraft with more immersion and authenticity. Some of the notable changes include performance improvements, an overhaul of lateral and vertical navigation, and the ability to have a custom EFB background. The new version features a significant changelog, which is listed below: ‍ v1.1.2 ‍ LNAV  Major overall system rewrite to better handle turns into initial fix and SID/STARS and holds. ‍ Systems New improvements: 1 - bleed PSI should be +/- 30psi during start 2 - LO OIL PRESS should be on at fuel lever on and ECAM oil pressure should be red, until 70PSI (goes out and goes green at 72PSI) 3 - engine generators should come online at 52% N2, not 49% 4 - Overhauled PW start sequence following feedback from real A300 pilot 5 – Optimisations to increase performance 6 - ENG FADEC CHANNEL 1+2  FAULT – ECAM logic [Feedback from real A300 pilot] 7 - Significant improvements to stability with WASM crashes and CTD Fixes: Fixed - WASM Crash on SEC-FPLN Deletion/Activation  Fixed - WASM crash doing right turns Fixed - WASM Crash on exiting Hold - EGSS ILS04 at ABBOT  Fixed – WASM crash related to terrain radar  Fixed - WASM crash when entering ZFW Fixed - SD Wheel Page - Green/Orange overtemp Arc showing around wrong wheel Fixed - Engine/APU Fire test logic corrected to match RW flow  Fixed - N1 Command/TLA Position Needle in wrong position during REV THRUST Fixed - When on glide aircraft can't be controlled Fixed - IRS mode and source selectors missing interaction Fixed - EFB remains off until Ext Power connected Fixed - If ISOL valves off fuel line is drawn between ctr and outer tanks Fixed - Showcase camera views Fixed - Quick views R and L view corrected to 90* Fixed - 3 max waypoints loading on AIRWAYS Fixed - ECAM FUEL Page - Right Inner fuel feed line not drawn  Fixed - Throttle Calibration not working (Throttle input not detected)  Fixed - TCAS traffic INOP Fixed - FCU Speed reverts to IAS when cruising in MACH mode once TOC is reached Fixed - Flight perf feedback – refined overall flight performance Fixed - Trim wheel missing integral lighting Fixed - Shutdown Checklist Fixed - FO Alt gauge OFF flag black pixels Fixed - FUEL SD page and left ECAM MEMO page updating at different rates Fixed - Fuel Pred - Pressing Fuel button in flight erases values Fixed - IRS Alignment logic  Fixed - Direct to logic – Now allows for direct entry change Fixed - VNAV Climb logic  Fixed - FMA/FMGS Logic  Fixed - MDCU Perf page logic Fixed - MCDU F-PLN page - END OF F-PLN stuck on L2 Fixed - Trim wheel set to 1.0NU, but when adjusting with key controls it snaps to 0NU Fixed - Speed targets in FMS don't match what PROF commands Fixed - TACT Mode logic Fixed - PROG - FUEL PRED PAGE - Altn airport EFOB showing as "-N&lt;-N" Fixed – Holds adjusted to follow magnetic course Fixed - ECAM - TO Mode Fixed - STBY Horizon lost alignment after landing when the APU on Fixed - Changing descent winds forecast does not affect T/D prediction | BTG Fixed - Engine Start Sequence logic Fixed - ND Config logic Fixed - ND Display logic Fixed - MDCU perf page logic Fixed - FD1 annunciation disappears from PFD Fixed - FMA modes logic corrected Fixed - BRK TEMP HIGH ECAM message not clearing when Brake Fan selected Fixed - MCDU flight plan display Fixed - Assigning a button to control brakes causes conflicting command Fixed - Secondary flight plan on the ND should be blue Fixed - "500" Callout on Takeoff in pax variant Fixed - Oil temp not rising fast enough Fixed - FLT CTL page missing title Fixed - FPLN Page - unable to input Lat/Lon as a fix Fixed - Erroneous T/D Fixed - Scrolling through F-Plan should be one wp per arrow press Fixed - CTD When loading into plane (FLY NOW button) Fixed - Rudder should still turn nosewheel by 6° Fixed - MCDU F-PLN page additions and corrections Fixed - ND Runway length filter for fields under 5000' length (may sometimes return smaller fields based on sim logic) Fixed - Plane stalls in VS mode when trying to hold a pitch below stall speed. Aircraft will now pitch down Fixed - Airway L620 not returning fixes on FLT plan page Fixed -  T/O Perf calc page hPa/inHg tied to WEIGHT UNITS option in settings Fixed - Weight &amp; Fuel changing mid-flight, then FU bugged and SBY Horizon bugged Fixed -  Loss of systems after returning from pause Fixed  -Systems and display freezing - LSGG-LFSB with the LUMEL 8K arrival, ILS Z 15 approach. Fixed -  CTD - KLAX star ANJLL4 via DNERO transition, ILS 25L via CRCUS Fixed  -Speedbrakes show as deployed on ECAM on spawn in Fixed - No Flex temp on TO calcs with PW Fixed - BUS 1 should be connected to ESS BUS, GEN OVRD should have an arrow [Feedback from real A300 pilot] Fixed -  Landing distance calculator bug fixed  Fixed - Elapsed Timer does not show "1" in 10h02m ET Fixed - Fix landing distance calculator (in current state, the METAR data does not sync) Fixed - T/o Perf calculator does not mirror altimeter units from settings Fixed - Eng Fire squib test still shows in Amber Fixed - [EFB] MTOW discrepancy on TakeOff Perf Calculator Added – You can now have a custom background on your EFB Fixed - FMS: Distance to T/D should report actual distance and not distance between last w/p and T/D (distance between last and to should be actual distance, not segment distance between waypoints. [Feedback from real A300 pilot] Improvement – Overhauled Packs off operations following feedback from real A300 pilot Fixed  - ILS freq selection: Only ILS freqs should be avail – uneven after “.” E.g.10/15/30/35…) .20/40/60 are not valid ILS freqs [Feedback from real A300 pilot]  Fixed - ECAM logic on start [Feedback from real A300 pilot] Fixed -  ECAM Brightness panel labels disappear when IDC Radios selected from EFB Fixed  - MODE CHG stuck on ND Fixed  - RMI Gauge VOR bearing/declination issue Fixed - Eng N1 should show until +/- 1% on shutdown Fixed - IMM EXIT prompt bug  Fixed - MCDU: PROG page - cannot return out of ENG OUT mode Fixed - FCU lights disappearing in flight (daytime) Fixed - Simbrief weights bugs Fixed – TOD ETA incorrect  Fixed - Winds have no effect on INIT B or FUEL PRED page Fixed - TRIP TIME and fuel burn predictions exaggerated Fixed  - FACT RWY19 TETAN 1A SID Fixed - FMS: OPT and MAX FL’s are in steps of FL005 [Feedback from real A300 pilot] ‍ Art Fixed - All outside animations and cockpit yoke tiller animations running at 5/10 fps Fixed - Stairs don't spawn on freighter Fixed - Backpanel  APU EGT, N1 and OIL gauge needles not lit at night Fixed - EGT warning light on GE engine config lighting up at PW limits Fixed - Oil QTY bugs animation no longer as smooth as before Fixed - Hole in rear of GE model (Checked all liveries) Fixed - FO TERR MODE GPWS decals missing Fixed - Floating fan blade numbers PW DHL (D-AEAF) Fixed - D-AEAF red texture line floating when bulk door opened Fixed - Reversed text on tyres when worn Fixed - Fuel Pressure Indicator Window missing on liveries Fixed - [XBOX][ART] Double edge around windows (and no textures) Fixed - L/R Stairs not showing when selected from EFB ‍ Sounds Fixed - External airport ambience sound adjustment Fixed – Various overhauls and minor tweaks  Fixed - Allow warnings/callouts/alerts volume to be controlled separately Fixed - Trim “Whooler” sound missing Fixed - APU external sounds  ‍ EFB Added can now create a custom background. The updated Airbus A300-600R is now available for download on the iniManager. At the time of writing, the aircraft is on sale and can be purchased from the iniBuilds Store for approximately $26.01. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniddu</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Dubrovnik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniddu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a010f4e94078d32d9948e9_dub1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Dubrovnik Ruđer Bošković Airport (LDDU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Dubrovnik-Neretva County with a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers. The airport opened in 1962 and quickly became Yugoslavia’s busiest. By 1987, it had already served nearly a million passengers.  In the 2000s, a new passenger terminal was built to replace the original from 1962, costing the administration 70 million euros. It’s the most modern terminal in the country so far.  It’s a hub for Croatia Airlines and many other European carriers, including Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Volotea, Vueling, and Wizz Air, serve it on a seasonal basis. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, an up-to-date layout, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.36, requiring at least 3.94 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350724</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases Airbus A350 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350724"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a1789bec8bb4bc29f9939d_a3501.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently uploaded a teaser video and an in-depth development update of their upcoming Airbus A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the most awaited addons for the platform so far. The short teaser video reveals some of the 3D art-focused details, along with a glimpse of the systems and sounds. Like their A300-600R, the A350 will feature fully modeled engine interiors, openable cowlings, and more. Users will be able to manage all possible maintenance options via EFB. The wear and tear system, also seen on the A300 to some extent, will be heavily improved. It will feature dynamic weathering of the aircraft, with paint peeling off the rivets, oil, and dirt streaks around potential leakage areas, dirt and grime on flaps, and more. It is said to build up as you fly the aircraft.  The cockpit features the same attention to detail, with PBR materials, high-resolution textures, and heavy optimization work to reduce VRAM usage without compromising visual quality.  Concerning the realism of the aircraft due to the apparent lack of data available, iniBuilds has said that—contrary to popular belief—there’s “quite a bit” of data around for core systems and overall functionality. To fill all the gaps, the missing spots were covered by renting a full-motion A350 simulator for multiple hours. They have also gathered twelve dedicated A350 experts to serve as a complimentary source of information. iniBuilds claims it will be not only visually stunning but will also far exceed anything else they have produced.  They have also made a FAQ section with many frequently asked questions regarding their upcoming aircraft and its features.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/300724</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes A300B4 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/300724"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a17f6e3df02ac1d8e38e9a_a3006.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a new development update on their upcoming A300B4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, covering their latest visual work on the cockpit. ‍ Their lead artist has been working hard for the past four months on recreating the remaining sections of the A300B4’s cockpit, taking into account every individual gauge, screw, knob, and panel, all with custom weathering and discoloration as per their reference aircraft. With the work now complete, Just Flight will be teasing new bits of the cockpit through the remaining development updates, starting with the center pedestal. ‍ They have authentically recreated the Carousel IV Inertial Navigation System (INS) Control Display Unit (CDU) on both sides. For those wishing for a more modern offering, the UNS-1 FMS will be an option. ‍ The following bits to be showcased are the stabilizer trim wheels, the speed brake lever, a flap/slat lever, the throttle levers, fuel cut-off switches, the parking brake handle, and some buttons. Lastly, the communications suite has 2 VHF control units, a transponder unit, two audio selector panels, weather radar controls, ADF navigation radios, and lighting controls.  The next development update will focus on the forward panel and autopilot.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/init33</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces T-33 Jet Trainer for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/init33"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a1853986721289168989ad_t331.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds, working alongside SimWorks Studios &amp; AceMaker aviation, has announced the development of a T-33 Jet Trainer for Microsoft Flight Simulator, part of their new “Premier” product line. Their Premier aircraft team comprises exceptional, high-quality 3D artists and programmers, as well as experts (pilots and engineers) who excel in crafting general aviation aircraft. The new project aims to further push the boundaries with extensive flight dynamic testing, greater system fidelity, and highly detailed visuals.  The T-33 is a turbojet training aircraft used by over 20 different air forces around the globe. Since its introduction, it has served a variety of roles, from an initial jet training platform to drone director, and even saw combat action during the Korean War! ‍ The upcoming add-on will feature highly detailed textures, an in-depth systems simulation, true-to-life handling characteristics, and a fully functional cockpit where every switch is operable. It will be available in two cockpit configurations: classic and modern, with a matching avionics suite. The complete feature list follows below: Exterior Art Features list:  Interior Art Features list: The expected release window is sometime around mid-August, and media partners will be allowed to showcase it a few days earlier. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777725</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777725"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a2c531c13d76899b69652f_update2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG recently issued a new update to their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing more stability improvements and mitigating another freeze-inducing code issue. Update 2.00.0041 is another micro update, focusing solely on stability improvements and error mitigation, as they are now switching their focus to wrapping up the upcoming 77F for beta testing. The changelog follows below: ‍ The 777-300ER is still under approval for the marketplace rollout. A testing build will become available early next week, and if things go well enough, it could be released in early August.  Last week’s 737 lineup update will become available for marketplace customers later today, bringing it up to par with the PMDG.com version. The same applies to the DC-6 texture update. Regarding implementing the new feature set from the 777 into the 737, the work is set to take place after the 77F is released. They plan to bring over the new navdata format and the new EFB functionality, which will take place through a series of updates as the work gradually passes through their testing process. Other 777 features, such as the new cabin lighting, openable cockpit windows, etc., still need to be evaluated and might or might not be carried over. ‍ The 777-300ER is available on PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/male25</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Velana International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/male25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a2d0bcd2991b5b9e31315f_male1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Velana International Airport (VRMM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Malé in the Maldives with a yearly average of 4 million passengers as of 2019. The airport started as a small strip of land on the island of Hulhulé in the early 1960s, with a runway made of slotted steel sheets. Four years later, the government and the residents started a joint effort to build a new asphalt runway, with four districts competing for a money prize for the fastest. Over 100 volunteers enlisted, and the runway was officially opened two years later. A decade later, the tourism boom in the Maldives led to the need for an international standard airport, and they figured it would be easier to upgrade the former Hulhulé Airport rather than build an entirely new one from scratch. With help from the International Airports Authority of India, the new airport was completed in 1981. Expansion work was carried out for the first time in 2018, with the construction of a new runway to serve longer aircraft. Although initially only used as a taxiway, it eventually got to serve its truthful purpose with the demolition of the old Trans Maldivian Airways seaplane terminal, which was in close proximity and not within international standards, therefore blocking the runway from being utilized. The demolition and eventual greenlight for usage only happened four years after completion. A new seaplane terminal was inaugurated in 2022 to replace the demolished one. It can accommodate more than 100 planes and handle up to 300 flights per day.  A new passenger terminal is also under construction and set to be completed in 2025. It will be over 78,000 square meters and handle up to 7.3 million passengers a year. It’s a hub for BeOnd, Maldivian, and Trans Maldivian Airways. Aeroflot, AirAsia, Air Astana, Air India, Air Seychelles, Austrian Airlines, Bangkok Airways, Batik Air Malaysia, Beijing Capital Airlines, British Airways, China Eastern Airlines, Condor, Discover Airlines, Edelweiss Air, Emirates, Etihad Airways, FitsAir, flydubai, flyme, Gulf Air, Hong Kong Airlines, IndiGo, ITA, Kuwait Airways, LOT, Malaysia Airlines, Manta Air, Neos, Oman Air, Qatar Airways, Royal Jordanian, Saudia, Shirak Avia, Sichuan Airlines, Singapore Airlines, SriLankan Airlines, Thai AirAsia, Turkish Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, Vistara, WizzAir, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed seaplane base, the new terminal (still under construction in real life), interior modeling, custom night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on their website for roughly $21.68, requiring at least 1.20 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/320232</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates Airbus A320 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/320232"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a41da33330d51949727e3e_installer3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update to their rendition of the Airbus A320 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes bug fixes, improvements, and a new installer. A brand new installer has been developed to speed up their release and update process. It breaks files into smaller parts and only fetches the parts that have been altered, significantly speeding up the whole process. They have gathered comparison data, and the difference is astounding: from 2 minutes and 14 seconds total (download and installation) to 35 seconds (fastest result). They also reiterate that the figures may vary depending on hardware specs and storage speed. The sounds have also seen a rework, with binaural microphone recordings straight from a captain’s headset during a full flight, with cross-referenced ADS-B data to ensure the audio matches the correct phases of the flight. The result, balanced and adjusted accordingly, is much closer to the real thing. They have also improved the over- and behind-wing experience with new N1 bearing recordings, airflow, N2, and behind-intake buzzsaw on the CFM56s. They also have done further sound balancing on IAEs, with new airflow recordings, buzzsaw improvements, and a new window vibration/rattle on both at high power settings. The atmospheric sound model also received its fair share of refinement. Different ambient conditions influence the engine sounds, as demonstrated in the video below, which showcases the difference between a takeoff in the cold and dry versus hot and humid. Last but not least, still regarding sound improvements, Fenix added two hydraulic pump options: Vickers and Parker, as per the real thing (it can be fitted with either), and their subtly different sounds. The systems and flight model were not massively improved due to their strong focus on the upcoming expansion (A319 and A321). Still, they have improved the ADIRU wind simulation, so the airplane gathers wind data through its sensors rather than fetching it through the simulator. The fly-by-wire was made slightly smoother in pitch while retaining precision, and the ground-to-air blend was made creamier. The full changelog follows below: ‍ The Fenix A320 is available on their website for roughly $64.33. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fss727</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Announces Release Date for Boeing 727-200F Add-on</title>
    <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fss727"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a6b1d07204103b480e16cc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio recently shared new information on its Discord about the upcoming Boeing 727-200F add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The developer revealed details about the release date and price of the aircraft. The new 727 by FSS is now set to be released to the public on August 6th at around 08:00 UTC. Originally, the release was planned for the end of July, but the team has decided to delay it slightly to ensure that the aircraft includes all the necessary last-minute updates before the release. Moreover, the team has announced that various content creators, both big and small, will have access to the aircraft on August 1st at 00:00 UTC. This will allow everyone to have a proper look at the upcoming 727 before its public release. It's important to note that the GNS-XLS, initially scheduled for the first release, will be delayed to allow for improvements to the INS system. The GNS-XLS will still be added to the aircraft, but it is expected to be included 1-2 months after the initial release. Lastly, the team has announced that the long-awaited Boeing 727-200F will be priced at $42. The upcoming aircraft will be available in just 8 days, and Threshold will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orgthd</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases MSFS Global Trees HD for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orgthd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a755c101aeca5c1a18e946_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released its newest add-on, MSFS Global Trees HD, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This add-on, created by developer Dmytro Krykunov, aims to enhance realism by replacing all standard vegetation with high-quality specimens. The add-on allows users to customize and shape the landscape in Microsoft Flight Simulator according to their preferences. It offers features such as the ability to manage project data, change vegetation seasons, and replace the default grass. Dmytro designed the add-on to ensure that the biome and its vegetation are vibrant, diverse, and of high quality. MSFS Global Trees HD comes with various features, including high-quality replacement of default vegetation, the option to change vegetation seasons, the ability to replace default grass with six new types of grass, reworked biomes, and a software tool to adjust vegetation seasons and grass types. This add-on requires 2.78 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx for approximately $13.90. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/heca12</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Cairo International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/heca12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a7b13265af9e261ed19cb7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released the X-Plane 12 version of Cairo International Airport (HECA). Following the release of its MSFS version, the team has now launched their rendition for X-Plane 12. Cairo International Airport serves the capital of Egypt, Cairo, and is situated approximately eight nautical miles from the city's central business district. The airport handles an average of 14 million passengers annually. The airport originally opened as John Payne Field Air Force Base during the Second World War. After the war, the airport was taken over by the Civil Aviation Authority, marking the start of its use for civil aviation. It eventually replaced the former Heliopolis Airport. Today, the airport has three terminals and serves as the hub for the airlines EgyptAir, Nile Air, Air Cairo, and Air Arabia Egypt. Additionally, a variety of other airlines operate to and from the airport, providing connections to destinations worldwide. The newly released Cairo International Airport for X-Plane 12 comes with a variety of features, including highly detailed models, SAM animated jetways, high-quality PBR textures on objects and ground, complete autogen around the airport, ground traffic, weather textures, and more. The scenery requires 1.87 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for about $25.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
