<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-04-24T18:21:27.203036+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hfasfs</id>
    <title>HiFi Releases Active Sky FS for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hfasfs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66214b88e66c718a4155a31b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. HiFi has recently released Active Sky FS for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a highly anticipated product among flight simulation enthusiasts. This new add-on brings a variety of advanced weather features to MSFS, including the popular Active Sky Weather Engine, Enhanced Cloudscape, and Active Air Effects. Active Sky FS has direct integration with MSFS, which provides seamless integration for users. The add-on includes both passive and preset weather options. Passive mode uses MSFS live weather data, while preset weather uses Active Sky’s weather data, giving users the option to choose the mode that best suits their preferences. This feature-packed add-on offers many exciting features, such as direct MSFS integration, ASFS preset weather, ASFS passive weather, active air effects, historical weather, enhanced cloudscape, Active Sky weather engine, ground snow simulation, and much more. The add-on requires 1GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $24.52. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/muc220</id>
    <title>sim-wings Updates Munich International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/muc220"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66215fcb5b8a467dda458eac_mupdate1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. sim-wings recently updated its rendition of Munich International Airport (EDDM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing a wide list of bugs and making many enhancements, keeping the scenery up to date with its real-world counterpart. It serves Munich and Upper Bavaria with a yearly average of 47.9 million passengers.  It opened in 1992, replacing Munich-Riem Airport, which served Munich from 1939 to 1992. It was deemed hard to expand because of the growing number of inhabitants around its proximity, leading to the desire to move the airport to a completely different location. Construction work started in 1980 in the small village of Franzheim, whose 400 inhabitants were moved elsewhere. Operations began on 17 May 1992, with Riem closing the night before. ‍ It's one of Lufthansa's main hubs, with a comprehensive route network. Condor, Eurowings, Eurowings Discover, and TUIfly Deutschland also base themselves at the airport. ‍ Update 2.2.0 includes many corrected taxiway signs, removal of floating objects, Terminal 2 improvements (improved Lufthansa sign, for example), the addition of a meteorology station near RWY 26L, jetway connection tweaks, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ It's available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $24.99, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/josfra</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/josfra"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662242952fac797feee444c5_jofra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AviationLads has put together a trailer showcasing Aerosoft's upcoming rendition of Frankfurt Airport (EDDF), the busiest airport in Germany, with a yearly average of 59.9 million passengers as of 2023. Developed by Jo Erlend Sund and his team, their Frankfurt rendition was announced during FSExpo 2023. Aerosoft has been updating us ever since with development progress reports on their official landing page for the scenery.  While there's no official feature list, the trailer showcases great attention to detail, with custom ground clutter, custom jetways, accurate taxiway markings, landside buildings, custom dynamic lighting, and more. The pricing and release date are still to be revealed, but Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tornad</id>
    <title>Indiafoxtecho Releases Tornado for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tornad"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66225c75e9679a26c0de91b5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Indiafoxtecho has recently released its latest aircraft, the Tornado, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This plane is a long-range, supersonic fighter-bomber, which made its first flight in 1974. Since then, it has been operated by numerous operators and is still in use by many today. The Tornado is a military aircraft manufactured by Panavia Aircraft GmbH. Its maiden flight took place in West Germany in 1974, where it was first used by the German Air Force. In total, the German Air Force received 247 Tornadoes, while the German Navy received 112. The aircraft has been operated by several countries, including the Italian Air Force, Royal Air Force, and Royal Saudi Air Force. Despite being an older model, the Tornado remains popular among aviation enthusiasts and is still used by some air forces today. The aircraft has been recently released and comes with a detailed visual model, multiple liveries, a realistic flight model, a detailed system simulation, a realistic sound package, and many more features. The add-on requires 2.23GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $31.94. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftlppt</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Lisbon Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftlppt"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66227b3fd8a6a69bfcb53261_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released its version of Lisbon Airport (LPPT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the Portuguese capital of Lisbon, it is the 12th largest airport in Europe, serving over 33.6 million passengers yearly. Lisbon Airport opened on October 15th, 1942 during World War II, but remained neutral throughout the war. This allowed both German and British operators to fly to the airport. By 1946, major airlines like KLM, Iberia, and Pan Am started using the airport. In 1959, the airport underwent major upgrades to handle airliners like the classic Boeing 707. In 1983, there were more upgrades to buildings and facilities, and in 1991, the first air bridges were installed. Since then, the airport has been growing and attracting tons of airlines to operate there. Today, TAP Air Portugal, Azores Airlines, easyJet, and Ryanair have hubs there, and you can fly all over the world from New York to Dubai or Amsterdam. The newly released Lisbon Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator includes many features, such as highly detailed buildings, PBR texturing, real-world elevation data, runway slope, custom jetways, custom lighting, and more. The add-on requires 1.03GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $18.12. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbsgru</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations &amp; db Scenery Release Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbsgru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618c9dead3989329b5a7ebe_gdru1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations and db Scenery have recently released their rendition of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves São Paulo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 41.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in the country. The airport's planning started back in 1967, when the government first considered renovating the airport infrastructure in the country and ran some studies to figure out which step to take next, leading to a straightforward conclusion: Congonhas (São Paulo's main airport at the time) was not big enough to sustain the ever-growing demand, nor could it be easily expanded, which led to a plan B: transforming a former Air Force Base into a full-fledged international airport. After decades of planning, construction started in 1980, with three runways and four passenger terminals in mind at first, which turned into two runways and two terminals due to time and cost constraints. It was inaugurated five years later and quickly became the city's primary airport.  ‍ Four years after the inauguration, the runways were extended, and the passenger terminals were expanded, bringing the overall capacity from 7.5 million passengers a year to 8.5.  A third terminal, planned for 2001, was built a decade later, along with Terminal 4. The first phase (of Terminal 4's construction) had it holding up to 5.5 million passengers a year, and the second phase brought it to its intended capacity of 8 million passengers, making it so the airport could handle 28.5 million passengers in total. The terminals were renumbered in 2015, with Terminal 4 becoming Terminal 1, Terminals 1 and 2 becoming Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 retaining its numbering. ‍ It's a hub for Gol Transportes Aéreos and LATAM Brasil and served by Azul, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, an up-to-date taxiway layout, custom landside, custom terrain mesh, custom ambient sounds, dynamic lighting effects, detailed ground markings, and more. It's available in the MSFS Marketplace for $9. Refer to the product page for further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsigru</id>
    <title>Vref Simulations Updates Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsigru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6622b1cafd245fc3bbf93dc9_gru1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Vref Simulations has recently updated their rendition of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding a new custom jetway model, new landside buildings, texture improvements, and more. Update 1.5, the first since its official release earlier this month, adds a new custom jetway model on Terminal 2, minor bug fixing, texture improvements, satellite imagery tweaks, landside tweaks, and new buildings. The changelog follows below: Changelog V1.5 The scenery is available on SimMarket for roughly $9.07, requiring at least 573.59 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/isisss</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Releases Changi Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/isisss"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6622b74dc00f4c31e61a8cc0_wsss1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Imaginesim has recently released the V2 of their Singapore Changi Airport (WSSS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Singapore with a yearly average of 58.9 million passengers, making it one of the world's busiest.  It was inaugurated 42 years ago when the Singaporean government was forced to build a new airport to cope with the region's ever-growing demand for air travel.  At first, their original plan was to expand Paya Lebar, the former main airport in Singapore, but the 1973 Oil crisis changed everything. By 1975, they had already decided to build a brand new airport at the eastern tip of the main island of Changi, at the Changi Air Base. After its first year of operation, the airport had already handled an average of 12.1 million passengers, which led to the construction of a second passenger terminal in the 1990s. Terminal 3 soon followed in 2008, and then Terminal 4 in 2017. Terminal 5, which is planned to be larger than all four combined, is expected to open in 2030. ‍ It's a hub for FedEx Express, Jetstar Asia, Scoot, and Singapore Airlines. AirAsia, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air India, Air New Zealand, All Nippon Airways, Cathay Pacific, China Southern Airlines, EVA Air, Garuda Indonesia, Hainan Airlines, IndiGo, KLM, Lufthansa, Qantas, Swiss, United Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-definition textures, performance optimization, custom VDGS, custom animated jetways, 52 square kilometers of total coverage, Terminal 5's construction area, and more. ‍ It's available on their website for roughly $24.75. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fps190</id>
    <title>Flight Procedures Simulation Releases Embraer 190 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fps190"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6623ea31a986b8d315c1d170_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Procedures Simulation (FPS) has recently released its Embraer 190 add-on for X-Plane 12. This is the next aircraft in line after the E195, which was released last summer. The developers behind the new Embraer 190 are the same as those who created the Supercritical Simulations Group (SSG), so this is not their first project for X-Plane. The Embraer 190 comes packed with a range of features. The Embraer E190 is a member of the Embraer E-Jet family. This Brazilian-made aircraft is a narrow-body airliner. The project was initially revealed by Embraer in 1997, but it was not officially unveiled until two years later. In 2002, the first E-Jet had its maiden flight, and the E190 model made its debut in 2004. The E-Jet family comprises of four commercial airliners, including the E170, E175, E190, and E195. To date, 568 E190s have been delivered, with the most prominent operators being JetBlue (48), Aeroméxico Connect (46), KLM Cityhopper (32), and Tianjin Airlines (31). Thanks to these operators, the E190 can be seen all over the world. The new Embraer 190 is packed with features, such as a highly accurate rendition of the E190, tons of animations, wing flex animation, custom lights, a detailed 3D cockpit, a custom FMS system, a custom flight model, custom sounds, an integrated tablet, and much more. The add-on is currently available on the X-Plane. Org Software Store for $69.00. However, there is a sale going on at the moment, and the price has been reduced to $55.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/chinok</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics CH-47F Available for Pre-Order</title>
    <updated>2024-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/chinok"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6623ef561207dc1b6e4f21c6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has recently previewed its newest helicopter for DCS, the CH-47F Chinook. Nicknamed “The Hook”, it is one of the most famous military transport helicopters in the world. It has been and is being used by over 20 nations worldwide. The famous helicopter is now available for preorder. Engineered for exceptional stability and control, the CH-47F’s tandem rotor configuration ensures agility and eases loading and unloading procedures. The design gives the CH-47F possibilities for operation in environments inaccessible to others. The absence of tail rotor interference permits rear ramp access on varied terrains, including unprepared or mountainous locations, capitalizing on its remarkable landing capability. Furthermore, the aircraft's design facilitates high-altitude flight up to 20.000 feet, surpassing other helicopters in its weight category. The CH-47F. currently on pre-order, will feature detailed external and internal modeling, cockpit and cargo hold, accurate flight model, and a fully interactive and VR-ready cockpit. No release date has been announced as of the publishing of the article. You can pre-order the Chinook on the ED store for $48.99. ‍ Stay tuned for more flight sim news to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpw38</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews PA-38</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpw38"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6624329a68bad3ce4dc08683_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has previewed their upcoming aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the Piper PA-38 Tomahawk, on YouTube. After the PA-28R Arrow, Turbo Arrow III/IV, and PA-28 Warrior II for MSFS, another General Aviation classic is under development. Based on a real-life Tomahawk, G-BNKH, PA-38 will, as always, feature accurate systems, high-quality modeling and texturing, realistic wear and tear, a variety of customization options, and an immersive sound set recorded from the real aircraft.  This two-seater 112hp piston-engine aircraft with a fixed-pitch propeller is one of the most famous training aircraft. Used all around the globe, JF decided to reflect its popularity in the diversity of liveries available at release. Liveries from the UK, USA, Germany, France, Belgium, Australia, and Slovenia, and a custom livery supporting the MSFS tail number. As of the publishing of this article, the release date and price of Just Flight PA-38 Tomahawk are unknown, but Threshold will keep you updated as always!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lga101</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates LaGuardia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lga101"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662687f3664455587651f087_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has updated their recently released LaGuardia Airport (KLGA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new update brings various features and improvements making the scenery more realistic. The new update for LaGuardia, v1.0.1, includes various improvements, fixes, and enhancements. See the full changelog below: ‍ Changelog v1.0.1: - VDGS textures improved, - PAPI light fixes, - TDZ lights added to RWY04, - GS double antennas fixed, - Jetway fixes, - Snowplows added, - Terminal fixes, - Improved stadium area, - Parkings added to AFCAD, - Some A parking removed from AFCAD, - Fixed AA Hangar LOD. The updated version of LaGuardia is available on Contrail for approximately $16.21 and requires a total storage space of 1.93GB. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftkbos</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Boston Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftkbos"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6627a2d6d6116c4cc6818a07_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has released an update for their version of Boston Logan International Airport (KBOS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new update comes with various improvements and new features. The latest update, V1.7, for Boston Logan includes several bug fixes and enhancements. Below is the complete changelog: ‍ Changelog V1.7: New Taxiway Layout at F, T, Q and N New Hilton Hotel Model Taxiway blue edge lights now flat models like realworld Fixed bad rendering on Lipstick Terminal E Improved LODs and Performance New night lighting on American Hangar to match real world Missing PAPI added to Runway 27 Red lights added to end of 22L Misc visual tweaks and improvements The newly updated version of Boston Logan International Airport is now available on Contrail for approximately $20.27 and requires a total storage space of 2.52GB. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwpspr</id>
    <title>RW Profiles Releases Springfield-Branson National Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwpspr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66291b0bd8da09705a0b3544_springers1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RW Profiles has recently released their rendition of Springfield-Branson National Airport (KSGF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Springfield and Branson in Missouri with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers as of 2023. It opened as Springfield-Greene County Airport in July 1945, replacing their former - much smaller - main airport.  American Airlines started scheduled service to the newly built airport in that same year, only pulling out in 1963. Chicago and Southern landed in 1948, and Ozark in 1951. Ozark was also responsible for the airport’s first scheduled jet service with their brand-new DC-9s in 1966.  The airport’s current name was adopted in 1992 as the administration attempted to capitalize on Branson’s ever-growing tourist industry (even though it’s around 80 km away).  In May 2006, construction work started on a new terminal, inaugurated three years later, designed by Reynolds, Smith &amp; Hills.  Allegiant Air, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, United Express, DHL, FedEx Express, and UPS Airlines serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, accurate night lighting, a custom runway, highly detailed models, up-to-date airport layout, LOD optimization, and an official GSX profile. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.24, requiring at least 2.35 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eca777</id>
    <title>Exclusive Closed Alpha and Public Beta Announced for FlightFactor’s 777v2 Release: Invitations Rolling Out </title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eca777"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66292049518cd676100f1e79_ram1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently published a statement on their social network pages with their final decision on the release policy of their upcoming Boeing 777 v2 for X-Plane, including an exclusive non-public alpha program and a public beta later down the line. A previous statement made by Ramzzess on X-Plane.Org Forums stirred quite a bit of drama from the community as it mentioned their ponderation of a beta release without any vertical guidance at all, which led to a poll and their decision to feature a non-public alpha program first, where a select few would be chosen to purchase and test the product after signing a non-disclosure agreement.  Later, a public beta will roll out with all the major features (except CPDLC). Therefore, once that is out, the public beta testers will not have to experience the 777 without a working VNAV. Invitations for the closed alpha have been rolling out since yesterday (23/04). The purchased keys will be permanent and grant access to future updates. They also made sure to highlight that there are no applications for the closed alpha, and invitees will be chosen by themselves. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsb244</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsb244"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662928fab802dffb292ad1cc_brazila1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has shared more previews of their upcoming Brasília - President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR), the third busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. A proper terminal building was inaugurated in 1971, designed by Tércio Fontana Pacheco, a Brazilian Air Force architect. The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more. It was divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The upcoming scenery is said to feature animated moving walkways, an up-to-date ground layout, terminal interiors, custom jetways with detailed interior, detailed landside, and more. There’s no release date yet, but it’s said to be coming soon. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
