<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-10-25T18:29:53.912566+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ran777</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS 2020 and Beyond</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ran777"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6700743a43d6279dcc6fba41_randy3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG has recently published a new development update delineating their plans for the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, pending updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, and their Boeing 777F, set to land before the new simulator releases. Robert Randazzo has divided the development update into two parts, concerning what is coming before MSFS 2024 releases and what is coming after it comes out in mid-November: ‍ The 737 Family is getting a significant update, which is supposed to get into testing soon. It brings many of the new features from the 777-300ER, like the new Navdata format. The process took longer than expected, but it's set to enter beta testing in the next few weeks. The update is scheduled to drop around the second half of October, bringing most of these planned changes for free. While it does diverge from their original plan of gradually rolling out the changes over September and October due to the memory corruption issue with the 777, the first update will bring a large chunk of the features, followed by smaller updates in the coming months to cover anything that might have been left unfinished. Updating the navdata via the tablet has been finally addressed, ultimately unlocking navdata updates for console users.  They will provide more information on the 737 update once it enters beta testing. ‍ The 777-300ER will get a new batch of liveries in the marketplace, mainly targeting console users, as the liveries can be obtained for free on PC. While they do not have a set timeline, they assume mid-October, like the 737 update. The 777F information is the exact same as yesterday's article, and the release is set for around the end of the month. ‍ Then, Randazzo hops right into the plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, regarding their current lineup being ported over to the new platform, new gameplay features from the new sim, new 777 expansions, 737 MAX, 747, and their "secret" project. ‍ Porting their product lineup to MSFS 2024 will begin as soon as they get their hands on the SDK. They are unsure whether changes will be required or not, nor do they know whether it's going to be straightforward, but they intend on bringing it over as quickly as possible within the limitations at hand. ‍ They have yet to have an answer on adding new MSFS 2024 features, such as walkaround and career mode compatibility, as they have yet to see the new platform. They will evaluate the features for their existing product lines and then determine the right course of action to make them compatible with the new stuff. Their primary focus will be on getting the products working fine first, and only then will they consider anything else.  ‍ The 777-200LR is projected to launch before the end of the year for both platforms, but PMDG makes sure to highlight that it's based upon publicly available marketing information from the new simulator. It does not take into account any possible challenges that might come with the advent of a new flight simulation platform and how that would impact higher priority items such as converting their pre-existing aircraft. The same applies to the 777-200ER. ‍ The 737 MAX project, on the other hand, has been deprioritized for the time being due to a higher-priority enterprise contract. That is because the developers working on the Max are also the same ones working on the high-priority enterprise project. They have been prioritizing the latter as it might play a factor in unlocking something for an upcoming post-747 project (hinted as a Big X Factor).  ‍ They also make sure to clarify they have nothing to do with the Asobo 737 Max, part of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024's default aircraft lineup. ‍ The PMDG 747 project has been underway since the beginning of the year. The developers are using all of the knowledge from their previous product lines to raise the detail bar a notch higher. They hint at a possible software build before the release of MSFS 2024 (for testing).  It's claimed to be their first product built with 3D scanning from inside and out, supported by high-detail images of the exterior surfaces using drone technology. That leads to "incredibly well-sculpted models that accurately capture even the really hard-to-model spots where compound curves can look different from all angles."  ‍ They do not have a projected release date for The Queen of the Skies, as the transition to MSFS 2024 will positively or negatively impact the overall process. PMDG will keep everyone updated with frequent development updates. ‍ Robert has also teased another – albeit so far "secret" – project, with an image of one of the steam gauges:  Their product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a330ms</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases A330 CEO Base Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a330ms"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6703f9e0da59a78affb1afc2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Aerosoft has recently launched the base pack for its long-awaited Airbus A330 expansion for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes the A330-300 PW variant. While some features are not included in the base pack, users can now fly this twin-engine wide-body aircraft. The first variant of the aircraft to fly the skies was the A330-300, which had its maiden flight in 1992. However, the plane did not enter service until 1994 with the airline Air Inter. After the A300, Airbus decided to design a new plane, the A330, as a descendant of the A300. Featuring fly-by-wire technology and a glass cockpit, the plane was very different from the original A300. In 2014, Airbus announced the new A330neo, making the A330 even more efficient. This variant entered service in 2018. As of the summer of 2024, a total of 1,610 A330 aircraft had been built. The plane is still being built and used to this day by airlines all over the world. The A330 CEO Base Pack includes the A330-300 with PW engines, with the RR and GE engine variants to be added later. The A330neo is also in development. The base pack offers various features such as a fully customized cockpit, custom fly-by-wire systems, custom autopilot systems, and more. It's important to note that there are some features not implemented in the base pack. Aerosoft has also confirmed that an update for MSFS 2024 will be provided free of charge. The newly released A330 CEO Base Pack requires 3 GB of storage space and is available at Aerosoft for $27.66. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx403</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Family for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx403"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670599b4f21739aca4db9393_1250410_20240307064302_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations recently issued a new update to its A320 family lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes performance optimization improvements, new ATSU features, and more. Update 2.2.0.403 features a substantial amount of changes on the systems front, with a new source of GPS ephemeris data, ILS autotune improvements, multiple MCDU fixes and tweaks, the addition of AOC FREE TEXT and AOC ATIS request via VATSIM and IVAO, cargo distribution on loadsheet, along with weight and balance code changes to support sharklets and ACTs in the future. Furthermore, art fixes were rolled out to address a safety card mishap (the A319 and A321 safety cards showed up on the A320), flap rod fixes on the A319 and A320, overhead bin improvements, and more. The EFB has also seen minor improvements, such as better cargo distribution to target an optimal CG setting, better take-off performance figures based on airport elevation, and a bug fix that prevents the EFB from starting blank if it had been in sleep mode during the previous session. The Flight and engine Models had also undergone improvements, with a fully reworked FADEC providing accurate FLX data and wholly mitigating the discrepancy between its assigned trust rating and what was, in fact, displayed. The changes also make it so that the FADEC rating will subtly change during the take-off roll, as the system is continuously computing the appropriate thrust output, thus causing variation on the EPR/N1. IAEs are still going to see further tweaks. ‍ The official changelog for the update follows below: ‍ The A320 Family is available on their website for roughly $104.81. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tol339</id>
    <title>Toliss Simulations Shares New A330-900 Previews for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tol339"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6705a5043a20474ad655bd6c_tol10.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Toliss Simulations recently shared new screenshots of their upcoming Airbus A330-900 for X-Plane 11 and 12, which will be released in 11 days (19/10). The fresh batch of pictures showcases some of the features that will be present in the aircraft, such as the Interactive Simulation Control System directly in the tablet, a new HUD (X-Plane 12 only), the brand new DRAIMS (Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System), and the runway overrun protection system. A few external screenshots were also shared a day prior, wearing the Airbus house livery in its full glory during multiple stages of a flight.  They have also stated that the beta phase has been well underway and that there are no major roadblocks to report, with the release still scheduled for the original date (19/10).  There’s no information on pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kiwhok</id>
    <title>KiwiFlightSim Releases Hokitika Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kiwhok"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6705af75ad660cb092e7069b_hok1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. KiwiFlightSim Limited has recently released their rendition of Hokitika Airport (NZHK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This uncontrolled aerodrome serves the homonymous city in New Zealand and has a yearly average of 40,000 passengers. The airport’s history dates back to the early days of aviation, with records going as far back as 1923 when Captain Maurice Buckley landed his Avro 504 in Hokitika. This marked a significant milestone for aviation in the region and demonstrated air travel’s potential to connect isolated communities on the West Coast. Eleven years later, Captain Bert Mercer established New Zealand’s first commercial airline – Air Travel NZ Ltd –, operating flights between Hokitika and other settlements in South Westland. Air Travel NZ’s route coverage expanded greatly during World War 2, taking passengers to Greymouth, Westport, and Nelson. Its location, though, has changed over the years because of the previous area’s susceptibility to flooding, leading to the construction of an entirely new airport in 1951. The new aerodrome attracted new airlines, with its first indeed scheduled service starting in 1953 with NAC, flying their DC-3 from Paraparaumu, Nelson, and Westport. It’s currently served by Air New Zealand, with ATR flights to Christchurch. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom aerial imagery, custom 3D modeling, custom ground service equipment, hand-crafted apron markings, custom night lighting, custom windsocks, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.43, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pesbia</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Releases Biarritz Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pesbia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6705b526454d14b3cd29b730_bia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Pilot Experience Sim has recently released the second version of its Biarritz Pays Basque Airport (LFBZ) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the homonymous city on the Bay of Biscay and has a yearly average of 970,000 passengers. The airport’s history dates back to 1936 when it was established as an airfield for private aviation, growing along with the demand for air travel in the area, which became exponential after the end of World War 2, leading to significant expansion work. The airport has continued to evolve over the previous decades, with infrastructure improvements, renovation work (the most recent one dating back to a decade ago), and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, PBR texturing, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/321426</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Family for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/321426"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67059a49775022bba0214876_fenixupdate3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update—and a subsequent hotfix—to their Airbus A321, part of their A319/A321 expansion from a few months back. The update replaces the CFM engine option from a CFM56-5B2 to a CFM56-5B3, offering 2000 lbf of extra thrust, making it the most potent CFM variant fitted on any A32X CEO. Besides the new engine, the update also brings a series of EFB fixes and improvements, along with tweaks to the avionics, systems, and flight model to accommodate the new engine option. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ A few hours later, they released a quick hotfix (2.2.0.426) to address an issue with contact points causing the A321’s nose wheel to sink into the ground and a preventive bug fix for low thrust output from the new engines under certain conditions. ‍ The A320 Family is available on their website for roughly $104.81. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lpptv2</id>
    <title>MK Studios Teases Upcoming Lisbon Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lpptv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670b01271275ed3f0397b111_lppt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. MK Studios has recently teased their upcoming rendition of Humberto Delgado Airport (LPPT) V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Lisbon, in Portugal, with a yearly average of 33.6 million passengers, making it the busiest in the Country. Its history dates back to 1942, when it opened during the height of World War 2 as a neutral airport, smuggling people in and out of Europe, regardless of nationality. Such neutrality made it so it was heavily monitored by both the Axis and Allied forces and even earned it a movie plot. The post-war period saw a fast expansion, reaching the 100,000-passenger mark by 1954. At that point, it was served by Air France, British European Airways, Iberia, KLM, Sabena, Pan Am, and Trans World Airlines.  The late 50s/early 60s brought a runway upgrade to accommodate larger aircraft such as the 707 and the DC-8. In 1962, a new 3130-meter-long runway allowed even bigger aircraft, such as the Boeing 747, for Lisbon’s first direct route to New York in the 1970s. A new terminal was built in 2007 for exclusive use by low-cost carriers. It features 22 check-in desks and fifteen departure gates. ‍ Terminal 1 was expanded shortly after, in 2011, with a large new shopping area, new airbridges and parking positions, and a new underground metro station. The airport’s infrastructure was also hugely improved during that period, with new cargo facilities, fuel storage, multiple refurbishments, and more. ‍ In 2019, the government unveiled a new expansion program, which has been widely opposed due to environmental concerns. ‍ It’s a hub for TAP Air Portugal and an operating base for easyJet and Ryanair. Aer Lingus, Air France, American Airlines, Air Canada, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, KLM, Latam Airlines, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, Turkish, United, and Wizz Air also serve it. ‍ The scenery is set to release in late October (23/10), and there’s no information on pricing yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/if73mp</id>
    <title>iFly Releases 737 MAX8 for MSFS in Pre-Release</title>
    <updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/if73mp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670d2eb0b1defa971db61422_PIC08.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. In an announcement on their Discord, developers at Flight One Software have made the pre-release version of the hotly anticipated iFly Boeing 737 MAX8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 available for purchase. The Boeing 737 MAX is Boeing’s newest narrow-body airliner series, developed in the 2000s and 2010s to replace the ageing 737 NG series. It features a redesigned fuselage, all-new winglets, and more efficient CFM LEAP-1B engines. It first flew in January 2016 and entered service in May 2017. In 2024, it is in service with 76 airlines across three variants. The 737 MAX is notable for the many technical problems that have plagued the aircraft.  In their announcement, Flight One Software said that this initial release is part of a “pre-release” rollout to “start testing purchasing through the iFly Manager”. According to Flight One, the iFly 737 MAX8 will include many features, including comprehensive systems, detailed 3D modelling, accurate sounds created by BorisAudioWorks, functioning cabin systems, and even a lavatory that flushes, something never seen before for any addon of its kind in MSFS.  The developers say that more information about the plane will be “posted later” but don’t specify an exact timeline. The aircraft is available for purchase at the Flight One Manager for $69.95 for new customers, but customers who have purchased the Prepar3D V5 version get a 40% discount, bringing the cost to $41.97, excluding local taxes. Support will be available via their Discord.  Flight One Software has not announced a date for the full release, but Threshold will keep you informed, so stay tuned for that and more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phomia</id>
    <title>Photorico Scenery Releases Mercedita International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phomia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670ff5e395aa313fc96c0f29_merceditas.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Photorico Scenery has recently released their rendition of Mercedita International Airport (TJPS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ponce, in Puerto Rico, with a yearly average of 215,000 passengers, making it the third busiest in the country. It was built in 1939 for airborne irrigation of sugarcane fields (which explains its name, given after the farm it served: Hacienda Mercedita). At first, it was only 260 meters long and 15 meters wide, with its first major upgrade only happening in the 1940s, when the United States Navy transformed it into a military airfield (it was eventually given back to Puerto Rico in 1947). It became Ponce’s main airport after the authorities determined the previous airport (Losey Field) didn’t meet the minimum safety requirements, leading to plans to construct a new proper airport at Mercedita Airfield.  It was officially inaugurated as Mercedita Airport in late 1955, with the first scheduled service starting only a decade later, in 1965. The airport did not operate international routes until 1971. The first runway revamp project began in the early 1960s, extending it to 914 meters and accommodating a wider variety of aircraft. With international plans in mind, though, they had to expand it again in 1971, bringing its length to 1,500 meters so that Boeing 727s could safely fly into the airport.  The late 1980s brought an even more expressive overhaul, a new runway expansion (2,100 meters), and a remodeled passenger terminal.  In the early 1990s, the runway was extended by 580 meters so that American Airlines could fly there from Miami. Multiple improvements to the terminal building also added 1,350 square meters of additional space. The runway underwent further expansion in 2010, reaching its current total length of 2,440 meters, making it suitable for any narrowbody jet aircraft. It’s served by Frontier Airlines and JetBlue, with flights to Orlando (Florida). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom PBR textures, custom night lighting, custom landmarks and VFR reference points, custom ground textures, and more.‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $13.49, requiring at least 362.49 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atepma</id>
    <title>Atelic Releases Madeira Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atepma"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6712da52bcb8b38248467723_mad1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Atelic has recently released their rendition of Cristiano Ronaldo International Airport (LPMA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Madeira, in Portugal, with a yearly average of 4.8 million passengers, making it the 4th busiest in the Country. Opened in 1964 with a single, 1600-meter-long runway, which was relatively short for safe operation due to the airport's tricky nature, considered by many as the "European Kai Tak."  Traffic demand kept on growing, which led to the construction of a new passenger terminal in the early 1970s. The figures by then were nearing the half a million mark (yearly). In the late 1970s, a TAP Air Portugal 727 overran the runway, crashing shortly after and killing 131 of the 164 passengers onboard. The accident led to an urge to extend the runway, which was carried on in the early 1980s, adding 200 meters of total extension.  Twenty years later, a much more significant extension project was carried on, which involved drilling 180 pillars deep into the bedrock to ensure maximum stability. It was considered as one of the world's most difficult engineering projects at the time due to the terrain at hand. Such a feat earned the airport an Outstanding Structure Award in 2004 by the International Association for Bridge and Structural Engineering. It recently underwent a modernization project by its operator, bringing its infrastructure up to modern standards and allowing the handling of 1,400 passengers per hour. The runway's pillared structure was also strengthened, just in case. It's a focus city for TAP Air Portugal and an operating base for Ryanair. Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Condor, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Smartwings, Transavia, TUI (UK, Belgium, Netherlands, Germany), United Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-definition terrain, an up-to-date ground layout, custom runway slope matching real figures, a full terminal interior, custom vegetation, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $22.44, requiring at least 1.60 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/toeneo</id>
    <title>Toliss Simulations Releases Airbus A330-900 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/toeneo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67142bc21a3582be41760263_toliss.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Toliss Simulations has recently released their rendition of the Airbus A330-900 for X-Plane 11 and 12, bringing the popular new widebody to the simulation realm with a vast feature list. The A330-900 is the largest widebody in the A330neo family. It retains the fuselage length of the A330-300 while offering unparalleled fuel efficiency and range. It also yields the lowest seat-mile costs among midsize widebody aircraft.  Toliss’ rendition includes a list of A330-900 specific features, such as the HUD (X-Plane 12 only), DRAIMS (Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System), ATSAW (Airborne Traffic Situational Awareness), ROW/ROPS (Runway Overrun Warning and Runway Overrun Prevention System), and TOS (takeoff surveillance). Their ISCS is now built into the EFB. It also includes a detailed Flight Management Guidance System with three independent MCDUs, two independent autopilots, SID/STAR and airways support, full VNAV guidance, altitude and speed constraints, equitime point computation, and more. Furthermore, it also sports a full-fledged fly-by-wire system with reversion between normal law, alternate law one and two, and direct law. The full feature list follows below: Detailed FMGS: Accurate systems: 3d modelling Usability features ‍ It’s available on X-Plane.Org’s Store for $89.99, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksdev</id>
    <title>MK Studios Publishes Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksdev"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6715bb521f2e2d594da2efab_zurich1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. MK Studios announced in their Discord server their plans for the remainder of 2024 and beyond, including a new airport on the North American West Coast (yet to be revealed) and two big airports in Europe.  Their upcoming Lisbon Airport V2 is still set to release on Wednesday (23/10), and the pricing is now known: roughly $18.46 (tax excluded). Owners of the previous version will get a 25% discount. V2 owners will be eligible for a free Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 upgrade. Still on that Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 note, all of their products released in 2024 will receive free upgrades, whereas older products will still demand further investigation as they were developed using different techniques which might impact performance negatively, and it may require the redevelopment of the ground poly and LODs. While the 2020 versions might work fine in 2024 without an upgrade patch, it won’t be officially supported and may induce issues. ‍ They have also announced two new European airports: Zurich Airport (LSZH) and Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL), which will be released in 2024 and Q1 2025, respectively. They also plan to update La Guardia (KLGA) once terminal C is fully finished and develop a new airport “on the top of the West Coast.” ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lisbon</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Lisbon Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lisbon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67193e1b1e00562091dba77c_lisbon1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. MK Studios recently released their revamped rendition of Humberto Delgado Airport (LPPT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the city of Lisbon, Portugal, and has a yearly average of 33.6 million passengers, making it the busiest in the Country. Its history dates back to 1942, when it opened during the height of World War 2 as a neutral airport, smuggling people in and out of Europe, regardless of nationality. Such neutrality made it so it was heavily monitored by both the Axis and Allied forces and even earned it a movie plot. The post-war period saw a fast expansion, reaching the 100,000-passenger mark by 1954. At that point, it was served by Air France, British European Airways, Iberia, KLM, Sabena, Pan Am, and Trans World Airlines. The late 50s/early 60s brought a runway upgrade to accommodate larger aircraft such as the 707 and the DC-8. In 1962, a new 3130-meter-long runway allowed even bigger aircraft, such as the Boeing 747, for Lisbon’s first direct route to New York in the 1970s. A new terminal was built in 2007 for exclusive use by low-cost carriers. It features 22 check-in desks and fifteen departure gates. Terminal 1 was expanded shortly after, in 2011, with a large new shopping area, new airbridges and parking positions, and a new underground metro station. The airport’s infrastructure was also hugely improved during that period, with new cargo facilities, fuel storage, multiple refurbishments, and more. In 2019, the government unveiled a new expansion program, which has been widely opposed due to environmental concerns. It’s a hub for TAP Air Portugal and an operating base for easyJet and Ryanair. Aer Lingus, Air France, American Airlines, Air Canada, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, KLM, Latam Airlines, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, Turkish, United, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life runway elevation profile data, custom jetways, custom vehicle models, PBR textures, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on Contrail and OrbxDirect for roughly $18.30, requiring at least 2.55 GB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners are eligible for a 25% upgrade discount. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmaadd</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Addis Ababa Bole International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmaadd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/671a86267f4a10bd5e99c6cf_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Barelli MSFS Addon has just released its version of Addis Ababa Bole International Airport (HAAB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This airport serves Ethiopia's capital, Addis Ababa, and welcomes over 11 million passengers annually. It is a vital hub with destinations all around the globe. Addis Ababa Bole International Airport opened in 1962, replacing the older Lideta Airport. Over the years, the airport has undergone numerous upgrades, including the addition of a secondary runway, an expansion of the original runway, a new terminal, and a new control tower, among other enhancements. Today, the airport serves over 11 million passengers annually and offers flights to various destinations. It acts as a hub for Ethiopian Airlines, and in conjunction with several other airlines, passengers can travel to locations such as Dubai, Tokyo, New York, and Paris. The newly released scenery package features detailed models, an updated taxiway, accurate taxiway signs, proper terrain elevation, dynamic lighting, custom jetways, and more. The add-on requires 1.02 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $17.25. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737105</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737105"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/671af5efc02bc4c34240722d_1250410_20240218194937_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently issued a major update to their Boeing 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing the new navigation database format from the 777, additional Ultimate Flight Tablet features, and a reworked flight model.  Update v3.00.0105 is claimed to be the most significant update since the first 737 variant was released two and a half years ago, representing PMDG’s “continuous commitment to provide new features and value to their Microsoft Flight Simulator customers on both PC and Xbox”. With a backport of multiple features from their recently released 777-300ER, the 737 lineup will now match some of its niceties such as the new navdata format, ground crew commands, navdata updates, and more via the Ultimate Flight Tablet, along with flight model tweaks and autoflight control logic improvements. The complete changelog and feature list are below: The developers recommend updating their Operations Center before updating the aircraft, or it may not apply the update correctly. The official instructions are below: The 737 lineup is available on PMDG.com and in the Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99 (variant-dependent). ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
