<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-02-26T18:21:10.445915+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aurabe</id>
    <title>AuraScenery Releases Aberdeen International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aurabe"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ca9f7197053f11d87fd461_aberdeen.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AuraScenery has recently released their rendition of Aberdeen International Airport (EGPD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Aberdeen, Aberdeenshire, and Moray in Scotland, with a yearly average of 1.9 million passengers. It opened in 1934 as Dyce Aerodrome, established by Eric Gandar Dower for his many enterprises, including a flying school, a flying club, and an airline, Aberdeen Airways.  ‍ It became an RAF base during WW2 (RAF Dyce), housing the No. 13 Group. Even though it had a few fighter aircraft, the base’s main purpose was photographic reconnaissance.  It was bombed twice by the Germans in 1940, but no damage was reported, thanks to a decoy site nearby that operated full-time thanks to an underground generator, leading the enemies to think it was an active air base. They had cleverly concocted a system where a flarepath and a rotating lamp would “simulate” taxiing aircraft. Nothing remains from the RAF days due to the constant expansion and development of the industrial areas around the airport, leading to many reconstructions. A new terminal was built in 1947, along with a new control tower.  It underwent a massive redevelopment program between 2016 and 2019, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It has recently been elected the Scottish Airport of the Year (2022) and the Hub of the Year (2023).  It’s a focus city for Eastern Airways, Loganair, and TUI Airways. Aer Lingus, airBaltic, BH Air, British Airways, Eastern Airways, easyJet, KLM, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Wideroe, and Wizz Air serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with more than 100 high-detail buildings, high-quality apron textures, detailed landscaping, realistic night lighting, custom ground materials, and highly optimized models. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $14.52, requiring at least 3.16 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxfrv</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Publishes A320 Block 2 Feature Review Video</title>
    <updated>2024-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxfrv"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65cbe36656dfb85750418540_fenixblock4.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations recently uploaded a video to their YouTube channel with a deep dive into the upcoming Block 2 update for their Airbus A320, showcasing some of the new features and intricacies of their new custom engine model. The 47-minute video begins with a demonstration of their new PA system, one of the new features of the upcoming update. Users will be able to have customizable PA sounds on a per airline (ICAO/IATA) basis, and the audio files will be played randomly (within a set time frame, of course) rather than as soon as a new action begins (boarding, deboarding, etc.) to simulate a human cabin crew.  Aamir Thacker, the CEO, then apologizes for the many delays and their recent “radio silence,” along with justifying why they have opted to delay it for so long and why it turned out beneficial in the long run, paving the way for future products with an accurate and entirely agnostic engine model that could be adapted to fit any need they might have in the future. The next part of the video covers the full GSX integration and the new Electronic Flight Bag, which was rewritten from scratch. GSX will now handle refueling, boarding, luggage, and pushback automatically, with no input required from the user or the need for external software other than GSX itself. The new EFB, while maintaining visual similarity with the previous, will be snappier and more feature-fledged than before, allowing for finer control of the settings and failures, along with their respective codes for troubleshooting with the quick reference handbook. The following five minutes cover the new flight model and their new stick dampening simulation, which aims to bring the feel of a real Airbus sidestick to our homes, albeit with a strong emphasis on it still not being exactly like the real thing due to how the real sidestick works in comparison to an average USB flight stick.   The remaining thirty minutes showcase the star of the show: the new external engine model and its many intricacies, including a demonstration of how to crank an IAE engine when it’s 42C outside and the exact opposite: the engine’s behavior when it’s cold outside and how icing on the fan blades can lead to potentially catastrophic issues. The final demonstration showcases compressor stalls, a rare but certainly concerning issue that can happen if the winds are “just right.” Aamir also mentions they have struck a new deal with ProSim, which will allow hardware such as physical MCDUs and FCUs to work with the Fenix, which was not possible before due to the nature of their first deal. Fenix has not revealed the release date for the update yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/panczd</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Updates Anchorage International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/panczd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65cbee388a97c1b2bb22faae_zdp1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently updated their rendition of Ted Stevens Anchorage International Airport (PANC) for X-Plane 12, the busiest airport in Alaska with a yearly average of 4.9 million passengers. ‍ Established in 1951 as Anchorage International Airport, it was later renamed in honor of Ted Stevens, a prominent U.S. Senator from Alaska. During World War II, the airport played a crucial role as a refueling stop for aircraft flying between the contiguous United States and the Soviet Union. ‍ In the post-war years, Anchorage became a key stopover for flights between North America and Asia, thanks to its strategic location at the crossroads of air routes over the Pacific Ocean. ‍ Currently, Anchorage airport is one of the busiest cargo airports in the world, handling a significant portion of air freight between Asia and North America and serving as a central hub for passenger flights. It’s a hub for Alaska Airlines, Atlas Air, FedEx Express, Polar Air Cargo, Ravn Alaska, and UPS Airlines. Air Canada, American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Ryan Air, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom taxiways and runways, custom orthophotos, 3D grass, custom buildings, SAM jetways, performance-friendly optimization, and more.  ‍ It’s available for free on the Threshold Forum. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwmia</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release Miami International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwmia"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ce5c031d3d35fe34a9177d_miami1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Miami International Airport (KMIA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Miami metropolitan area with a yearly average of 52.3 million passengers, which makes it the 9th busiest airport in the United States. It opened in 1928 as Pan American Field, after Pan American World Airways, which had purchased a plot of land beside a pre-existing Miami City Airport (dating back to the early 20s) to build it.  World War 2 led to the construction of Miami Army Airfield, which sat south of the Pan American Field with separate runways yet was listed as a single facility by some airport directories. Right after World War 2, in 1945, Miami established a Port Authority and purchased Pan American Field from Pan American World Airways, eventually merging it with the Miami Army Airfield in 1949.  A new passenger terminal was opened in 1959, the largest central airport terminal in the world at the time, with five concourses and a 270-room hotel. It was later renovated and expanded through the 1990s. The airport currently features three terminals and six concourses, with 131 gates in total.  It’s a hub for ABX Air, American Airlines, Amerijet International, Atlas Air, Avianca Cargo, Eastern Airlines, FedEx Express, Havana Air, iAero Airways, IBC Airways, LATAM Cargo Chile, Mas Air, Nothern Air Cargo, Sky Lease Cargo, UPS Airlines, Western Global Airlines, and World Atlantic Airlines. Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air France, Alaska Airlines, Avianca, Condor, Copa Airlines, Emirates, Finnair, ITA Airways, JetBlue, Level, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, Swiss, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and Volaris also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution custom ground textures, real-world ground dirt, a detailed terminal area, animated jetways, 60+ landside buildings, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $23.00, requiring at least 4.94 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxichi</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Chișinău International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxichi"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ce6f2740a9abe6822b4f31_chisi.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has recently released their rendition of Chișinău International Airport (LUKK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Moldovan city of Chișinău with a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers. Its history dates back to 1926, but a passenger terminal was only built in the 1970s.  ‍ More than thirty years after its construction, the passenger terminal underwent a modernization program, which included constructing an annex terminal building of 46,000 square meters and renovating the old terminal, increasing its passenger handling capabilities to 5.4 million passengers a year. ‍ It’s a hub for FlyOne and HiSky. Aegean Airlines, airBaltic, Austrian Airlines, Azerbaijan Airlines, Eurowings, Freebird Airlines, Georgian Wings, Israir, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Southwind Airlines, TAROM, Turkish Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR, up-to-date ground layout, custom landside models, 3d passengers, animated flags, custom aerial imagery, and a basic terminal interior model. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.92, requiring at least 2.71 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsaom</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Aomori Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsaom"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ce72d4d32036facdfcba56_aomori.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Aomori Airport (RJSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Aomori Prefecture in Japan with a yearly average of 992.000 passengers.  ‍ The original airport dates back to the early 60s, but geographic limitations of the existing site led to a position shift in the late 1980s. A small part of the old airport is still within the premises of the new one. It first featured a 2000x60 meter runway, which was extended to 2,500 meters in 1990.  ‍ The runway underwent further extension work in 2005, from 2,500 to 3,000 meters. The ILS equipment was also upgraded to handle Cat-3a fog conditions, which are common around the area. ‍ The terminal building was recently renovated, with increased capacity for international customers, a praying area for Muslims, and aesthetic changes. ‍ ANA Wings, Fuji Dream Airlines, J-Air, Japan Airlines, and Korean Airlines serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, custom jetways, custom groundpoly, AI-traffic compatibility, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.86, requiring at least 33.29 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/61tliv</id>
    <title>61tree Studio Releases Livingstone International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/61tliv"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ce7745a36f075d9e3596b0_livingstone.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. 61tree Studio has recently released their rendition of Harry Mwanga Nkumbula International Airport (FLHN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Livingstone, Zambia, with a yearly average of 175,000 passengers. ‍ Built in 1950 as a domestic airport, it was rapidly internationalized due to its proximity to Victoria Falls, one of the world’s largest waterfalls with a width of 1,708 meters.  ‍ It was heavily upgraded between 2011 and 2017, with several improvements to its facilities and infrastructure. It included a new terminal building, a new main runway, and new apron lights.  ‍ The new terminal building can handle up to 1 million passengers a year. ‍ Airlink, CemAir, FlySafair, Kenya Airways, Proflight Zambia, and Zambia Airways serve it. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, custom landside buildings, and more.  ‍ The developer claims the scenery is about 70% complete as of right now, with updates to follow soon. The list of things to come includes more surrounding buildings, an ATC tower interior, more shops and interiors, a security room, a medical emergency room, more vehicles, and more animated people. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.93, requiring at least 989.90 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol018</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta 1.8</title>
    <updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol018"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ce8b4722ad89852b1304c2_volanta18.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated Volanta to version 1.8, bringing many bug fixes and a “Teams” feature where users can create their own teams with statistics, a leaderboard, and a distinct icon color on the map. Volanta 1.8 brings image cropping, an enhanced airport view with clearer navigation, extra flight tooltips, squawk, and vertical speed display, emergency flights are highlighted on the map, new aircraft icons, an improved search experience, and enhancements to the party system, with doubled message length, in-session unread message counter, and more. The “parties” are now temporary and automatically disband after 72 hours, being replaced by the “Teams,” which are permanent groups of up to 10 members with custom statistics, leaderboard (flight time, flown distance, landing rates), and a distinct coloring on the map to differentiate between teams, friends, and other users. The changelog for the update follows below: ‍ Volanta can be downloaded for free on their official website. A Premium membership is available for roughly $4.14 a month, unlocking real-world schedules, flight parties, a mobile app, customized stream overlays, flight replay, remote pause, cloud-based autosaves*, aircraft persistence*, unlimited 4K cloud screenshots, time sync**, and a premium badge &amp; status. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! * FSX, P3D, and MSFS ** FSX, P3D ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpa16</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes PA-38 Tomahawk Development Update </title>
    <updated>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpa16"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65cfe14fbfe05ab154c924b3_pa381.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a new progress update on the development of the Piper PA-38 Tomahawk for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engined low-wing fixed tricycle gear general aviation airplane primarily used for flight training, touring, and personal use. ‍ The developers have worked hard over the past few weeks on systems, modeling, texturing, sounds, and additional features that will be mentioned in the future.  ‍ ‍ They have implemented an interactive walkaround mode, accessible via the EFB, allowing users to navigate the aircraft's exterior and interact with various components. A mini checklist will show which components can be checked and interacted with, ranging from chocks, tie-downs, tow bar, control surfaces, stall warning tab, and the propeller. ‍ The PA-38 Tomahawk will also feature wear and tear simulation, with components wearing out over time, with different wear rates depending on how the aircraft is treated. Distinct operational behaviors will result in different wear rates, as in real life. Components will be repairable, and high wear will render it unsuitable for flight. ‍ The instruments will be affected by the amount of suction in the vacuum system, particularly noticeable when starting the engine, making the attitude indicator and direction indicator wobble as the suction increases.  ‍ Their texture artist has been retexturing the entire exterior, which is not reflected in the provided screenshots (it still shows the old texture set, as it's serving as a placeholder until the new set is ready).  ‍ There is still no release date information, but they say the finish line is getting closer.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfltor</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Tornado GR1 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfltor"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65cfe6d82f553d7a4c7a0333_tornado.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a progress update on the development of their Tornado GR1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a twin-engine combat aircraft jointly developed and manufactured by Italy, the United Kingdom, and Germany.  ‍ First flown in 1974 and officially introduced in 1979, the Panavia Tornado was operated by the German Air Force, Royal Air Force, Italian Air Force, and Royal Saudi Air Force, with 990 units built in total.  ‍ Just Flight’s rendition is modeled after the ZA465 “Foxy Killer,” who served with the No. 16 RAF Squadron during the Gulf War (1990-1991) and is now preserved for posterity by the Imperial War Museum Duxford. ‍ Their livery artist has been creating 8K liveries that will be included with the Tornado GR1 at release. They will cover the IDS and ECR variants across the Royal Air Force, German Air Force, German Navy, Italian Air Force, and Royal Saudi Air Force in a mixture of standard and special liveries. The liveries they have showcased are all UK-centric, with more to come in future development updates. ‍ Unlike some of their previous projects, they claim to have entirely scratched the old code from P3D, writing all the systems from scratch. Work is said to be well underway, with functionality added to the electrical, fuel, and hydraulic systems that lay the foundations for all other systems. While it’s no small feat, they have a dedicated systems coder, and the process should progress at a good pace, with Just Flight believing that it will bring the level of their simulation up to the highest standard within the confines of what is possible with Microsoft Flight Simulator. ‍ They will share more information as it progresses, and Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxswe</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Swedish Triple Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxswe"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65d0fc3c65753f6a2982c302_triplepack.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has released the Swedish Triple Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a package with three Swedish airports (Umeå, Kiruna, and Scandinavian Mountains Airport) developed by independent developer Marcus Nyberg. ‍ The Swedish Triple Pack features an accurate rendition of Umeå (ESNU), Kiruna (ESNQ), and Scandinavian Mountains Airport (ESKS), with snow piles during winter, custom high-resolution ground textures, custom GSX profiles, unique static aircraft, and more. ‍ Umeå Airport, inaugurated in 1962, is the seventh busiest in Sweden, with a yearly average of 960,000 passengers. BRA Braathens Regional Airlines, Croatia Airlines, Jonair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic serve it. ‍ Kiruna Airport was inaugurated in 1960 and averages around 270,000 passengers yearly. Eurowings, Norwegian Air Shuttle, and Scandinavian Airlines serve it. ‍ Scandinavian Mountains Airport is one of the newest airports in the world, inaugurated in 2019. It was the first airport to feature a completely remote control tower. BRA Braathens Regional Airlines, Scandinavian Airlines, Transavia, and TUI fly Netherlands serve it, albeit seasonally. ‍ The scenery pack is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $29.98, requiring at least 8.53 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthslc</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Salt Lake City Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthslc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65d664e6115fe2515ffa658d_feelslc.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Salt Lake City International Airport (KSLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Salt Lake City metropolitan area and Wasatch Front with a yearly average of 26.9 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built on Basque Flats, a wide flat area on the Salt Lake Valley that was deemed appropriate for constructing a landing strip. In that same year, it held the Great International Aviation Carnival, with the presence of many aviation pioneers, including Glenn Curtiss and his newly invented Seaplane that took off from Salt Lake in front of 20,000 spectators, making international headlines. ‍ Nine years later, the United States Postal Service began flying mail to SLC, stimulating the city’s administration to improve the infrastructure further by buying a plot of land near the airport and building a hangar and other facilities.  ‍ The first terminal was built in 1933, costing $52,000.  ‍ With WW2, the airport became a USAF base, eventually getting a third runway. The post-war results were primarily positive, with 42 weekday departures in 1957. ‍ By 1960, a new terminal was needed, and Brazier Montmorency Hayes &amp; Talbot took on the challenge of designing it. Seven years and 8 million dollars later, it was ready to roll. That’s also when Salt Lake City got granted its international status, with a direct flight to Calgary. ‍ With the airline deregulation in 1978, SLC became a hub for Western Airlines, which had the same Brazier Montmorency Hayes design and built a terminal with murals by artist LeConte Stewart.  ‍ In 1987, Western Airlines merged into Delta Air Lines, with Salt Lake City remaining as one of their major hubs. ‍ A redevelopment program was started in 2014 to modernize the airport, gradually replacing its old infrastructure. Airport funds, passenger charges, and federal grants funded it. ‍ The first phase of the new terminal was opened in 2020, with Concourse A sporting 25 gates and B with 21, both connected by a mid-field underground tunnel.  ‍ As mentioned, SLC is a Delta Air Lines hub, flying passengers worldwide, directly or indirectly connecting via other hubs. They have 57.12% of the current passenger market share, followed by SkyWest with 18.77% and Southwest with 11.17%. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed buildings, PBR texturing, custom ground poly, custom animated jetways, an animated TRAX line train, an up-to-date AFCAD, improved taxiway lighting, custom ground clutter, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.59, requiring at least 683.61 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia37</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia37"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a9a2d24bcaac26dd4c31b3_a300mon.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their rendition of the Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing bug fixes, flight model improvements, and more. Update 1.0.7, the seventh so far, addresses the VS mode bug, improves the ground handling flight model, fixes an MCDU sound bug, and more. The changelog follows below: ‍ ‍ iniBuilds also states that a re-log-in on Navigraph in the EFB might be necessary after applying the update. The aircraft is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.55, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrp120</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Previews X-Plane 12.1.0 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrp120"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65d91a889df74096a227afca_xplaneupdate.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently previewed  X-Plane 12.1.0 on their blog, which is currently under private testing and set to release as a public beta soon, bringing graphical improvements, flight model tweaks, improved weather, and more. While the update was initially meant to be a graphics-focused release, Laminar has also implemented new aircraft systems, improved the flight model, weather, ATC system, and a physics-based camera that moves with the aircraft.  The graphics - their primary focus for this update - now feature cloud shadows on water, bloom lighting effects, robust contrast adaptive sharpening, softer ground shadows, MSAA improvements, improved CPU performance, better water opacity and turbidity, and a new screenshot utility with DoF and Exposure controls. It will also bring new particle effects, such as sparks from pavement collisions, ground spray from aircraft wheels and engines, and brown/white-outs while flying helicopters and powered lift aircraft. The aircraft systems were heavily upgraded, with additions to the G1000 simulation such as ADS-B simulation, stormscope page, traffic map page, airport METAR flags, NDB + VOR pages, WAAS/ Test Satellite Constellation, a boot-up overlay, and plugin interoperability, allowing third-parties to easily modify the G1000 for their specific needs. Glass avionics will now be implemented via plugin, making it easier for developers to integrate them into their aircraft.  The new flight model will bring a manual flap system (and a dial-a-flap functionality, too), electric clutches for helicopters, and single-lever control for turboprops, if equipped. The weather system will use a new server, and the METAR parsing will be improved, making it closer to real life. Clouds will look less blocky as a direct consequence of better data parsing. Last but not least, the new physics-based camera, which might come in 12.1.0 or a future update, with camera motion based on the aircraft's acceleration. ‍ There's no date for the official release yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbans</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Anacortes Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbans"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65d99124979f07a2186cdbe7_anacortes.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Anacortes Airport (74S) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use general aviation airport serving Anacortes, Washington, with a yearly average of 9,000 aircraft operations. ‍ It was built in 1968 and inaugurated in 1969 on land purchased by the Port of Anacortes using FAA grant money. ‍ It’s included in FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems for 2017-2021 as a local general aviation facility, corresponding to 73% of its yearly traffic as of 2014. Air taxis make up the other 17%. ‍ Developed by Andreas Hegi, the scenery was completely rebuilt for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with a 3D terminal interior, custom PBR textures, an accurate ground layout, custom airport signs and markings, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.35, requiring at least 1.89 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fe24ra</id>
    <title>FSExpo 2024 Moves to Rio Las Vegas; Dates Remain</title>
    <updated>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fe24ra"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65da7c26da23836dfae105c3__Z8A0350%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In an announcement made on both their website, the team behind FlightSimExpo have announced that the 2024 event will move resorts from the Tropicana Las Vegas, to the Rio Las Vegas, and being held on the same dates as originally planned, from Friday, June 21st through Sunday, June 23rd, 2024. The FSExpo team says no action is needed from those who have already booked rooms at the Tropicana, and more information will be coming soon.The event was originally planned to take place at the Tropicana Las Vegas, but the unexpected closure of the Tropicana that was announced last month, the event team scrambled to move resorts. In a herculean effort, the team managed to secure a venue contract in just 25 days, which is a remarkable feat considering the fact that this process usually takes months. The team also shared more information about the new accommodations at the Rio, which will feature rooms in the newly renovated Ipanema Tower, if rooms are booked through the FSExpo link. Starting in October 2023, resort-wide improvements have been introduced, including dynamic dining experiences, fully refreshed public spaces (including the pool), and a complete renovation of more than 1,400 rooms in the Ipanema Tower. Along with more than 15 full- and quick-service restaurants including a new food hall, there are four on-property shows including Penn &amp; Teller, WOW - The Vegas Spectacular, and Comedy Cellar. ‍ The nightly room rate at the Rio will be slightly cheaper than what was offered at the Tropicana, with $149USD on Friday and Saturday nights, and $69 on other nights, plus taxes and fees, and a booking link will be provided soon with more details, with a $25 food voucher included if you book with their link. ‍ If you have booked at the Tropicana and already paid the deposit, a full refund will be issued soon. Additionally, if you have not independently canceled your reservation, you will receive a $25 rideshare voucher to help cover your travel from the airport to Rio in June. ‍ If you have not booked yet, the FSExpo team strongly encourages you to book at the newly renovated rooms in Rio’s Ipanema Tower once their booking link becomes available. Along with enjoying a discounted rate of approximately $172/night (includes taxes/fees for a Thursday-Sunday stay), attendees can expect a $25 credit per booked room toward food and beverage at Rio. In Summary: ‍ Also, Threshold is proud to announce we are attending FSExpo 2024 in person! Look forward to interviews, and in-depth coverage on everything that happens during the event! We’re super excited to meet members of the Threshold Community in Vegas!Threshold will keep you updated once we get more information, so stay tuned for that, and more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
