<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-10T18:23:28.736887+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msrafx</id>
    <title>Mountain Scenery Releases ALPS for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msrafx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638b741fd5db463992fb990b_alps1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="332734"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Frank Dainese and Fabio Bellini have recently released the ALPS UHD package for X-Plane 12, covering 8000 square kilometers of alpine area between Italy, France, and Switzerland. It includes four main packages: Eiger Park, Matterhorn Park, Aosta, and Mont Blanc, along with the main peaks of the Alps.  The aforementioned packages feature an accurate reconstruction with 3D models and photographic textures, with all the major cities and towns with their respective custom building placement (churches, stations, monuments, public buildings, etc.) and houses that match the local architecture. All major airports and airfields are included (5 main airports, 15 airfields, and 46 heliports), with their respective characteristics. The complete feature list follows down below: It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $49.95 with a 17% discount (default price is $59.95), requiring at least 3.3 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssdtbl</id>
    <title>SLH Sim Designs Releases Terrance B. Lettsome International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssdtbl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638cb795ece8b2670552ddc8_tupj1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="280212"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SLH Sim Designs has just released their rendition of Terrance B. Lettsome International Airport (TUPJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main airport serving the British Virgin Islands, and previously known as Beef Island Airport. It’s a gateway to other smaller islands in the archipelago and a bridge away from the main island (Tortola).   It underwent a Major renovation in 2004, which included a runway expansion to allow operation of larger airplanes. It also added a new 4300 square meter terminal building, an enlarged flight apron, a new control tower, and 150 extra parking stalls.   It’s served by many regional airlines such as Air Sunshine, Cape Air, LIAT, Silver Airways, VI Airlink, and Winair. American Eagle set to begin flying to Terrance B. Lettsome in June 2023 from Miami. Curiously, there is a $20 departure tax for anyone above the age of 5.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with modeled interiors for the terminal and tower, accurate terraforming and runway slope, dynamic night lighting, animated road traffic with functional toll gates, true-to-life airport landside recreation, custom taxiway and signage lighting, and 4K PBR textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.81, requiring at least 272 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxioth</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Doha Hamad International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxioth" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638df236bd27f82c6148bd15_doha5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="371489"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has just released their rendition of Doha Hamad International Airport (OTHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Qatar with a yearly average of 36 million passengers. Opened in 2014, it replaces Doha International Airport as Qatar’s main airport, built on 22 square kilometers of land and able to handle 320,000 aircraft movements and 2 million tonnes of cargo per year. DOH is the first Middle Eastern airport to get the Skytrax's World Best Airport award (2021 and 2022), ending a nearly decade-long streak of Singapore’s Changi. ‍ It’s the hub for Qatar Airways, with a route network that covers most of the globe, from their next-door neighbors of Abu Dhabi to San Francisco. Such high coverage makes it so other carriers don’t have much of a financially logical reason to fly to Doha, but there are still a couple of them such as Air Canada, Air India, British Airways, Conviasa, Finnair, and Malaysia Airlines. The scenery features a high-detail recreation of the airport, with an updated ground layout, high-quality ground markings and buildings, PBR textures, custom clutter objects, a basic terminal interior with the World Cup theming, 3D passengers, animated passenger train inside the terminal building, custom jetways, Qatar Airways hangar with an animated door, animated RGB road masts and flags, and support for the Aerosoft VDGS system. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.07, requiring at least 1.4 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tadprg</id>
    <title>Tailstrike Designs Releases Prague Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tadprg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638dffdb883d9bfb0edf0be1_vaclav1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="196617"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Tailstrike Designs has just released their rendition of Václav Havel Airport Prague (LKPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main gateway to Czechia with 85 years of history and over 15 million passengers yearly, home to Czech Airlines and Smartwings. Formerly Prague Ruzyně International Airport, it was renamed after the last president of Czechoslovakia and the first president of the Czech Republic (Václav Havel) in 2012.   With an intricate intra-European and international route network, PRG is regularly visited by Aer Lingus, Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Emirates, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and many other. Eurowings Europe and Ryanair have a base in Prague, with significant summer and winter networks.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models of the terminal, hangars, and buildings, along with true-to-life taxiways (as of 2022), tower and terminal interior, photorealistic PBR textures, custom animated jetways, realistic night dynamic lighting, and support for the Aerosoft VDGS module.  It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for $24.99, requiring at least 5 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflrfp</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Fokker F28 Video Preview </title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflrfp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638e0d5e3f4e8506d7265317_fokker1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="872414"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published another development update on their Fokker F28 Fellowship for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing the lighting (internally and externally) in a 3 minute long video around an Air Anglia F28-4000. According to the developers, there are 50 dynamic lights covering the exterior, cabin, and cockpit.   The Fokker F28 Fellowship is a twin-engined regional jet developed in the late 60s, with its first flight in 1967 and introduced in 1969, with 241 units built after a 20 year run (production ended in 1987). Multiple variants were developed, with the F28-1000 seating up to 70 passengers, the F28-2000 housing 79 people, and the later revision, the F28-4000, featuring quieter engines (Rolls-Royce Spey 555-15H), a redesigned cockpit and modified wings, and increased seating (up to 85 passengers). It was then superseded by the Fokker 70 and 100.   As of 2019, there are no current operators of the F28 around, with Fly-SAX being the last to operate it commercially. Garuda Indonesia was the largest former operator, with 62 of them. Other Major operators include the Ansett Group (13), AirQuarius Aviation (4), and Biman Bangladesh Airlines (4). The Ansett Group was also responsible for the longest nonstop F28 route in the world, between Perth and Kununurra, roughly 2300 km apart.   There’s no information on release date or pricing yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inip40</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases P-40F Warhawk for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inip40" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638e2c2e145661f624e2e103_p401.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1298377"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has just released their rendition of the Curtiss P-40F Warhawk for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engined classic fighter first flown in 1938. It was the third most produced American fighter in WW2, with 13,738 units by the end of the production cycle in late 1944, playing an important role during the war, used by most allied powers.   From the hot and dry Deserts of the Middle East to the dampness of Europe, the Warhawk has been everywhere in WW2, with over 200 allied fighter pilots becoming aces flying the P-40. It remained in active use well after the War, by Brazil, Egypt, Finland, and Turkey. The Brazilian Air Force was the last to retire their fleet, in 1954. The iniBuilds P-40F features the latest in CFD (Computational Fluid Dynamics) implementation from Microsoft, including the primary flight surfaces, control surfaces, and the propeller, with an authentically modeled Merlin engine which performs close to real-life figures (with feedback from type-rated pilots), a fully modeled fuel system, an electronic flight bag with maintenance page, moving map, radios, and weather information. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ The airplane is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.43, requiring at least 2.99 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kausmfs</id>
    <title>Dominic DesignTeam Releases Austin–Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kausmfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638ef23655f464fbf8202b53_Screenshot%202022-12-06%20at%201.41.38%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4150568"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Dominic DesignTeam released their rendition of Austin–Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The product will bring the Texas airport to life with high quality models, customized objects such as signs and passengers, and detailed textures. 	According to the developers, the scenery will feature PBR textures, dynamic lighting, and custom jetways. Additionally, for added realism, all pavements have been “painstakingly hand-crafted” and ground markings have been modeled based on the real life airport. 	Austin–Bergstrom International Airport, located 5 miles from Austin downtown, is one of the main international airports serving the city. It provides flights to some 75 destinations around the world. Top operators at the airport include Southwest, Delta, and American Airlines. Currently, Dominic DesignTeam’s Austin Airport can be purchased on simMarket for $18.99 USD or EUR 20.10, excluding any sales taxes that may incur. The developers recommend at least 870M of free space in order to successfully install the product.</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksrvn</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Rovaniemi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksrvn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638f7b34fdc31d1a20d021ba_efro1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1117127"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released an update to their rendition of Rovaniemi Airport (EFRO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Finland with 500,000 passengers per year. It’s visited by many airlines during the winter season, which includes Aer Lingus, Air France, easyJet, Eurowings, Ryanair, Transavia, and Turkish Airlines.   Built in 1940, featuring two grass runways, and used as a Luftwaffe air base and supply center during the Second Soviet-Finnish War between 1941 and 1944. Rebuilding work started in 1948, with regular traffic returning in the beginning of the second half of that year.   The current terminal building finished in 1992, with its first expansion happening in 2000 (and the inclusion of jetways). The runway underwent renovation work in 2016, with new pavement and LED lights, and 2019 marked the completion of the terminal’s third enlargement.  The scenery update added conditional visibility to the winter objects, smoke effects for cold weather, glass improvements, and general fixes. The complete feature list for the scenery follows down below: It’s available on Orbx Direct for $6.69 (on sale, 50% off), requiring at least 1.23 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbmyl</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces McCall Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbmyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638fa581410b823612bbcd65_call1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="455971"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator by an independent developer (Mark Taylor). It’s a city-owned public-use airport in McCall, Idaho, categorized in the FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems as a general aviation facility.   With 80 hectares of total area and a 1,862m long runway, McCall averages around 119 flights per day, and over 43,000 a year, with 84% of them being General Aviation flights, 16% air taxi and the remainder comprehending military traffic.   The scenery features realistic ground and apron texturing (including the recent apron resurfacing), true-to-life night lighting, PBR textures, extensive LOD work focusing on optimal performance, custom static aircraft, airport specific windsocks, 160+ custom objects, many custom animations, and hand placed vegetation.  Orbx plans to ensure that owners of the first version, previously released by Mark Taylor on another reseller, will be redeemable on Orbx Direct via license key.   The scenery landing page is available here, although it’s not available for purchase yet.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbosl</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Oslo Gardermoen for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbosl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638fc11ecaf33e597c68abe5_osl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1758242"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Norway, nearing 30 million passengers per year with almost 200 destinations. It’s home to Flyr, Norse Atlantic Airways, and Wideroe.   The airport’s history dates back to 1740 when the Norwegian army used Gardermoen (then Fredericksfeldt) as a camp. It remained as such until 1860, when barracks and stalls were constructed to house more people and protect against the harsh weather. Insulated buildings were the next logical upgrade, in the early 1900s. It became an airport in 1912 when the first of many flights took off.   Gardermoen was taken over by the nazis during the German occupation in 1940, building the first aircraft facilities and two runways with 2,000 meters each. The Norwegian Air Force took it back as soon as WW2 ended, housing three fighter squadrons. In 1946, Braathens SAFE used the facilities as their technical base, which only lasted for two years. It was also during that period when Oslo Gardermoen became the reserve airport for Fornebu, which used to be the main airport. All the intercontinental flights were redirected to OSL because Fornebu was undergoing runway extension work. It wasn’t until 1998 that Gardermoen became the main airport in Oslo.  The scenery will feature custom orthoimagery, PBR textures in 4K, interior modeling, 3 different types of animated jetways to match the real world, fully functioning VDGS on all appropriate gates, custom ground service equipment, and optimization work to warrant good performance.  It is allegedly coming in January 2023, priced at roughly $21.00. There’s no information on the install size yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mexfaa</id>
    <title>Mex High Flight Releases Tahiti International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mexfaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63913bc4204b611dbe188f28_tahiti1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2324223"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mex High Flight has recently released their rendition of Faa’a International Airport (NTAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, connecting Tahiti to the World. Also known as Tahiti International Airport, it’s home to Air Tahiti and Air Tahiti Nui, with domestic flights to other islands in French Polynesia and intercontinental legs to Canada, Chile, France, Japan, New Zealand, and the United States.  Aside from the local airlines,  it’s also visited by Air France (Los Angeles and Paris), Air New Zealand (Auckland), Delta Air Lines (beginning in late December 2022, from Los Angeles), French Bee (Paris Orly and San Francisco), Hawaiian Airlines (Honolulu), and United Airlines (San Francisco). The yearly figures sit around 1.6 million passengers total. With a single, 3,420 meters long runway, Tahiti International can accommodate large aircraft such as the Boeing 747 and the Airbus A380.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR texturing, realistic night lighting, hand-placed objects, realistic AFCAD, friendly framerate, and GSX compatibility.  It’s available on SimMarket for $18.40, requiring at least 513MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ecugal</id>
    <title>Ecuavirtual3d Releases San Cristóbal City &amp; Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ecugal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6392389be3fb77845d05b634_galap2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2256824"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Ecuavirtual3d has just released their rendition of San Cristóbal de Galápagos and its airport, San Cristóbal Airport (SEST), for Microsoft Flight Simulator, both in the archipelago of the Galápagos Islands in Ecuador. The airport is served by Avianca Ecuador, Equair, and LATAM Ecuador, with flights to Guayaquil and Quito. The yearly figures sit at around 200,000 passengers.   With a single 1,900m long runway, the approach to both ends happens to be over the ocean, sitting just at the coast of San Cristóbal.   The scenery features a faithful replica of the airport, with accurate modeling based on original references, fully customized ground textures, custom taxiway signs, custom traffic on the avenues, a control tower with an interior, taxi routes for airplanes, and static objects, vehicles, and aircraft.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.90, requiring at least 93 MB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsgemb</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Uploads New Embraer 175 Teaser Video for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsgemb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63938aabe43a3a0bf9a3da58_1756.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1126836"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG, in partnership with AviationLads, has teased their Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator again, focusing on the interior. In 44 seconds, there’s a glimpse of the cockpit (including a cold &amp; dark power up) and the passenger cabin, with attention to interior lighting.   It is the second teaser so far, with the first one airing last friday and showcasing the external modeling, engine sounds, and different liveries from some of the 12 real-world operators.   According to a Facebook post by AviationLads, the next teaser will be “more technical” with a systems showcase, due next week.  The E175 is part of the Embraer E-Jets family, seating 78 to 88 passengers in different cabin configurations, with a range of 1800 nautical miles on the standard variant. There are 12 operators around the World, with SkyWest being the largest (193 aircraft).   There’s no information regarding pricing or release date yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpnbr</id>
    <title>RDPresets Announces Bergen Flesland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpnbr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639390e458c4aa2d4c611a84_bergen1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="743439"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced their rendition of Bergen Flesland Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6.5 million passengers. It’s owned and operated by Avinor (state owned company).   It’s a focus city for Bergen Air Transport, Bristow Norway, CHC Helikopter Service, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe, making for a huge domestic and international network. CHC and Bristow feature an unusual type of passenger traffic, transporting people to offshore oil platforms in the North Sea. It’s visited by many other airlines such as Air France, airBaltic, Finnair, Flyr, Icelandair, KLM, Lufthansa, and WizzAir, along with seasonal carriers.  The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with a modeled interior, custom ground textures, and detailed landside buildings.   It should be available tomorrow on the RDPresets Store. There’s no information on requirements yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxmyl</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases McCall Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxmyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6393997608813abdd302ff66_kmyl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2065484"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, by their newest independent developer Mark “Milo” Taylor, which already made a rendition of MYL under MSX Creations. This new rendition is an overhaul of the previous work, with custom library objects, scenery placement and re-texturing.   It is a city-owned public-use airport in McCall (Idaho), categorized by the FAA as a general aviation facility. It had 43,600 aircraft operations between August 2009 and August 2010, averaging 119 flights per day, 84% of which comprehended general aviation traffic, and 16% were air taxi, with the remaining 1% being military traffic.    With a 1862m long runway, McCall Mun. Airport can accommodate most private jets and medium-range airliners.   The scenery features true-to-life ground and apron texturing (including the recent apron resurfacing), realistic night lighting, PBR texturing, level of detail work to warrant good performance, multiple custom static aircraft, airport specific windsocks, over 160 custom objects, multiple custom animations, and hand-placed vegetation.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $19.06, requiring at least 3.64 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdscae</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Teases São Paulo Catarina Executive for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdscae" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394c9ab55496a9252a993a0_catarinacover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1999138"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently teased their rendition of São Paulo Catarina Executive International (SBJH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the Metropolitan Area of São Paulo, Brazil. It’s the first private executive airport with International status in the country, built on 5.2 million square meters of land and situated near the main business centers of the state.  The airport development project aims to bring together characteristics from the best general aviation airports in the World, such as Teterboro and Paris Le Bourget, with help from companies such as Airport Consulting Vienna (ACV) and Ramboll, a Danish consulting engineering group. Built to accommodate up to 200,000 take-offs and landings per year, including long range jets, thanks to its 2500 meter long runway. It's the only executive airport in Brazil with authorization to operate flights to New York, London, and Paris. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR models, a "98% accurate" terrain mesh, fully updated satellite imagery, custom objects, and models built based on projects sent by the airport administrator. There’s no information on install size or release date yet, but said to be coming soon (awaiting Marketplace approval).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
