<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-03-15T18:25:16.273694+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ledinc</id>
    <title>LeAeroDesign Releases Incheon International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ledinc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6405fa744ecf3bc18df4c1e3_inch1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="194070"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LeAeroDesign has recently released their rendition of Seoul-Incheon International Airport (RKSI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the largest airport in South Korea and among the busiest in the world, with a yearly average of 70 million passengers!  Incheon opened in 2001 to replace Gimpo International Airport as the main airport in South Korea and handle the extra international air traffic that the former airport was unable to (as seen during the 1988 Olympics and the early 90s). Construction work started in 1992 on reclaimed land between Yeongjong Island and Youngyu Island, taking eight years to finish and facing an economic crisis delay.   It is the main hub for Korean Air, Asiana Airlines, Jeju Air, and Polar Air Cargo. The current record figures revolve around 71 million passengers a year, with Korean Air being responsible for 26% of the market share, followed by Asiana Airlines and Jeju Air with 18.04% and 8.09%, respectively. Destination-wise, Hong Kong is the busiest, with 3,149,768 passengers, followed by Osaka-Kansai (2,840,003), and Tokyo-Narita (2,783,677).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Seoul-Incheon, with highly detailed 3D models, highly-detailed 3D markings, PBR optimization, photorealistic terrain, high-detail taxi lights with realistic light visibility angles, enhanced 3D lighting, correct localizer &amp; glideslope path, realistic pushback procedures and VDGS (GSX Pro dependant).  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $23.34, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfshah</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Frankfurt-Hahn Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfshah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6407aaf8b972a00dd4a4ca78_hah1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2625063"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Frankfurt-Hahn Airport (EDFH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the low-cost oriented gateway to the Rhineland. ‍ Hahn dates back to the early 1950s when it was founded by occupying french forces and taken over by the USAF a year later, where it initially hosted the 7356th Air Base Group, responsible for improving the facilities and getting it into an operational state. The USAF made use of the Hahn Air Base up until the early 1990s when it was handed over to Germany. The German government decided to transform the Air Base into a civil airport to alleviate the traffic at Frankfurt International Airport.  Nowadays, the airport averages around 1.3 million passengers yearly, served by either Ryanair or WizzAir, the two low-cost giants that operate in Hahn. The Irish carrier offers seventeen fixed destinations (and fifteen seasonals), and the Hungarian sports eight destinations.  As a curiosity, Frankfurt-Hahn recently filed for bankruptcy and sold to a new investor in mid-2022 which ended up not transferring the funds, and now they have signed two preliminary contracts with two new potential buyers, one of them being no more no less than the owner of the Nürburgring.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, custom GSE, custom lighting, custom ground markings, landside buildings, ground clutter, and hangars. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.03, requiring at least 396.14 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jtsrho</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Rhodes International Airport v3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jtsrho" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6407bc154fbab68934a227da_rho1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="306899"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. JustSim has recently released their new rendition of Rhodes International Airport (LGRP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Greece with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  Built in 1977 to replace the old Rhodes Maritsa Airport, which was deemed too cramped for passenger traffic, it covers an area of 60,000 square meters, sporting a single, 3,305-meter-long runway. The airport underwent multiple expansion work over the years, with the most recent one dating back to 2005, consisting of the inauguration of a new passenger terminal.  The airport is now owned by Fraport-Greece, which recently introduced an investment plan to further improve the airport, with a general clean-up, improved lighting, an upgrade to sanitary facilities, free wi-fi, terminal remodeling, a new fire station, more check-in counters, etc.   It’s served by many airlines on a seasonal basis (summer only), including Aegean Airlines (one of the few with a year-long route), Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Lufthansa, Olympic Air, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Transavia, WizzAir, and others.  JustSim’s new Rhodes features better 3D models, improved textures, and excellent landside detail.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.89, requiring at least 1.18 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hifacs</id>
    <title>HiFi Simulation Technologies Releases Active Sky XP 12 Beta for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hifacs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640a1cbd048f1d39c7ff1441_asx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1287933"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. HiFi Simulation Technologies has recently published a development news update where they talk about the upcoming release of Active Sky XP 12, which has now been made available for everyone under an open beta program.   Active Sky XP 12 is the next installment of their popular weather engine for X-Plane, making use of the new regional weather system API in X-Plane 12 to provide high levels of accuracy and realism in weather depiction, with a precise portrayal of clouds in regards to their size, height, type, coverage, precipitation, and more. It’s all made possible thanks to the utilization of high-resolution global weather data and their cloud-based weather network system.  The new weather engine is fully integrated with X-Plane 12, providing smoother transitions, better clouds, and new lighting, resulting in an improved visual weather experience, according to HiFi.  The new features include active air effects, which enhance internal X-Plane turbulence and air effects, providing enhanced turbulence, drafts, thermals, terrain-based wind effects, surface friction, gusts, variability, wake turbulence, microbursts, and more (wake turbulence effects are XP 11 only). The weather system uses the simulator’s internal cloud depiction to warrant maximum performance and smoothness, including compatibility with Virtual Reality (and optimization). The complete list follows down below:  Active Air Effects  Enhances internal X-Plane turbulence and air effects, providing enhanced turbulence, drafts, thermals, terrain-based wind effects, surface friction, gusts, variability, wake turbulence, microbursts and more (XP12 includes internal wake turbulence, AS Wake turbulence enabled for XP11 only – Some effects may be limited/unavailable in XP12). High-Performance Weather Depiction  Uses internal X-Plane cloud depiction for maximum performance and smoothness – VR compatible and optimized! Active Sky Weather Engine  An evolved version of the Active Sky platform brings the core features that made Active Sky the leading weather engine for other platforms: Advanced weather synthesis and interpolation, high-resolution global winds aloft, realistic air and atmosphere effects, a comprehensive weather data network, integrated visual mapping and planning, and much, much more Voice Weather Delivery  Active Sky ATIS and Flightwatch are available at any time by listening on 122.00, 122.02 or 122.03 for closest station, actual/current interpolated conditions and destination weather reports, respectively Mobile Companion App  Use any device/browser to connect with Active Sky over your network and view and control the weather ‍  It’s available on the HiFi Shop for roughly $38.06 (the XP12 product page isn’t up yet, but Active Sky XP 12 is a free upgrade from Active Sky XP). The purchase page for Active Sky XP 12 is still labeled as coming soon because it’s under an open beta program. At least 500 MB of free disk space is required to install the product. Shout out to Josh M on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! The imagery, except for the cover, is from Active Sky XP (previous version) ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gazhos</id>
    <title>GazSim Releases Hostomel International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gazhos" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640b9524f05bbe3214d7ac99_hos1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1687586"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GazSim has recently released their rendition of Hostomel International Airport (UKKM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, home to the Antonov Design Bureau and the operations base from where the now-destroyed AN-225 used to operate its special cargo flights for decades.   The airport’s history dates back to 1959 when the construction work started. It was originally built as a top-secret in-house flight testing and improvement base for Antonov. The commercial cargo operations, which it’s famous for, began in 1989, together with Antonov’s attempt to demilitarize. Antonov Airlines uses the facilities for their cargo operations, consisting of transshipping, storage, border control, and aircraft maintenance.  A year ago, the airport was heavily damaged after an intense battle, which ruined most facilities and parked aircraft, including the famous Antonov AN-225 Mriya, the former largest cargo aircraft in the world.  The scenery is an accurate recreation of what Hostomel International Airport looked like before February 2022, with all of the Antonov Aircraft based there, including the AN–74, the AN-2, the AN22, and the AN-225. There are over fifty custom static and animated buildings (and aircraft), 2K and 4K PBR textures, the famous AN-225 hangar with an AN-225 in there that despawns if you wish to fly the AN-225 yourself, two animated hangars, a TimeShift feature allowing you to see the aftermath of the February incident by setting the date accordingly, fully recreated taxiways, a staff entrance gate (animated), and a history museum with multiple Antonov aircraft and their history. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.99, requiring at least 1.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. 10% of the proceeds go towards the AN-225 rebuilding effort.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hdae</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Daegu International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hdae" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640ba0c30945bdf631e6d564_daegu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="4166295"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Daegu International Airport (RKTN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 5th busiest airport in South Korea with a yearly average of 4.6 million passengers.  The airport was established in early 1937 as Taegu Airfield when South Korea was ruled by the Japanese. In the 1950s, it was utilized by the USAF as one of their airfields, consisting solely of a dirt and gravel runway and two concrete buildings. It was upgraded for the first time in mid-1950, with a new 1,500m long runway made of PSP (pierced steel planking). Months later, it got another 200 meters of PSP, making it 1,700m long. A 2,700m long concrete runway came a year later, by the hands of the 930th Engineer Aviation Group.  Nowadays, Daegu is no longer a military airfield but it still shares its infrastructure with the South Korean Air Force, which makes it highly illegal to take pictures of the apron, runway, and military facilities. It sports a single-passenger terminal and a parking lot for 1,097 cars.  It’s served by seven airlines: Asiana Airlines (Jeju), Jeju Air (Taipei), Jin Air (Jeju, Taipei), Tigerair Taiwan (Taipei), T’way Air (Bangkok, Cebu, Da Nang, Fukuoka, Guam, Hanoi, Jeju, Nha Trang, Osaka-Kansai, Taipei, Tokyo-Narita, Yanji, Zhangjiajie), and VietJet Air (Da Nang).   The scenery features hand-made ground texture sets, a fully modeled terminal with an interior, custom-built PBR jetways with realistic variations, animated humans, animated traffic, and a custom GSX profile. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.88, requiring at least 1.30 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vuekia</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Kilimanjaro International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vuekia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640ba7b023a0a162c475125f_kili1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1749805"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Kilimanjaro International Airport (HTKJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Arusha and Moshi in the Kilimanjaro Region (Tanzania). It’s the largest airport in the northern part of Tanzania in both size and passenger volume. Dating back to the early 1970s, built with the help of the Italian government, responsible for helping finance the construction costs with a long-term loan. It went on to become the first privatized airport in Africa in 1998, owned by the Kilimanjaro Airport Development Company (KADCO).  It is the gateway to the Kilimanjaro, Mara, and Manyara Regions, which house the Mount Kilimanjaro National Park, Arusha National Park, Tarangire National Park, Lake Manyara National Park, the Ngorongoro Conservation Area, the Serengeti National Park, and more. It’s often labeled as the “Gateway to Africa’s Wildlife Heritage.”. It’s served by fourteen airlines, with domestic, intra-African, and international routes. It includes Airkenya Express, Air Tanzania, Coastal Aviation, Edelweiss Air, Ethiopian Airlines, Kenya Airways, KLM, Precision Air, Qatar Airways, Regional Air Services, RwandAir, Safarilink Aviation, Turkish Airlines, and Uganda Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled main terminal and control tower (with interiors), an Air Tanzania hangar, the KIA fire station, a fully operational apron with correct parking positions, custom taxiways and taxi signs, updated runway, and LOD optimization for better performance. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.65, requiring at least 304.11 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winsan</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Santiago Pérez Quiroz Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winsan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640ce6e8e86598564c176a28_ara1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2556956"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Santiago Pérez Quiroz Airport (SKUC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Arauca in Colombia with a yearly average of 130,000 passengers as of 2014.  Built in 1979 and named after Santiago Pérez Quiroz, a Colombian military officer and politician who governed the district of Arauca in the early 20th century, it has undergone many renovations over the years to improve its facilities and services. It currently plays an important role in the region's economic development by linking it to commercial hubs in the country.  Sitting just 2 kilometers south of the border with Venezuela, the airport is currently one of the most important in eastern Colombia, served by three different airlines: EasyFly (Bucamaranga), Satena (Bogotá, Bucamaranga), and SEARCA (Bogotá).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with its main terminal, landside buildings, realistic ground markings, custom ground clutter, and custom vegetation around the terminal.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.41, requiring at least 100.53 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxava</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces the Piaggio Avanti II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxava" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640cee861a36d85cff22f383_ava1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="258570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has made a surprise announcementon their Discord with external pictures of their upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the most unique private airplanes ever made. The Piaggio Avanti II is an evolution of the Piaggio Avanti, originally introduced in late 1990 after four years of flight testing. The original concept goes even further back in time, to 1979, when engineering studies started and design choices were tested in wind tunnels in the subsequent years by Professor Jan Roskam from the University of Kansas and Professor Gerald Gregorek from Ohio State University. The final design choice was finally made in 1982, with the fuselage development starting a year later. The first prototype only took off in 1986, with the Italian certification to come in early 1990. The Avanti II got certified in late 2005, featuring an uprated Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-66B turboprop engines, flying faster and more economically, and a  new Rockwell Collins glass cockpit set. With 70 planes ordered in the first few months after the certification, the fastest civilian turboprop twin (according to Flying Magazine) was rather successful. ‍ Aside from the five external shots, there is no information regarding system depth, features, pricing, or a potential release date. Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pilcip</id>
    <title>PILOT’S Releases Boeing 314 Clipper for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pilcip" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640cfe42fdd67b78c498a8cd_clip1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1400596"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PILOT’S has recently released their rendition of the Boeing 314 Clipper for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a long-range flying boat from the late 1930s with enough range to cross the Atlantic and Pacific.  The original conception dates back to 1936 when Pan American Airways requested a trans-Pacific flying boat that could carry twice as many passengers as the Martin M-130. Boeing’s project won the bid with an order for six aircraft. Sporting four 1,600 hp Wright Twin Cyclones, and a 45m wing from the canceled XB-15, the B-314 saw its first test session two years later, out of Elliot Bay in Seattle.   The 5,930km range required a tank that could fit 16,070L of gasoline, with the 314A requiring an additional 4,500L and 1,100L of engine oil for both. It could seat 68 passengers and 5 tonnes of cargo, had a total length of 36 meters, 46 meters of wingspan, 6.2 meters of height, and weighed around 22 tonnes when empty. It could cruise at 210 miles per hour at 6,200 feet.  None of the twelve Boeing 314s survived the test of time, more so, they were all cannibalized for parts, scrapped, or written off. A non-profit oceanographic organization (Underwater Admiralty Sciences) plans to survey, photograph, and recover two sunken 314s, but nothing has been done yet (probably due to the extremely high costs of such an operation).  The virtual rendition was built from the ground up for Microsoft Flight Simulator with a study-level concept in mind. It features a complete virtual cockpit with accurately simulated navigation and radio room, a Sperry Type A Gyropilot (partial implementation, with updates to come),  authentic gauges, the inclusion of the long-range variant (314A), a custom sound package by ArezOne-Aviation Soundstudios, authentic color matching, simulated shore power when the B314 is moored, a comprehensive set of manuals, navigation aids to feed the Gyropilot, and more.  It’s available on the PILOT’S Shop for roughly $31.89, requiring at least an i5 with 2.8ghz or an AMD equivalent, 8 GB of RAM, 4 GB of VRAM, and an active internet connection. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/faddha</id>
    <title>Final Approach Design Simulation Releases Dhaka Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/faddha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640e37356c311e2a8248b461_dhaka1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1359685"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Final Approach Design Simulation has recently released their rendition of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (VGHS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Dhaka City, the Capital of Bangladesh.   The airport was initially inaugurated in the early 1980s as Dacca International Airport, then re-inaugurated three years later as Zia International Airport. It was built with consultancy help from Aéroports de Paris, the group behind Charles de Gaulle, Orly, and Le Bourget. The terminal area saw its first expansion work in 1992, with the addition of boarding bridges and equipment and a multi-story car parking for over 500 vehicles. Further upgrades came 20 years later down the line, with the addition of ILS, distance measuring equipment, and two new boarding bridges. The latest upgrade involved the interiors, with several improvements to the main concourse and toilets.  With four terminals, two for international flights, one for domestic operations, and one for VIP personnel, Dhaka Airport handles an average of 6 million passengers annually. A fifth terminal, Terminal 3, is under construction and said to complete in 2024, with 26 boarding bridges, 12 conveyor belts, and 115 check-in counters.  It’s the main hub for Biman Bangladesh Airlines, offering 29 destinations both domestically and internationally. Regent Airways, Novoair, US-Bangla Airlines, Sky Air, and EasyFly Express also use Dhaka as their hub. It’s visited by 31 international airlines, including Air Arabia, Air India, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Qatar Airways, and Singapore Airlines.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed ground poly, 4K PBR textures for ground and 3D buildings, high-detail 3D buildings, static vehicles, ground service equipment, animated jetways, custom ILS, terminal interior, custom dynamic lighting, realistic night textures, AI traffic support, updated taxi layout with two new taxiways, LOD optimization for performance, custom volumetric 3D grass, and realistic tree vegetation.  It’s available on SimMarket and iniBuilds Store for roughly $23.28/22.85, respectively, requiring at least 1.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nmm777</id>
    <title>NMM: Stratosphere Studios 777-300ER/ERF</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nmm777" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640e422b4e36b905b5cc81c1_777_icon11.png.55cbbee9a0f2fd05f8e1bf55f6605403.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="279629"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Stratosphere studios 777-300 for XP12 is the latest aircraft to feature in our no-money Monday series, highlighting the very best and brightest in freeware aircraft and scenery.  The team behind the 777-300 have been keeping sim pilots up to date in their development forum. Recently they have informed everyone that the primary modelling of the aircraft both exterior and interior are more or less done, with 50 functional buttons and systems and they are now working on fine-tuning the 777 and making it as realistic as they possibly can The aircraft currently features detailed modelling, a detailed EICAS and EFIS system along with default avitab integration.  This exciting freeware aircraft is available to download on the Xplane.org forum  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwphx</id>
    <title>BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim Release Phoenix Sky Harbor International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwphx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640eb072c700f6b04fa6bb28_phx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2502340"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim have partnered up again to develop a rendition of Phoenix Sky Harbor International (KPHX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 8th busiest airport in the United States and 11th in the World.  Sky Harbor’s history goes back to 1928, when it was built by Scenic Airways, making it the fourth airport in Phoenix. The airport was sold not much after to Acme Investment Company as a consequence of the Stock Market crash of 1929. They owned it for six years, and then the city of Phoenix purchased the whole thing for $100,000.   The Wall Street Journal ranked PHX as the best airport overall in the country among the 20 largest, with praises to its short screening waits, fast wi-fi, good restaurants, and cheap Uber fares to get downtown.   With a yearly average of 45 million passengers, Phoenix consolidates itself as one of the busiest hubs in the World. Southwest (36.21%), American Airlines (33.46%), and Delta Air Lines (7.04%) compose the top three carriers in market share, with Denver (1,087,000), Seattle-Tacoma (831,000), and Las Vegas (813,000) being the busiest domestic destinations. Internationally, three tourist destinations in Mexico take the crown, with San José del Cabo being the busiest (352,461), followed by Puerto Vallarta and Cancún, with 245,749 and 215,088, respectively.  The airport has two terminals (T3 and T4), with T1 and T2 marked as “retired.” Terminal 3 has 25 gates, and Terminal 4 has 92.   The scenery features an accurate rendition, with high-resolution custom ground textures, landside buildings, airline codes assigned to their respective parking stands, FSLTL traffic compatibility, animated jetways, custom ground markings, and an animated Sky Train.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $23.30, requiring at least 3.50 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to troponaut on the Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/caebol</id>
    <title>Caelus Aerial Releases Bologna Guglielmo Marconi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/caebol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640f83b4909590574abd594f_bol1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="969172"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Caelus Aerial has recently released their rendition of Bologna Guglielmo Marconi Airport (LIPE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 8th busiest airport in Italy with a yearly average of 9 million passengers.  The airport's history dates back to 1933, when the original airport was erected. It was in the 1970s that they built the current one, 500 meters away from the former. The old one turned out too small to handle the passenger volume increase from there onwards. The "new" terminal, recently expanded, covers an area of 36,100 square meters, with 24 departure gates and 5,500 square meters of shopping area.   The airport is one of the Italian hubs for Ryanair, with 53 non-seasonal destinations and 14 seasonal. WizzAir is another prominent visitor with 11 destinations in Eastern Europe. The airport is visited by multiple non-LCC European carriers such as Aegean Airlines, Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Swiss, TAP, and Turkish Airlines, along with a list of other rather popular LCCs such as Eurowings, easyJet, and Vueling.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with detailed models of all the buildings, accurate runway, apron, and taxiway markings, PBR materials, and partial interior modeling of every part of the terminal that faces the apron, an animated monorail, surface movement radar, weather radar, and runway guard lights.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $16.93, requiring at least 588.82MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winlet</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Alfredo Vásquez Cobo International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winlet" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6410ece742bbf39f4b153ba9_let1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3021293"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Alfredo Vásquez Cobo International (SKLT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Leticia in Colombia.   ‍  Inaugurated in 2003 and named after the former governor of the Department of Amazonas, of which Leticia is the capital. It’s the main gateway to southern Colombia and an essential hub for air transportation of regional products, such as rubber and nuts. The traffic figures sit at around 100,000 passengers a year.   It’s visited by Avianca, LATAM Colombia, and Viva Air, with direct flights to Bogotá. SATENA, a government-owned regional carrier, also operates in Leticia with routes to La Chorrera, La Pedrera, San José del Guaviare, and Tarapacá.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail model of the main terminal, custom ground markings, landside buildings, custom clutter, and landmarks.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.85, requiring at least 228.31 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmxmum</id>
    <title>Project MAX Releases Mumbai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmxmum" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6410fa6836623341ca172952_vabb1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3119200"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Project MAX has recently released their rendition of Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport (VABB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Metropolitan Region of Mumbai, India. It’s the 2nd busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 49 million passengers, and the 41st in the World.  Mumbai International Airport was conceived as RAF Santacruz in the 1930s and played an essential role during World War 2 while housing several Royal Air Force squadrons. It covered an area of 610 hectares, with three runways. It saw the first bits of civil action in the late 40s when the RAF handed it over to the Director General of Civil Aviation, which had the RAF hangars converted into a passenger terminal. It was only a short time until they had to expand, with the construction of a new terminal sometime in the late 50s and new equipment that would allow nocturnal operations.   The jumbo jet era brought even more traffic into the already constrained airport, with a terminal that could only handle about 600 passengers at the same time having to deal with twice that amount. It quickly became the most congested airport in the country, awarding it an honorable mention from Time magazine as a “black hole” rather than a terminal building. To make matters worse, the International section caught on fire in 1979, killing three people. The airport owners were urged to expand the structure with a 110 million rupee project expected to reach completion by 1981. Construction began in 1977, earning its end in late 1980.   The airport saw further modernization work proposed in 2003, when it was already handling 38% of the country’s aircraft movement, rounding up at around 13.3 million passengers, leading to another congestion nightmare. A consortium won the bid to operate, manage, and modernize the airport, a process that happened progressively over the years.  It’s a hub for many Indian airlines, including Air India, AIX Connect, Vistara, Akasa Air, Go First, and IndiGo, offering a comprehensive domestic and international network. It’s visited by many carriers from all around the globe, with the most prominent being Air France, All Nippon Airways, British Airways, Cathay Airways, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Singapore Airlines, Turkish Airlines, and United Airlines.  The scenery features a detailed 3D model for the terminals, buildings, props, and landside buildings, detailed ground poly, custom ground markings, a detailed terminal interior, high-detail airside with ground service equipment and static aircraft, specular mapping and PBR on ground poly, dense fps-friendly custom autogen, bonus 3D scenery of VAJJ, night textures, and custom AFCAD. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.12, requiring at least 433.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
