<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-11-15T18:21:09.299015+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsdza</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Zagreb Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsdza" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6544f1157d5693757edfacb6_zagreb.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="823063"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Zagreb Franjo Tuđman Airport (LDZA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Croatian city of Zagreb with a yearly average of 3.1 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1962, replacing an airfield near the village of Lučko. It originally featured a 2,500-meter runway with a 1000 square meter terminal, replaced within three years by a state-of-the-art 5000 square meter terminal. The runway was lengthened to its current capacity in 1974. ‍ The airport was upgraded in the early 2000s with an ILS system and a terminal expansion, adding 10,000 square meters to its total area, and it was later expanded even further in 2017 with the construction of a brand new, 70,000 square meter terminal, increasing its yearly passenger handling capabilities to 5.5 million passengers. ‍ It’s a hub for Croatia Airlines and one of the European bases for Ryanair. Aegean Airlines, Air France, Air Serbia, Air Transat, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Eurowings, Finnair, flydubai, Iberia, KLM, LOT, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Qatar Airways, Trade Air, Turkish Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom buildings, custom clutter and vehicles, custom lighting, and custom jetways. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.99, requiring at least 391.58 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fl2jax</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Jacksonville International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fl2jax" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654579b89480561f50d4a74f_jax.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1044016"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Jacksonville International Airport (KJAX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Jacksonville Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 6,500,000 passengers.  Jacksonville International was conceived as a replacement for Imeson Field, which has served Jacksonville since 1927. It was simply not big enough to handle the increased demand for air travel, and the runways could not be expanded due to terrain limitations.  ‍ The airport's growth could have been faster, with only two million passengers annually by 1982 (way below expectation). However, the 90s saw a massive increase, with the average hitting the 5 million mark. In 2000, they approved an expansion plan to rebuild the landside terminal, central square, main concessions area, and a parking area expansion. ‍ In 2006, they rolled out the second phase of the expansion program, rebuilding concourses A and C, designed by Reynolds, Smith &amp; Hills. The crisis of 2009 stopped any other ongoing expansion work, with the old Concourse B being demolished and only considered for rebuilding ten years later when the traffic figures were healthy again. The pandemic, though, halted that project. ‍ Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Silver Airways, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. American, Delta, and Southwest hold most of the market share, with 20% each. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom lighting, high-detail models, and performance-friendly optimization.  ‍ It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.78, requiring at least 5.89 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orte12</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces TrueEarth Great Britain for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orte12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6548dce89921ac30e7595c3f_britain.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437111"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of TrueEarth Great Britain for X-Plane 12, bringing color-corrected imagery with custom autogen, hand-crafted POIs, and more. ‍ Unlike the X-Plane 11 version, TrueEarth GB for X-Plane 12 will bring 3D trees with individually set heights, improved water masking using the sim’s new water model, soundscape support, and fully native seasonal changes. ‍ The TrueEarth Great Britain series is divided into three parts: North, South, and Central, covering the entire United Kingdom with high-quality satellite imagery, hundreds of points of interest, a custom mesh, millions of buildings at their correct height and location, and VFR landmarks. ‍ The release date is yet to be announced, but Threshold will keep you informed!Shout out to Luke for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dddaus</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Announces Austin-Bergstrom International for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dddaus" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65495cd36c6d0d9092ac343d_aus.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="410084"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DominicDesignTeam has just announced their rendition of Austin-Bergstrom International (KAUS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Greater Austin metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.   Built on what remained of what once used to be the Bergstrom Air Force Base, it is now the third busiest airport in Texas, with over 76 destinations (domestic and international) and approximately 510 arrivals and departures on a typical weekday as of 2018. It is an important airport for Southwest Airlines, which takes 34% of the market share as of 2021, followed by American Airlines and Delta, with 22% and 13%, respectively. Destination-wise, Los Angeles is the most popular, with 543000 passengers. Dallas and Atlanta are second and third, with 530000 and 513000, respectively.   There’s no pricing information, and the release date is sometime this week, according to their Facebook page.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p82uft</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates Universal Flight Tablet for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p82uft" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6549652f9f5b016c7574b83d_1250410_20231106143004_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1534175"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued an update to their 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a list of changes and improvements to their newly released Universal Flight Tablet.   It focuses on the tablet alone, with many changes that range from performance calculation tweaks to general QoL improvements. The complete changelog follows below: PMDG 737 for MSFS: Airplane Build 3.00.0082 (Tablet 1.1.1) 0012611: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Dynamic calculation of OPT derate when OPTIMUM selected (emvaos) 0012476: [EFB - Simbrief] CRZ data on dashboard's Flight Details is unclear, not useful (cbpowell) 0012751: [EFB - General] Change the order of OAT/WIND/QNH to WIND/OAT/QNH, like every OPT, to match the sequence of the METAR (cbpowell) 0012674: [EFB - General] ICAO entry fails using Onscreen Keyboard for certain ICAOs (rmurdoch) 0012720: [EFB - General] CTD when zooming quickly on map (rmurdoch) 0012736: [EFB - Performance and Computational] OPT LDA calculated incorrectly if using meters for units (cbpowell) 0012730: [EFB - General] Issue when entering wights with the virtual keyboard (rmurdoch) 0012723: [EFB - General] On screen keyboard is missing the / symbol (rmurdoch) 0012731: [EFB - Performance and Computational] OPT runway heading field should accept both 360 and 0 degrees (rmurdoch) 0012741: [EFB - General] Replace METAR parser with a more robust solution (rmurdoch) 0012744: [EFB - General] Implement new map tiling server in the tablet (rmurdoch) 0012592: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Runways below a certain length should not be displayed nor selectable (cbpowell) 0012579: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Permit OPT wind entry as + / - value to represent head and tail wind (cbpowell) 0012710: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Display runway slope percentage to a decimal precision (cbpowell) 0012690: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Invalid landing solutions should be clearly messaged on OPT pages (cbpowell) 0012675: [EFB - Performance and Computational] METAR parser cannot parse M00 temperature, does not load any OAT on OPT pages (rmurdoch) 0012581: [EFB - General] METAR not showing when there is /// on certain fields (rmurdoch) 0012725: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Permit user editing of runway elevation and length in OPT pages (cbpowell) 0012743: [EFB - General] Downloaded simbrief wx/rte files have trailing garbage characters (cbpowell) 0012618: [EFB - General] METAR display missing in certain unparseable situations (rmurdoch) 0012679: [EFB - Performance and Computational] Incorrect Takeoff Runway Length for KJFK 31L (cbpowell)​ ‍  ‍ Randazzo has also reinforced PMDG’s commitment to the customer base, with plans to update the UFT on a weekly/bi-weekly basis with new fixes and features: “Since the release of our PMDG 777 for Prepar3D back in 2012, PMDG has taken the view that part of the value you get in your PMDG product is our ongoing commitment to post-release commitment to our work. Generally speaking, we build in 5+ years of development/features and improvements into every product we sell- and this is true of our new product lines in Microsoft Flight Simulator as well!”. He then concluded: “The tablet is part-and-parcel of that development philosophy. In the post release period of any PMDG product you can expect to see a rapid iteration of changes/fixes/features. Over time that iteration cycle will slow from weekly to monthly to quarterly, depending upon the backlog of features that we have for you”. ‍ ‍ The update is available now for PMDG.com customers, and the marketplace release will depend on Microsoft’s intake process.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/d12aus</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Austin-Bergstrom International for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/d12aus" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654a95f0b4921ca04f22c39e_kaus.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="397167"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DominicDesignTeam has just released their rendition of Austin-Bergstrom International (KAUS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Greater Austin metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.   Built on what remained of what once used to be the Bergstrom Air Force Base, it is now the third busiest airport in Texas, with over 76 destinations (domestic and international) and approximately 510 arrivals and departures on a typical weekday as of 2018.  It is an important airport for Southwest Airlines, which takes 34% of the market share as of 2021, followed by American Airlines and Delta, with 22% and 13%, respectively. Destination-wise, Los Angeles is the most popular, with 543000 passengers. Dallas and Atlanta are second and third, with 530000 and 513000, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, realistic ground markings, and hand-crafted pavement.   It’s available on X-Plane.Org for $18.99, requiring at least 5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfuxv</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases World Update XV</title>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfuxv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654a9d1dbc9bd32bb9aed54f_updatexv.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="330568"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Microsoft Flight Simulator team has released a new world update, improving the Nordics and Greenland with fresh satellite imagery, 90 hand-made points of interest, five hand-crafted airports, ten cities, and enhanced digital elevation models. Developed in conjunction with Bing Maps, Vexcel, Maxar, Gaya Simulations, Orbx, and Kjetil Garpestad, the new world update significantly improves Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, the Faroe Islands, and Greenland.  The ten cities with improved photogrammetry are Gothenburg, Linköping, Malmö, and Visby in Sweden, Aarhus, Copenhagen, Frederikssund, Odense, and Roskilde in Denmark, and Oslo in Norway.  The custom airports, developed mainly by Gaya Simulations, are Iceland’s Akureyri Airport (BIAR), Norway’s Mo i Rana Airport (ENRA), Sweden’s Kiruna Airport (ESNQ), and Finland’s Ivalo Airport (EFIV). The sole exception is Leknes Airport (ENLK), developed by Kjetil Garpestad, an independent developer.  The update includes four discovery flights, three landing challenges, and three bush trips.  It’s available right now for Microsoft Flight Simulator owners.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bouvat</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Paris-Vatry Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bouvat" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654ab4687b780d6ec23dd4c8_vat.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="874497"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released their rendition of Châlons Vatry Airport (LFOK) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the champagne region in Northeastern France and close enough to Paris (135km) to be considered by Ryanair as one of the Parisian airports, with a yearly average of 61,826 passengers as of 2018.  It was built as an air base in 1953, housing fifty fighters in 3 large hangars. With France withdrawing from the integrated NATO structure in 1967, the Americans left the base, leading to its closure. The French Air Force then used it for training until the early 2000s, when it was sold to civil interests and converted into a civilian airport.  Besides handling occasional passenger traffic, it’s also a training pilot site for many airlines, such as Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, KLM, Transavia, Transavia France, and Swiss. Its relatively long runway has also seen use by Airbus for aircraft testing.  It’s served by Ryanair, with flights to Marrakech and Porto.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with up-to-date orthoimagery, 4K PBR textures, custom HD forests and vegetation, 3D volumetric grass, 3D people, 2023 layout, custom dynamic lighting, dynamic weather effects (X-Plane 12 only), and custom ground markings.  It’s available on their website for roughly $14.75, requiring at least 2.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vulcan</id>
    <title>Just Flight Provides Avro Vulcan Progress Update</title>
    <updated>2023-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vulcan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654bbdeee86d8867d44c6120_FOR.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="156906"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has released an update on their upcoming Avro Vulcan for Microsoft Flight Simulator via their website today. The Avro Vulcan, developed by Avro/Hawker Siddeley, is a British bomber that took its first flight in August 1952. The Vulcan, also known as the V bomber, was developed as part of the British atomic weapon program, designed as a medium-range bomber with the capability of carrying one 10,000 lb. bomb over a distance of 1,500 NM. It can also carry standard bomb loads of up to 20,000 LBS.  The Vulcan's iconic shape is attributed to its delta wing design, which provides stability without the need for a horizontal stabilizer. The original Vulcan was powered by the Rolls Royce Olympus 201/301 low bypass turbojet engine, capable of producing up to 20,000 pounds of thrust and enabling the Vulcan to reach speeds of up to 561 knots with a service ceiling of 55,000 Feet. The aircraft was in service with the Royal Air Force until October 2015, when it was officially retired. Just Flight is focusing on the Vulcan B Mk. 2 XM655, which is located in Wellesbourne Airfield. The simulation will include air-to-air refueling and maritime radar reconnaissance variants that were once used by the Royal Air Force. This progress update provides information on the progress made on the project by Just Flight. To ensure the Vulcan's unique engine sounds are perfect, Just Flight is "holding back" on the sound preview video. The team has made significant improvements on the interior and exterior lighting and other functionalities of the EFB app. The accuracy of the aircraft lighting has been improved by up to 20 controls in the cockpit using new reference material. Eight switches on the right console will control the exterior lighting, including air-to-air refueling, probe lighting, rotating beacons, and other indicational lighting.  The EFB has new features and user interface improvements, such as a configuration menu that allows for the toggling of various aircraft equipment. Fuel menus let you see quantities without using MSFS menus, and they also include options to control Air to Air Refueling. The radio system is also being worked on to improve operational flow for the user. The Vulcan's complex radio system will be streamlined for better usage in the sim. Just Flight has not published a release date, but it indicates the release is on the horizon. To read the full update see their website here. ‍ As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2ac14</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2ac14" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654bbfdf422e19d9529a6036_comanche.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="772939"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently issued a new update to their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing changes to the sound system and multiple bug fixes.  Update 1.4, the fourth so far, restores proper engine preheater functionality, changes the sound system to Wwise (making it so it all runs within the simulator and the volume control is now shared with MSFS), fixes point and drag behavior with the gamepad, and more. The complete list of changes follows below: Version 1.4.0 Changes   The add-on is available on their store for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eyvian</id>
    <title>Eyevionics, an Innovation in Home Cockpit Software, Announced</title>
    <updated>2023-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eyvian" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654bcaee5318fec17aa936fa_eyevionics_fb_hd.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2824044"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Eyevionics, a new entrant into the home cockpit space, has been announced. Intended to integrate with MSFS, it brings multiple facets of a glass cockpit to mobile devices like the iPad.   ‍ Addressing the lack of any proper glass cockpit solution for MSFS on external monitors, Eyevionics integrates many aspects of the cockpit into one, such as the PFD, MFD, and EFIS. According to the app’s creator, Fabian Lauer, the goal for Eyevionics is “to start an app on one, two, three devices, set up its user interface for the flight you want to fly with a few touches and then just go fly.”  Eyevionics is still in active development, but boasts an ever-growing list of features already implemented into the app, which include: ‍ Many features are still under development for the app, such as: ‍ Eyevionics is planned to release initially with support for iOS, as well as Android tablets, and expect to release sometime in 2024.  For more information, and further announcements, visit eyevionics.eu, or their X (formerly Twitter) account here.  ‍ As of the time of writing, no pricing information has been announced, but Threshold will keep you informed as announcements come out about this exciting new entrant into the home cockpit space! </summary>
    <published>2023-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbns3</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Idaho’s “Not So Deadly 3” Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbns3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654ce6042d7cc0b98829ae75_ns3.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1131321"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released a new set of backcountry airstrips: Cabin Creek, Wilson Bar, and Marble Creek, all in Idaho. The “not so deadly” name alludes to the previously released - and much deadlier - Deadly 3.   Cabin Creek is in the Frank Church River of No Return Wilderness, with an airstrip surface susceptible to water and prop wash erosion. Measures were taken to minimize water erosion, such as installing water bars, but it hasn’t mitigated the erosive effect of prop wash. It’s a 1,750-foot-long dirt strip, requiring proficiency in mountain flying due to the challenging nature of the surroundings.  Wilson Bar is a simple turf strip with 1,500ft of total length. It is very close to the MacKay Bar airstrip and their campground.  Marble Creek has a 1,160-foot-long bumpy strip, with soft sandy soil for the first 400 feet on runway 4, followed by large bumps that reduce braking effectiveness. A hill on the south end of the runway will make it hard to land on 04, and runway 22 is over a large hill. It’s short, challenging, and surrounded by tricky terrain.  Developed by Milo Taylor, who also made the Deadly 3 and McCall Municipal Airport, the pack features three landing spots with varying degrees of difficulty, with an extensive vegetation library, new animated animals and birds, new effects, and more.  The scenery is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.77, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/joeosl</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Oslo Gardermoen for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/joeosl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654ce8dc0a9404696ff00894_osl.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712039"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Jo Erlend has recently previewed the progress on the Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Norway with 30 million passengers yearly.   Oslo Gardermoen is the main airport serving Oslo, located approximately 47 kilometers northeast of the city center and opened in 1998 as a replacement for the outdated Fornebu Airport, which had been operating since 1939. It was built to modernize and expand Norway’s airport infrastructure and improve accessibility to the capital city, quickly becoming the Main hub for domestic and international travel in the Country.   The new previews showcase the progress made on the eastern technical area with its many maintenance hangars, catering centers, etc.    There is no price or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you updated!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fseveg</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo Releases Initial 2024 Event Schedule and Travel Details</title>
    <updated>2023-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fseveg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65526ffb85352f31a737e7f2_fsexpo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="657733"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FlightSimExpo has shared the initial event schedule for 2024, along with travel details and a cost breakdown for attendees staying on property at Tropicana Las Vegas.   The event starts on Friday, June 21, with a series of seminars and announcements from some of the biggest developers, with a welcome reception at night featuring light fare and a free drink. On Saturday and Sunday, attendees can access a 40,000+ square foot exhibit hall with the latest and greatest in flight simulation hardware and software.   The organizers invite members, content creators, and developers to apply to host a seminar or panel discussion at the show. They can apply here.   There will be activities on the days surrounding the event, including air traffic control facility tours, planespotting trips, and more.  They have negotiated significantly discounted hotel rooms for attendees wishing to stay at Tropicana Las Vegas, with rates varying from $75 for Thursday and Sunday nights to $155 for Friday and Saturday, plus taxes and a resort fee. The all-in price for Thursday to Sunday is around $188/night. It also includes in-room bottled water, wireless internet for up to five devices, and free parking in designated areas. To book, visit FlightSimExpo’s website here. Phil Coyle, FSA’s co-founder, reminds everyone that the room rates are subject to availability, urging people to book early if possible.  They have also negotiated with Delta, United, and codeshare partners, with up to 10% in savings available on hundreds of domestic and international flights.   The event registration will open in December, costing $50 for a limited time, exclusive to FSA members. Click here to become a member, free of charge.</summary>
    <published>2023-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barbuc</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Bucharest Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barbuc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655279e1e64737911f69c59b_buc.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="477450"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Bucharest Henri Coandă International Airport (LROP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Bucharest’s metropolitan area with a yearly average of 12 million passengers.  It was used as an airbase by the Germans during World War 2 and then taken over by the Romanian Air Force afterward until its conversion into a commercial airport in 1965, followed by heavy modernization and expansion (the new runway was one of the longest in Europe at the time).  A VIP lounge was inaugurated in 1969 for Richard Nixon’s visit (American president), and a new passenger terminal was inaugurated in the following year, with a total capacity of 1,200,000 passengers per year for domestic and international flights.  It underwent a three-phase expansion program in the 90s, starting with constructing a new departure terminal and airside concourse. The second phase led to the construction of a domestic terminal, a control tower overhaul, and the transformation of the old terminal building into a dedicated arrivals hall. The third and final phase involved the extension of the airside concourse with fifteen new gates and a departure hall expansion. Both expansions added 55,600 square meters to the terminal’s total area.  It’s a hub for Animawings, HiSky, Ryanair, TAROM, and WizzAir. The visitors’ list includes Aegean Airlines, Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Eurowings, KLM, LOT, Lufthansa, Qatar, Swiss, and Turkish Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.37, requiring at least 166.49 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsthu</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Thunder Bay International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsthu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/655298f66cb740cfc125fa6b_thunder.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="628993"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Thunder Bay International Airport (CYQT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Thunder Bay in Ontario, Canada, with a yearly average of 800,000 passengers.  It was built in 1938 as an unemployment relieving strategy, housing the No. 2 Elementary Flying Training School during World War 2, part of the British Commonwealth Air Training Plan.   It was heavily renovated in 1994 by constructing a new airport terminal with two jetways, a large food court, a gift shop, and an arcade.  The government handed over ownership to the Thunder Bay International Airports Authority in 1997, a non-profit organization.   Air Canada Express, Air Canada Rouge, Bearskin Airlines, Flair Airlines, North Star Air, Porter Airlines, Sunwing Airlines, Superior Airways, Wasaya Airways, WestJet, and WestJet Europe serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom ground poly, custom jetways, ai-traffic compatibility, performance-friendly optimization, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.89, requiring at least 45.41 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
