<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-04-05T18:29:12.351957+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpa12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases PA-28-161 Warrior II for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpa12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67dc37a1bfcade78275d816f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight has just released the native version of the PA-28-161 Warrior II for X-Plane 12. This new version, developed by Just Flight and Thranda Design, is packed with various new features. The new add-on takes full advantage of X-Plane 12's capabilities. It includes revamped flight dynamics, 8K textures for both the interior and exterior, PBR materials, a new EFB, and more, enhancing the aircraft's accuracy. If you have previously purchased the PA-28-161 Warrior II for X-Plane 11, you are eligible for a 20% discount on the new X-Plane 12 version. The new  PA-28-161 Warrior II for X-Plane 12 is now available from Just Flight for $42.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aacrv2</id>
    <title>Aerosoft CRJ V2 Releasing on the 25th of March</title>
    <updated>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aacrv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67dc39ba9c05093705c08efa_rbqgpla7s2xylziwxebx.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. The Aerosoft CRJ, one of the first aircraft addons for MSFS is set to receive a large update on the 25th of March. The Bombardier CRJ is one of the most successful regional aircraft in history, with a total of 1,945 units built between 1991 and 2020. The CRJ700 series, which began production in 1999, includes the CRJ 700, CRJ 900, CRJ 1000, and CRJ 705 models. The seating capacity of these aircraft ranges from 66 to 104 passengers, depending on the specific variant. The CRJ series is widely utilized by regional airlines around the world, with SkyWest and Endeavor Air being the largest operators of this aircraft. Aerosoft has announced that the CRJ v2 will feature a completely remodelled cabin and an improved flight model. It will also include full integration with Navigraph charts and additional features. The update will address bug fixes and expand customization options. All variants, including the CRJ700, 900, and the CRJ 1000, will be available through a single purchase. The Aerosoft CRJ v2 will be released on the 25th of March and will be compatible with both MSFS 2020 and 2024.  ‍ For more details on the Aerosoft CRJ v2, refer to the Aerosoft website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777321</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777321"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published a new development update with further information on their effort to bring the 777 product line to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 in what appears to be a “big week for 777 testing”. Their beta team has recently been given access to working beta builds of the 777-300ER, 777-200ER, and 777F for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. PMDG finally feels confident enough in the platform to let their testers try it out without feeling like they would be wasting their time and effort. For those unfamiliar with the saga so far, PMDG was initially somewhat skeptical about Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, not in regards to the platform’s capabilities per se but more so on the compatibility aspect, even though Asobo had promised it would be pretty straightforward to port content over. Their skepticism was proven right over time, and the transition has been anything but smooth, with the first glimmer of hope only showing up with the release of SU1 beta in January 2025. They launched an all-hands effort at the time using undocumented methods and practices for the new platform, ensuring it would not be a merely “half-assed” drag-and-drop port but an actual solid conversion that would last and show their quality. The so-called herculean effort has apparently paid off, and they continue to work hard to ensure it will be stable and compliant in MSFS 2024 on PC and Xbox. ‍ Despite sharing many common elements with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, the new platform has plenty of significant changes that were not documented yet or were partially/wrongly documented, which has contributed to slowing down the process quite substantially. ‍ On top of ensuring compatibility, PMDG has also been hard at work upgrading the 777 product line with new MSFS 2024-only features and further polishing it with hundreds of bug fixes, tweaks, changes to handling characteristics, performance improvements, and a near-full refactor of the sound environment using new recording equipment, new processes, and even collaborating with their coding team to build even more fidelity to the airplane’s relatively rich sound environment. ‍ The company is excited to be testing the 777 lineup in MSFS 2024 finally (and soon the DC-6, or so they hint), but there is still no release date in mind until they know for sure it’s ready. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their official website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99 If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdxv2o</id>
    <title>iBlueYonder Releases Portland International Airport V2 for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdxv2o"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ddde94c2dcf4adcd6c94eb_pdx1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iBlueYonder has recently released their upgraded rendition of Portland International Airport (KPDX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, bringing its ground layout and overall infrastructure up to 2025 standards. The airport opened in 1936, replacing Portland’s Swan Island Municipal Airport, which was deemed too small and impossible to expand due to space constraints. The new project had a much larger area to work with and generated a greatly needed number of jobs, helping many families during the Great Depression.  Employing over 1000 workers, the airport’s construction was said to be one of Portland’s most significant public works improvements during the New Deal era. It was not without its challenges, though: the airport’s low-lying area was highly susceptible to flooding due to its proximity to the Columbia River, which led to the workers having to cover the area with over 4 million cubic yards of sand to help drain the water, along with a series of dikes to keep flooding at bay. By 1941, two runways capable of handling larger commercial aircraft were ready, and it temporarily served as a military airfield for the United States Army Air Forces during World War II. A new terminal opened in 1959, still serving as the present facility, albeit heavily upgraded.  The terminal was first renovated in the 1980s, ensuring Portland was ready for future needs. Ticketing and baggage claim areas were expanded and renovated, and a new concourse was added in 1986. A full reconstruction of Concourse E in 1992 and the opening of Concourse D in 1994 followed. New concourses (A, B, and C) were inaugurated a day before 9/11, giving its present H-shape. Further terminal expansion was only carried out in the early 2020s (part of it was absent from iBlueYonder’s first rendition). Part of the new expansion work is still ongoing and scheduled to launch in late 2025, but the developer has already brought it to the virtual realm of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. It’s a hub for Alaska Airlines and served by Air Canada Express, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, British Airways, Condor, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, Icelandair, JetBlue, KLM, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, Volaris, and WestJet Encore. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, a highly detailed terminal building with full interiors, custom jetways, many new buildings and garages, custom ground service equipment, and a custom GSX Pro profile. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $19.96, requiring at least 3.67 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilgw</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces London Gatwick Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilgw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67dde76ffe85203834ea32a1_lgw.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of London Gatwick Airport (EGKK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves the Greater London Urban Area and has a yearly average of 40.9 million passengers, making it the second busiest airport in London and the eighth busiest in Europe. ‍ The airport was built in the mid-1950s on top of a preexisting military facility (RAF Gatwick), and its buildings were designed by Yorke Rosenberg Mardall.  ‍ On the other hand, RAF Gatwick took over an aerodrome from the 1920s, which had been operating commercially since the 1930s after authorization from the Air Ministry. Its first terminal, the Beehive, was inaugurated in 1935.  ‍ The 1990s saw huge upgrades to the airport due to British Airways’ decision to build Gatwick as their secondary hub upon acquiring Dan Air, which led to their significant dominance at the turn of the millennium. ‍ Shortly after that, though, British Airways decided to de-hub the airport, which led to the growth of a popular low-cost carrier, easyJet. ‍ It’s a British Airways hub and an operating base for BA Euro Flyer, easyJet UK, Norse Atlantic UK, TUI Airways, Vueling, and Wizz Air UK. Aegean Airlines, Air China, Air Europa, Air India, Air Transat, airBaltic, Atlantic Airways, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Corendon, Croatia Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Eastern Airways, Emirates, Ethiopian, Freebird Airlines, Gulf Air, Iberia Express, Icelandair, ITA, JetBlue, Kenya Airways, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Nouvelair, Qatar Airways, Royal Air Maroc, Ryanair, Saudia, Singapore Airlines, SunExpress, Swiss, TAP Air Portugal, TUI Airways, Turkish Airlines, Volotea, Vueling, and WestJet also serve it. ‍ There’s no information on pricing or release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350105</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350105"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e1b6ddb846c49b9cce2201_filly.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing further bug fixes, improved GSX integration, ETP (Equal Time Point) functionality, and more. Update v1.0.5 brings a vast list of changes and improvements to systems, art, and sounds, along with improved GSX integration, including an automatic GPU connection on spawn, GSX payload and fuel synchronization, single GPU logic, auto jetbridge connection, and an auto-deboarding trigger. Furthermore, the update also includes support for Equal Time Point calculations, including a dynamic option that calculates the equal time point between two specific reference points rather than from origin to destination, aiding with ETOPS planning. Additionally, the MSFS 2024 version now features time marker aural feedback designed to assist with procedural timing during various phases of the flight. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ v1.0.5Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️Addition - Add ETP functionFixed – WASM Crash EFIS_Gauge_Draw when loading ANF in NAV mode after IRS alignment on both ND at same timeFixed - WASM crash doing abeam to directFixed - WASM Crash on NG Data UpdateFixed - Copy active SEC" has magenta dots in SPD field bugFixed - On the Ground, the F/CTL SD Page should not display all of the data. bugFixed - PFD speed tape alignment adjustments bugFixed - FCTL SD page display logic bugFixed - Chrono keeps going even during PAUSE AT TOD-pause bugFixed  - Add engine windmilling (bug)Fixed - Cruise below 10,000 issue with speed constraints bugFixed  - Step clb distance errors on FPLN page bugFixed - Cursor flashing box behaviour and alignment formatting bugFixed - S/C consistently moving in FPLN page bugFixed - Wind Data insertion not correct bugFixed - Cruise managed target during sel spd incorrect bugFixed - Dual Engine Failure Scenario - Gears visually down but not actually down bugFixed - DTO issue when the same wpt is in plan twice bugFixed - Traffic diamond and altitude overlapping bugFixed – VNAV - When you are at TOD and close to 1-2 miles and press DES it seems to CLB before it goes down the path bugFixed - GLS EDDF Z 07R issue bugFixed - SEC-FPLN should not go to TEMP as its not active bugFixed - Vmax (Vfe) incorrect behaviour during retraction bugFixed - Missing memos bugFixed - Unlatched DES prioritizing path over speed bugFixed - DES SPD LIMIT issues bugFixed - TERR Does not turn off when TERR SYS set to OFF bugFixed - WXR Does not turn off when WXR/PWS set to OFF bugFixed - Incorrect DES MN/IAS profile bugFixed - Rudder input not disconnecting the AP bugFixed - C/L Menu - Add a RESET ALL buttonFixed-  ISIS QNH display issue when above 30.00 bugFixed - ISIS coordinates bugFixed - ISIS longitude decimal blocked bugFixed - Approach checklist issue bugFixed - MORA display flashing on CA NDFixed- VD Dash seen past the destinationFixed – Some SND bugsFixed - No grid mora in ND bugFixed - RWY inside of VSD terrain bugFixed - VD grey area incorrect in these ranges bugFixed - Polar: track indication on PFD heading tape and ISIS bugFixed - [v0.0.9] Cargo door opening/closing too fastFixed - Master warning still not flashingFixed - Unable to cancel master warning aural by pressing the MW buttonFixed - ATHR disconnection by setting levers to idle missing indicationsFixed - OIS TO PERF, MTOW PERF bugFixed - Add Throttle Calibration reset buttonFixed - Reset throttle calibration buttonFixed - OIS GSX drop down menu needs a lot of double confirmation to get certain GSX functions acceptedFixed - Pack off take off, AIR PACK1(2) OFF appears with no time delayFixed - ENG 1(2) BLEED OFF should show status inopFixed - EFB Takeoff Performance: When I enter the takeoff weight using a , instead of a . (the European way) the field fills normally with the weight, but when I click COMPUTE it gives me an error that no weight would be entered.Fixed - Loadsheet OIS page pax numbers don't add up bug in some cases .Fixed - OIS land perf confusing display of marginsFixed - Display type (OLD/NEW) not correct on spawn, especially problematic on 24 as LIVERY CFG not respectedFixed - Pressing TAB toggles textbox input if any textbox is visible on OISFixed - UX/UI Improvements for contrast and readabilityFixed - OIS ENR: Unable to see any map other than STANDARDFixed - ECAM STS recall behaviour missing bugFixed - First officers EFIS BARO when pre-selecting is in the format of what the captains EFIS BARO is set to bug 3D Art 🎨🖌️Added: FS2024 Windshield rain effect with functioning wiper mask.Fixed: FS2020 Windshield rain effect with functioning wiper mask broken in 1.04.Fixed: Fixed armrest floating parts after animationFixed:  FS20/24: Some animations broken/missingAdded: Pilots visible in cockpit in FS2020Added (due to high demand): Pilots visible in cockpit in FS2024 (Experimental, sometimes pilot will spawn in wrong pose/position)Fixed: Zooming too far out in cockpit causes flashesFixed: Cockpit and Cabin Overhead Temp Selectors do not line upFixed: FS20: Cathay and Qatar missing tail logoFixed: Linear gear animations copied to LODs from LOD0.Fixed: FS24: Nodes optimized/useless skins further on LODs resulting in a small performance boost.Fixed - Domelight switch in cockpit doesn't switch the dome light onFixed - Slide arming lever has no effect on armingFixed - Engine Fan cone is heavily affected by frame generation.Fixed - Some animations broken/missingFixed - Illuminate N/W DISC light in the gear pin box when bypass pin insertedFixed - Screens glitching when moving cameraFixed - Cockpit lighting and displays flicker at extreme wide angle POVFixed - Minor colour format line EWDSounds 🔊Fixed - Modified AP disc sound logic; sidestick dc emits a quieter toneFixed - Increased thud noise to AP clunkFixed - Fixed avionic shutdown sounds cueing incorrectlyFixed - Fixed abrupt cutoff of cockpit avionics on shutdownFixed - Fixed ground roll sound disappearing when switching cameraFixed - Wind noise during takeoff adjustedFixed - Added sound to baro knobsFixed - Fixed event cue with FO side sunshadesFixed - Ground rumbling sound added at higher speedsFixed-  General ground roll mixing adjustmentsFixed - Engine level adjustments in flightFixed- Engine light off sound volume marginally increasedFixed - Fixed some aural callout levels were unbalancedFixed - Reduced intensity of aural speaker reverb effectFixed - Reduced audio ducking of cockpit avionics as engine n1 increasesFixed - FS20 Cabin announcement volume increaseFixed - Fixed FS20 manipulator sounds too quiet when engines are runningFixed - Fixed FS20 Cabin announcements quiet at rear of aircraftFixed - Fixed FS20 cabin ambient sound levels too quietFixed - 90-60 altitude callouts added ‍ The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/emb153</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family 2.0 &amp; Lineage 1000 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/emb153"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e1bbbcf4b39e1b3bc549b7_xcr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts recently released the long-awaited E-Jets Family 2.0 and the Lineage 1000 expansion for X-Plane 11 and 12. The update brings never-before-seen features, improvements, and a vast list of bug fixes, along with the fifth member of their aircraft product line. Aside from the new addition to the fleet, the changes with update 2.0 to the whole E-Jets family are substantial, bringing the “most authentic” (according to the developer) E-Jets in flight simulation. They have managed to fix X-Plane’s dark cockpit lighting issue by developing their own ambient lighting modifier, featuring three different lighting options (default, dynamic, and natural). Furthermore, the new update brings heavy autopilot improvements, including a glide path autopilot mode with precise vertical guidance for RNAV approaches, like a “fake ILS.”  The EFB tablet underwent massive changes, including improvements to UI and usability and a new settings page for preferences and sound adjustments. They have also introduced a new custom fuel system to all the E-Jets, with special attention to the Lineage 1000’s auxiliary tanks and their automatic fuel transfer process. The full release notes can be found here with further information on the update. The complete family is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $149.95,  whereas the upgrade price is $84.99 if you already own one of the E-Jets. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/m80324</id>
    <title>Rotate Updates MD-80 Pro for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/m80324"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e1cec6612a8f7902706a25_amd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate recently issued an update to their MD-80 Pro for X-Plane 12, adding new features, a tuned performance model and predictions to match X-Plane 12’s latest flight model adjustments, and many bug fixes. Update 1.51 also brings Apple Silicon support, an autoland mode, and more. The changelog follows below:  ‍ - Added AUTO LAND mode to autopilot. - Added AUTO LAND test. - Added AUTO G/A mode and annunciators. - Added MAP mode with terrain display to the WX instrument. - Added compatibility with Apple Silicon architecture. - Added PUSH position for altitude control in FGCP. - Added compatibility of lights for NewSky and other third party addons. - Added compatibility with improved X-Plane de-icing system. - Improved outflow valve wheel behavior. - Improved autobrake friction to match landing distances. - Improved brake temperatures logic. - Tuned engine performance and fuel burn. - Tuned aerodynamics. - Tuned localizer guidance. - Improved FMC performance predictions. - Fixed CTD when xPilot or other addons write to multiplayer plane's datarefs. - Fixed RTO triggered with aircraft stopped. - Fixed transmission for MIC selection in Audio Control Panel. - Fixed vertical speed control wheel actuator in VR. - Fine tuned some sounds. - Fixed pressurization loss when descending in idle. - Fixed a bug in vertical deviation indication. - Fixed a bug in VVI display. - Fixed autopilot mode transition from FMS-EPR to EPR-LIM. - Fixed geometry in IRS annunciator. - Added commands to control lights. - Fixed minor bug in OpenAL initialization. - Fixed a memory leak in VR when floating windows are resized. - Fixed a bug in navaids processing during initialization. ‍ The add-on is available on X-Plane.Org for $59.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/acrjd</id>
    <title>Aerosoft CRJ v2 Release Delayed by a Week</title>
    <updated>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/acrjd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67dc39b062c86ebb2893ef2a_axky3iklicjt5fyrt05l.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft CRJ owners awaiting the launch of the CRJ v2 will have to wait a little bit longer than first anticipated, as the release has been delayed by one week. Nearly four years after its initial release, the CRJ is receiving a free v2 update, set to feature a remodelled cabin and an improved flight model. However, Aerosoft has decided to push back the update by one week to ensure the best possible experience for users at launch. Originally scheduled for March 25th, the update is now set to launch on April 1st ‍ Benjamin from Aerosoft shared an official statement earlier today: ‍ “We would like to inform you that the CRJ v2 update has been delayed by one week. The new release date is April 1st. This is to ensure the best possible quality and that the update ships with as few issues as possible, including some you may have seen in the preview streams/videos this weekend. We know you all have been waiting for a long time for this update, but we would rather release a few days later than publish the update in an incomplete state. Thank you for your patience and understanding!” Stay updated with Threshold for the latest news, reviews, and more. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon</summary>
    <published>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ufkasc</id>
    <title>UFK Announces Airbus Steering Console</title>
    <updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ufkasc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e59ffe599fef467f7f3067_3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Universal Flight Kit, one of the new players in the world of flight sim hardware producers, has just announced their first product - the Airbus Steering Console. As the name suggests, the console is a 1:1 replica of the A320 steering console, with a 12-bit plug-and-play steering tiller with a metal base, 5V console/floor light, and attachment templates for various sidesticks (some of them being VKB, VIRPIL, Thrustmaster). As mentioned earlier, the console features an aluminum steering tiller, along with a functional PEDAL DISC button with a metal base, realistic amber built-in backlit panel (BIBL - one of their upcoming products), aluminum trash tray with a lid, and comes with screws, hardware and instruction manual. The console is made out of an MDF frame and has realistic vent grills. UKF’s newest product can be bough from their website for $299.95 during the pre-order period, and $399.99 as a standard price.The shipment begins on 2nd April, and it is also possible to order the F/O side version. It is compatible with all FS20 and FS24 aircrafts (including the most popular ones coming from developers like Fenix, PMDG, iniBuilds, Aerosoft, FBW, FSLabs, ProSim etc.), and with X-Plane 12 and ToLiss products.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fx320n</id>
    <title>Fenix Announces A320NEO family for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fx320n"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e6e1610162be660eaedf2e_neo-leap-hero.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix has just posted its 2025 roadmap, detailing planned updates for the current A320 CEO family, compatibility improvements for MSFS 2024, and a new NEO variant. A320 and A321 NEO Announcement The major highlight of the roadmap is the announcement of an all-new A320 and A321 NEO. After extensive research and development, Fenix has created a completely new “NEO” standard ECAM system from the ground up, which is independent of ProSim. This advancement allows for even deeper system modeling. This is not merely an updated A320 CEO with new engines; it is a fully developed A320 NEO simulation. According to Fenix, the entire aircraft has been rewired, encompassing every sensor and generator. They have also developed a fully functional DRAIMS panel, although visuals are not yet available for display. Both the CFM LEAP engine and the Pratt and Whitney Geared Turbofan will be fully represented in the simulation. Additionally, the Fenix A320 NEO will be a standalone product, meaning that prior ownership of the A320 CEO family is not a requirement. Upcoming Big Fenix Update Fenix has announced that a major update for the A320 CEO family will be released in a couple of weeks. This update will include the addition of A139 sharklets, the implementation of the Weather Radar, and new landing dynamics that enhance flare and ground effect behavior. Several upgrades to the Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) will also be introduced, such as support for Lido charts and a improvedV-Speeds calculations. Additionally, there will be audio improvements, including a new 3D AEVC soundscape for the flight deck and a redesigned IAAE V2500 soundset. Fenix says they will provide a full changelog shortly. ‍ For more details on the Fenix A320 NEO and A321 NEO, along with the upcoming big Fenix update, refer to Fenix’s website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/305106</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/305106"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e1b6ddb846c49b9cce2201_filly.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued another update to their A350 Airliner add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, introducing an autosave system, bug fixes, major system refinements, and more. Update v1.0.6 is the most significant update yet, bringing a powerful and flexible autosave system with user-configurable time intervals, saving the full state of the aircraft, including system variables and position data. It bypasses the default save/load system, warranting full control and fidelity of all systems. Furthermore, the update also brings a wealth of bug fixes, further refinements on many departments (systems, art, etc), and much more. The complete changelog follows below: v1.0.6Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️Fixed - During an Autoland the RETARD callout should play at 10ft, not any higherFixed - Issue with swapping SEC in edge casesFixed - SEC PERF missing some computed valuesFixed – Tweaked LDA approaches logicFixed – LS button logic adjustmentsFixed – Tweaking Manual ENG startFixed - FPLN formatting incorrect in TRK/DIST sectionFixed - Editing RNP accuracy doesn't saveFixed - Taxi camera light linked to main taxi lightFixed - Issue with NEXT WPT input nbr 2Fixed - F-PLN INFO btn on the active fplan logicFixed - Route summary  formatting incorrectFixed - OIS screen movement feedback 2Fixed - Issue with NEXT WPT input nbr 1Fixed - Route summaries in the SEC flight plan bugFixed - FCU MACH PRESEL is not workingFixed - WASM Crash - EFIS Exception - Undo on TMPYFixed - Undoing more than one action causes a blank TMPY f-plnFixed - Up and down double chevrons on sec f-plan aren't working correctlyFixed - Clearing top line in MFD behaviourFixed - Turning SPD knob while on managed speed issueFixed - Signs in auto show as on in cabinFixed - CABIN READY message does not reset after landing. If doing a second leg it will still display even though the passengers have not boarded etc.Fixed - Swap DB confirmation box issueFixed - Pull speed knob selects managed instead of current speedFixed - VD bracket behaviour incorrect when reaching destinationFixed - TRAF button should turn on when ADIRS line upFixed - Major: MLG sinks too much into the ground during touch downFixed - A359/K Bogie animation on landing gear sinks into ground on touch-downFixed - Gravity feeding and balancing bugFixed - Can't turn on Display Fix anymoreFixed - GSX/Push back causing damage to tires in FS24 meaning user is unable to taxiFixed - F-PLN INTERCEPT time on FIX INFO page incorrectFixed - Incorrect MORA range shown in NDFixed - Ability to type using your keyboard on the RH side display.Fixed - FADEC powering up timings adjusted per further dataFixed - Checklist typoFixed - Allow scrolling in dropdown using scroll handleFixed - Not sensed ABN list issueFixed - 1 window missing inside paneFixed - FAP screen texturesFixed - CAB PRESS indicator in door lights up depending on distanceFixed - Cathay livery, forward bulkhead low res textFixed - Incorrect SLIDE ARMED door indication by the doorFixed - Add Gear Bay Light to both 900 and 1000Fixed - Doors armed in EFB bugAddition – More technical ECAMS (HYD)Fixed - STATUS page items should update while a failure is activeFixed - PRIM 3 should fail if DC1 failsFixed - GREEND HYD LO PRESS doesn't have the LDG GRVTY EXTEND deferred itemFixed - the STATUS page should show deferred itemsFixed - FO Side OIS GSX menu disappearing mid-flightFixed-  reset NG code buttonFixed - Options page for CalloutsFixed - ZFWCG with GSX fuelingFixed- -1000 variant maintenance page to include correct number of tiresFixed - OIS Maintenance: disable options in flight or with engines runningFixed - Added mouse position cursors to OISFixed - Added GND SPLRs FAULT logic to failureFixed - FUEL R(L) MAIN+STBY PMP FAULT failures items now differentiate correctly between pumps abnormal off or failedFixed - PRIMs/SECs should show fail only in flight or on ground with engines on (verified from real aircraft)Fixed - FAP not functionalFixed - FAP - Cabin Lighting levels not changing w/ FAPFixed -  Add "Set Default Panel State" optionFixed - FAP not working for cabin lights?Fixed - FAP: Avionics bay and cargo bay lights not workingFixed- OIS full load pax numbers per class does not add up 3D Art 🎨🖌️Fixed -  Brake Fans Spinning Texture ImprovedFixed - APU Cowling AnimationFixed -  Slat Positions IncorrectFixed- RAT Animation adjustmentsFixed- APU stairs characterFixed - window missing paneFixed - White livery business class seat numberingFixed - cab press and arming indicatorsFixed - door press and arming logicFixed - engine cowling not being lit up by landing lightFixed - wing lights disappearing before fx takes overFixed -  FS24 added cabin rainAdded - MLG lights (minor)Added: APU manNote: Chocks may not appear visually in some instances. Under review. Sounds 🔊Improvement - Hydraulic sound overhaulFixed - No hyd yellow noiseFixed -  external hydraulic sound distancingFixed - Exterior engine shutdown sound improvedFixed - Improved exterior sound leaking insideFixed - Rain sounds more noticeable in various situationsFixed - Increased levels of spoiler dragFixed - Improved faders of various system soundsFixed - Wiper volume increaseFixed - more ambient sound to respective volume slidersFixed - Increased vol of both low and higher type AP discFixed -  distancing of exterior ambient soundsFixed - event coning of some exterior sounds (were going mute aft of aircraft)Fixed - 90-60 altitude callouts added ‍ They have also recently shared a roadmap for the A350’s development, promising a bunch of new features, more ECAM logic, geo-specific GPS jamming, new features, etc, as per the image below: The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stsbov</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Bovec Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stsbov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67eb0d3ca829f44b5b577767_bovec1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. ST Simulations recently released their rendition of Bovec Airport (LJBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which serves the municipality of Tolmin in Slovenia. Built in 1962, Bovec is an important airfield in the country. It is located in the Slovenian Julian Alps at an elevation of nearly 1450 feet, which makes it perfect for parachuting events (which are held yearly) and general aviation. Its single 900x40-meter asphalt runway and slightly high elevation make it a great challenge regardless of the size of the airplane. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models and an up-to-date ground layout. It also offers performance-friendly optimization with MSFS 2024’s new LOD system, a custom hangar with an interior, landside buildings, custom objects, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.79, requiring at least 349.29 MB of free hard disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crj041</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases CRJ V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crj041"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ec63171d5d53f777a4e4e1_crj1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has recently issued a major update to their CRJ 550/700/900/1000 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing a list of improvements, compatibility with MSFS 2024, and much more. Version 2 features a fully remodeled cabin (on a per-variant basis), a revised flight model based on the simulator’s new aerodynamics, full Navigraph charts implementation, partial GSX integration, weather radar, a landing distance calculator, extensive customization options for knob acceleration, sounds, autopilot configuration, throttle calibration, etc. The full changelog follows below: The update is free for V1 owners, and new customers can acquire it directly from the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $50.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol111</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta Tracking Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ede84006d2282d11f6d3c5_social.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx recently updated Volanta with a real-time tracking feature for premium members, polling the aircraft’s position locally every second. The new update also brings several bug fixes and new enhancements. Update 1.11 is one of Volanta’s most significant updates yet, featuring real-time tracking for premium members, improved map performance, ultra-low hardware usage when minimized, 3D mode tweaks, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Volanta can be downloaded for free on their website. Certain features require a premium membership.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1222</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.2.0 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1222"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ef0ee9572b607093dd0c18_lgt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research recently released a major update to X-Plane 12, which brings massive improvements to cloud rendering, lighting, environmental effects, and graphics performance. Their graphics team has been working to mitigate the famed dark cockpit issue, bringing significantly improved interior rendering quality. The light coming into the cockpit correctly follows the aircraft's contours and structural details. Furthermore, the graphics engine's exposure handling has also been improved, bringing exposure fusion—a familiar feature on most modern smartphones—to the virtual realm of X-Plane 12. It consists of taking multiple photos at various levels of exposure and then automatically stitching them together, yielding a potentially impressive-looking result.  The sky brightness has also been tweaked to ensure it's more natural and doesn't burn people's retinas. Ground object brightness values have also been tweaked to ensure they are not overly bright. Their graphics engine as a whole has also undergone changes, with an upgrade to their shader compiler, which manages resources more efficiently and thus brings smoother performance figures. Texture handling has also been tweaked to ensure faster loading times and more efficient rendering. Their VRAM management method has also been tweaked, ensuring it prioritizes smaller memory requests before large ones, aiding total memory allocation. Additionally, it makes multiple attempts to allocate memory before giving up, allowing the system to free up space when needed and ultimately reduce the chances of blurry textures or slow performance overall. The cloud rendering system has also been changed, with a small radius surrounding the camera's viewport sporting high-quality clouds, nearly eliminating cloud pixelation effects around the airplane. They hint at it being a stepping stone to other cool rendering effects in the future. Last but not least, they have also changed how their light rendering system works by breaking them into tiles, yielding better performance in demanding environments such as large airports and cities. In addition, they have also made minor changes to colors, bringing more realistic color accuracy, improved sky rendering, better cloud shadows, cloud shadows on clouds, cloud-aware ambient light, and more realistic shadows overall. Detail has also been enhanced on surface textures around airports, and weather effects now also show outside of the airport's area, accumulating on main roads, as suggested by the community. ‍ The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Known Issues ‍ Fixes and Enhancements General ‍ Graphics ‍ ‍ Scenery ‍ The update is currently available on the public_beta branch on Steam. Laminar customers can get the update by toggling “Check for new betas as well as updates”. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
