<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-04-24T18:22:33.654069+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsdar</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Darwin International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsdar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/643db6a76651ab84ee24db58_darwin1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="558845"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Darwin International Airport (YPDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the tenth busiest airport in Australia with a yearly average of 2.0 million passengers.  Darwin Airport started as Parap Airfield in 1919, operating as a civilian and military field. It played an important role during WW2, used by the Allies to project air power into the Pacific. Soon after the war, the military airfield part was made available to civilian traffic, and the former civilian part was closed down.  A new passenger terminal was made in 1991, increasing the passenger handling capabilities of the then-primary domestic and international airport of the Northern Territory. It wasn’t until 2015 that it got massively expanded. An 85 million Australian dollar expansion project brought the terminal from 16,000 to 27,000 square meters, with new airline lounges, more check-in stands, and six boarding gates.   The airport is served by Airnorth (Alice Springs, Broome, Cairns, Dili, Elcho Island, Gove, Groote Eylandt, Katherine, Kununurra, Maningrida, McArthur River Mine, Milingimbi, Tennant Creek, The Granites, Townsville), Alliance Airlines (Dili), Fly Tiwi (Gapuwiyak, Milikapiti, Minjilang, Nguiu, Pirlangimpi, Ramingining, Tennant Creek, Warruwi), Jetstar (Adelaide, Brisbane, Cairns, Denpasar, Melbourne, Singapore, Sydney), Qantas (Adelaide, Brisbane, Melbourne, Perth, Sydney), QantasLink (Adelaide, Alice Springs, Broome, Cairns, Canberra, Dili, Townsville), Singapore Airlines (Singapore), Virgin Australia (Adelaide, Brisbane, Melbourne, Perth, Sydney), and Virgin Australia Regional Airlines (Perth).  The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with custom photoreal terrain, custom jetways, realistic ground markings, and custom ground clutter.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.48, requiring at least 721.77 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taihon</id>
    <title>TaiModels Releases Hong Kong International for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taihon" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/643e1c8b1b7bb55f672535fd_vhhh1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2001378"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TaiModels has recently released their rendition of Hong Kong International (VHHH) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the 8th busiest airport in the World with a yearly average of 71 million passengers.  Hong Kong International was built to replace the old  Kai Tak Airport, deemed too small to handle the amount of traffic it was dealing with and the insane amount of complaints from airlines because of all the delays that were a direct consequence of the fact it just could not scale up to the demand. Planning studies started in 1974, with construction work only kicking in almost 20 years later, in 1991. Completion was achieved in early 1998.  Built on a large artificial island, the total area of the airport (12.48 square kilometers) corresponds to nearly 1% of Hong Kong’s total area.   The airport is a hub for Cathay Pacific, Greater Bay Express, HK Express, and Hong Kong Airlines and is visited by over 100 other airlines with more than 180 destinations. It’s also the World’s busiest cargo airport, hosting Air Hong Kong, Cathay Cargo, DHL Aviation, Hong Kong Airlines Cargo, Kalitta Air, Polar Air Cargo, and UPS Airlines.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Hong Kong International Airport, with high-quality textures, complete autogen around the city, ground traffic plugins, weather textures for X-Plane 12, high-detail models inside the terminal, PBR materials, performance-friendly optimization, and compatibility with X-Plane 11 and 12.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $28.54, requiring at least 4.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsfed</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Federico Fellini International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsfed" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/643e22b65ddf1aa245719048_rimini1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2766353"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Federico Fellini International Airport (LIPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Rimini in San Marino.   Its history dates back to the early 1930s when the first airfield was built in Rimini. Initially, the airfield was used primarily for military purposes during World War II. After the war, it was converted into a civilian airport.  Over the next few decades, Rimini-Miramare Airport underwent several renovations and expansions, including the construction of a new passenger terminal in the 1960s. However, as air traffic to the region continued to grow, it became clear that the airport needed to be further upgraded to meet the needs of modern aviation.  In the late 1990s, plans were made to upgrade the airport and expand its facilities. The new airport was designed by the architect Marco Bacchini, and the construction work began in 2004. The project included the construction of a new passenger terminal, a new control tower, a new runway, and other facilities.  The new airport was officially opened on June 15, 2011, and was named Federico Fellini International Airport in honor of the famous film director born in Rimini.   It’s served on a seasonal basis by Albawings, Iran Air, Luxair, Neos, Ryanair, and WizzAir (the only one to offer a flight all year long to Tirana). The passenger figures sit at 900,000 a year.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, landside buildings, custom clutter, custom night lighting, and realistic ground markings.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.57, requiring at least 251.81 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rotm11</id>
    <title>Rotate Update MD-11 For XP11 &amp; XP12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rotm11" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64403b66f033f9d2df9e7b6d_Rotate-MD-11-Banner-02.jpg.495edcb2ce6c1690be93851f0d6e8f61.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="47807"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate has recently released an update for their popular MD-11 aircraft which is available for both Xplane 11 and 12. This latest update focuses mainly on a large variety of improvements and fixes and will without a doubt improve our overall experience with the aircraft.  The MD-11 can be updated through the Skunkcrafts updater or through a fresh download from your store of purchase!  The Lengthy Changelog includes:  -Improved LNAV trajectory calculations. - Fixed various issues found in SID/STAR procedures LNAV display and guidance. - Improved VNAV flight path calculations and guidance. - Implemented flight path interception after early descent command. - Fixed a bug in performance predictions due to ISA deviation influence. - Fixed some FMA modes displayed during descent and approach. - Improved deceleration distance calculations. - Improved thrust prediction during IDLE configuration. - Fixed a bug affecting V/S mode when flying with speed brakes extended. - Fixed a bug in AFS not acquiring VCL target after acceleration phase. - Added FMC GO AROUND page. - Fixed a bug in AIRWAYS page. - Made throttle and reverser hardware configuration more user-friendly. - Added support for throttle beta/reverse axis configuration. - Allow brake commands and toe brakes to work together. - Improved product license check to eliminate unnecessary activation requests. - Fixed altitude clearance enforcement in T/O CLAMP mode. - Fixed centre landing gear geometry. - Fixed landing gear bogie tilt. - Fixed a bug in Navaids auto-tuning system. - Fixed a bug in Fuel Tail Management System. - Fixed a bug in temperature dissipation through Fuel System components. - Fixed a bug in engine EGT indication. - Fixed a bug in ILS selection by frequency in NAV/RAD page. - Fixed a bug in Autobrake ARM TO warning. - Fixed a bug in CG calculation (XP12 only). - Fixed aircraft sometimes sitting on tail on startup. - Fixed indications in ND during ND alignment. - Fixed WXR RNG and TLT indications logic. - Fixed flight time indication logic. - Fixed a bug in FIX reference info radial. - Fixed a bug in deletion function deleting the wrong waypoint. - Fixed a bug in HDG bug arc command. - Fixed a bug in AFS that prevented the transition from LOC ARM back to NAV. - Fixed a bug in overspeed protection. - Include FMC slope/wind FMC fields in Situations presets. - Fixed a bug in HDG bug indication during LOC mode. - Fixed a bug in the ND aircraft icon during TRK mode. - Fixed a bug that affected reception and audio control of navaids morse signals. - Fixed TCAS symbols showing outside the HDG arc in ND. - Added dashes to altimeter readout above +/- 3000fpm. - Removed navaid information in ND for auto-tuned navaids. - Fixed a bug in the CAB PRESS RATE indication. - Improved compatibility with the Better PushBack plugin. - Fixed problem with VRAM usage in VR floating windows. - Tuned exterior and cockpit lights (XP12 only). - Improved wing-flex animation. - Removed excessive dirtiness from engine smoke. - Fixed animations in copilot MCDU keys. - Fixed some visual errors in the cockpit. ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/colcap</id>
    <title>ColombiaVFR Releases Capurganá Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/colcap" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64405e8213ef9de50a180f3f_capu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1662703"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ColombiaVFR has recently released Capurganá Airport (SKCA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the coastal town of Capurganá in Colombia.   The city isn't accessible via roads, meaning only airplanes and boats can get there, making the airport an important - and fast - link to the rest of the country.  The airport is operated by the Colombian Civil Aviation Authority and has a small terminal building that provides basic facilities such as check-in counters, waiting areas, and restrooms.  Capurganá Airport is known for its scenic location, surrounded by lush tropical forests and crystal-clear waters. The airport is near some of Colombia's most beautiful beaches, including Playa Blanca and El Aguacate. As a result, the airport is a popular destination for tourists who wish to explore the region's natural beauty and enjoy outdoor activities such as hiking, snorkeling, and fishing.  Despite its popularity, Capurganá Airport has limited flight options, with only a few airlines operating regular flights to and from the airport. The airport is also known for its challenging approach, as the runway is on a narrow strip of land between the sea and the mountains, making landing and takeoff difficult in certain weather conditions.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-detailed custom models, custom clutter, and lots of minor details such as graffiti art (as per real life), an abandoned airplane, and more.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $16.46, requiring at least 1.61 GB of free hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/v1spoc</id>
    <title>V1 Studio Releases Poços de Caldas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/v1spoc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6441779d6cc29275d40c7f2c_pocos1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3676796"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. V1 Studio has recently released their rendition of Walther Moreira Salles Airport (SBPC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Poços de Caldas, Minas Gerais, Brazil.  Inaugurated in early 1938 (making it one of the oldest airports in Brazil), with the presence of the then president, Getúlio Dornelles Vargas, it was built with ambitious plans of linking the city to Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo, and Belo Horizonte. VASP and Panair, present at the inauguration ceremony, were the first airlines ever to serve Poços de Caldas Airport, followed by Aerovias Brasil in 1945.   Since 1991, the airport no longer has scheduled flights, used exclusively for private aircraft, air taxis, and pilot training.    It’s the second highest airport in Brazil between medium and large-sized airports, at an impressive 1,260 meters above sea level.   Three years ago, the airport underwent revitalization work, with all the taxi lines and markings on the runway being repainted, lighting improvements, and the installation of optical fiber cables for a future meteorological station.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom lighting, high-detail airport buildings, custom-made vegetation, and a  realistic ground layout. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket and GearDown Simulations Store for roughly $8.20, requiring at least 1.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fvrtar</id>
    <title>France VFR Releases Tarbes–Lourdes–Pyrénées Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fvrtar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6441809f7813f7c9fe87ced2_tarbes1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4067184"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. France VFR has recently released their rendition of Tarbes–Lourdes–Pyrénées Airport (LFBT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the community of Tarbes in France with a yearly average of 450,000 passengers.  The airport was built in the 1940s as a military airfield, dabbling into commercial service after WW2, with commercial flights beginning operating from the airport in the early 1950s. The airport was gradually expanded over the years, and in 1968, a new terminal building was constructed.  In the 1980s and 1990s, the airport underwent significant renovations and upgrades. In 1988, a new runway was built, which enabled larger aircraft to operate from the airport. In 1993, a new passenger terminal was opened, designed to handle up to 800,000 passengers annually.  The airport has been used for commercial and military purposes throughout history. During the Gulf War in the early 1990s, the airport was used as a base for French military operations. In recent years, the airport has become a vital hub for pilgrimage tourism, with many flights carrying Catholic pilgrims to the nearby city of Lourdes.  The airport is served seasonally by AeroItalia (Forli) and AlbaStar (Bergamo). EasyJet (Milan-Malpensa), Ryanair (Bergamo, Charleroi, Dublin, London–Stansted, Malta, Rome–Ciampino), and Volotea (Paris-Orly), on the other hand, offer flights all year long.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution aerial ground imagery, detailed ground markings, photo-realistic 3D buildings, realistic night lighting, custom runway slope, multiple charts provided, and compatibility with the VFR France product range.  It’s available on SimMarket for $9.02, requiring at least 298.02 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hjme</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Jackson-Medgar Wiley Evers International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hjme" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644312d46645872b2d3d97a4_medgar1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="174734"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Jackson-Medgar Wiley Evers International Airport (KJAN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Jackson metropolitan area with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  The airport opened in 1963, replacing Hawkins Field, Jackson’s former main airport since 1928. Construction took around three years and came at a total cost of 6 million USD (equivalent to 56,000,000 USD in 2023).   It’s named after Medgar Evers (since 2005), a Mississippi Field Secretary for the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), who was assassinated in June 1963.     The airport is served by American Eagle (Charlotte, Dallas-Fort Worth, Washington-National), Delta Air Lines (Atlanta), Southwest Airlines (Atlanta, Baltimore, Houston-Hobby, Orlando), and United Express (Houston-Intercontinental). In addition to passenger flights, the airport handles cargo shipments, with UPS flying to Louisville.  The scenery features a highly accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models of the terminals (and their respective interiors), hangars, buildings, and other facilities. Taxiways, aprons, and stands have their layouts on par with real life, with custom jetways and realistic dynamic lighting.   It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.47, requiring at least 4.36 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atp330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Teases Progress on the A330 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atp330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64431893d7c75a1c781e6e3b_baxter1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2957111"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently shared further information on the development of their Airbus A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including a batch of new images, the entrance into a closed beta stage, and more!  Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft's Product Manager, fed their A330 Preview Thread with a fresh batch of external imagery of their upcoming widebody, along with the information their beta testers can now send exterior shots of the aircraft. He then described the product's current stage regarding models, textures, animations, flight modeling, FADEC, manuals, autopilot, systems, etc. Description of which follows down below, verbatim: ‍ Modeling, texturing, and almost all animations are solid. No worries about that.  In fact, Stefan and Anne are already working on the next bus.  Flight modeling, Engine modeling, and FADEC were massive issues, but we are 99% sure we can get within 3% of correct behavior. Any pilot will tell you that is fine as one airframe differs from another. Having two engines on one aircraft that differ by 3% is fine. Don't be mistaken, 3% is pretty much state-of-the-art.  Manuals and E-manual are more or less okay. The PDF manuals will be fine and available on release, the E-manual which is one of the highlights of the project as we want to get even beginners to be able to fly the A330 will be available but will need to be updated with the latest changes in code. Autopilot still needs work but is basically not very complex. It flies the route, does a cool ILS intercept, and lands fine. Systems are more or less okay. This is one area where you can spend another 20 years because where the real aircraft just has to display what is happening, we need to model why it happens. So when a computer decides the cabin needs to be heated a bit, a system will divert heat from an engine to a heat exchanger and feed the warmed air to the cabin. That means the engine will be affected, the electrical system will be involved and that means the generators will need to provide a bit more power. And that drops the thrust of the engine. See the complexity? We have a whopping lot of that code running because of some professional spin-offs of the bus projects. It's there and somewhere in Germany, a developer is crying because no customer will ever see it.  EFB, we are very proud of the EFB.  and while we need some tweaks, all is well. Navigraph, NavDataPro, weather, runway data, simbrief integration, are all working. I just love to be able to update the weather data automatically before planning an arrival, The fact we incorporated our own sat imagery so you can be sure you are doing your taxi route okay.. cool. MCDU, LNAV, VNAV... That is where we have most work open. Logically as it is by far the most complex part of the aircraft. LNAV seems to work, VNAV not so much but we know what we need to do.  ECAMS, loads of tweaks in fonts, placement, and things like that open (we had some bad luck in that part) but it is not code that affects flight.  Still one of my main worries now. Marketplace. This is the work you need to do to get something on the Marketplace. Not only contracts but a whopping lot of things you have to add. Not complex but I still need a few days on that for sure. Installer/Protection. With our own Aerosoft One system that is tried and tested (our DRM has not been hacked and has next to makes life for the customer easier (no need to enter any serial!s)) we are not worried about that at all.  Support, they are fully included in the testing so they should know what they need. Marketing. This department will be getting all information from me very soon.  They will invite streamers to have a look at the product before release and get the word out to websites and magazines. Sales still have to make sure that all our associate sale channels get all the marketing data and on release the files.  BaxterChico, one of their testers, has also shared some screenshots:  There's still no information regarding pricing or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed as things progress! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd78m</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737-800 on MSFS Marketplace</title>
    <updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd78m" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644320aab627599e589e465e_pi1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1641159"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG recently released their Boeing 737-800 airliner on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace, nearly eight months after it was initially released on their website in August 2022.  The PMDG 737-800 is a feature-rich simulation of the Boeing 737-800, featuring all new models, textures, and sound environment. They claim it’s the “ultimate realization of flight simulation.”   The feature list includes a fully customized system simulation for all major and minor system components, a highly sophisticated logical simulation of onboard information systems and aircraft management, with a customized flight model bringing enhanced physics augmentation, rigid body physics for wing or tail surfaces, fully customized flight control systems, accurate resolution cockpit displays, interchangeable equipment options for cockpit instrumentation, native PMDG datalink simulation compatible with Simbrief integration, and more.  The developers also made sure to list some of the upcoming features, which are still under development: an electronic flight bag, high-resolution cabin models and landing gear bay interiors, new Asobo-reliant features such as weather radar, and more.  It’s now available on the Marketplace for $69.99 and on PMDG’s Store for the same price, along with all the other variants.  Images are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nsswra</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Wrangell Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nsswra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64443a0b313edb3945f01e3a_wra1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="969865"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Northern Sky Studio has recently released their rendition of Wrangell Airport (PAWG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Wrangell in Alaska with a yearly average of 15,000 passengers.  In 1920, a landing field was established in Wrangell, used primarily by floatplanes. Over the next few years, improvements were made to the landing field, including installing a beacon in 1925 and constructing a small hangar in 1928.  During World War II, the U.S. Army constructed a more substantial airfield at the site, which was used to support military operations in the Aleutian Islands. After the war, the airfield was turned over to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), becoming a public airport.  In the 1950s and 1960s, the airport underwent significant upgrades, including extending the runway to its current length of 5,999 feet and constructing a new terminal building. These improvements helped to increase the airport's capacity and improve its safety.  In 1985, the airport received a major renovation, which included the construction of a new control tower and the installation of new navigation and communication equipment. The renovation also included improvements to the runway, taxiways, and apron and the construction of a new fueling facility.  The airport is served by Alaska Airlines daily, with routes to Ketchikan and Petersburg using the Boeing 737-700.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed representation of its buildings and overall structure, full PBR materials, shading and occlusion on buildings, high-resolution textures, and custom orthophoto for the airport's surrounding areas.   It's available on SimMarket for roughly $12.08, requiring at least 2.85 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmazan</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Zanzibar Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmazan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644441ea8177d415a147229d_zanzi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="516707"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Abeid Amani Karume International Airport (HTZA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Zanzibar City with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  The airport was built in the 1930s by the British colonial government, primarily as a military airfield. During World War II, the airfield was used as a base for Allied forces fighting in the East African campaign.  After the war, the airport was converted for civilian use and underwent significant upgrades in the 1960s.  In 2011, the airport was renamed Abeid Amani Karume International Airport in honor of the first President of Zanzibar, who played a significant role in the country's struggle for independence from British colonial rule.  In recent years, the airport has undergone significant renovations and upgrades, including constructing a new terminal building and expanding the apron to accommodate more aircraft. These improvements have helped increase the airport's capacity and overall passenger experience.  It's the hub for ZanAir, Zanzibar's domestic airline, with flights to Arusha, Dar es Salaam, Pemba Island, Saadani, and Selous. The visitors' list includes Air France, Air Tanzania, Azur Air, Coastal Aviation, Condor, Edelweiss Air, Ethiopian Airlines, Eurowings Discover, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, and Turkish Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, an updated ground layout, custom night lighting, and custom clutter.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.39, requiring at least 114.91 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dspxen</id>
    <title>Dark Space Releases xEnviro 1.20 for X-Plane 12 </title>
    <updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dspxen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64444ecdfebe30f7ba99323b_xe1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1395797"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Dark Space has recently released the long-awaited version 1.20 of xEnviro, making it fully compatible with X-Plane 12, bringing realistic weather simulation to the newly released flight simulation platform.  ‍ xEnviro 1.20 is an adaptation of 1.18 for the new platform, with a similar feature set and improved performance: no more than 10% of the framerate is compromised once the weather engine is running (using the recommended settings), making it more performant than 1.18 was. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ ### Added - New architecture to accomodate procedural changes. ‍ ### Changed - Sound processor temporary disabled. - Visual effects temporary disabled. - Cloud shader revision. - Shaders moved to HDR rendering. - More accurate light phase with glory and fogbow. - Default X-Plane precipitation temporary enabled. - Aerodrome surface set using X-Plane runway condition. - UI colors changed to match X-Plane palette. ‍ ### Removed - Sounds settings. - Realistic aerial perspective. - Realistic night perspective. - Control water waves. - Draw wet aerodrome surface. - Draw drifting snow. - Draw snow in mountains. - Seasonal changes. - Windshield effects. - Volumetric aircraft lights effect. - Lens flares. - Diffraction spikes. - Glorious sun. - Custom rain. - Custom snow. - City lights. ‍ The developer highlights that certain features were now temporarily removed and currently relying on native X-Plane functionalities, such as the xE sounds, waves, and seasonal changes. It is also stated that they will try to re-implement the features they have removed (refer to #removed in the changelog above). ‍ Featuring industry-standard sky modeling, physics-based cloud visualization, and weather and time-dependent changes in atmospheric lighting, xEnviro aims to bring truly volumetric clouds to the world of X-Plane 12. ‍ xE 1.20 is a free upgrade for previous owners of the X-Plane 11 version. They state it will remain a free upgrade for the foreseeable future: “All updates within 2023 and likely 2024 will be free. A transition to 2.0 version would necessitate a substantial upgrade from the current capabilities of version 1.18”, stated the developer. ‍ It’s available on Threshold Store for $69.69, requiring at least a GTX 1050Ti or equivalent for the bare minimum and an RTX 2070 or equivalent for optimal performance.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2ind</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Indianapolis Executive Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2ind" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64455214ce0dc4625b14dc76_indy1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="614498"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of the Indianapolis Executive Airport (KTYQ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, located in Zionsville, Indiana, serving the city of Indianapolis with a yearly average of 41,810 aircraft operations as of 2019.  The airport started its life as Terry Airport in 1957 by the hands of Campbell Aviation. It originally had two runways (a 1018x18m bituminous runway and a 914x61m turf runway), ten hangars, and an administration building. They eventually added 26 more hangars within a couple of years.  It was sold to a new company in 1965, which made a couple of upgrades to the airport thirteen later: the main runway got lengthened and widened to 1570x23, along with the addition of high-intensity runway lighting, visual approach slope indicators, a non-directional beacon, and an instrument landing system.  After getting classified as a reliever airport to Indianapolis International Airport in the 1980s, they got funding from the government to further improve the infrastructure, adding underdrains, extra land for approach protection, and a new runway lengthening to the current 1,700 meters.  The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with a meticulous reproduction of all the buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night effects, high-detail ground service equipment, performance-friendly optimization, complete set of signs, fencing, vegetation, PBR materials, static aircraft (optional), authentic internal details and parallax internals.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.87, requiring at least 47.58 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wigper</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Perales Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wigper" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64467a9e8cba02f09a404dd8_perales1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2411836"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Perales Airport (SKIB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ibagué in Colombia with a yearly average of 74,428 passengers as of 2019.  The airport was established in 1919, during the early years of aviation in Colombia, as a grass airstrip for military and civilian aircraft.  In 1933, the Colombian government began constructing a more permanent airport facility at the site, named Perales Airport, after the local area. The airport was officially inaugurated on February 7, 1934, with the landing of a Douglas DC-2 aircraft from the Colombian airline SCADTA (now Avianca).  During the mid-20th century, Perales Airport played an important role in the development of aviation in Colombia, serving as a stopover point for commercial flights between Bogota and the country's southern regions. In 1955, the airport was expanded by constructing a new terminal building and control tower, which remained in use until the early 21st century. ‍ The airport underwent a significant renovation and expansion project in 2018, which included the construction of a new passenger terminal and extending the runway to accommodate larger aircraft.   Perales National Airport is an important transportation hub for the Tolima Department and surrounding areas. It provides easy access to popular tourist destinations such as the Nevado del Tolima mountain range, the Cocora Valley, and the Los Nevados National Natural Park.  It's served by Avianca and EasyFly, with direct flights to Bogotá and Medellin-Olaya Herrera, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail terminal and its interior, realistic ground markings, custom night lighting, and an updated ground layout.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.17, requiring at least 272.55 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shasul</id>
    <title>Shadescene Releases Sultan Mahmud Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shasul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644682b9020cdaf0fd892d58_shade1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3736156"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Shadescene has recently released their rendition of Sultan Mahmud Airport (WMKN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Kuala Terengganu in Malaysia with a yearly average of 919,829 passengers as of 2019.  The airport was established in the 1920s as a small airfield, used primarily for military purposes during World War II, serving as a base for the British Royal Air Force (RAF) and the Japanese Imperial Army.  After the war, the British colonial authorities expanded and upgraded the airport to accommodate civilian air travel. It was renamed Sultan Mahmud Airport in honor of Sultan Mahmud Al-Muktafi Billah Shah, the 16th Sultan of Terengganu.  In the following years, Sultan Mahmud Airport became an important transportation hub for the Terengganu region, connecting it with other parts of Malaysia and neighboring countries. The airport underwent several upgrades and modernizations to keep pace with the region's air travel growth.  In 2008, a major renovation and expansion project was undertaken to upgrade the airport's facilities and increase its capacity. The project included constructing a new terminal building, a new runway, and other airport infrastructure improvements.  Today, Sultan Mahmud Airport is one of the busiest airports in Malaysia, serving as a vital economic driver for the Terengganu region, supporting tourism, trade, and other industries. The airport continues to evolve and expand to meet the growing demand for air travel in Malaysia and the surrounding regions.  It's served by four airlines: AirAsia (Kuala Lumpur-International), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur-Subang), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur-Subang), and Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur-International).   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with an accurate replica of the terminal, custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, high-resolution textures, custom jetways, hand-placed taxiways, and runway light system, custom night lighting, and hand-crafted ground markings and textures.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $9.87, requiring at least 544.11 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
