<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-02-05T18:30:02.131451+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/grutbf</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Grumman TBF Avenger for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/grutbf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6795c3d361a267f1da7cc5f4_avenger5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of the Grumman TBF Avenger for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This WW2-era airplane was developed for the United States Navy and Marine Corps and eventually adopted by many air and naval aviation services worldwide. It was designed in 1940 to replace the Douglas TBD Devastator, offering an airplane that was very much in line with the technology adopted by the Axis forces at the time, in complete contrast to the Devastator, which was considered obsolete by 1939. The Avenger was designed to easily fit in aircraft carriers, with easily stowable wings that allowed way more airplanes to fit in the same carrier.  With a maximum speed of 447 km/h, 1456km of total range, and a service ceiling of 22,600 feet, the mighty Avenger was one of the most iconic World War 2 bombers, permanently changing naval warfare.  Crafted with Paul Bennet’s expertise (an aerobatic pilot who happens to own one of the last airworthy Avengers), the add-on features realistic aerodynamics, high-quality sounds, high-quality 3D modeling and texturing, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.68, requiring at least 2.23 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cp2020</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Announces ChasePlane for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cp2020"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67980a55024e3305b1018fc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 has recently announced that ChasePlane will soon be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. They have released a video teasing this exciting new camera plugin, after releasing an initial teaser video on their social media pages which is unfortunately now gone. ChasePlane was widely recognized within the Prepar3D community and was considered a must-have tool for many flight simulation enthusiasts. Since the launch of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, there has been a strong demand for this plugin; however, development faced challenges due to the limitations of the original camera API. Thankfully, it appears that these issues have now been resolved, and the plugin will soon be ready for users. The teaser and announcement video revealed that the upcoming plugin will offer a fully customizable camera system for MSFS and will incorporate real physics as well as view sharing, and various modes like FlyBy and Cinematic Mode. While no specific release date or price has been provided, the video concludes with a message stating "coming soon," suggesting that the release is not far off. ‍ We will keep you updated as more information becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hcak</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Akron-Canton Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hcak"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6799508b8ef5699f6a6d0ec7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly2High has recently launched its version of Akron-Canton Airport (KCAK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Situated in Ohio, the airport serves the cities of Akron, Canton, Cleveland, and Massillon. Each year, the airport welcomes nearly 700.000 passengers. The airport opened in 1946, initially intended for defense purposes during World War II, although its construction was delayed. In 1948, passenger flights began operating at the airport. The first terminal was established in 1955 and underwent expansions in 1962 and 2020. Today, the airport accommodates passenger airlines such as Allegiant Air, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, and United Express, along with the cargo airline Castle Aviation. These airlines offer destinations including Chicago, Las Vegas, Los Angeles, and many more. The scenery features a highly detailed rendition of the airport, main terminal interiors, custom jetways, custom lights, and more. The newly released scenery requires 3.9 GB of disk space and is available on iniBuilds for $15.59. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsogal</id>
    <title>FSoares Previews Upcoming Galeão International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsogal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6799bd57d8d9954f53198017_gig1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSoares has recently teased the development progress on his Rio de Janeiro/Galeão International Airport (SBGL) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is the main airport serving Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with a yearly average of 14.5 million passengers. It was opened in 1952 on top of a preexisting Brazilian Air Force base that was utilized by international long-haulers, which were too heavy and too large for SBRJ’s (Rio’s domestic airport) 1300m runway. With the ever-increasing international demand, they finally built a passenger terminal, which was progressively expanded until 1977. A new terminal building was opened that year, and all scheduled passenger traffic was transferred there. It’s still in use today as Terminal 1. Terminal 1 was first renovated in 1991 in preparation for the United Nations Earth Summit (held in 1992), and its annual capacity increased to 7.5 million passengers. Eight years later, Terminal 2 was opened, with 24 jetways and a capacity of up to 7.5 million passengers yearly. ‍With the imminence of the World Cup and the Olympic Games in 2014 and 2016, respectively, Infraero (the airport’s former manager) unveiled a $431 million upgrade and expansion plan for Galeão, including the renovation of Terminal 1, the completion of Terminal 2, and the expansion of the parking lots. The new concessionary revised the plans and included a new pier with 26 jetways, a new apron for 97 aircraft, and 2640 parking spaces. The $400 million sum quickly jumped to $800 million instead. Aerolíneas Argentinas, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, Azul, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Flybondi, Gol, Iberia, ITA Airways, JetSmart Argentina, JetSmart Chile, KLM, Latam Brasil, Latam Chile, Latam Peru, Lufthansa, Paranair, Sky Airlines, TAP, United Airlines, and Voepass serve it. ‍ There is no information on features, pricing, or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrbir</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2025 Receives Record-Breaking Initial Registrations</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrbir"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665de94849a2f1d685a19e71_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The organisers of FlightSimExpo 2025 have announced a record number of initial registrations for the event. Over 500 people have already registered for the expo, which will take place in Providence, RI, from June 27th to June 29th. The current ticket prices for the event are valid until March 1st.  ‍ Here are the ticket prices by category: ‍ - Non-FSA Members: $80 - FSA First Officers: $72 - FSA Captains: $64 (The first 250 FSA registrants will receive a special price of $50.) ‍ All tickets include access to seminars and exhibition halls from Friday to Sunday, as well as recordings of the sessions. ‍ For virtual access to seminars, the fee is $15, which is free for FSA Captains. For the latest updates on discounts and information related to travel and logistics for the expo, please visit the FlightSimExpo website. The best ticket rates for FlightSimExpo 2025 are available until March 1st and can be purchased online. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lisvra</id>
    <title>Lisium Releases Riga International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lisvra"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679b0f7cb8872e8bab39f912_riga1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Lisium has recently released their rendition of Riga International Airport (EVRA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 (full compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will come shortly). The airport serves Riga, Latvia, and has a yearly average of 6.6 million passengers. It was built in 1973 to replace Spilve Airport, which was deemed outdated and unable to accommodate the projected passenger figures for the next few decades. The passenger terminal was expanded twice (2006 and 2016), gradually increasing its passenger handling capabilities to ensure the airport could keep up with the ever-growing demand. It’s a hub for airBaltic, Norwegian Air Shuttle, SmartLynx Airlines, RAF-Avia, and Ryanair. British Airways, Finnair, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Skyline Express Airlines, Smartwings, Turkish Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom PBR materials, parallax interiors, an up-to-date ground layout, highly detailed models, and accurately modeled interiors.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.75, requiring at least 1.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da4xls</id>
    <title>COWS Releases DA40-XLS for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da4xls"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c4be2e4cdede0dcd9c1d4_moo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS has recently released their long-awaited rendition of the DA40-XLS for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. With over 2,200 built, it is one of the most popular trainer aircraft in existence. Their rendition reproduces the XLS variant, which is a “deluxe” version of the DA40 with a full Garmin G1000 suite, WAAS (Wide Area Augmentation System), TAS (Traffic Alert System), and more. The add-on features a high-fidelity model with high-resolution textures, an accurate model based on reference imagery, properly placed placards, true-to-life performance and handling based on over 1000 hours of testing from real-world pilots, a full suite of custom systems with fully customizable circuit breakers, EIS and cylinder physics simulation, custom combustion simulation for startup, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ The add-on is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $25.02, requiring at least 1.30 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avapia</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces Release Date for Upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avapia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c91d63c4ee07a49406e99_pia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightFX recently announced a release date for their upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, along with the release of a launch trailer and pricing information. The Piaggio Avanti II is an evolution of the Piaggio Avanti, originally introduced in late 1990 after four years of flight testing. The original concept goes even further back to 1979, when engineering studies started, and design choices were tested in wind tunnels in the subsequent years by Professor Jan Roskam from the University of Kansas and Professor Gerald Gregorek from Ohio State University. The final design choice was finally made in 1982, with the fuselage development starting a year later. The first prototype only took off in 1986, with the Italian certification to come in early 1990. The Avanti II got certified in late 2005, featuring an uprated Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-66B turboprop engines, flying faster and more economically, and a new Rockwell Collins glass cockpit set. With 70 planes ordered in the first few months after the certification, the fastest civilian turboprop twin (according to Flying Magazine) was rather successful. The add-on promises a faithful recreation of the Piaggio Avanti II. It will be available in the MSFS Marketplace for $24.99 next Thursday (06/02).‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2uni</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases University of Illinois Willard Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2uni"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c96d1974e436502d15024_uni1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 Scenery recently released their rendition of the University of Illinois Willard Airport (KCMI), serving the Urbana metropolitan area, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020.  While it was dedicated in late 1945, airline flights were to start nearly a decade later, in 1954, albeit in a very barebones manner, as the passenger terminal was only erected in 1960. By the late 1960s, Willard was the second-busiest airport in the state. However, it crumbled within a decade after the Airline Deregulation Act of 1978. Airlines found service to smaller airports inefficient and expensive. Airfares went up, whereas they went down at bigger airports like Chicago O’Hare, quickly killing the demand and leading many airlines to leave the airport altogether. A new passenger terminal was built in the late 1980s and remains used today. Until eleven years ago, the airport was home to the University of Illinois Institute of Aviation, which was voted by trustees to be closed in 2011, and everything was transferred over to Parkland College in 2013 so that the enrolled students could complete their courses.  Parkland College still operates the airport, providing an annual subsidy of $433,000. It’s currently served by a single airline, American Eagle, which flies passengers to Chicago O’Hare and Dallas/Fort Worth.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with full-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, performance-friendly optimization, custom vegetation, PBR materials, custom static aircraft, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.84, requiring at least 70.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mci224</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Kansas City International Airport V2 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mci224"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c9bb1bd800d775e97af72_kanser1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TropicalSim has recently released an updated version of their Kansas City International Airport (KMCI) V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport is the second busiest in Missouri after St. Louis, with a yearly average of 9 million passengers. The newly released version brings the airport layout up to current standards, with the new single terminal opened in 2023 that replaces Terminals B and C, with 40 gates in total. It also uses new SDK features such as the new LOD system, night lighting improvements, and ground layout edits to match the latest satellite imagery, excludes, and vegetation.  Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express currently serve it. SWA has the majority of the market share, with 45.43% of the traffic figures, followed by American and Delta, which have 14.27% and 14.08%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the new airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, native MSFS24 night lighting, PBR texturing, custom jetways, and a custom interior. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.91 and requires at least 457.73 MB of free hard disk space to install. V2 for MSFS 2020 owners are entitled to a free upgrade, and V1 owners can purchase the new scenery for a discounted price of $17.28. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rafhon</id>
    <title>IM Scenery Releases RAF Honington for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rafhon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679ca2f0e51d1bb0e7efbc6f_hon1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IM Scenery recently released their rendition of RAF Honington (EGXH), a Royal Air Force station in Suffolk, England, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024.  Construction started in 1935 and was undertaken by John Laing &amp; Son, an investment group now known as John Laing Group, which boasts 177 years of history. The opening occurred two years later, nearly right in time for the beginning of World War 2. Based in Honington at the start of the war, the IX Squadron ran the first British bombing raid of the Second World War, attacking the Kriegsmarine in the Baltic. In 1942, the airfield was transferred to the United States Army Air Forces and upgraded to a class A Bomber base. It was eventually transferred back to the RAF once the war was over, primarily utilized by the RAF Transport Command and later by the RAF Bomber Command in 1949. In the 1950s, a 9,000 ft concrete runway was built and completed in 1956. In the 1980s, it was selected to become a base for the RAF’s Panavia Tornado fleet, with the IX Squadron being reformed there and becoming the world’s first operational Tornado squadron. ‍ In mid-1992, it was decided that Honington would become an RAF Regiment Depot, with the Tornado fleet wholly leaving the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully custom objects with PBR textures, custom night lighting, custom ground poly, custom terraforming, and custom static aircraft. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $8.30, requiring at least 712.1 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42cpm</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes Introduction to ChasePlane for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42cpm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a03568493d826e0a991328_cp1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 has recently published a blog article providing more information on their recently announced ChasePlane plugin for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, covering its features, MSFS 2024 compatibility info, and lots of in-game footage. They start by mentioning that their teaser was only teasing the cinematics system, which is one of the possibilities offered by their new product: switching effortlessly between cockpit view, external angles, and even airport cameras if you so desire. Custom presets can be easily created and shared online with seamless bind controls. ‍ For the unfamiliar, ChasePlane was originally released in 2016 for Microsoft Flight Simulator X, later being made compatible with Prepar3d and rapidly becoming the de facto camera application for ESP-based simulators at the time. It would only be natural for them to develop it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 when that came about, but technical limitations have made that impossible until very recently, which is why it’s only a thing now, almost five years after the simulator’s release.  ‍ ChasePlane will initially be released for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 only, but they do have Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 in mind and already have a working build, albeit unstable due to the simulator’s very early nature. That makes it hard for them to commit to a public release, as an update could break everything. “We can’t afford to waste time chasing a moving target,” concluded Edson Soriano, Parallel 42’s Managing Director. Due to platform limitations, ChasePlane will not be compatible with Xbox.  ‍ The add-on will feature a highly realistic physics-based camera behavior based on extensive research and real-world pilot footage, warranting realistic motion that dynamically responds to the environment, embracing the flight model rather than altering it. Pilots can feel the vibration during the take-off roll, the rush of turbulence, and the fluid shifts during maneuvers. They have embedded videos demonstrating the camera system on the “realistic” preset with different aircraft and conditions. Users can adjust the settings regarding intensities, etc., with sliders. The complete feature list for the product follows below: ‍ They have not yet been able to provide information on a potential release date or pricing, but it’s said to be coming soon.  ‍ Parallel 42 is ensuring the software is stable through extensive beta testing, ensuring it’s launched in a relatively solid state, thus creating a smooth sailing experience for the customers. They are currently working on refining the user interface, polishing features, and ensuring overall smoothness on a wide range of hardware. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfhav2</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces V2 Update for Hawk T1/A</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfhav2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a0e6befa9df6d7d57b7c1a_image1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has announced a significant update, version 2, for its Hawk T1/A advanced trainer. This update introduces a variety of changes, the most notable being the addition of MSFS 2024 support. ‍ New and improved flight model According to Just Flight, the original flight model was no longer working as well as it used to, prompting the team to completely redesign it from the ground up. The team emphasises that the Hawk still must be flown in a realistic manner, just as it was before. New weapons functionality You can now fire Sidewinder missiles, drop practice bombs, and jettison payloads. The static weapons are also included in the PC and Xbox Marketplace versions, though they won't have animation. ‍ New liveries The following liveries have been added to the Hawk T1/A Advanced Trainer: Green smoke is now available with the Saudi Falcons livery. There are limits on the amount of smoke that can be produced per flight, just as in real life. Options to refill or enable unlimited smoke are also included. ‍EFB improvements ‍Version 3 of Just Flight’s EFB now includes a redesigned interface and features such as Navigraph enroute charts. ‍ ‍MSFS 2024 compatibility ‍Just Flight states that the aircraft will be available from third-party retailers as well as through the MSFS 2020 marketplace. It will also be offered in the MSFS 2024 marketplace once that becomes available. Current owners can download the updated aircraft for free from the Just Flight website, with the update soon to be available from third parties. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrwi2</id>
    <title>Astralis Studios Previews Region of Waterloo International for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrwi2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a0ec4443dfbc3c35f6cf94_Screenshot_2025-02-02_204543.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Astralis Studios has recently showcased their upcoming Region of Waterloo International Airport (CYKF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This airport serves Kitchener-Waterloo and surrounding areas seeing 118,541 aircraft movements in 2018. The airport was opened in 1930 and was used mainly for flight instruction. At the end of World War 2 there was a push for a larger and more appropriate place for private and commercial aviation in the area. In 1948, the Waterloo-Wellington Airport Commission acquired a larger site in the Breslau area and a new airfield was completed there in 1950. The then K-W Municipal Airport became a general aviation facility in 1969. Today, it is served by airlines such as WestJet, Sunwing, and Flair Airlines. Non-stop commercial flights from Waterloo include destinations such as Calgary, Vancouver, Cancun, Halifax and more. In addition to commercial traffic, the airport is a popular general aviation hub and is home to the second largest flight training centre in Canada, Waterloo Wellington Flight Centre, as well as a plethora of privately owned hangars. This scenery includes over 60 custom objects, custom ground markings, enhanced night lighting as well as PBR texturing. It will be released on February 6th and will be available for $15.99 on all platforms. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for all of your flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kra024</id>
    <title>FlyDesign Releases Krakow-Balice Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kra024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a1d90118932095932e524d_kra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyDesign has recently released their rendition of John Paul International Krakow-Balice Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Kraków, Poland, with a yearly average of 11 million passengers.  Its construction started in 1964, opening for civil aviation three years later, in 1967. A passenger terminal was only built four years after its civil opening. The 1970s brought further development work to accommodate larger aircraft: a longer runway, new taxiways, and high-intensity runway lights. A new terminal was inaugurated in the late 1980s after the authorities deemed the actual capacity to be subpar compared to the projected traffic figures for the upcoming decade. Thus, it was inaugurated in 1993, followed by apron upgrades in 1995. New modernization work was carried out in 2002, focusing on improving the international passenger experience. Such effort was not in vain, and international routes increased in the following years. A separate domestic terminal (Terminal 2) was opened in 2007, and at the time, plans were underway to build an entirely new terminal in addition to Terminal 2. Ryanair opened their second Polish base in Kraków in 2012, basing two 737-800 aircraft there and connecting Kraków to many destinations across Europe.  Krakow-Balice became the first regional airport in Poland to reach over 9 million passengers yearly in 2023.  ‍ ‍ Due to the recent increase in traffic, the authorities have announced an upgrade plan to build a new terminal. The current terminal is not large enough to meet the projected demand for the future. ‍ It’s a focus city for Buzz Air (Ryanair Poland), Wizz Air, and LOT Polish Airlines. Aegean Airlines, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, hand-placed vegetation, fully dynamic lighting, high-definition buildings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.00, requiring at least 924.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sflphu</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Phuket International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sflphu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a1df1c67b05e122e6a0820_phu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SiamFlight recently released their rendition of Phuket International Airport (VTSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves the island of Phuket, Thailand, and has a yearly average of 17.2 million passengers, making it the third busiest airport in Thailand. Built in 1988 to accommodate only 6.5 million passengers yearly, it operated nearly at capacity for almost 30 years, until a new expansion project brought the figures to 20 million passengers per year (12.5 million passengers on the new terminal, 6.5 on the old one). It currently has three terminals: Terminal 2 handles international flights, Terminal 3 handles domestic operations, and Terminal X exclusively handles charters. Due to space constraints, Phuket has reached its capacity limit, which led the authorities to consider a rail link to Krabi International Airport for traffic alleviation in the near – or distant – future. In addition to the link, there’s a plan to build an entirely new airport elsewhere to serve Phang Nga, Phuket, and Krabi. It was supposed to be a multi-phase project, with phase one to start in 2022 and reach completion by 2025, but everything was indefinitely put on hold.  It’s a focus city for Thai Airways International and an operating base for Bangkok Airways, Thai Lion Air, and Thai AirAsia. Aeroflot, Air Arabia,  Air China, Air India, Azur Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Condor, Emirates, HK Express, IndiGo, Jetstar, Korean Air, Mahan Air, Nok Air, Qatar Airways, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, TUI, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terminals with an interior, custom ground textures, custom jetways, landside buildings, hand-placed taxiway guidance signs, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.38, requiring at least 196.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
