<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-09-17T18:30:56.685573+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xworld</id>
    <title>X-WORLD Europe Released For X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xworld" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631e5ade0228d10a8e8f8a95_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="481665"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Highly popular scenery package X-World developed by SimHeaven has released its European scenery package for X-Plane 12! In a post on their website, SimHeaven have announced the free scenery package which is now available.  The post on their website states;  "X-World continues for X-Plane 12 the successful and high quality sceneries for X-Plane 11 like X-Europe, X-America and so on. Objects are not set by an autogen rule, they are set  following OSM data in addition with Microsoft building footprints, which leads to a more realistic look and feel." SimHeaven go on to further explain;  "X-WORLD is a series of scenery packages covering the whole world, each continental package is separate available: X-World_Africa, X-World_America, X-World_Antarctica, X-World_Asia, X-World_Australia-Oceania, X-World_Europe" The download for X-Europe can be found here. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fisf6f</id>
    <title>Flyingiron Simulation Releases its F6F Hellcat</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fisf6f" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631f1fa7aad167d92aefa828_f6f-32_900x.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="93348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flyingron Simulations released its long-anticipated F6F Hellcat, adding to its ever-growing war-bird hangar. In WWII, the Grumman Hellcat served primarily as a NAVY bird on aircraft carriers. It replaced the F4F Wildcat to take on the A6M Zero. The Hellcat later became one of the top performing combat aircraft of the war gaining over 5,000 kills by the end of World War II. Flyingiron has brought the Hellcats legacy to Microsoft Flight Simulator with meticulous attention to detail. Flyingiron has also gained recognition for its Spitfire and P-58 models developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The F6F-5 HELLCAT is for sale for the reasonable price of $45 AUD.  ‍ The model is well detailed and handcrafted, taking over six months to complete. A few notable features include attention to aircraft systems and thermodynamics, factors to be considered in terms of wear and tear, and power plant management. Expect a learning curve when flying the Hellcat, which will challenge your manual flying skills. The F6F will be an exciting aircraft to switch to if you are used to flying today's modern birds. Usability features include a virtual tablet with customization options, maintenance, live aircraft monitoring, and more.  For a complete list of features including the product manual, check out the Hellcat product page here on the Flyingiron Simulations site. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcdesh</id>
    <title>DC Designs Announce Harrier Update and Surprise Fighter Project</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcdesh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631fbedc50514036f29d3eea_305975846_507159501412807_4030653392269115163_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="488607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DC Designs have posted a news update to their Facebook page detailing requested features from several customers. One such request from customers is if the Harrier could bow as it does in real-life air displays, as seen in this video. Here is the response. ‍  “I had not had the chance to test this until recently, and yesterday was able to give it a go. The answer was: yes you can! However, to balance the Harrier while performing the bow and not climb, drift, or descend is really difficult even in light winds. The aircraft’s engine thrust responds to N2, which means there is a lag between adding or removing power, and the thrust altering to climb or descend in the hover, which complicates things even further.” Check out more test footage of the Harrier here. The developer also dropped hints of a "Secret project” within the post. Just today the project was announced via Facebook as a partnership with a new developer “CJ Simulations". The pair are working together in bringing the Eurofighter Typhoon to FS2020.  This will be a well detailed model with a fully operational cockpit. The Typhoon will have a custom flight model simulating its unique delta canard system. You can expect many liveries and visual aerodynamic effects to be featured with this fighter as well. DC Designs also released a video displaying the Typhoon's maneuverability, aerodynamic effects, and modeling details! The Eurofighter is slated to be released in October for PC and XBox. We’re looking forward to these releases. DC Designs is known for their awesome fighter aircraft for FS2020, especially the F-14 Tomcat. We’ll keep you updated with more information here at Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xjetyt</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Posts Demo of E-Jet Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xjetyt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632108ad4487d2aba354ade2_ejets001.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="80107"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The X-Crafts team has taken to their YouTube Channel and posted a full flight video in their rendition of the Embraer E-195 demonstrating the new FMS, new autopilot systems, and new displays. While most of the team has remained tight-lipped since the FSExpo Showcase, the team has brung steady work and the continuous development of their E-Jets Family.  The video starts off at LOWW and showcases the complete programming of the WIP FMC, and shows off the new EFB, with at a glance looks to include takeoff and landing perfs, checklists, ground service, and integrated Avitab, along with a weight and balance tab. Ending the video off, the demo ends with the programming once again of the FMC for landing at LYBE, and we watch as the aircraft comes to the gate and ends the flight. Note that this product is still very much a WIP. The team has stated that there will be a paid upgrade for XP12 for both the E175 and E195.  No ETA has been stated by the development team. Follow Threshold for more news!</summary>
    <published>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tolair</id>
    <title>Toliss Release Airbus Fleet Update For XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tolair" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6321cbba84352de43604d648_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1855944"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Developers Toliss have released an update for their X-Plane Airbus range bringing their popular A319 and A321 variants into XP12. The aircraft will be available to those who owned them in XP11 for $10.99 each via the X-Plane.org store The discount will be automatically applied to your account, Toliss have explained.  A variety of new features have been added to the A319 just some of them include; ‍ The A321 has also received a variety of updates and new features;  To read a full list of new features and changes to the A319 and A321 check out their store page here We will endeavour to keep you updated on Aircraft and Scenery that are brought into XP12 as the weeks go on.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/free-xp12-dataref-compatibility-checker-released</id>
    <title>Free XP12 dataref compatibility checker released</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/free-xp12-dataref-compatibility-checker-released" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6321e4fa65e57a9302a2988d_usage.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="253387"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Porting existing addons to XP12 has been somewhat turbulent for developers with complex addons. Fabrice Kauffmann published free software assisting developers with migrating addons from XP11 to X-Plane 12. According to a post at Helisimmer.com, the script scans OBJ, LUA, and SND files for obsolete datarefs. Addon developers will save time updating addons to XP12 using his free tool. Thanks to Fabrice Kauffmann; this will help the growth and improvement of X-Plane 12! The software is free for Windows 10/11 and available on GitHub!  Threshold, bringing you the latest in flight sim news! </summary>
    <published>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/versim</id>
    <title>Vertical Simulations Releases Free Update for KSYR for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/versim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63225537927e0a30ea9bc3d1_screencapture.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="381865"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Vertical Simulations has announced on his Discord that he has just released a free update for KSYR in X-Plane 12. Previous owners of the X-Plane 11 version will find the updated version under their ‘account page’ section on his website – https://verticalsims.com/ – Additionally, purchasers of the original scenery from SimMarket &amp; the Xplane.org store will also find the update available to them.  Also within the announcement, Vertical Simulations noted the following Changelog improvements found in the new update: ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12d2</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 Developement Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12d2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6322c3784d1e217427e02bd4_Screen-Shot-2022-08-28-at-1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="3839634"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier today, Ben Supnik took to the X-Plane Developer blog to post about the current state and findings with X-Plane 12 since its initial early access release just two weeks ago. In the post Mr. Supnik highlights the rationale behind releasing X-Plane 12 for early access when the simulator is far from being fully developed, as there are “...still over two hundred open bugs.” Mr. Supnik immediately stressed how important it is to Laminar Research that the “entire X-Plane community be involved in X-Plane 12’s growth,” and not be confined to a limited number of beta testers.  Major areas of improvement include clouds, in which Mr. Supnik explains that the development team is working on shaping and cloud quality, improving resolution, correcting artifacts, and improving overall performance. The developer goes on to point out that clouds are some of the most taxing graphics on any system and it’s a “give and take” relationship between performance and quality. Lighting is another focus of improvement for the developer as they want to correct and improve the auto-exposure and tone mapping within the sim.  For those X-Plane 12 users who are dissatisfied with the Boeing FMC in the highly anticipated Airbus A330 that shipped with the default aircraft upon initial release of X-Plane 12, you’ll be happy to know that the developer is working on a proper Airbus MCDU for the plane. This update is expected to ship during early access, but with no specific mention of a date at this time. Mr. Supnik lastly points out that a few new SDK and authoring features are “mostly completed” and will ship during early access as well. Mr. Supnik further hinted at allowing third party access to the in-sim weather system.  Additionally, the development team at Laminar will continue to optimize the sim’s GPU usage while beginning to optimize VRAM use (as they have not done so at this point). For users of X-Plane 12 who are having VRAM issues, Mr. Supnik suggests lowering the simulator's resolution. Lastly, Mr. Supnik mentioned that over the course of the past weekend, some of the development team met to do planning and roadmapping for the sim. He disclosed that beta 3 should be coming out “shortly” (with no specific date or bug the planned update will fix). Mr. Supnik also disclosed that X-Plane 12 has been submitted to Steam and is currently in review. He’s hopeful that X-Plane 12 will be available soon on the Steam platform for those interested in picking up the simulator there instead of through the developer’s site.  If you are interested in picking up X-Plane 12 now, you can do so by visiting the official website for X-Plane here. Threshold will keep you updated on any new developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gblfr2</id>
    <title>Global Forests v2 Released for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gblfr2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632346180134bbee25dbffcf_19f241_849b3f55ced84a338f83fc94add3cb8e_mv2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="92185"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Geo Reality Design recently released v2 of its Global Forests addon for X-Plane 12, adding more immersion, replacing and, enhancing X-Plane's vegetation. Global Forest 2 covers three regions, Europe, North America, and Asia-Oceania. V2 complements Global forests V1 for seamless integration with Ortho4XP, terrain, and X-Plane 12’s seasons! Over 400 .for files utilized with various trees, vegetation, and density data. Based on real-world information using vegetation height/density from global map data to provide that living world feel, something bush pilots would greatly appreciate! Global Forests v2 is on the X-Plane.ORG store for $15.00. Check out this video on their YouTube page for additional footage!  ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xoxpv3</id>
    <title>xOrganizer V3 for X-Plane 12 Available Now</title>
    <updated>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xoxpv3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6324ea1ff699ddf5ffcc5aeb_4_airports.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="120855"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular third party addon xOrganizer has officially been released for X-Plane 12 and is available now via the X-Plane.Org Store. xOrganizer is a third-party software that gives accessability and users a peace of mind when it comes to their files. While the structuring for X-Plane files can be simple, it can be challenging for new users to overcome that roadblock on their simulation journey. xOrganizer helps assist those users into structuring everything from the scenerypackages.ini file, to making sure all aircraft are up to do date. While it can keep the proper order of your scenery files, xOrganizer is also includes a scenery map, detailing where and what scenery packages you have installed and the package X-Plane is currently using. In a simple UI, it outlines plugins, aircraft, and scenery, and gives the option to the user whether or not they use the assistance of software. Customizablity is also added for the extra touch and accessablity for users. If you are interested in the full feature list, you can view it on their store page. If you interested in upgrading or purchasing this product for yourself, you can find it over at the X-Plane.Org Store. For v2 customers, check your account page and you'll see a discount code you can use at checkout.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ixxp12</id>
    <title>IXEG Provides Future X-Plane 12 Development Updates</title>
    <updated>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ixxp12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6324eff0c67f2c1fb7331486_IXEG-Iberia.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="179905"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In a recent statement on the X-Pilot forums, IXEG developer Tom Kyler provided a brief insight into what the IXEG has been working on. In the post, Mr. Kyler alluded to the fact that his focus has been primarily on porting over the MU-2 into X-Plane 12 and that he’s closing in on the final stages of that. After the MU-2 project is completed, Mr. Kyler states that, “...the 733 will move back into rotation as the primary focus of development with the port to version 12 being the first priority.”  Mr. Kyler continued to express that the IXEG 733 (in its current state), is “minimally operable” in the updated simulator. Once the developer stabilizes the aircraft, Mr. Kyler expects they will set up a ‘volunteer forum’ where people will be able to provide feedback to the developer regarding the behavior and bugs with the aircraft. Mr. Kyler also released a screenshot of the cockpit of the 733 in X-Plane 12. Concluding his statement, Mr. Kyler recommends keeping X-Plane 11 on your pc if you want to continue flying the IXEG aircraft in the interim.  As always, Threshold will keep you updated for any further updates from IXEG. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfsdu</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Release Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfsdu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6324f2f929529240ad2c7888_Cirrocumulus646-Forum.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="176630"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The development team for Microsoft Flight Simulator has posted a brief update on the flightsimulator.com blog regarding present and future updates with the sim. The short post starts out by expressing gratitude for all those who have provided the development team with valuable feedback regarding the sim update 10 beta. The MSFS team have opted not to update the marketplace this week, and instead postpone the marketplace update until next Thursday, September 22 in order to, “...align with SU10 dependencies.”  The development roadmap has been updated and frequent updates will continue to be released for the SDK–which should have third-party developers jumping for joy. World update 11: Canada is slated for release September 28th, while the 40th Anniversary Edition and SU11 are both scheduled for release on November 11th.  As always, Threshold will keep you up-to-date with developments as they unfold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thru20</id>
    <title>Thranda Designs Previews Cessna U206G Stationair</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thru20" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325c78a56d6f1dc9d15b4b3_xp12-thranda-u206g-stationair-aug20-2022-08.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="231412"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Designs’ recently announced, Cessna U206 Stationair has got its first video preview, where it’s shown performing a visual approach into Powwatka Ridge, Oregon.  ‍ Thranda Designs has published a short video, where their recently announced Cessna U206G Stationair for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12 can be seen in action from inside the cockpit, landing into 03R Powwatka Ridge in Troy, Oregon.  ‍ To learn more about the upcoming aircraft, check out our previous post. Stay tuned to Threshold for further information on the matter. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shxa12</id>
    <title>SimHeaven Release X-World America For XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shxa12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325ca6078d241e1048b702d_simheaven.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="449911"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimHeaven have released their popular X-World America scenery for XP12.  The package download is 7.4 GB, extracted to 13.8 GB. Announcing it in a post on their website they have said;  The free scenery can be installed here</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csc510</id>
    <title>Cockspur releases new C510 Mustang Trailer </title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csc510" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325f2a7e87e89277cb389e4_C510_Promo_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="970411"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A very cool corporate jet is on its way! Cockspur, an FS2020 developer of the A22 Foxbat and the SG38 Schulgleiter, has posted a recent trailer of its C510 Mustang. The project has been under development and is making significant progress. The trailer shows an accurate rendition of the Citation Mustang, a light business jet capable of seating up to four passengers with a range of about 1,100 nautical miles.   Cockspur's trailer also shows interior details, as well as an air ambulance variant still in beta. Navigation options include the NXi or FS2020’s stock G1000. Interactive features include an iDevice for controlling various aircraft components, controllable doors, window blinds, and more. Check out the official trailer here on Youtube. Check out Cockspur's official Discord here.  Expect more updates and info soon here at Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12ea</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 now out on Steam!</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12ea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6325f73fea9e2c7687a7c0c0_header.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="23198"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The long-awaited flight simulator by Laminar Research is finally available on Steam for $59.99, where customers will be able to test the platform as it progresses through the early access phase.  According to Laminar, it should be under early access from 3 to 5 months, where developers plan to improve the volumetric clouds, tweak the lightning system, implement a fully customized Airbus MCDU, and brand new third-party interfaces for add-on developers. To read the complete feature list, please refer to this post. ‍ ‍ It’s important to note that X-Plane 12 is also available directly via their website for the same price and with identical features. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
