<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-10-14T18:20:39.342323+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bougpe</id>
    <title>Boundless Teases Free Inverness Update for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bougpe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6520717900dfb92f04bfd043_gpe2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437337"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released a short teaser video on their Facebook page showcasing the progress of its upcoming update for Inverness Airport (EGPE), bringing new ground textures, animated ground traffic, and more.  Inverness Airport is the main gateway to Northern Scotland, with a yearly average of 900,000 passengers as of 2019. It’s served by AlbaStar (seasonally), British Airways, easyJet, KLM, and Loganair.  The update will bring updated ground textures, animated ground traffic, upgraded lighting, upgraded lorry textures, upgraded terminal textures, a reduced file size, and an option to run without static aircraft.  ‍ While the update is not out yet, the previous version is available on their store for roughly $15.89, requiring at least 2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hspr</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Abraham Lincoln Capital Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hspr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65207d5d991a874fdbadf87f_spring1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="901806"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Abraham Lincoln Capital Airport (KSPI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Springfield, Illinois, with a yearly average of 145,000 passengers.  The airport opened in 1947, replacing Springfield’s former main airport, which was deemed inadequate for commercial operation due to terrible infrastructure. Initially, it sported three 5300 ft runways, a service apron, a temporary passenger terminal, and T-hangars for 38 airplanes.  ‍ The terminal was recently upgraded with funds from the Airport Improvement Program, a grant sponsored by the FAA. They have also improved the FBO, hangars, roadways, and parking lots.  It also houses the Capital Airport Air National Guard Station, making it a civil-military airport. It’s a 91-acre facility, hosting the 183d Fighter Wing, an Illinois Air National Guard Unit.   Traffic-wise, 64% of it is general aviation, 20% military, 15% air taxi, and only 2% corresponds to commercial. Allegiant Air, American Eagles, and Breeze Airways serve it with short regional ops.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and high-detailed models of all buildings.   It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $9.49, requiring at least 3.54 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwsan</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release San Diego International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwsan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6521bba174398f41fac4a04e_san1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="546503"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld &amp; AmSim have recently released their rendition of San Diego International Airport (KSAN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Californian city of San Diego with a yearly average of 22 million passengers, making it the third busiest in the state.  The airport was opened almost 100 years ago in 1928, the first federally certified airfield to serve all types of aircraft, playing an important role in testing sailplanes during the early 1930s.   It was taken over by the US Army Air Corps in 1942 to house the heavy bombers manufactured in the region. It led to an incredible expansion work that made the airport jet-ready even before the advent of commercial jet aircraft.   It was returned to the city right after the war, with Pacific Southwest Airlines starting service in 1949. By 1957, there were an average of 42 daily departures from American, United, Western, Bonanza, and PSA.  Paderewski Dean &amp; Associates built Terminal 1 and 2, which replaced the original terminal with a much larger area and modern infrastructure for the time (1967 for Terminal 1, and 1979 for Terminal 2).   A third terminal was built in 1996, along with a Terminal 2 expansion in 1998 that added 300,000 square feet to its total area.  It’s an operating base for Southwest Airlines and a focus city for Alaska Airlines. Air Canada, Air Canada Express, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, Japan Airlines, JetBlue, Lufthansa, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet also serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, a detailed terminal area, animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures, surrounding buildings, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.34, requiring at least 2.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ptable</id>
    <title>PMDG’s Universal Flight Tablet Set To Release Soon</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ptable" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6521dff7e1dde357d0673269_1250410_20230614041115_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2455681"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo from Precision Manuals Development Group has published a new development update, bringing exciting news about the Universal Flight Tablet, the 777, and pending updates for their existing lineup.  After nearly a month of complete silence, Randazzo says, “the fruit trees are now in bloom,” with their long-stuck projects and updates beginning to appear shortly, while also anticipating that the last quarter of this year and the next quarter will be “quite a bit of fun.”  They have decided on a release date for the Electronic Flight Tablet and have also started working on preview material, which should appear shortly. The release date will be shared along with the material, with PMDG warranting that users will know about the release date well in advance.  The UFT update will be a free micro-update for PMDG.com and Marketplace customers, but the latter will take longer to see the light of day because of Microsoft’s intake process. They estimate around 2-3 weeks from the release on their official website, and it’s just guesswork based on the average time it takes, according to their empirical data.  The 777 has not entered beta due to issues with the development team, but they are pleased with how it’s coming together, with handling characteristics and feel that are entirely unmatched, or so they claim. Previews will be held back for now as they want to show something remarkable.  Updates for the 737 were held back on PC because the new update will bring the EFB. Marketplace-wise, they are still dealing with the 3.00.0072 update that has been stuck for two months. They expect to get that sorted out soon.  PMDG has been working along with Working Title to find a fix to an issue with their DC-6’s gyropilot behavior, and they will roll out an update as soon as it’s ready.  The 737 lineup and the DFC-6 can be found on PMDG.com or via Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fleham</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fleham" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6522f1e541e2da0763da3258_schi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2880824"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has recently released their rendition of Amsterdam Airport Schiphol (EHAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the world's third busiest airport by international passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 72 million passengers. ‍ It opened 1916 as a military airbase, eventually converting into a civilian airport after WW1. It was captured during World War 2 by the Germans and destroyed. The rebuilding process started soon after, and it became the main airport of the Netherlands in 1949, undergoing an expansion project that sacrificed the town of Rijk to make room for their ambitious plans.  ‍ It was expanded again in 1967, with a new terminal area still partially used today (Departure Halls 1 and 2). Parts of the original piers (C, D, and E) are also from that period. A further modification was required in the 1970s to ensure Boeing 747 "compatibility," and a new pier was made for widebody aircraft in 1977. ‍ The 1990s brought further modifications, as the airport's new size meant the old control tower was not tall enough to oversee all of it, leading to the construction of a new one in 1991. Then, a new departure hall and a new pier (G) were added in 1993. ‍ With the construction of a sixth runway in 2003 came the need for another control tower to ensure they could oversee everything again. One was not enough. ‍ It's a hub for KLM, KLM Cargo, KLM CItyhopper, and Martinair, with the first being the Netherlands' national carrier. EasyJet, Transavia, and TUI fly Netherlands also have operating bases at the airport, flying people all over Europe. The visitors' list is quite substantial, as one would expect from the third busiest airport in the whole world, including the likes of Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air India, Air Malta, Air Transat, American Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Croatia Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Etihad Airways, JetBlue, Korean Air, Royal Jordanian, Ryanair, Turkish Airlines, and United Airlines. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, terminal interior models, PBR materials, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, custom terrain, and more. ‍ It's available on FlyTampa's website for $21.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpg16a</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Announces H160 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpg16a" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65256afc9a2dbce68e9dfbe4_5_2048x.png.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2109112"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has announced that their next project is another Airbus helicopter, the H160, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The announcement comes a week after they posted a teaser photo of the silhouette of the helicopter on their Discord server.  The Airbus H160 helicopter is a medium utility helicopter that was introduced in 2011, and was designed and engineered to bring many features from modern airliners and fixed wing aircraft, such as advanced avionics and autopilot systems, to a helicopter. The H160 production also borrowed many techniques from the Airbus A350. On the product page, Hype Performance Group says that this is their most complex project to date, and will include a myriad of features, including, but not limited to: The Hype Performance Group H160 will be released on Friday, October 27th, at a price of $49.99 USD (excl. tax). For the full list of features, you can visit the H160 Product Page.Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skyoil</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Heerema Oil Rig for MSFS!</title>
    <updated>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skyoil" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6525977ea8f5ed1dfa76399c_5-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="308520"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyline Simulations recently released their newest scenery add on, Heerema Oil Rig for MSFS! Skyline Simulations has been known for developing scenery for the three major sims (MSFS, X-Plane, and P3D) for ten years.  Skyline brings us a detailed lifting platform for Microsoft Flight Simulator in their latest release. This Semi-Submersible Crane vessel built by Heerema Marine Contractors is their second largest SSCV by Heerema, capable of deep-water installation to 14,200 metric ton installations, according to their website. The Thialf holds many lifting records and has the world's largest SPAR platform. ‍ Skyline Simulations offers features such as 3D modeling accurately designed with detailed technical schematics and drawings. Visual enhancements include UHD Custom Textures with the latest painting techniques and PBR Materials. Other neat features include custom lighting and animations to bring more life to the rig. The model also features hard surfaces and platform wave oscillations to challenge your rotor wing skills. Put your Heli skills to the test, check out, and purchase Heerema OilRig here on Skyline Simulations' website for only $5.30. Check out their further scenery offerings in their website catalog here! ‍ ‍ As usual, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2pre</id>
    <title>UK2000 Teases Glasgow Prestwick Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2pre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6525a9474faa46195525e8bf_pre1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="281548"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has recently teased their work on a rendition of Glasgow Prestwick Airport (EGPK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in Scotland with a yearly average of 445,211 passengers.  ‍ It was officially opened in 1935, despite operating as an airfield for longer (since the early 1910s). Passenger facilities were added in 1938 and remained untouched until the government made them compatible with jet aircraft. ‍ The RAF used Prestwick to control trans-Atlantic flights during World War 2 as a gateway for US Army personnel and a training base for RAF pilots. ‍ Its commercial duties started right after the war, with a transatlantic flight between Prestwick and New York. ‍ The main runway was expanded in 1960 from the original 2,100 meters to 3,000 meters, which is still its current length.  ‍ During the early 1990s, Prestwick was in shambles, desperately needing “rescue,” which came in the form of a takeover from a Canadian entrepreneur (Matthew Hudson), who constructed a railway station beside it, making it the first Scottish airport with its own railway station. To this day, Matthew’s rescue effort is unanimously recognized as heroic. ‍ Ryanair embraced Prestwick in 1994, with a route from Dublin and a second route a year later to London Stansted. A third one followed suit in 1998, taking passengers to Paris-Beauvais. ‍ 1998 also marks the ownership transfer from Matthew Hudson to the Stagecoach Group, a transport group based in Perth, primarily focused on buses, trams, and train services. They sold it three years later for 33 million pounds. ‍ Infratil, a Kiwi company, was the new owner from 2001 onwards, responsible for revamping the main terminal in 2005 and redecorating most of it with very controversial touches. ‍ After over a decade of ownership, Infratil decided to call it a day and pass it on to a new owner, which was no less than the Scottish government. They paid an incredible sum of 1 pound for it.  ‍ As of June 2019, the airport is up for sale.  It’s currently served by Ryanair, with flights to Alicante, Faro, Lanzarote, Málaga, and Tenerife-South. ‍ There is no information about features yet, but they have mentioned it’s releasing soon for roughly $18.41. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nuspra</id>
    <title>Nu Simulation Releases Pranoto Samarinda International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nuspra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6527056ec9df2cc1e68e7562_pranoto.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="326221"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Nu Simulation has recently released their rendition of Aji Pangeran Tumenggung Pranoto Samarinda International Airport (WALS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Samarinda and East Kalimantan in Indonesia with a yearly average of 662,000 passengers.  Opened in 2018, Sungai Siring Airport replaces the former Samarinda Airport from 1973, deemed unsuitable for the city’s future due to expansion impossibilities (lots of urban development around its surroundings, giving it no room to grow), and it was already causing issues by the early 2000s when one out of twenty-five flights experienced delays due to the lack of stands. ‍ Planning started in 1992, with construction beginning in 2005 and going through multiple delays after, which was initially scheduled for mid-2009. It only opened twelve years later, at a total cost of 400 million dollars.  ‍ It covers an area of 470 hectares, with a passenger terminal occupying 16,468 square meters of total space, featuring four jet bridges.   ‍ Expansion plans include a new passenger terminal, an additional cargo terminal, and aircraft maintenance facilities.  ‍ Batik Air, Citilink, Lion Air, Super Air Jet, Susi Air, and Wings Air serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, a terminal interior, custom runway textures, and more.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $6.35, requiring at least 143.31 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/felind</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Indira Gandhi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/felind" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65270a5f7c78e4832bf6bc89_vidp.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1181723"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Indira Gandhi International Airport (VIDP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the National Capital Region in India with a yearly average of 65 million passengers, making it the 7th busiest airport in the world. ‍ ‍ It was built as Palam Airport in the early 1960s, engineered to comport an average of 1,300 passengers per hour, which worked well enough for around 20 years, when the airport reached 30 million passengers for the first time, leading the administration to build a larger terminal in the 80s (four times larger!), inaugurated in 1986. Upon its inauguration, the airport was renamed Indira Gandhi International Airport. ‍ A third terminal was built in 2010, handling all of the international traffic, while T1 and two were shared between three budget domestic airlines. ‍ It’s a hub for Air India, Alliance Air, FedEx Express, IndiGo, Quikjet Airlines, and Vistara. The visitors’ list includes Air Arabia, Air Astana, Air Canada, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Air Mauritius, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Drukair, Egyptair, Finnair, ITA Airways, Japan Airlines, KLM, Qantas, Singapore Airlines, Swiss International Air Lines, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and Vistara. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom animated jetways, custom ground textures, improved lighting, ground clutter, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.86, requiring at least 1.19 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lisven</id>
    <title>Lisium Releases Ventspils International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lisven" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65271829814b22bbb448a74d_vent%601.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1226453"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Lisium has recently released their rendition of Ventspils International Airport (EVVA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ventspils in Latvia. ‍ It was founded in 1939 as a basic airfield, with its first major revamp in 1975, including constructing its first asphalt runway and an apron. It was served by many AN-24s, AN-2s, YAK-40s, and MI-2s, flying scheduled routes between Ventspils and either Riga or Leningrad (St. Petersburg).  ‍ The state also heavily used it for border control, pipeline control, forest patrols, traffic control, etc.  ‍ ‍ In 1983, the government decided to cease operations and close the airport, which was only reopened in the late 90s after the demand for it reached an all-time high post-Soviet Union’s collapse.   ‍ Rehabilitation work started in 1999, was completed two years later, and allowed operations to resume after many years of inactivity. Commercial operation began in 2008 for a few months and dropped immediately because of low passenger figures (less than 8,000).  ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully modeled interiors, government-provided satellite imagery, high-resolution 3D models, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.58, requiring at least 601.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftpams</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftpams" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65272eac188c9a1944919110_eham.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2687568"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has recently issued an update to their rendition of Amsterdam Airport Schiphol (EHAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a list of improvements and bug fixes.  ‍ Amsterdam’s first update adds missing fencing around the K-apron, ground texture fixes, smoothness improvements on elevated taxiways, adds a LOC model that was absent, optimizes the viewing distance of 3D lighting, and addresses runway 18R’s alignment. ‍ The scenery is available on their official website for $21.99, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install.Shout out to nxther for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfratm</id>
    <title>Got Friends Releases AviTar Series for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfratm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65274c2469e45fd170052d81_Screenshot%202023-10-11%20at%209.30.02%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2032520"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Got Friends, developers of well loved aircraft and pilot avatars, has released another foray into avatar development for Microsoft Flight Simulators, the AviTars Series for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  ‍ This release builds on their very popular freeware “Man's Best Friend” mod, and adds more advanced technology and higher detailed character models to the simulator. The models integrate with the IK Chain animation system, and work with the MSFS core, so they are able to grab and move the yoke, rudder pedals, throttles, and mixture on any aircraft that has used the animation system. Many addons are already compatible, such as the popular Comanche 250 by A2A Simulations, and many aircraft from developers like Flying Iron Simulations and Touching Cloud. The Got Friends’ AviTar Series includes three avatar packs. The first pack is a re-launch of the popular Man’s Best Friend pack, including integration with the AviTar system, and includes eight new cats, and one new dog, The next pack, dubbed “Valor” includes six warbird pilots to take out on missions. The third pack includes many of the community’s favorite Twitch streamers, including TwoToneMurphy, TheDukeNewComb, WestCoastWilly, BurstixTV, FordorLearnToFly, and OohCando. The Valor pack is a payware product, and can be acquired in the Got Friends store for $4.99 USD. The Valor and Man’s Best Friend packs are both free. The inital release will be for PC only, but Got Friends is planning on a Marketplace and XBOX release sometime in the future ‍ For more information about Got Friends’ amazing AviTar series and to get them for your sim, visit the Got Friends Store. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthtus</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Tucson International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthtus" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65286384c896130c9806f772_tus.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1482961"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Tucson International Airport (KTUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Arizona with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers. ‍ It was built in 1948, replacing the former airport (Tucson Municipal), the first municipality-owned airport in the United States (circa 1919). They used three hangars that were utilized by WW2 manufacturing companies as the base infrastructure, along with a wooden control tower from the same era.  ‍ A proper control tower was built a decade later, and commercial operations started two years prior with American, TWA, and Frontier.  ‍  A new terminal was inaugurated in 1963, with an international inspection station. It had already been operating internationally two years before, with Aeronaves de Mexico flying to Hermosillo. It was remodeled twice in the 60s and 70s.  ‍ Twenty years later, the administration expanded the main terminal from 150,000 square feet to 300,000, rebuilding the concourse into separate structures with jet bridges. Further renovation happened in 2005, adding 82,000 square feet to the terminal and renumbering the gate layout. ‍  Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR texturing, custom animated jetways, custom ground poly, improved lighting, hand-placed ground clutter, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.68, requiring at least 695.96 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inipsp</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Palm Springs International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inipsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6529bf75cd04126ce0527b35_psp.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1940922"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of Palm Springs International Airport (KPSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Palm Springs area in California with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. It was built by the US Army as an emergency landing field in 1939, later improved to serve as a staging field during World War 2. It was then sold to private buyers in 1946 and purchased by the City of Palm Springs in 1961 to become Palm Springs Municipal Airport. Airline service started with Western Airlines in the mid to late 40s, followed by Bonanza Air Lines a decade later.  Palm Springs was transformed into a dual runway airport in the 1990s and expanded with a new concourse in 1999, increasing its passenger handling capacity.  The pandemic aftermath brought record growth, thanks to the arrival of Southwest Airlines with year-round flights to Oakland, Phoenix, Denver, and Vegas (the latter started a year later).  Air Canada, Air Canada Rouge, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Flair Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet currently serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, highly detailed models, custom night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, LOD optimization, and more. It will be released next Friday (Oct 20) for roughly $18.17. Media previews will begin two days prior.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pricgh</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Releases São Paulo-Congonhas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pricgh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6529cdc7bc22a0f97c694b8a_cgh.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="254252"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Paulo Ricardo Scenery Designer has recently released their rendition of São Paulo - Deputado Freitas Nobre Airport (SBSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 18 million passengers. Although initially planned in 1919, it only opened in 1936, with a 300-meter-long dirt runway, serving as an alternate airport to Campo de Marte, São Paulo’s first airport. Commercial service began that year with a flight to Rio de Janeiro, served by VASP.  ‍ Twenty years later, Congonhas was the third busiest airport in the world for air cargo while also serving all international flights to and from São Paulo, as the runways were long enough to accommodate the aircraft from that time period, which was no longer the case in the 60s and 70s, with the advent of passenger jet aircraft, which led airlines to look for an alternative (Viracopos Airport, in Campinas). ‍ The late 50s marked the creation of the famous air shuttle between Congonhas and Rio de Janeiro (SBRJ), with regular departures every half-hour. It used to be an agreement between three airlines (VASP, Varig, and Cruzeiro do Sul), with Transbrasil joining the partnership in 1968. The deal was dissolved in 1999 after airlines decided to operate their shuttle flights independently. ‍ It was São Paulo’s main airport until 1985 when Guarulhos Airport was officially opened, and restrictions were imposed to limit CGH’s daily flights. Even with all the restrictions, Congonhas still manages to be the most popular domestic airport in the city because of its convenience (Congonhas is closer to the city’s heart).  ‍ The airport lost its international category in 2008 after multiple restrictions were imposed regarding aircraft size, landing weight, etc. The Airbus A320 and the Boeing 737-800 are the largest aircraft allowed to operate in Congonhas, while it had previously dealt with DC-8s, 767s, and A300s. Accidents such as the TAM Airlines Flight 3054 (17/07/2007) made it more restrictive. ‍ AENA has recently won a 30-year concession to operate the airport, which had been previously owned and operated by Infraero, a government-owned company. ‍ It’s currently served by Azul Brazilian Airlines, Azul Conecta, GOL Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, true-to-life landside, multiple city landmarks, a detailed terminal interior, custom ground clutter, custom weathering, and more. It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for $16.99, requiring at least 5.8 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
