<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T18:57:40.847685+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw73724</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases PMDG 737NG Sound Set for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw73724"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696ae8aceb3db727c924c883_borisng1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works has recently released their long-awaited sound set for the PMDG 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The set brings meticulously engineered sound captures from the cabin, engines, environment, and more. Recorded with state-of-the-art audio equipment from a real 737NG airplane, Boris Audio Works’ latest product promises a comprehensive audio package with a clear engine, cabin, fans, pack, ground roll, buttons, hydraulic pump sounds, and cabin chatter for extra immersion. ​ Furthermore, the package includes a headphone simulation with noise cancellation for those seeking a more realistic audio experience during their virtual journeys. ‍ The complete feature list follows below: ‍ ‍ MSFS 2024-only additions:  ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $10, requiring at least 108.38 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddradom24</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Warsaw-Radom Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddradom24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696aeeb4d221e2f6ed06f3ac_radom1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their freeware rendition of Warsaw-Radom Airport (EPRA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Radom, Poland, with an average of 112,610 passengers per year. It was built in early 1929 as a training facility for Poland’s first civilian pilot training school, and was eventually handed over to the military in 1932, which greatly expanded the facility by buying additional land and building hangars, barracks, and a shooting range. It then became a training facility for military pilots and paratroopers. As soon as World War 2 started, the base was heavily damaged by bombings, completely destroying the aircraft based there, some of the hangars, and forcing the crew to evacuate. The Germans took over the airport and used it to train and prepare their pilots for combat on the Eastern Front.  By the end of the conflict, the airport was once again heavily damaged and mined, requiring extra effort from the Polish Army to get it back into shape, which they have done rather promptly. They have been conducting pilot training sessions continuously since mid-1945. In mid-2006, Radom’s municipal administration established Port Lotniczy Radom S.A., with a hefty budget, to operate as a civilian airport. It wasn’t until the early 2010s that the necessary work was carried out to prepare the airport for such a task, though. In 2012, they bought Lodz’ airport's former terminal (disassembled) and reassembled it the following year, completing it a year later.  AirBaltic and Czech Airlines were the first to embrace the new airport with scheduled services, albeit quickly giving up after yielding suboptimal traffic numbers.  In the late 2010s, the administration decided to repurpose Radom as a low-cost airport, which initially drew strong opposition, especially given that the region already had two major airports (Modlin and Chopin).  The new terminal building was completed in 2022 and inaugurated in mid-2023. ​ It’s served by Enter Air, LOT Polish Airlines, Mavi Gök Airlines, and Wizz Air. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom 3D models, custom ground service equipment, performance-friendly optimization, an up-to-date ground layout, and much more. ​ It’s available for free on Contrail, requiring at least 2.41 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcs26r</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Outlines DCS World Roadmap for 2026 and Beyond</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcs26r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696c1b0419e861478f69cebc_In_Dev2%20(3).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has published a comprehensive set of newsletters, detailing what’s ahead for DCS World in 2026 and beyond, combining a forward-looking technical roadmap with a look back at recent campaign releases and what’s still to come. At the core of the 2026 plans is continued work on the long-awaited Dynamic Campaign, with development now heavily focused on strategic and tactical AI behaviour, ground force interactions, and the supporting user interface.  Eagle Dynamics says internal testing is already underway, across multiple maps and force compositions, with tools planned to allow players to interact with Air Tasking Orders, objectives, and mission data in far more depth than before. Another major pillar is the transition to the Vulkan API, described as being in late-stage development. The move is expected to unlock modern rendering features, such as improved frame generation support, expanded DLSS and FSR options, cockpit ray tracing, and better VRAM management.  Alongside this, further performance work, visual effects upgrades, and expanded multi-threading on the simulation side remain in progress. Beyond core engine work, Eagle Dynamics highlighted improvements to weather, explosions, and visual effects, a new navmesh system for better AI ground pathfinding, and a complete overhaul of ATC and radio communications. Mission State Save, introduced in 2025, will also continue to expand, with additional waypoint and AI behaviour data planned to be preserved between sessions. On the content side, 2026 will see continued support for existing aircraft and maps, completion of the Afghanistan and Iraq terrains, and progress on new modules, including the free Flaming Cliffs-level Su-25, alongside longer-term projects, such as the F-15C and F-35A.  The Pacific Theatre of Operations remains a major focus, with the F6F Hellcat, A6M5 Zero, a dedicated WWII Marianas map, and a large PTO assets pack, all forming the foundation for 1944-era operations. Eagle Dynamics also published an extensive campaign retrospective for 2025, highlighting a strong year for single-player content across multiple eras and aircraft, from WWII to modern combat. Looking ahead, a wide range of new training, historical, and story-driven campaigns are already in development for 2026 and beyond, as the ecosystem of third-party campaign creators continues to grow.  Further details are expected in upcoming updates. You can read Part 1 of the roadmap here, Part 2 here, and the Campaign Retrospective here.  As always, we’ll keep you updated. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asevs3</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Mt. Everest Airports Vol. 3 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asevs3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696c232ca5c920998325a3b5_XlTYwNdEyiI-HD%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has released Mt. Everest Airports Vol. 3 – Namche Bazaar to Basecamp for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, continuing its high-altitude scenery series with a focus on helicopter and specialist mountain operations. The third volume centres on the Khumbu region of Nepal, featuring a detailed recreation of Syangboche Airstrip, the highest fixed-wing airstrip in the area, and the final runway before Everest.  From there, the package shifts its attention to rotary-wing flying, adding a highly detailed Namche helipad, 18 additional helipads, and an extensively modelled Everest Base Camp area. Aerosoft has placed particular emphasis on terrain and elevation accuracy, with upgraded data for the Khumbu Glacier and Icefall, improved valley terrain, and an enhanced Mount Everest summit.  Other features include custom villages, suspension bridges, and a “living world” layer with people and animals. Mt. Everest Airports Vol. 3 is now available from the Aerosoft Store for $13.60 (excluding VAT), with an official trailer also available on YouTube. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rowb10737</id>
    <title>Rowsfire Launches B107 B737 Overhead Panel Pre-Sale </title>
    <updated>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rowb10737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696eff23c042e456b914a633_overhead1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Rowsfire has recently launched the pre-sale for their upcoming B107 Boeing 737 Overhead Panel, with an attractive discount for early pre-orderers (up to $140 off). With a mainboard crafted using SMT PCB technology, it’s built to ensure a long lifespan and overall reliability, bringing the experience of fiddling with the switches on a Boeing 737’s overhead panel to the comfort of your home.  With a 4mm-thick, scratch-resistant acrylic front panel, Rowsfire’s overhead is designed to conveniently fit on many desks and home cockpit layouts.  On the software side of things, it’s operated by MobiFlight in tandem with Rowsfire’s own app, working right out of the box with PMDG, and support is also planned for iFly, Zibo, and Laminar Research's default 738.  Furthermore, the overhead panel does not require any external power; it relies on a single USB-A cable to function. The overhead is available for pre-order on their website, starting at $559.99 (for pre-orders until Jan 25), then $599.99 (for pre-orders until Feb 1st), and finally $699.99, the original retail price. Free worldwide shipping is included. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fzaa12</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases N'djili Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fzaa12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696fa961884841b3b9911f95_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FSDG has recently released its rendition of N'djili Airport (FZAA) for X-Plane 12. The airport, located in the capital city of Kinshasa, is the largest airport in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. The airport was opened in 1959 and was initially used primarily by the airline SABENA. However, by 1960, it became a major hub for Air Congo following the independence of the Democratic Republic of Congo. The airport was a central battleground during the Second Congo War in 1998. In 2015, a new international terminal was opened, increasing the airport's capacity to accommodate one million passengers annually. Today, the airport serves a variety of airlines, including Brussels Airlines, Compagnie Africaine d’Aviation, Congo Airways, and Qatar Airways, providing connections to destinations around the world. The newly released scenery features an accurate depiction of N'djili Airport, along with detailed models, dynamic lighting, reflective textures, and much more. The newly released N'djili Airport is now available from FSDG for approximately $19.93. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/klasfs24</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Las Vegas V3 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/klasfs24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696fe92a0c4fbf74256abf17_615962126_1330058805589639_1253997061265417993_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyTampa has recently released an updated version of their Las Vegas scenery, now officially compatible with MSFS 2024. Harry Reid International Airport opened in 1943 and serves nearly 60 million passengers each year. FlyTampa's update features corrected elevation data, improvements to the Instrument Landing System, modifications to taxiways, enhanced graphics, performance updates, and updates to the city, including the addition of the Formula One circuit. The full changelog follows: ‍ The scenery is now available on FlyTampa’s website for $19.99. Owners of Las Vegas V1 can upgrade to V3 for $5.99. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsw2ws</id>
    <title>Microsoft to Attend FlightSimWeekend 2026</title>
    <updated>2026-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsw2ws"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697228f413cb7d3845505511_619202282_122492390240011805_4356232105144046158_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. With just two months to go until FlightSimWeekend 2026, the organisers have revealed that Microsoft Flight Simulator will attend the event in person for the first time. Microsoft’s presence marks a significant moment for FlightSimWeekend, with the team behind the simulator set to appear live across Saturday, 21 March and Sunday, 22 March. Attendees will be able to visit Microsoft Flight Simulator at Booth 1, where they can see the latest developments on the platform and meet members of the team. FlightSimWeekend 2026 takes place from 20–22 March 2026 at the Aviodrome Lelystad, and is expected to welcome thousands of simmers, developers, and aviation enthusiasts. Alongside Microsoft’s debut appearance, the event will once again feature a wide range of exhibitors, hands-on simulator setups, community meetups, and special evening events, including the Captain’s Dinner and Flight Sim Awards. Tickets for FlightSimWeekend 2026 are already on sale, with weekend and single-day options available. With Microsoft Flight Simulator now officially joining the exhibitor lineup, this year’s edition is shaping up to be one of the most notable in the event’s history. Threshold will also be attending the event, so if you're planning to be there, be sure to say hi! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdpkea</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases Helo Kearny Heliport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdpkea"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697425bcb983c51332c748be_kearny1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently released their rendition of Helo Keany Heliport (65NJ) for X-Plane 12, one of the largest North American heliports with almost 30 helipads. The largest vertical-lift facility on the entire East Coast is a premier FBO that bridges the gap between New Jersey’s logistics hubs and Manhattan’s skyscraper-laden skyline.  Located only two minutes away (flying time, of course) from Manhattan, it’s an ideal staging ground for corporate shuttles, news crews, and tourism operators who need immediate access to the city without the operational hurdles - and costs - of landing directly in Manhattan’s public heliports.  ZDP’s rendition recreates the area with very high fidelity, including all 29 helipads, 5 fuel pads, and a transit pad. Furthermore, it also includes a few static helicopters provided by Jetset.  It’s available for free on Threshold, requiring at least 21.41 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a340previews2</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Shares New A340-600 Previews for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a340previews2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69742ad8ed924cbcaa95f257_forty1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has shared new previews of their upcoming A340-600 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showcasing the texture work around the flight deck and a couple of external shots. Developed in conjunction with Toliss, Aerosoft’s A340-600 promises a high-fidelity rendition of the intriguing four-engine beast launched by Airbus in 1993, with a deep systems simulation, an accurate 3D model, and realistic physics.  From the next development update onwards, the developers will start hiding hints in some pictures, and five copies will be given away among everyone who finds them all (one per post). There’s still no pricing or release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidfw</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases First Trailer for MSFS 2024 Dallas Fort Worth</title>
    <updated>2026-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidfw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69769f4ac5b4443003fe3798_KDFWForumBannerScenery.png.8d6a8bfd18d00be4df924a39ebf3a277.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just released the first official trailer for its upcoming Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. iniBuilds is recreating one of the world’s busiest aviation hubs, capturing the immense scale of Dallas Fort Worth with its five terminals, complex taxiway network, elevated bridges, and surrounding infrastructure. Built natively for MSFS 2024, the scenery makes use of the latest SDK features, with a strong emphasis on performance, despite the airport’s sheer size. The newly released trailer highlights many of the airport’s defining elements, including the fully modelled and animated Skylink Air Train system, extensive apron areas, and detailed terminal architecture.  iniBuilds has confirmed a comprehensive feature set, including over 180 custom models, bespoke ground textures, up-to-date airport layout data, detailed dynamic lighting, HD jetways, accurate taxi signage, and an official GSX profile. Level of Detail optimisation has been applied across to ensure smooth performance, even during peak traffic scenarios. Scenery Features: While no release date or pricing has been announced, iniBuilds says Dallas Fort Worth is “coming soon,” with content creators and streamers expected to receive early access ahead of launch.  We’ll keep you updated. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbcol</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Coleman A. Young International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbcol"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6976e331cde507f64957bd1f_coleman1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Coleman A. Young International Airport (KDET) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Detroit, Michigan, with a yearly average of 32,850 passengers. It opened as Detroit City Airport Terminal in 1927, designed by architect Perry A. Fellows and built by W. E. Wood Co., after five years of searching for an adequate location and carrying on the necessary construction work.  Two years later, the administration built the first hangar, and it quickly rose into Detroit’s main airport at the time. It was Detroit’s main airport until 1947, when Wayne County Metropolitan Airport took over the majority of the flights. That happened in large part because Detroit City Airport couldn’t be expanded further due to a cemetery in the vicinity, which local residents did not agree to demolishing. Traffic kept on dying over the years, with airline service completely ending in 2000 and the airport’s focus shifting over to pilot training and handling private/corporate flights.  The FAA has recently approved a plan to improve the airport’s infrastructure - the first in 30 years - which should theoretically unlock more than 100 million USD in federal funds over the next decade, allowing the administration to work on a new control tower, improved taxiways, and a regulation-compliant safety zone. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-crafted custom assets, custom ground textures, PBR texturing, fully modeled interiors, custom night lighting, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $13.83, requiring at least 2.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prirecnew</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Releases Recife International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prirecnew"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697837c7ac820c8c5d187e4b_recife1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Paulo Ricardo has recently released their rendition of Recife/Guararapes—Gilberto Freyre International Airport (SBRF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Recife, Pernambuco, Brazil, with an average of 9 million passengers per year. It was built during World War 2 to replace an airfield at the same location. In the years following the conflict, it became a strategic technical and refueling stop on routes from South America to Europe. A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1958, and its two runways were extended at the time to accommodate larger aircraft. In the late 1970s, an agreement was reached with Infraero (a state-owned airport operator) to further develop the airport, leading to renovations in 1982 and expansion work in the 1990s. A new passenger terminal, including a shopping mall and a concourse, was built in 2004, increasing its passenger handling capacity from 1.5 million a year to 9 million. In late 2009, the government invested 8 million BRL into upgrading the terminal for the 2014 World Cup, adding eight more jetways and modernizing the infrastructure. It’s a hub for Azul Linhas Aéreas and is served by Gol Linhas Aéreas, LATAM Brasil, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a highly detailed passenger terminal with a partially modeled interior, city landmarks, an up-to-date ground layout, and much more. ​ It’s available in the Marketplace (2020 and 2024) for $11.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kissar24</id>
    <title>Kiss Simulation Releases Sarajevo International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kissar24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6979965e7fe095501abb745a_sara1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Kiss Simulation has recently released their updated rendition of Sarajevo International Airport (LQSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving the city of Sarajevo in Bosnia and Herzegovina, and averaging 1.3 million passengers a year. It was built in 1966 and opened for traffic three years later, although domestically. International operations began a year later, with Frankfurt as its first international destination.  The first renovation happened nearly 20 years later for the 1984 Winter Olympics, with a new terminal building, a runway extension, and navigational system improvements. The terminal was expanded in 2017, with a new 10,000-square-meter building capable of handling up to 2 million passengers a year. Its mountainous terrain and unpredictable weather have led to multiple financial losses over the years, most notably in December 2015, when over 40% of flights were canceled. The only way they could fix it would be by moving the threshold an additional 200 meters, which would shorten the runway, which is not ideal given that it’s already relatively short at 2,600 meters.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, including the new terminal extension, a custom runway profile, a real-world ILS profile, custom-made ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, runway weathering, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for $15.50, requiring at least 1.75 GB of free hard disk space. Owners of the 2020 version are entitled to a free upgrade. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mcucal</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update 13: California for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mcucal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697a6de6510e591e618372b9_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Out of the blue, Microsoft has released its latest city update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. City Update 13 significantly enhances various cities across California. This update includes improvements in 18 different urban areas, such as San Francisco, Los Angeles, San Diego, and others. The 18 different areas have been accurately recreated using TIN (triangulated irregular network) surface texturing. The updated regions allow users to explore what the Golden State has to offer. It's important to note that Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 users must manually update both World Update II and World Update X from the in-Sim Content Manager for City Update 13 to function properly. This requirement does not apply to users of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The new city update is now available for free in the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff77xp</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Updates 777 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff77xp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697a88c173625a40a6c70465_MedalTVXPlane1120260111124133509.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has released another update to their 777 series for X-Plane 12, bringing version 2.3.12 to the addon. This update follows the numerous and regular updates that FlightFactor has done on their 777 since its first release. The update does not bring any new features to the aircraft, but does fix multiple bugs. ‍ In this update, Flightfactor has updated the manual, fixed the storm light switch, fixed deicing issues, and much more. The full changelog can be viewed below. Changelog:  ‍ ‍ The FlightFactor 777v2 can be purchased on the X-Plane.org store for 89 USD. There are also various other expansions that can be purchased for the aircraft, including the engine expansion, the freighter upgrade, or a pack combining all three. ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
