<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-01-22T18:30:47.283653+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cows40</id>
    <title>COWS Previews DA-40XLS for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cows40"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6777ba733775d04f1b4677f9_IMG_0221.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS recently previewed its upcoming aircraft on their YouTube channel - the DA40-XLS. This marks the second aircraft they have developed, after the DA42. The Austrian single-engine light aircraft is one of the most popular trainer aircraft, with over 2,200 DA40s produced. Based on the also successful DA20, Diamond Aircraft Industries designed a four-seat prototype, named DA40 Diamond Star.  The COWS DA40 is based on the XLS version. Considered as a “deluxe” version, it features a G1000 glass cockpit with WAAS (Wide Area Augmentation System) capability, Garmin GDL69 datalink, and a TAS traffic alert system.  Their rendition will feature custom-designed systems with interactive circuit breakers, EIS, and custom cylinder simulation. While the price and the release date for X-Plane 12 are still undisclosed, the developers have mentioned that they are targeting the release of FS20 and FS24 in early 2025.  As always, Threshold will keep you updated with any news and updates about the COWS DA40-XLS! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/in350l</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases Liveries Launching with their A350</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/in350l"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6778e2ab7a1ff80d75622940_Skjermbilde_2025-01-03_223440.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iniBuilds has released another teaser for their upcoming A350, showcasing the liveries that will be included at launch through a video shared on their social media. The video showcases six liveries belonging to airlines from around the world: Delta, Japan Airlines, Scandinavian Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, Lufthansa, and Emirates. This is in addition to Cathay Pacific, Iberia, and British Airways, which have also been teased previously. Highly anticipated, the iniBuilds A350 aims to become the first study-level A350 in Microsoft Flight Simulator. According to iniBuilds, the aircraft will feature detailed 3D cabins, a comprehensive flight attendant panel, custom terrain radar, and intricate system simulation. It also includes Navigraph integration, SimBrief import, complex maintenance simulation, and a multitude of failures and emergency situations. ‍ The aircraft was originally scheduled for release in 2024, but its launch has been postponed to 2025 to ensure a "fantastic product at launch." Additionally, the aircraft will be available for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and 2020, despite it being initially planned as an exclusive for the 2024 version. IniBuilds cited stability issues with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 as the reason for this decision. Stay tuned to Threshold for additional updates on the iniBuilds A350, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/headwind-simulations-previews-custom-cockpit-for-airbus-a339x</id>
    <title>Headwind Simulations Previews Custom Cockpit for Airbus A339X</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/headwind-simulations-previews-custom-cockpit-for-airbus-a339x"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6778e366f5752188801a943d_Skjermbilde_2025-01-04_023619.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Freeware developer Headwind Simulations has recently showcased a preview of the upcoming custom cockpit for its A339X project, in a video posted on the AviatorCro YouTube channel. Until now, the aircraft has had a cockpit based on the FlyByWire A32NX [...] According to Headwind, the footage presented does not feature a completely new model or a full A330 cockpit; however, it represents a significant improvement in quality. Several changes are immediately apparent, with the design and geometry of the main panel standing out as the most notable. It is no longer a "hybrid" between an A320 and an A330. Additionally, a third Multi-Function Control Display Unit (MCDU) has been added, and lighting controls have been fully integrated. Some systems have also been improved, such as adding the "north reference" feature, which allows for switching navigational reference from magnetic to true north. This update is Phase 1 and will not include a redesigned overhead panel, as that will be part of Phase 2. Headwind Simulations has also indicated that Phase 2 will be released once the necessary systems are in place.  The update is scheduled for release in January 2025 and will be exclusive to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 for the time being. ‍ For additional updates on the Headwind Simulations A339X, and more, stay tuned to Threshold.  Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeda20</id>
    <title>Aerobask Releases Diamond DA20 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeda20"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/677eface2fec9895be78714f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerobask has recently launched its version of the Diamond DA20 for X-Plane 12. This small two-seat aircraft is now available for flight simulation enthusiasts looking to expand their general aviation options in the X-Plane 12 hangar. The Diamond DA20 is a Canadian-built aircraft that originated from the Austrian-built DV20. It is manufactured by Diamond Aircraft. Over 1,000 DA20s have been produced, and production is still ongoing. The DA20 serves as the predecessor to the larger Diamond DA40. This aircraft is utilized for both civilian and military purposes and is particularly popular among flight schools around the world, where it is used to train future pilots. Aerobask's version of the DA20 features a 3D cockpit, PBR textures, a flight model by X-Aerodynamics, custom dual Dynon SkyView Touch, Synthetic Vision, a full FMOD environment, windshield effects, and more. The newly released Diamond DA20 is now available at the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $34.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/akdupd</id>
    <title>AKD Studio Updates GLF550 and GLF650</title>
    <updated>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/akdupd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678034ce29020b7a799c59d2_GLF650ER_AKD%20-%202024-11-07%2021.09.37.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AKD Studios has released the first update of the year for its whole lineup. The v2.21 for GLF550 and v1.02 for GLF650 improve engine performance and MCDU, along with many bug fixes. The update introduced the new SASL (3.18.0), engine start-up times, and external light improvements for both aircraft, while the 650 received interactive window shades in the passenger cabin, as well as the option to store the RAT. The bug-fixing part brought in various fixes for the MCDU, logic improvements for TCAS, AP, and air condition temperature management. The full changelog is as follows: • Added option to stow the RAT(use option in the Menu)(XP11/XP12) - GLF650 ONLY • Added windows shades in the cabin (XP11/XP12) - GLF650 ONLY  • Mapped flight number in MCDU to x-plane dataref "sim/cockpit2/radios/actuators/flight_id"(XP12/XP11)  • Added improvements to Engines Start-UP time(XP11/XP12)  • Added improvements to external lights(XP11/XP12) • Updated SASL to 3.18.0(XP12/XP11)  Fixed:  • Fixed Map line disappears when proceeding to a waypoint with a holding pattern(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed MCDU Flight plan list page (Part of the text not visible on the screen)(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed MCDU HOLD page sometimes not working in XP11(XP11) • Fixed MCDU "Check IRS Position" msg bug(XP11/XP12)  • Improved logic for changing from IAS to MACH(XP12/XP11) • Fixed Overspeed sound and Stall warning(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed minor bugs with air-cond temperature logic(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed LAT/LONG waypoints entering(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed display of N2/N1 on EICAS(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed FMOD clicking sound bug(XP12/XP11)  • Fixed Custom TCAS logic bugs(XP11/XP12)  • Fixed Minor bugs(XP12/XP11) The update can be downloaded via the Skunkcrafts updater, or downloaded from the X-Plane.org store. The GLF business jets are available for purchase at the X-Plane.org store for $44.95. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdtro</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases Troll Airfield for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdtro"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6781d8ab03eaea950555458b_troll1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Colombian Virtual Design recently released their rendition of Troll Airfield (ENOE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which serves the homonymous Norwegian Research Station in Antarctica. Opened in 2005, the airfield was purpose-built to serve as the center of the Dronning Maud Land Air Network (DROMLAN), which is essentially a multinational cooperation using Troll as a hub to provide intercontinental service to Antarctica, supporting up to long-range planes such as the 767. With a 3,000-meter-long ice runway and no infrastructure, it can only operate under visual flight rules. The airport itself doesn’t have any buildings or structures, and the research station provides all services, including ground handling. ‍ They follow strict safety protocols to prevent damage to the Antarctic soil. These protocols include storing all fuel in large barrels or tanks placed on special absorbent mats, and there’s a plethora of equipment to handle any potential spillage disaster. It’s served by Hi Fly, Icelandair, Norse Atlantic, Royal Air Force, Smartwings, and PrivatAir on a chartered basis. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airfield, sporting a highly detailed modeling of the research station, true-to-life landmarks, ground clutter, and much more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.73, requiring at least 61.84 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bornor</id>
    <title>Borgillios Scenery Releases Norrköping Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bornor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6781dc88da0536d7773933d9_norr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Borgillios Scenery recently released their rendition of Norrköping Airport (ESSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves Norrköping and has a yearly average of 103,298 passengers.  Founded in 1934, Norrköping is Sweden's oldest commercial travel airport. Although mostly commercial throughout its history, the Swedish Air Forces briefly used it during World War 2.  The airport's traffic peaked in the 1980s, followed by a significant decline shortly afterward due to the rise of high-speed rail connections and the development of larger commercial airports.  Despite the challenges, efforts have been made to revitalize the airport and attract new airlines and routes. The airport's location in a strategically important region and its history and infrastructure offer potential for future growth and development. Nowadays, the airport only gets seasonal charter traffic from Braathens International Airways, Pegasus Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, high-detail buildings (terminal, hangars, etc), and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $10.30, requiring at least 166.64 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmltbj</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Teases Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmltbj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6782dd3880656284ae181f69_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently teased its next project, likely for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, based on the teaser. The team is travelling to Turkey, specifically to the city of Izmir. It appears that Izmir Adnan Menderes Airport (LTBJ) will be the next scenery developed by MM Simulations. Izmir is a popular holiday destination in Turkey, renowned for its beautiful coastal views. It attracts numerous vacationers from across Europe. Each year, Izmir Airport handles over 10.5 million passengers and serves a wide range of destinations, including scheduled, seasonal, and charter flights. ‍ Details regarding the release date, features, and pricing have yet to be announced, but we will keep you updated as soon as this information becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrpns</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases Sayak Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrpns"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67863c34bfe29fd5a5b0a5d6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airwil Sceneries has just released its rendition of Sayak Airport (RPNS) for both X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Located on Siargao Island in the Philippines, the airport is also referred to as Siargao Airport. Originally built in 1963 under former President Diosdado Macapagal, the airport was designed to accommodate small 19-seater planes. However, significant changes occurred in 2008 when the airport underwent renovations as part of a program aimed at boosting economic activity. Following these improvements, the airport could handle larger aircraft capable of carrying over 70 passengers. Further modernization and expansion took place in 2013. Today, airlines such as Cebgo, PAL Express, and Sunlight Air operate flights to destinations including Cebu, Clark, Davao, and Manila. The newly released rendition of Sayak Airport is rich in features, offering a realistic representation of the airport, including a detailed passenger terminal, a modelled control tower, and more. The scenery requires 1.27 GB of storage space and is now available at SimMarket for approximately $6.15. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xskttn</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Trenton-Mercer Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xskttn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67868dd52f5e0ed382d2481d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. XWind Studios has recently launched its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024: Trenton-Mercer Airport (KTTN). Located in Trenton, the capital city of New Jersey, this airport is a hub for Frontier Airlines, serving approximately 600,000 passengers annually. Trenton-Mercer Airport's history dates back to 1907 when the first airplane landed on Alfred Reeder's field in Ewing. Skillman Airport opened to the public in 1929. During World War II, the local General Motors plant transitioned to manufacturing torpedo bombers, leading to airport expansions to accommodate test flights for these aircraft. The airport was later renamed Mercer County Airport and eventually became Trenton-Mercer Airport in 1995, linking it to the city of Trenton. In 1998, the airport replaced human weather observers with an automated weather system. Although the county plans to replace the old terminal, residents have opposed this idea. Today, Frontier Airlines is the only airline operating at the airport, offering flights to destinations such as Atlanta, Orlando, Tampa, Fort Myers, and West Palm Beach. The newly released scenery hosts a range of features, including high-quality, optimized textures, detailed terminal interior designs, custom taxiway signage, comprehensive imagery of the entire airport, and much more. The scenery requires 3.95 GB of storage space and is available on the iniBuilds Store for $10.38. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jlgrp4</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Rhodes International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jlgrp4"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67869650a2fb9d490056cc95_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. JustSim has released its first scenery fully adapted for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, revisiting a previous destination: Rhodes International Airport (LGRP). Rhodes is a popular summer destination in the Greek Islands, attracting over six million passengers annually. Civil aviation on the island began after World War II with the opening of Rhodes Maritsa Airport, which served as the main airport until Rhodes International Airport, also known as Diagoras International Airport, was inaugurated in 1977. Over the years, the airport has seen improvements, including expanded taxiways and a new passenger terminal that opened in 2005. In 2015, the airport was privatized and is now managed by Fraport AG/Copelouzos Group for a period of 40 years. Today, Rhodes International Airport hosts numerous airlines offering scheduled, seasonal, and charter flights to various destinations across Europe. According to JustFlight, the new scenery features high-resolution ground textures, high-resolution building textures, highly detailed 3D models, custom animated ground vehicles, and much more. The scenery requires 1.66 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $17.28. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ed2025</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Posts DCS 2025 and Beyond Video</title>
    <updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ed2025"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678a9159a7f32bf69bada631_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has unveiled its DCS 2025 and Beyond video, marking the start of the year for the team. This annual preview highlights new features and add-ons that will enhance the DCS experience. Viewers can expect an in-depth look at upcoming innovations for the flight simulation platform. The video begins by introducing Dynamic Campaigns, a feature that has been highly requested by the community for some time. For the first time since its announcement in last year's video, footage of the upcoming MiG-29A is shown in-game. Additionally, the Eurofighter Typhoon Tranche 1 and 2 are showcased after being absent for two years. Throughout the video, there are glimpses of Berlin, hinting at a potential new map, likely set in Germany. Other teasers include enhanced ground assets, a new variant of the Mirage F1M, the C-130 from Airplane Simulation Company, the Sparrowhawk HUD for both the F-14A and F-14B, and the F-100 Super Sabre. The video suggests that there is a wealth of exciting upcoming content to look forward to. At the video's conclusion, developers announced two exciting new aircraft for DCS. Development will begin in 2025 for a full-fidelity F-15C, an agile air superiority fighter, and an F-35A, a stealthy multirole fighter. Both are expected to be released in 2026. Once more information about any of the teasers is available, we will make sure to let you know. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl292</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates Airbus A321Ceo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl292"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de4adcd06a5053536bb2_labsup3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs has released another update to their newly released Airbus A321Ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. This update brings a realistic implementation of the Rockwell Collins WXR-2100 system (weather radar) and a series of fixes and improvements. Update v11.0.1.292—the fourth since its release—highlights the weather radar implementation. It seamlessly integrates the powerful Rockwell Collins suite, which has been meticulously designed to interact with the live weather environment in MSFS and produce accurate radar returns. They have also expanded their hardware integration, adding compatibility with WinWing, MiniCockpit, WingFlex, and more.  Besides the weather radar and new hardware integration, the update also brings numerous bug fixes, improvements based on user feedback, performance improvements, and an overall more stable system behavior. The highlights follow below: ‍ AOC ‍ Display and Cockpit Updates: ‍ Electrical and Power Systems: ‍ Flight Control Logic and Sensors: ‍ Flight Deck and Hardware Integration: ‍ ‍ FMGC: ‍ Flight Warning and Control: ‍ ‍ Navigation and Radios: ‍ ‍ Performance and Calculations: ‍ ‍ Sounds: ‍ Techlog: ‍ Weather Radar: ‍ The add-on is available on their website for $69.95. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simgmz</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Guardia Marina Zañartu Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simgmz"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678bc9aad9d514fbfc2b3dd7_zanartu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Simulación Extrema has recently released its rendition of Guardia Marina Zañartu Airport (SCGZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which serves Puerto Williams on Navarino Island, Chile. It was inaugurated in 1957 by President Carlos Ibáñez del Campo and named after a local naval aviation pilot, Guillermo Zañartu Irigoyen. It's the world's southernmost airport with scheduled flights, solidifying its history in aviation. ‍ It connects Navarino Island to Chile and the rest of the world, providing a vital link to an otherwise isolated region. Aerovías DAP serves it with scheduled flights to Punta Arenas and Santiago del Chile. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled passenger terminal, custom ground textures, custom ground clutter, and more.  It's available in the MSFS Marketplace for $11.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/psgmff</id>
    <title>PerfectSoft Studio Releases Fès-Saïss Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/psgmff"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678c2e986aa799876bcc8f50_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PerfectSoft Studio has released its rendition of Fès–Saïss Airport (GMFF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Located in Morocco, it serves the city of Fez and connects various destinations across Europe, welcoming approximately 1.4 million passengers annually. Fès–Saïss Airport is one of the busiest airports in Morocco. It aims to connect the region to Europe, a goal it has successfully achieved with a steady increase in flights. The airport reached the milestone of welcoming over one million passengers annually back in 2017. Operated by the Moroccan Airports Authority, it features a runway that is 10,500 feet long, capable of accommodating a variety of aircraft. The airport serves airlines such as Air Arabia and Ryanair, offering destinations like Amsterdam, Barcelona, Brussels, and many more. The newly released scenery features realistic modelling, PBR texturing, 4K textures, high-detail 3D models, and hand-placed vegetation, among other features. The scenery is available for around $15.41 on the SimMarket. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd118</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd118"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678c68106aa799876b0f315e_1250410_20240201232908_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published their first development update of the year, which includes further information on the progress of porting their current product line over to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, their upcoming 777-200ER, and more. They are still waiting for Asobo to address specific issues with MSFS 2024 that seem to be blocking the conversion for the time being (memory allocation issues, instability, etc). They have forwarded their findings to the development team and hope these fixes will be made available by SU1.  While they hope that SU1 will allow them to work with MSFS 2024, they are not entirely optimistic yet: “In our experience, there is still downside risk that getting these two fixes rolled into the platform might simply move us forward a few spots, so that we can crack our shins on the next obstacle,” explained Randazzo. The plans for product line compatibility remain similar, with the DC-6 being made compatible yet not bringing any new features per se, the triple sevens eventually making their way into the new platform, and the 737 is undergoing a major overhaul with new sim features such as walkaround, career mode features, upgraded textures, new models, a brand new cabin with a working cockpit door, enhanced gameplay features and interactivity within the cabin environment, and new sounds.  The 737 will also receive an update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which aims to fix the spinning logo bug on the Universal Flight Tablet. Their upcoming 777-200ER is entering beta testing, and PMDG plans to release it for MSFS 2020 and 2024 (like the 777F). Due to the existing workload, no new features are planned for the product. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
