<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-01-06T18:21:15.034010+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gkfa</id>
    <title>Golden Key Studio Releases F-111 Ardvark For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gkfa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65874afa4e4124d02bf27138_chrome_MD6qQXfE8R.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Golden Key Studio (also known as GKS) have released their rendition of the F-111E Ardvark for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The release comes just days after the most recent update on the project’s development.  Originally developed by General Dynamics in the early 60's, the F-111E, nicknamed the Aardvark, was a pioneer for the development of features that would become a staple of modern combat aircraft. The Ardvark was the first production aircraft to feature variable-sweep wings. The platform also played a pivotal role in the design of modern after-burning engines. The Aardvark first entered service with the USAF in 1967, and the Australian government later purchased the E variant of the F-111. While the RAAF only ever deployed their F-111s as a deterrent, the USAF flew over 4000 combat missions in both the Vietnam and Gulf Wars. The USAF retired their F-111s in 1996 while the RAAF had theirs in active service until 2010.  ‍GKS promises users of the F-111 will experience an authentic flight model with impressive graphics and a highly detailed cockpit featuring accurate aircraft systems. GKS has kept the development of the Ardvark pretty quiet overall, and while there isn’t a ton of information available on their latest offering it is expected that it will be up to the same standard as their MiG-21.  For more flight simulation updates be sure to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini350</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini350"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65911ed7cd9c0ce21ec663c5_image.png.051e0ac6d66aa7250bd9ccaff8484286.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer iniBuilds have announced their next major project, the Airbus A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The unveiling, released as part of iniBuild’s 2024 roadmap, comes as a surprise for the community and adds to the developer’s lineup of upcoming aircraft that includes the A380 and the A300-600R. ‍ According to iniBuilds, the team has already been working hard on the A350 over the past few months and, as shown in the WIP previews provided, has completed a great part of the plane’s exterior modeling. The finished product is expected to feature both the -900 (2 winglet options) and the -1000 variants.  In addition, iniBuilds is currently looking for individuals such as pilots and engineers who have experience working with the A350 in effort to improve the realism of the final product. ‍ Currently, the iniBuilds is forecasting a release date sometime in 2024, though a specific date is yet to be announced. Threshold will keep you updated on the progress of the A350, including its features, pricing, etc.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfmt</id>
    <title>Got Friends Releases Freeware Mozzie Mk III</title>
    <updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfmt"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6587b774045c2647b0ef9bc8_MOZZIE_2_1800x1800.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Got Friends, who you’ll know from their F4F Wildcat and Double Ender project, have released a new freeware helicopter for Microsoft Flight Simulator with a purpose.  Got Friends has developed the Mozzie Mk III as a way to help fundraise to help the father of one of their developers who needed emergency brain surgery to save his vision, you can read more about the situation on the family’s gofundme page. As of writing the freeware project has raised over $350 through the gotfriends website with others donating directly to the gofundme.  The Mozzie Mk III is a single-seat ultralight helicopter with an open cockpit. Powered by a V-twin motorcycle engine the Mozzie is designed as a conventional tail rotor helicopter and as such is capable of autorotations. Overall the Mozzie is a very easy helicopter to fly and the perfect introduction for anyone wanting to learn how to fly them in the sim. You can download the Mozzie and donate directly to the gofundme through the Got Friends website.  On behalf of the writers and staff at Threshold, I’d like to wish Scott a quick and easy recovery, our thoughts are with the entire Yaeger family this holiday season.  </summary>
    <published>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmp777</id>
    <title>PMDG Previews Upcoming 777 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmp777"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658a0b264e4124d02b1cff0e_t7.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published another development update with further information on their upcoming Boeing 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with four new screenshots showcasing its external model.  Randazzo strongly emphasizes the modeling work placed on the triple seven, with accurate color distortions according to the viewing angle, visible and detailed rivets, and surface irregularities around the joints of the radome and the forward gear doors.  ‍  The tail area also brings great detail, with visibly different looks between the surfaces made of carbon fiber and aluminum.  ‍  They also report their upcoming product performs almost the same as their 737 lineup, meaning it won’t be particularly demanding despite the alleged 3D model improvements.   The fly-by-wire simulation, with its control laws and inherent oddities, is said to be accurately represented. Failures will be a possibility, too.  It’s still undergoing beta testing, with more than 200 reports so far during the first phase of testing, half of which were already fixed, according to Randazzo.   More previews will be shared with the community in the days and weeks ahead, and they seem “happy with the pace and character of the testing they have been doing thus far.”  There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fswl35</id>
    <title>Flysimware Learjet 35A for MSFS Releases for Early Access</title>
    <updated>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fswl35"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658d98d750a91e0a7c257086_sV2UWfE.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flysimware has released their Learjet 35A into early access. The Learjet 35A, which was previously available in P3D, has been updated to take use of new features found in MSFS. According to Flysimware users of the older FSX/P3D version will notice this product to be more accurate with a steep learning curve to understand the compex systems of the aircraft.  The Learjet 35 first flew in 1971 ands started production in 1973, with the upgraded Learjet 35A starting production in 1975. The learjet 35 is a light business jet that can carry about 8 passengers. The learjet 35A is an upgraded version of the airplane with more powerful TFE731-2-2B engines and upgraded avionics. The 35A also supported wing-tip fuel tanks that extended the range of the aircraft to around 2,700 Nm.  The Flysimware Learjet 35A is currently in early access, with no manuals or tutorials included at this time. Flysimware stated that the product is flight worthy, however a discord is available to discuss systems and aircraft bugs, updates will be available to address bugs before the final release. The FSW Learjet 35A currently supports the Asobo Garmin 530 as well as both the PMS/TDS GTN 750.  To join this early access period for the Flysimware Learjet 35A, head over to the Flysimware Store. The cost to join the early access is $39.99 USD and will include an update to the final release when available. For more information about the product, see the Flysimware Discord.  </summary>
    <published>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniuae</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniuae"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658e3c811516bf3a35353721_inia300.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of the Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the modern and longer version of the classic A300, certified in 1984 and still operating today for many cargo airlines and a few passenger airlines.  The Airbus A300-600 is an extended version of the A300B2 and B4, with two additional rows of seats, powered by two General Electric CF6-80C2 engines, and making use of the A310 cockpit, with no need for a flight engineer like the older A300s. 313 A300-600s were sold between its inception and 2007, when production stopped.  The add-on features authentic systems, a custom FMS, custom VNAV and LNAV, custom hydraulic, pressurization, electric, and fuel systems, a maintenance system with cautions and warnings triggered by ignoring it, realistic RNAV, and autoland capability. The flight model is tuned to represent the aircraft’s behavior and intricacies accurately.  The textures are PBR and up to 8K quality, with lower texture packs available for lower-end systems. The cockpit and external models for the passenger and cargo variants were entirely reworked.  The sound environment is fully tridimensional, using real recordings of the engine and cabin switches.   Additional features include an Electronic Flight Bag, a basic ground handling set, and pre-set cargo loads with visual models.  It’s important to note that the PW engine variant and CPDLC/ACARS will be available later.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.55, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniu36</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniu36"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658e3ce4907680bdcf3367a3_inia3003.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated their newly released Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing various issues ranging from VNAV tweaks to CTD mitigations.   Version 1.0.1, the first patch for the A300 so far, brings a substantial list of fixes and improvements to their brand-new release for MSFS. The changelog follows below:   The airplane is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.55, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sayinai</id>
    <title>SayIntentions.AI Receives Launch Date and Updates on Pricing</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sayinai"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65902e79129400a37b98b792_Untitled-1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Several months ago, we covered a potentially game-changing AI Air Traffic Control (ATC) system activated and controlled using your voice. SayIntentions.AI enables users to employ natural language and phraseology commonly used in real-world aviation communications. The primary goal is to provide users with a lifelike, interactive communication experience, making SayIntentions.AI ideal for those new to learning aviation radio communications. The team behind SayIntentions.AI, (formerly known as SmartSky.AI) plans to launch the product on January 15th, 2024. Their vision is to "create something that is not only comprehensive but also undeniably more enjoyable to use than flying solo," while addressing the challenge of making live ATC less intimidating. ‍ Since the initial announcement, the team has made significant progress. SayIntentions.AI can now support Class B, C, and D airspaces, providing services such as flight following, radar services, traffic advisories, closed traffic pattern work, Air Traffic Services (ATS), Terminal Radar Approach Control (TRACON), Air Route Traffic Control Center (ARTCC), Visual Flight Rules (VFR) transitions, routes, and flight plans for every airport in the United States. Sayintentions.AI works with both X-Plane and Microsoft Flight Simulator with flexibility across both sim platforms. ‍ Additional features include custom voices for specific airports, and controllers will possess their own personalities, adding uniqueness to certain areas. The team outlined various procedures in a Reddit post, including noise abatement procedures and guided directions to specific landmarks as well. ‍ SayIntentions.AI also includes a student pilot mode designed for learning the ropes, with more patient controllers allowing users to ask questions, prompting ATC to provide assistance. The team is fine-tuning the last five percent to achieve the perfect finished state. Pricing details are still in progress, set with a subscription-based service at a monthly rate of possibly $15-20. A trial version will be available around the Lake Tahoe Reno, Nevada area, allowing users to "try before you buy."To learn more about SayIntentions.AI see the Reddit post, website, SayIntention.AI's Discord and check out the demo YouTube video below. You can also sign up for the wait list via SayIntention.AI's website! ‍ ‍ Of course stay tuned to Threshold for more news and updates on SayIntentions.AI!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxbl2</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Previews Upcoming A320 Block 2 Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxbl2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6592d24222a5204134d84e6d_iaewen1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has broken the silence on New Year's Eve about their long-awaited Block 2 update for their A320 add-on, showcasing the IAE engines, cockpit improvements, new night lighting, and some of the new features that will be part of the update. They have worked around most of the issues they ran through during the development phase, with only weeks separating it from an official release after an eleven-week delay concerning the predicted initial release date.  The new cockpit shows a new - thinner - center window pillar, side windows, and new configuration options, such as the absence of DCDUs, which is typical in North and South America. They have entirely remapped the cockpit textures, cutting the memory footprint in half. Externally, new wings, wingtips, nose, and landing gear are expected, along with a new soft-body physics system for the tires, showing actual compression that will vary with the aircraft's weight.  Physics-driven weathering will also be present in Block 2, with an accurate simulation of the dirt accumulation around the engine and its surroundings.  ‍ The already showcased shadow-casting lights make a return in today's update, showing how it looks with the new V2500s and the many improvements made to the night environment experience inside the cockpit. A deep dive into the new systems and simulation aspects is coming soon.  There's no release date available for the update yet. Threshold will keep you informed on the matter!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da42vi</id>
    <title>COWS shows off the upcoming DA42-VI for MSFS and X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da42vi"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6592f5aa9a3b5154f6bba82f_BANN.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. COWS, the development team responsible for the upcoming DA42 aircraft in Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12, has recently unveiled a teaser, showcasing their latest project. The trailer provides a glimpse into the noteworthy visual features that COWS has meticulously focused on. COWS is aiming to deliver the most accurate DA42 TDi experience for both flight simulators. According to the team, the COWS DA42 promises the ultimate multi-engine experience through its emphasis on precise flight modeling, detailed systems modeling, and the implementation of an in-house COWS NXi COWS G1000 replica. This replica will boast numerous screen configurations and menu operations, complemented by the inclusion of RAIM prediction. The detailed operational experience has been carefully crafted to cater specifically to students, offering a platform to practice critical procedures and maneuvers. The entire project is built by the hands of DA42 pilots and student pilots to ensure accuracy in both Microsoft Flight Simulator/FS2024 and XP12. Originating from the late 1990s brainstorming sessions, the DA42 has undergone numerous iterations during its 24-year production span. The latest iteration, the DA42-VI, has gained popularity among consumers as a luxurious four-seater featuring modern construction, materials, and cutting-edge avionics. Additionally, the DA42 has made significant inroads into the flight training market, serving as a robust twin-engine trainer utilized globally to prepare pilots for complex multi-engine aircraft types.Renowned for its efficiency, the DA42 offers unique engine options, such as aerodiesels co-designed with Mercedes-Benz and Austro Engine GmbH. The Austro diesels contribute to a remarkable 46% improvement in fuel efficiency compared to the gasoline models. COWS is currently putting the finishing touches on the project, indicating an imminent release within the next few weeks. While no details regarding pricing or specific vendors have been disclosed at this point, anticipate the release of such information as the project approaches a confirmed launch date. Keep an eye on Threshold for additional updates regarding the release of the COWS DA42-VI!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/para42</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases a free new utility for Microsoft Flight Simulator.</title>
    <updated>2024-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/para42"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6595adc63c4cf7f2e3a204ea_Main.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently released Simstaller for FS2020. The software is designed to detect add-on conflicts and installation issues related to the complexity of installing modifications to the simulation. It is a lightweight standalone application that runs in the background of Windows. Initially, Parallel 42 planned to offer the utility as a payware product but later realized that it was a must-have for users who download from community sites like flightsim.to.   The Virtual File System (VFS) scans and detects issues, alerting you to packages that override critical core operations or unintended game modifications. With Simstaller, you can identify who or what is overriding the functions of the simulation. Simstaller provides welcome relief for individuals fatigued by the constant need to troubleshoot errors and pinpoint the root causes of issues within Microsoft Flight Simulator's community folder. ‍The Parallel 42 Simstaller app is available free on parallel42.com. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hcar</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Cartagena Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hcar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65972ccc02552f718f5db512_cartagena.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Rafael Núñez International Airport (SKCG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Cartagena, Colombia, with a yearly average of 7.2 million passengers.  It was built in 1946 as Crespo Air Field, with TACA Colombia being the first airline to serve the city, albeit very briefly, as they went under a year later, with LANSA taking the remaining slots.  By 1979, the airport averaged around 99 flights a week, which was not enough in terms of touristic volume for the local hotels, leading to pressure for an airport redevelopment in 1982: a new passenger terminal and a runway extension, allowing for bigger aircraft. It is now the fourth busiest airport in the country.  It’s a hub for Avianca and served by Air Century, American Airlines, Arajet, Avianca Costa Rica, Clic, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Edelweiss Air, JetBlue, KLM, Latam Colombia, Latam Peru, Spirit, Wingo.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, high-detail buildings, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.37, requiring at least 1.21 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kissar</id>
    <title>Kiss Simulation Releases Sarajevo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kissar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659731c1f041642de77632a0_sara.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Kiss Simulation has recently released their rendition of Sarajevo International Airport (LQSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Sarajevo in Bosnia and Herzegovina with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers.  It was built in 1966 and opened for traffic three years later, although domestically. International operations only started a year later, with Frankfurt being its first international destination.   The first renovation happened nearly 20 years later for the 1984 Winter Olympics, with a new terminal building, a runway extension, and navigational system improvements.  The terminal was expanded in 2017, with a new 10,000-square-meter building able to handle up to 2 million passengers a year.  Its mountainous terrain and unpredictable weather have led to multiple financial losses over the years, with the most memorable one dating back to December 2015, when over 40% of the flights were canceled. The only way they could fix it would be by moving the threshold an additional 200 meters, which would shorten the runway, which is not ideal given that it’s already relatively short at 2,600 meters.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with the new terminal extension, custom runway profile, real-world ILS profile, custom-made ground textures, up-to-date ground layout, runway weathering, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.18, requiring at least 792.15 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini102</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini102"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659886bafbae95c3795e4091_a300update.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a substantial list of fixes and changes to the flight model, systems, sounds, and more.  Update v1.0.2, the second A300 update and the biggest so far, brings a massive changelog encompassing a multitude of fixes and improvements. The changelog follows below:   The add-on is available on the iniManager Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cph100</id>
    <title>Cockspur Releases PH100 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cph100"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6581875cba258cbc09117127_411476662_346824141428470_4464571675854412464_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur has announced the release of their PH100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Known for their light business jets and general aviation aircraft in MSFS, Cockspur has now unveiled the PH100, an rendition of the Embraer Phenom 100. Their recent release of the Cessna Citation Mustang garnered popularity from the Microsoft Flight Simulator community, and anticipation for the PH100 has been building steadily. This project started as a side endeavor right after the Mustang release but was kept under wraps until an intriguing teaser trailer was unveiled in early December 2022. Recent beta testing, marked by live streams offering glimpses of the development progress and features, has further stoked the excitement. The PH100 has become one of the most eagerly awaited aircraft in the MSFS community, with Cockspur teasing its release date via their Facebook page just this week. In the real world, the Embraer Phenom 100 is a significant player in the corporate jet market. Manufactured by the renowned Brazilian aircraft manufacturer Embraer, the Phenom 100 is classified as a VLJ (Very Light Jet), with its larger sibling being the 300E. The Phenom 100 made its maiden flight on July 26, 2008, and has since achieved immense success, becoming one of the most popular light jets on the market. A new configuration of the Phenom will set you back approximately $3 million, and with over 400 units produced, it boasts a strong presence in the aviation world. Cockspur has recreated this popular aircraft within Microsoft Flight Simulator, offering a plethora of features that faithfully replicate its real-world counterpart. These features include Garmin G1000NXi avionics with a custom FADEC system, meticulously replicated switches, and authentic functionality to provide a true-to-life piloting experience. Dynamic systems bring the experience of managing and operating the Phenom's unique systems, closely mirroring the real-world aircraft. Flight dynamics have been finely tuned based on feedback from actual Phenom pilots, enhancing the overall immersion of flying the PH100. The visual modeling is equally impressive, with accurate 3D modeling, animations, and texturing that add to the overall authenticity. The PH100 package includes 11 liveries, with support for FS2020's dynamic registration system. Additionally, a paint kit is included, allowing users to create their custom liveries or recreate their favorite designs. To ensure a smooth download experience, Cockspur recommends using a download manager, especially during high server loads. Additionally, they suggest utilizing the recently released Simstaller by Parallel 42 (//42). The PH100 is available for purchase through the Cockspur store, priced at 26.99 € / 29.48 $. To find out more information regarding the release and features see the product page here. For support and further information on the PH100 visit Cockspur's Discord or Facebook.  ‍ As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!  </summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skylab</id>
    <title>VSKYLABS Aerospace Simulations Releases Robinson R44 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skylab"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6598a0fc6bfd855983d32fa9_vskylabs-r44-v3.0-011.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VSKYLABS Aerospace Simulations, well-known for introducing unique niche aircraft to the X-Plane flight simulator, has recently launched the release of their Robinson R44 Raven II project. This release follows VSKYLABS' previous introduction of the iconic SR-71, a supersonic spy plane from the Cold War era. Showing an continuing commitment to delivering iconic aircraft, the VSKYLABS team has updated the R44 in a significant release, aligning it with compatibility for the latest version of Laminar Research's  X-Plane 12.0.08, complete with refined flight dynamics and more.R44, a four-seat rotor-wing aircraft made by Robinson Aircraft in Torrance, California, evolved from earlier models like the R22, boasting a larger cabin and improved performance. With over 5,000 deliveries, it's one of the best-selling GA helicopters, finding use in various applications from sightseeing to government operations. Over the past several weeks, the team has diligently worked on various aspects of the update. Their primary focus has encompassed deep-tuning the drive train simulation, enhancing aircraft performance and handling qualities, and improving auto rotation and landing skid dynamics, all while enhancing engine power gradient accuracies. This substantial update also introduces graphical improvements, including an all-encompassing PBR setup to align with X-Plane 12's rendering engine. Additional default liveries were also added to the package for more variety. Furthermore, the update addresses sound by converting FMOD sound packs to v2.0x and introducing physics-based blade angle slap sounds. This update is available to existing customers of the VSKYLAB R44 package through the auto-updater. VSKYLABS recommends downloading the store build package to "bridge the gap between the user-end progressive version and the base build version." You can access the complete update log and purchase the Robinson Raven on the VSKYLABS website at www.vskylabs.com. The project is also accessible via the x-plane.org store website. As usual, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
