<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-12-06T18:22:57.791093+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflana</id>
    <title>AirfoilLabs Releases C172 NG Analog for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflana" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569cdc493dc44bf355019da_ana1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="411196"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AirfoilLabs has recently released their rendition of the Cessna C172 NG Analog for X-Plane 12, one of the most popular trainer aircraft ever produced, with 44,000 units built since its introduction in 1956.  The Cessna 172 stands as an iconic figure in aviation, often serving as the initial aircraft for many aspiring pilots. Equipped with a 175hp piston engine operating at 2400rpm, it maintains a cruising speed of 125 knots and can ascend to a maximum altitude of 13,000 feet.  AFL’s new C172 features a new 3D model built from scratch, using X-Plane 12’s brand-new flight model to provide a realistic simulation experience. The engine performance was tuned and correlated with performance tables, warranting accurate behavior under different circumstances and weather. The complete feature list follows below: New X-Plane 12 Features: 3D Model FMOD Sound Flight Model Aircraft Systems Electrical System Engine Logic Failure Management System and Scenarios Saving C172 Knowledge Base User Interface and 2D Panels Aircraft Options Checklist and Performance Ground Operations Walk Feature and QuickLook Camera with Collisions   It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $49.95 (temporary discount). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwarl</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Arlington Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwarl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569d17f4abb95f11cc0f49e_arl1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="637406"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Arlington Municipal Airport (KGKY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Arlington, Texas, with a yearly average of 151,000 passengers (as of 2006).  It’s a reliever airport for DFW and DAL and housing companies such as the Bell Helicopter division of Textron.   Unlike most US airports, KGKY doesn’t have an IATA code.  97% of the airport’s yearly operations consist of general aviation traffic, with only 3% corresponding to air taxi.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled terminal building, custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures, custom night lighting, and animated people.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.53 and requires at least 1.10 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Cristian Ionescu for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phenom</id>
    <title>Cockspur reveals their next project, the Phenom 100</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phenom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569fc0ad20d9edb4524fa12_image_2023-12-01_093018018.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1024570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur has recently published a new video on Facebook and Discord, showcasing what appears to be an almost finished Embraer Phenom 100. Cockspur is renowned for its Cessna Mustang and its latest Cessna 162. The one-and-a-half-minute video provides a quick look at the intricate details that Cockspur is known for—the avionics in the video feature the GARMIN 1000, similar to those present in the real aircraft. The video also showcases the exterior details, which look intricate based on the close-up shots. The cabin is fully modeled, as expected. Although the developer has yet to release much information regarding specific features, we can expect to receive more details on this project soon. The Embraer Phenom 100 is a part of the Phenom corporate jet brand, manufactured by Brazilian aircraft manufacturer Embraer. The Phenom 100, the smallest model in the range, is classified as a VLJ (Very Light Jet), with the larger model being the 300E. Phenom 100's first flight took place on July 26, 2008, and since then, it has brought Embraer immense success with the Phenom brand. A new configuration of the Phenom will cost you around $3 million. With over 400 built, it is one of the most popular light jets in the market. The Phenom is powered by two Prat and Whitney turbofan engines, producing 1,750lbs of thrust each. This engine configuration gives the Phenom 100 the ability to cruise at 400 knots with a maximum altitude of 14,100 feet with a range of about 1,300 NM. The Phenom has a single pilot rating thanks to many of its automated features. With its Prodigy Touch flight deck and Garmin 1000, these systems are highly streamlined to reduce pilot workload. The Phenom's BMW-designed cabin can comfortably carry up to five passengers. To see more, check out the video of the Phenom by Cockspur here. ‍ As always, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f14tom</id>
    <title>Heatblur and IndiaFoxtEcho provides F14 pricing and potential release date.</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f14tom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656a06ee7a31e43cb4e38e1d_339315414_586097866798612_8442083217038018754_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="261332"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Heatblur and IndiaFoxtEcho have provided a potential release date for the F-14 Tomcat! The much-anticipated F-14 Tomcat project update was communicated to users via the Heatblur and IndiaFoxtEcho Discord. IndiaFoxtEcho also gave a preview of the Jester toggle wheel function, which allows you to control different elements and features of the F14, departing from the usual "Tablets" seen in various other aircraft addons. According to IndiaFoxtEcho, the F-14 will be available on the Flight Simulator Marketplace (unarmed), the Heatblur store, SimMarket, Orbx, and more. The team is in its final stages, waiting for the green light from Microsoft. The wait is on for the Xbox version tests to complete, and it will likely be released alongside the PC version, which will be identical except for the radar functionality on Xbox.  The pricing and a possible release date of December 7th have been proposed for USD 34.99, with discounts for previous DCS F-14 owners. However, IndiaFoxtEcho has indicated issues with the system, which currently keeping the discounts unconfirmed at this time.  As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulator news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vssy</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases KMSY For X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vssy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656b85d7ad9b3d899545267a_m5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1211252"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Scenery developer Verticalsim has released an updated version of their Louis Armstrong New Orleans International Airport (KMSY). The release is an update to the X-Plane 11 version of the same sceneries and includes up to date airport layout.  Louis Armstrong New Orleans International Airport is located in Kenner, Louisiana, just over 10 miles west of downtown New Orleans. The airport features two runways with the longer of the two being over 10,000 feet long. The airport sees nearly 12 million passengers and over 100,000 aircraft operations each year.  The X-Plane 12 release of Verticalsim’s KSMY features 2k UHD PBR texturing, animated ground traffic (via the Groundtraffic plug-in, colour graded Satellite imagery, SAM jetways, and native X-plane weathermaps. Those who previously purchased the X-Plane 11 version of KMSY can enjoy the new one for just $4.99 USD on both the X-Plane.org store as well as VerticalSim’s website. To stay updated on all things flight sim be sure to keep your eye on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jffkf1</id>
    <title>Just Flight Posts Fokker F70/F100 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jffkf1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656b8cc21ad6b55384be0a08_5_F100_Ext_5_MzSZJ3QCJ.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="79790"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Coming shortly after their recently released Avro Vulcan, Just Flight has posted an update on their website regarding their upcoming Fokker F100 and F70. The development update mainly highlights the door and cabin configurations available for the aircraft at launch. The Fokker F100 and F70 were developed from the earlier F28. Both airframes offer a larger cabin and payload than the F28 and updated avionics. The F100/F70 features 2 Rolls-Royce Tay Mk 650-15 or Mk 620-15 Turbofan engines. The larger of the two engine options has a thrust output of 67 kN which allows the F100 to cruise at Mach 0.77 for a maximum range of over 1700nm. The upcoming F100/F70 will include 4 different door options as well as an interior that is customizable through the included paint kit. Just Flight also teased a fan favourite feature from the F28 that will be making another appearance, and that is the music reproducer panel that allows users to use custom boarding music for the enjoyment of their virtual passengers. The update goes on to state that moving forward they will be working on fine-tuning the artwork of the aircraft as well as improving other things such as cabin lighting. Currently Just Flight have not revealed a planned release date or pricing. Be sure to keep an eye on Threshold to stay up to date on all your flight sim news!  </summary>
    <published>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csrh66</id>
    <title>Cowan Simulation Announces Robinson R66</title>
    <updated>2023-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csrh66" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656d662e7b1ec669df55c3e6_406397880_867915018667583_5861474370581973188_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="253132"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Renowned for their high-quality helicopter add-ons for both Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane, Cowan Simulation (cowansim) has taken to their Facebook page to announce that their next project is a Robinson R66 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  The Robinson R66 is the newest helicopter available from the famed helicopter manufacturer. With production starting in 2007, over 1000 R66s have been built to date. Powered by a Rolls-Royce RR300 Turboshaft engine paired to a two-bladed prop the R66 is operated by a single pilot and has room for up to 4 passengers or 1200 lbs of cargo. The R66 cruises at 110 knots and has a maximum range of 350 nm. The R66 is the only Robinson helicopter to feature a separate cargo hold.  The update on Cowan’s Facebook page didn't offer a ton of information about the upcoming helicopter but did feature several screenshots that show off different cockpit layouts. From the screenshots, it looks as though the R66 will come with both analogue gauges as well as glass panels including what looks to be a GTN 750. There's currently no information on pricing or a release date, however, the post did say that updates for their other projects “will be released soon as well”.  Continue following Threshold to stay up to date on all things flight sim!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdgzk</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Designs Releases Stow Marie Great War Aerodrome</title>
    <updated>2023-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdgzk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656e1e537b9f01cc89fe6cb8_stowmaries21.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="334307"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Burning Blue Designs has released their rendition of Stow Maries Great War Aerodrome. Stow Maries offers the opportunity to visit one of the last remaining aerodromes from World War 1 that’s still in operation today. First established in 1916 during the height of the Great War, Stow Maries Aerodrome served as a base for the Royal Flying Corps (RFC) and later the Royal Air Force (RAF). Stow Maries played a pivotal role in defending London from German air raids. Located in Essex, Stow Maries Aerodrome still operates today and features many original buildings. The aerodrome also offers a museum on-site that hosts a large collection of WW1-era aircraft that would have been based at Stow Maries. More information on the museum can be found here. ‍Burning Blue Design’s offering for Microsoft Flight Simulator features the current layout for the airfield as well as 90 custom objects with full PBR textures. Users can also expect high-resolution colour-corrected ground textures a completely custom windsock and anemometer. Upon landing at Stow Maries you’ll be welcomed by a true-to-life representation of the museum’s real-world static aircraft lineup which includes an Avro 504K, a Sopwith Pup replica, and an Albatross D.V. The scenery also features animated hangar doors and gates that close at night as the museum does. You can find Stow Maries Aerodrome on Burning Blue Design’s website. ‍For all your flight sim updates be sure to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slhgpy</id>
    <title>SLH Sim Designs Releases Maurice Bishop International (TGPY)</title>
    <updated>2023-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slhgpy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656f73d61bb012106ac174c7_TGPY1_1080x.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="98262"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery Developer SLH Sim Designs have released their scenery pack for Maurice Bishop International Airport (TGPY) in Grenada for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new scenery builds upon SLH’s already solid selection of Caribbean airports.  Located about 5 miles south of the capital St. George’s, on Grenada’s southernmost point, Maurice Bishop International is the main arrival airport for those visiting Grenada from international destinations. Featuring a single 9000ft runway, Maurice Bishop International sees an average of 14 daily flights from 13 carriers. ‍  SLH has packed their TGPY scenery with features including custom 3D modelling, 6k PBR textures, and dynamic lighting. Users can expect an up-to-date airport layout that includes custom taxiway signs with realistic ground texturing and ‘grunge’. Included in the custom 3D models are true-to-life exteriors and modelled interiors. SLH has also included static sea traffic near the airport. The Maurice Bishop International scenery pack can be purchased from SLH Sim Design’s website here for $15 USD. Stay tuned to Threshold for all the latest flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ifp73m</id>
    <title>iFly Releases First Preview of 737 MAX for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ifp73m" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656fd98b279935768f97854b_MSFS-MAX1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1950712"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a post on their forums, developer iFly has shared a small preview of their upcoming 737 MAX for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The teaser image, which only shows a small part of the underbelly section, and appears to be the left main landing gear.  ‍ From this single image, iFly hopes to show that the final product will have quite a bit of visual detail. You can see the detail that they have gone to model the gear cables, strut, and little details like the roughness of the rubber tyres. iFly also says that this preview image was taken months ago, and much progress has been made since then.  iFly is mainly known for their 737 product line for Lockheed Martin’s Prepar3D, most recently being their rendition of the Boeing 737 MAX for Prepar3D V5. In a post on their Facebook page, iFly commented about the system depth of their upcoming airliner, saying, “While MSFS is amazing, for raw simulation of true aircraft systems, we believe P3Dv5 allows for the highest level of system simulations using raw C++. P3Dv5 may not have the eye candy of MSFS, but for true immersion, CAT III approaches, and more, we believe the iFly MAX on Prepar3D v5 can barely be beat.” They also added that the project is “still some time away as it is a major new development,” and that for a Microsoft Flight Simulator product, “time-to-market for a study-level-simulator takes longer compared with the FSX/P3D lineage.” While we do not know much about this new entrant into the MSFS airliner market, Threshold will keep you informed whenever we get new information, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcb407</id>
    <title>Dreamfoil Provides Bell 407 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcb407" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656fe7f08a4a6fb816d52f30_408248023_1224564918460434_4784041602513073307_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="699156"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Dreamfoil Creations who are fresh off of the release of their Schweitzer S300CBi have provided an update regarding the development of their upcoming Bell 407 for X-Plane 12.  ‍ The Bell 407  is an iconic helicopter that was first introduced in 1996. The Bell 407 was developed from the older Bell 206L LongRanger, featuring a 4-bladed rotor, a sleeker rotor housing, and larger windows. The 407 is equipped with an Allison 250-C47B turboshaft engine providing over 800 shaft horsepower. With seating for 5 and a maximum takeoff weight of 6000 lbs, the 407 is capable of flying 324 nm with a cruise speed of 133 knots. ‍ In the update posted to their Facebook page, which featured a single picture, Dreamfoil stated that the external texturing work for the new 407 is about 85% complete. The update also includes information about a poll taken on their forums that showed a majority of users would prefer an analogue cockpit over a glass panel based on the X-Plane Garmin G1000. The update also suggested that the 407 will come with options for both a Garmin 430/530 GPS set-up as well as an option to use the G1000h based on X-Plane’s G1000. At this time there's no information regarding price or a potential release date, however, it seems that the helicopter is coming together quite well. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold, your home for everything flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oabimm</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces British Isles Mesh for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oabimm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656ff0a8be2b17d08a896c35_image.png.3fc1fac0438d43605f97b7e87847612a.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3686287"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a post on their forums on Tuesday, Orbx has announced their newest product, the British Isles Mesh for Microsoft Flight Simulator, being developed by Dymtro Krykunov. The British Isles Mesh follows the release of six other terrain and mesh enhancement products, such as NZ Mesh, Alaska Mesh, South America Mesh, and Himalayas Mesh, all for MSFS. According to Orbx, British Isles Mesh will cover practically the entirety of the British Isles, including, but not limited to, Great Britain, Ireland, the Isle of Man, the Shetland and Orkney Islands, as well as the Inner and Outer Hebrides.  They also mention that the island of Ireland “has had particular focus by crafting a new mesh from ALOS satellite DEM data,” and that there are “over 200 locations added with a remarkable 2m/pix resolution.”  While Orbx has not said anything about a possible release date for the British Isles Mesh, Threshold will keep you informed once we find out, so stay tuned! </summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrsu14</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 14</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrsu14" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/656ffabbed365d84aa15be5d_ScenicAtol37419-Forums.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="904381"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has released their latest Sim Update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing with it many bug fixes, changes, and new features to the simulator. ‍ The major new features in this update include new Assistance features with their new Flight Plan Assistance setting, as well as fixes to the Air Traffic Control systems, improving instruction logic and phraseology. Sim Update 14 also adds a new aircraft, the Cirrus SR22 G6, complete with avionics made in partnership with Working Title. However, this upgraded Cirrus is only available to customers who have purchased the Premium Deluxe upgrade for the sim.  ‍ Another significant change is the removal of the iniBuilds A320neo from the update. Initially promised to be slated for this update by Jorg Neumann, Head of Microsoft Flight Simulator in their September Dev Livestream, and included in the SU14 Beta, it is now absent. According to the Sim Update 14 patch notes, Microsoft explains that the reason behind the delay was that during testing they “encountered an application crash rate on console that is too high to pass certification.” Recently, the iniBuilds A320neo has come under fire from accusations that it stole code from the popular open-source A320neo made by FlyByWire, thus allegedly violating the General Public License. This change has left some users speculating whether the accusations of stolen code were the actual reason behind the delay.  ‍ Also included in Sim Update 14 are the changes to the atmosphere and lighting in the sim, as mentioned in Microsoft’s November Dev Livestream. These highly requested changes fix sky colors and make the atmosphere and horizon look more realistic. There have also been fixes to the snow coverage and icing systems and other changes to live weather. As with all of the Sim Updates, there are a whole host of small tweaks and squashed bugs that are too many to list here, but you can find the full patch notes on Microsoft’s website here. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsssma</id>
    <title>The Secret Studio Releases Sultan Mahmud Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsssma" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65705cb0382e3e9c84a01010_mah1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1410647"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Secret Studio has recently released their rendition of Sultan Mahmud Kuala Terengganu International Airport (WMKN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Kuala Terengganu in Malaysia with a yearly average of 919,829 passengers. ‍ It was established in the 1920s as a small airfield, used primarily for military purposes during World War II. It served as a base for the British Royal Air Force (RAF) and the Japanese Imperial Army.‍  After the war, the British colonial authorities expanded and upgraded the airport to accommodate civilian air travel. It was renamed Sultan Mahmud Airport in honor of Sultan Mahmud Al-Muktafi Billah Shah, the 16th Sultan of Terengganu.  In the following years, Sultan Mahmud Airport became an important transportation hub for the Terengganu region, connecting it with other parts of Malaysia and neighboring countries. The airport underwent several upgrades and modernizations to keep pace with the region's air travel growth.  In 2008, a major renovation and expansion project was undertaken to upgrade the airport's facilities and increase its capacity. The project included constructing a new terminal building, a new runway, and other airport infrastructure improvements.  Today, Sultan Mahmud Airport is one of the busiest airports in Malaysia, serving as a vital economic driver for the Terengganu region, supporting tourism, trade, and other industries. The airport continues to evolve and expand to meet the growing demand for air travel in Malaysia and the surrounding regions.  It's served by four airlines: AirAsia (Kuala Lumpur-International), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur-Subang), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur-Subang), and Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur-International).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality custom buildings, PBR textures, an in-house VDGS system, custom ILS, custom animated jetways, custom terraforming, a detailed terminal interior, and custom ground traffic.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $12.97 and requires at least 888.37 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sws12l</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Releases Pilatus PC-12 Legacy for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sws12l" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657081a7a0ced81f059649fc_pc12.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="842134"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios has recently released their rendition of the Pilatus PC-12 Legacy for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engined turboprop aircraft first flown in the early 1990s and popular among corporate transport companies, government agencies, and air-ambulance operators.  Its development was announced in October 1989 at the National Business Aviation Association (NBAA), and it had been under development for a few years prior under high levels of secrecy (they had commenced the prototype assembly by the time it was announced). It was believed to be the first single-engined aircraft capable of flying at high speed across long distances, a market that was unheard of back then. The prototype was completed in May 1991, and the first flight took off only 30 days later.   While the original plans were for a mid-1991 certification, a wing redesign delayed progress by a few years, with the certification only being issued in March 1994 (Europe) and July 1994 (United States).  It has undergone multiple improvements over its production span, with more powerful engines, new avionics, noise reduction measures, new propellers, increased speed and range, and more. It was also modified by other aviation firms that added their enhancement packages.  The variant at hand was certified in 2005, and it's powered by a Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-67B engine, with a range of 1742 miles, a maximum take-off weight of 4,740 kg, and a cruise speed of 500 km/h.   The add-on features an accurate simulation of the PC-12, developed with help from Pilatus Aircraft and Fly7 Executive Aviation, replicating the real aircraft's handling behavior with correct propeller beta and reverse operation, custom ITT simulation, and realistic flap deployment timings. It also includes various custom systems, ranging from a custom aileron-rudder interconnect system to usable circuit breakers, PMS GTN, TDS GTNXi, and Sky4Sim Tablet compatibility. The complete list of features follows below:   It's available on their store and Contrail for roughly $26.98, requiring at least 3.95 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! </summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flykuu</id>
    <title>Fly X Simulations Releases Kuusamo Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flykuu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65709c7372a9dd58d1d3711f_kuu.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="519604"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly X Simulations has recently released their rendition of Kuusamo Airport (EFKS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the northeastern part of the Northern Ostrobothnia in Finland with a yearly average of 87,000 passengers.  It was inaugurated in 1972, with a regular scheduled route between Oulu and Kuusamo starting that same year. The original runway length was around 800 meters, which was expanded for the first time in 1974 to 1,500 meters so that larger aircraft could visit it.   In the late 1980s, the passenger terminal was inaugurated, and the runway was extended to 2,000 meters so they could get jet traffic.  The late 1990s brought the final runway extension (to 2,500 meters), and the passenger terminal was expanded for the first time.   In the early 2000s, the airport was granted its international status and underwent a renovation and expansion of its terminal building.  It’s served by Finnair with a daily route to Helsinki and visited by Lufthansa, Jet2, TUI Airways, and TUI fly Netherlands on a seasonal basis.\  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings (including wear and tear), high-resolution PBR textures, accurate airport buildings, and a detailed airside terminal interior.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $11.32, requiring at least 409 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
