<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-10-13T18:34:44.979970+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sclatr</id>
    <title>SkyCatsLab Previews ATR 72-600 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sclatr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e3e7a5541385cd447c1f31_ATR_72_-_2025-10-05_19.25.45.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SkyCatsLab has recently shared some previews of their upcoming ATR 72-600 for X-Plane 12, showcasing daytime and night cockpit shots, along with work-in-progress exterior PBR textures.  The images highlight flight deck modelling, FCP and displays, the overhead and circuit breaker panels, oxygen masks, night lighting, and turboprop, wing, and exterior. Test builds with a fully functional cockpit are currently being evaluated by the internal testing team and several experienced ATR 72 pilots, who are assessing systems operation, indications, performance, navigation, and the flight model. As for release, SkyCatsLab continues to target a 2026 release window. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiblr</id>
    <title>TaiModels Releases Kempegowda International Airport (VOBL) for XP12 and MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiblr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e4e1f280bb7a9641757474_Screenshot%202025-10-07%20114430.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. TaiModels has just released their rendition of Kempegowda International Airport (BLR/VOBL) for X-Plane 12, MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Located 35km (22mi) from the city, it serves Bengaluru and is the third busiest airport in India, with over 41 million passenger operations in 2024. Opened in May 2008, replacing the old HAL Airport. Originally, the airport had a single runway, accompanied by a terminal with 8 jetbridges, one double-arm jetbridge, and 9 remote parking stands. In February 2009, the airport was renamed in honour of the founder of the city, Kempe Gowda I.  The first airport expansion was launched in 2011 and finished two years later. The passenger terminal size has been doubled, with additional check-in desks, immigration, and baggage-reclaim facilities. A single domestic gate and 3 international gates were also added.  The latest airport expansion was completed in 2021, where the airport received another runway and a second terminal, allowing it to handle between 55 and 60 million passengers annually. The TaiModels’ rendition of the Kempegowda Intl’ features handcrafted PBR ground textures and markings, detailed terminal interior, accurate airport lighting and custom-made night lighting, optimised performance, tower laser effects, and animated screens and escalators. The scenery is available for purchase on the iniBuilds store for approximately $21.91, requiring at least 1.82GB of free disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini34r</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini34r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e578fc93a665ecf1700bc7_ini340.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just released its new A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing the rather laggard, four-engined Airbus into the sim. The package covers passenger and freighter variants, with a choice of the EIS1 and EIS2 avionics suites. You will find a custom FMS with SIDs, STARs, and secondary flight plans, LNAV/VNAV, and CPDLC integration via Hoppie. More than 100 ECAM pages are included, alongside failures, terrain radar, and features such as geo-specific GPS jamming, affecting TCAS and GPWS. The iniBuilds EFB has also been reworked for planning and turnaround tasks. It supports SimBrief import, chart integration, maintenance, and wear tracking, ground equipment control, performance tools, autosave options, and scenario management for training.  The aircraft also offers full GSX compatibility and time-warping capability. The cockpit and exterior use detailed PBR assets, refined lighting, and a wide set of animations. iniBuilds has also included custom visual effects, including wing and engine vortices, precipitation spray, heat blur, and weathering states. A sound set crafted by IniBuilds partner Echo19 accurately depicts the CFM56 engines, with added attention to flap, hydraulic, and cabin ambience. Plenty of liveries are also available via the iniManager. The iniBuilds A340 Airliner is available now on the MSFS 2024 Marketplace for $59.99, excluding taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tbfpha</id>
    <title>TechnoBrain Further Previews Haneda Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tbfpha"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e57fbbfeb93b865cca6457_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. TechnoBrain has recently shared a variety of new screenshots of the upcoming Haneda Airport (RJTT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The team has been working on this international airport for some time, and the new screenshots highlight the intricate details being incorporated into the project. Haneda Airport was the fourth-busiest airport in the world last year and serves as the main airport for Tokyo, Japan. It acts as a hub for All Nippon Airways and Japan Airlines while accommodating numerous other airlines. Together, these airlines help the airport manage approximately 85 million passengers annually, coming from destinations around the globe. The pricing, release date, and specific features of the scenery have not been announced yet. We will keep you updated with more information as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mpb17i</id>
    <title>MicroProse Unveils B-17G Early Access for MSFS 2020/MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mpb17i"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e58b74c362b307b9587d25_microprose-b17g-flying-fortress_13_ss_l_250930114352.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse has just revealed the targeted release of their B-17G Flying Fortress for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, now set for October 9, 2025. A Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version is set to follow.  The aircraft opens the studio’s Heritage Valour Collection, a line focused on historically significant warbirds.  The team said they will launch in Early Access once the aircraft is ready, then issue rapid updates for about eight weeks. The aim is to refine systems, art, and usability, with community feedback. At launch, the package will include a high-fidelity flight model, hand-crafted 4K PBR textures, interior and exterior vibration effects, and authentic audio, captured from the flying B-17 “Sentimental Journey”.  Animated crew stations and period details feature throughout. A fully functional electrical system with circuit breakers, a maintenance model, visible wear, and an in-sim clipboard for common functions is also included.  Optional modern avionics will be available for those who prefer more contemporary navigation, and the aircraft also comes with a Wwise-powered soundset.  Work left before release includes liveries, a crew configuration system, deeper maintenance options, a paint kit, and support for the MSFS 2024 walk-around mode.  MicroProse says real-world B-17 expertise has informed the flight dynamics and systems tuning, with the broader goal of preserving and presenting historic aircraft to a new audience.  For more information about the project, you can visit the official home page. The team also shared a roadmap, covering future planned development. The planned feature list for the Early Access version is as follows: Key Features (Early Access)‍ The MicroProse B17G Flying Fortress will release for Early Access on October 9th 2025. Those interested in joining from day one can register their email with JustFlight, through the official product page. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfoctu</id>
    <title>Got Friends Brings Full 2024 Compatibility to 23 Products, A32 Vixxen in Beta</title>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfoctu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e59d9be5abe8d4c22886a1_MEDIA_BANNER_comp.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Got Friends has released a broad compatibility update, covering 23 freeware and payware projects, bringing its line-up forward for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024.  Work has been done across environmental sounds, animations, broader code, and long-requested quality-of-life fixes have been implemented. Two legacy items remain pending: the 40th Anniversary Pack and the Avatar Collections, which are not yet compatible. Alongside the updates, Got Friends says its next aircraft, the Aeroprakt A32 Vixxen, has now entered beta. The project is being developed with Aeroprakt USA and Heavenbound Aviation in Johnstown, Ohio.  The flight school has built a custom panel with RealSimGear avionics, tied to an MSFS 2024 build for training use. Accompanying the aircraft’s release will be a small scenery rendition of the school's 5OI8 Mcknight Airport. The A32 Vixxen will include numerous variants and options, including steam and analogue instrument layouts, AirTrac tyres, with wheelpants for paved operations, and Tundra tyres for bush flying. Pricing has not been finalised, though the team indicates it will be in line with previous releases. Got Friends is targeting a near-term launch for both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. To purchase any of Got Friend's aircraft, visit their website here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsw26r</id>
    <title>FlightSimWeekend 2026 Opens Exhibitor Registration, Announces New Event Details</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsw26r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e67651ee1bac598bd161de_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The FlightSimWeekend Foundation has officially announced that registration for commercial exhibitors at FlightSimWeekend 2026 is now open. The annual event will be held at the Aviodrome Aviation Museum in Lelystad, Netherlands, from March 20th to 22nd. In addition to the opening of registrations, the team has shared several new details about the upcoming event. The team announced that FlightSimWeekend 2026 will introduce a new expansion hall, larger booth formats, and a variety of exhibitors from around the globe. Niels Voogd, the Chairman of FlightSimWeekend, stated that after gathering feedback from both exhibitors and visitors at recent events, the team decided to increase capacity and further enhance the quality of presentations. Jannes van Gestel, the Finance &amp; Operations Lead, added, “This expansion represents a new chapter for FlightSimWeekend.” As the community continues to grow rapidly, the team aims to provide everyone—whether hobbyists or industry leaders—the space they deserve. Magnus Lorvik, Senior Accounts &amp; Projects Manager, concluded by mentioning that the new hall will allow for even more engaging content for visitors to explore. For the 2026 event, Navigraph, Honeycomb Aeronautical, and iniBuilds will serve as the primary partners. These companies are returning to enhance the event with expanded exhibits and exclusive showcases in the new exhibition zones. The team emphasises that these partners have played a crucial role in the event's success. Additionally, the event will welcome new major partners for the first time, including one of the most recognisable names in the flight simulation industry. In the coming weeks, the team will provide more details as additional exhibitors and partners are confirmed. ‍ Exhibitors interested in learning more about opportunities at the event can find a brochure here, and registration is available here. Please note that exhibitor registration is open only to commercial parties. Non-profit communities and organisations will be able to register next month, in November, using a separate form. The FlightSimWeekend Captain’s Dinner will be returning this year, alongside the second edition of the Flight Sim Awards. Last year marked the inaugural Flight Sim Awards, which honoured various developers and their contributions to the flight simulation community in partnership with FSElite, Threshold, and Cruiselevel. This event is scheduled for Friday, March 20th, at the Van der Valk Hotel Lelystad. ‍ In addition to the Captain’s Dinner and the Flight Sim Awards, the team has announced a new social event called the FlightSimWeekend After Dark Party. This event will also take place at the Van der Valk Hotel Lelystad and aims to bring together exhibitors, partners, and the public for networking and celebration in a relaxed and festive atmosphere. Tickets for both events will be made available to the general public at a later date. FlightSimWeekend 2026 will introduce several changes and improvements to enhance the visitor experience. The event will feature increased floor space with a redesigned layout to reduce crowding and improve flow. Full-scale rigs, multi-station demos, and centrepiece installations will occupy a larger area at the event. Developers from around the world will be in attendance, and alongside commercial exhibitors, freeware projects, global networks, and grassroots clubs will play a significant role. ‍ For exhibitors and partners, the event will include standardised modular booths as well as a limited number of large plaza booths. Professional system walls and fascia signage will provide a clean, organised look throughout the venue. As always, the environment will be welcoming to everyone, from major brands to community projects. If you're interested in learning more about the history, current status, and future of the event, be sure to read Magnus's comprehensive article. For information about the upcoming event, including travel arrangements, logistics, and other details, please visit the FlightSimWeekend website. FlightSimWeekend 2026 will be held at the Aviodrome Aviation Museum from March 20th to March 22nd. The public exhibit will take place on Saturday, March 21st, and Sunday, March 22nd. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bb757b</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations 757 for MSFS Enters Beta Testing</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bb757b"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e6f29c83c40b344f7382f9_Octscreenshot1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. After several weeks of quiet development, BlueBird Simulations has moved its Boeing 757 into stage one of beta testing, the first time external testers have had access to the plane. In a brief message posted to their Discord server, BlueBird confirmed that while not every system is fully implemented yet, this new phase represents a significant step forward. BlueBird also posted a beta roadmap, outlining the three planned stages of the testing phase. BlueBird explained that this initial testing stage focuses on select systems, with external feedback now helping shape the aircraft’s refinement.  The team expects all three planned beta phases to take many months, stretching well into 2026, as they continue to polish systems and ensure stability across both MSFS 2020 and 2024. An in-depth update video and further screenshots are expected either later this year or shortly after the Christmas period. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw777</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Sound Set for PMDG 777 Releasing “Within a week”</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw777"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e825ae36e8fa413e131714_FZgv8Jl0EfI-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. After six months of hard work, Boris Vanian, of Boris Audio Works, has confirmed that his long-awaited PMDG 777 Sound Pack is finally imminent. The trailer showcases the 777’s immense presence in detail, from the hydraulics and engines to the individual cockpit switches and air conditioning.  Streamers are already getting early access, meaning first impressions and showcases should begin appearing shortly. Boris expects the official release to follow “within a week”, though an exact date has yet to be confirmed. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/738previews2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Teases 738NG for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/738previews2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610eb67b707eee4de3d07f4_1250410_20240201232913_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has published a teaser image of their upcoming Boeing 737-800NG for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The image shows the progress on the cabin, which is “not edited in any way, straight out of the sim,” they state. As previously announced, PMDG decided to bring a fully improved version of their 737NG lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 rather than just a compatibility patch. The new version includes a proper cabin, openable cockpit windows, and an overall quality bump on modeling and texturing, while also including MSFS 2024-only niceties such as the new walkaround mode. ‍ Development has recently sped up after the developers were finally done with the 777 lineup, shifting their efforts to bring the 737NG to the new platform. Considering how prevalent the NG is in real-world operations, this is perhaps one of the most awaited updates thus far.  ‍ ‍ There is still no information on the release date or the pricing, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflf2822</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases F28 Professional Update for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflf2822"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8ced3491c2df85c132c91_fukki1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has teased the progress on their v2.2 upgrade for the Fokker F28 Professional, which will land for free (for previous owners) on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 (PC and Xbox).  While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. They will also include MSFS 2024’s pre-flight walkaround mode and a new EFB tablet model with a window-mount option. The complete 2.2 changelog and release information will be published very soon. In addition to the ongoing work on the F70/F100 and the F28, Just Flight is also hard at work on an update for the 146, which includes MSFS 2024 compatibility. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimbkordxp12</id>
    <title>Nimbus Simulation Studios Teases Chicago O’Hare Intl for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimbkordxp12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8d1e05353762223a1f1f0_kord1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has recently previewed their progress on Chicago O’Hare International Airport (KORD) for X-Plane 12, the world’s fourth busiest airport, with a yearly average of 80 million passengers. Their new O’Hare aims to fully exploit X-Plane 12’s new technologies, bringing realistic wetness, season support, detailed terminal interiors, and much more.  There is no information on the release date yet, but they say it’s getting “closer and closer”. Pricing hasn’t been revealed either. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar2020comp</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations’ Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 Now MSFS 2020-compatible</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar2020comp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8f5cb32270f9082184456_aerostar2020.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. A2A Simulations has recently released the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version of their Accu-Sim Aerostar 600, which was initially only compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. As previously mentioned on their previous development update on Discord, the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version of the Aerostar 600 doesn’t bring full feature parity with the 2024 version due to limitations, such as the walkaround system, and dynamic wear and dirt visuals, but it includes the full Accu-sim fidelity and system depth aside from that.  The optional MSFS 2020 download is already available on the store page, and it is free for owners of the 2024 version. A fresh purchase warrants access to both versions. ‍ The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/at3401</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Detail A340-600 Pro for MSFS in New Video</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/at3401"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e958a93b0e859a60623522_Baiix3leqhI-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has initiated a developer video series for the Airbus A340-600 Pro, sharing the most in-depth look yet at the upcoming jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  In this first episode, community manager Rafi speaks with ToLiss founder Torsten Liesk, outlining how the collaboration splits responsibilities, how the flight model has been built, and what systems depth to expect. ToLiss is handling aircraft systems, avionics, custom flight and engine models, and flight logic. Aerosoft is responsible for the 3D model, visuals, and publishing. The teams say this plays to their strengths, complex Airbus systems from ToLiss, art and presentation from Aerosoft. Rather than porting code straight from X-Plane, ToLiss has spent two years creating new flight, ground, and engine models, tailored to MSFS, that behave similarly to X-Plane.  That includes workarounds for MSFS limitations, such as MSFS supporting only one aileron per wing, and a ground-handling model, developed with McGill University, to improve tyre friction, braking, and taxi dynamics. The behaviour has been validated by real-world A340-600 pilots, aiming to match the same feel of the X-Plane version. Systems are modelled at the component level, including pumps, valves, actuators, and reservoirs, so actions and failures produce natural downstream effects, rather than scripted outcomes. The team is targeting around 200–250 user-triggerable failures across hydraulics, electrics, pneumatics, flight controls, and engines. The FMS will include secondary flight plans, route offsets, temporary edits, and constraint-aware VNAV, with managed and selected modes. For long flights, a situation save/load system offers automatic saves at user-defined intervals, allowing recovery after crashes or convenient mid-route pauses.  A “jump to next waypoint” is also available, with time and fuel adjustments. Confirmed integrations include Hoppie CPDLC/ACARS and SimBrief flight-plan import. Navigraph support is under evaluation due to MSFS differences from X-Plane. Aerosoft’s video is the first in a series that will continue to show off progress, towards an eventual launch. There is no release date or pricing yet. Previously, the team also shared a video highlighting various systems and fault modes present within the A346. We will keep an eye on the weekly updates and share key developments as they land. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mpb17</id>
    <title>MicroProse Releases B-17G Flying Fortress Early Access for MSFS 2024 </title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mpb17"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e96fa5ee2f9b4571f83890_B-17_Valor_YouTube_thumbnail_out_now.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse has released its Boeing B-17G Flying Fortress for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the first entry in the studio’s Heritage Valour Collection. The add-on is available in Early Access, with development scheduled to continue through regular updates. The package focuses on historical detail. The cockpit, crew stations, and turret positions are fully modelled, and the sound set was captured from the real B-17, Sentimental Journey. A custom flight model has also been built for MSFS 2024.  At launch, you get five liveries and an in-sim clipboard for simple crew setup. Optional modern avionics, a maintenance mode, additional liveries, and expanded crew tools are planned for the Early Access phase. MicroProse says updates will roll out on a frequent cadence, adding features consistently, ahead of the full release.  The B-17G is available now via Just Flight at an introductory price of US$32.99, rising to US$39.99 on full release. The download is about 3.2 GB. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw777sp</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases PMDG B777 Sound Pack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw777sp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e9ffe7b88b3f092b9f854a_boris1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works recently released their PMDG B777 Sound Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The pack features all three engine variants (GE90, Trent 800, and PW4000) in incredible detail, with unique tonal character and authentic ambience.  In addition to the fully re-recorded engine sets, the pack also offers authentic cockpit and cabin ambience, detailed switch, hydraulic, and environmental systems, headphone simulation, subtle differences between older and newer GE engine variants, and much more. Developed in collaboration with Dave from Fenix Simulations - known for his commendable work on Fenix’s A320 lineup -, the 777 sound set redefines the PMDG 777 experience. Customers can buy the engines separately (GE90, Trent 800, and PW4000) for $7.83 each or the full pack for $14.92. Buyers of the 2024 version get the 2020 version for free, and vice versa. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
