<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-05-24T18:31:40.925501+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350109</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350109"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/681fbf688268c3fcd013e64a_a350new1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued another update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, improving core areas, fixing bugs, and adding larger new items. The VNAV system underwent a major overhaul, with improvements to vertical profile adherence and constraint handling, as well as the addition of Constant Mach Segments, Continuous Descent Approach, and Estimated Take-off Time.  Furthermore, iniBuilds has also added dynamic icing and snow effects, GSX integration for de-icing, and hot brake disc visuals on both platforms.  The ECAM system also expanded with new fuel, icing, braking, and thrust logic alerts. They have also done audio work to refine the cabin ambience, engine dynamics, and touchdown feedback, aiming to close the gap between their virtual rendition and the real thing. Optimization work was carried out under the hood to warrant better performance, with code cleanups and restructuring reducing the overhead and thus improving the framerate.  The complete changelog for the update follows below: v1.0.9Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️Added: CDA implementationAdded: ETT ImplementationAdded: CMS (Constant Mach Segment)Added: HCF Taxi implementationFixed: FMS sequencing when selecting arrival runwayFixed: BATC ATC auto tuningFixed: Aircraft unable to level off after autosaveFixed: Manual MAN TOGA thrust limit revisedFixed: Autosave - Throttles and A/THR not respected on loadFixed: Landing capacity downgrade sound kicks in too lateFixed: No RETARD sound when thrust IDLE at 20 ftFixed: FS20 - No TOD and overflow UTC estimatesFixed: VD end bar offset with selected headingFixed: VD minor formatting, Decel should be in front of all text/linesFixed: Incorrect LAND mode in SLS approachFixed: Incorrect confirmation msg when re-selecting SLSFixed: WXR behavior when Setting SURV to DEFAULTFixed: Decel pseudo wpt should change to white when on selected speedFixed: Aircraft slowly shifts position over time despite chocks ONFixed: MAILBOX missing "RECALL" buttonFixed: Messages don't appear in the ATC COM menuFixed: SPD error at fms message should read "SPD ERROR AT xxxx"Fixed: TOGA go around but thrust stuck at GA SOFT and suddenly increasing on its own at ACCELFixed: GA soft behaviour tweaksFixed: 121.870 is invalid freqFixed: SLS approach: channel info missing in arrival pageFixed: No brake pressure from cold and dark in edge casesFixed: MFD TO page format after phase sequencedFixed: Incorrect SELECT FLS confirmation boxFixed: Timer inconsistenciesFixed: Step climb should now show T/C while climbing from SC pointFixed: NAVAIDS: reselect glide has incorrect confirmation msgFixed: FMS POSITION/IRS page - alignment displayFixed: Disengaging FD should synchronize AFS CP valuesFixed: RMP incorrect display when MIC selected on HF2Fixed: Arrival Page behaviour allows for independent segment changes (RWY/APP/STAR)Fixed: FMA FPA not showing the FPA valueFixed: VNAV: ALT CSTR not respected in managed CLBFixed: TELEX via HOPPIE not workingFixed: FCU BKUP issues with formatting and functionalityFixed: FMS - FPLN drawing issueFixed: ADIRS - temp availabilityFixed: Unable to delete local time offsetFixed: On initiation of go around the FCU VS window displays +0000Fixed: On go around from TRK-FPA the VS window displays the VS at time of the go aroundFixed: ILS/DME lettering on NAVAIDS page flashingFixed: Sideslip index on PFDFixed: ND - ILS course pointer drawing has offsetFixed: NOISE on PFD should not display when only 1 engine is onFixed: VNAV -  ALT CSTR not being respectedFixed: ADS-B not pulling dataFixed: FUEL&amp;LOAD change computing N&lt;-N to dashesFixed: Fuel Calc - More EFOB at ALTN than DESTFixed: Tail strike pitch limit too highFixed: ALT constraint ignored when flying in ALT at same level as the next constraintFixed: SPD LIMIT ignored if not on NAVFixed: Level-off Symbol is inaccurateFixed: FMS 2 does not open sub menu itemsFixed: FIX INFO WPT selection issueFixed: DES SPD LIM can't be changedFixed: Brake pressure not showing on Wheel SDFixed: Managed speed doesn't respect FLFixed: SDL LIMIT in wrong place in F-PLNFixed: FPLN SPDLIM pseudo wpt and distances around it incorrectFixed: Managed speed, Decel in ND shown white when should be magentaFixed: SEC FPLN - Modifying ALT CSTR in SEC goes into ACTIVEFixed: Go around, while on flap 3 the slats auto retracted incorrectlyFixed: EDDW-EDDN: After T/C next waypoint showing below cruise levelFixed: SEC menu overlap and clicking "through”Fixed: STEP ALTs related issuesFixed: SID showing impossible SPD LIM 250/10000 7nm after TOFixed: ANJILL4 KLAX 25L VNAVFixed: Vnav issues KATL OZZZI STARFixed: CPDLC - SayIntentions - unreliable store and recall of messagesFixed: MFD Departure, changing SID and erasing change causes a mismatch in the DEP pageFixed: SPD LIMIT ignored if not on NAVFixed: Main fuel pump FAULT quick flash not showingFixed: The ETA for TOD is incorrect - see refFixed: LL spacingFixed: ENG start: high EGT incorrect startupFixed: Fuel not draining from center tank firstFixed: ATU faults not showing failed bus on ECAMFixed: Logitech radio panel not working as intendedFixed: AVNCS SMOKE doesn't light up when using ANN LT TEST - @foliainfxFixed: QRH reflects ground vehicle lightsFixed: Pax cabin: rain on RH pax windows moves rearwards to frontFixed: Aircraft unable to level off after autosaveFixed: RS pitot covers not responding to windFixed: Missing cockpit texture in document rackFixed: Taxi camera light linked to main taxi lightFixed: Engine covers in place but not visible?Fixed: Taxi gear bump noise always on regardless of ON&lt;&gt;OFF selectionFixed: MEMO: no smoking/mobile flicker on/off with gear retractionFixed: TO INHIBIT disappears immediately when the aircraft lifts offFixed: Eng start fault ecam with single engine taxiFixed: Park brake ecamFixed: ANF does not auto-activate upon touch-down/rev thrustFixed: Ground roll sounds not tied to GROUND SURFACE VOL control sliderFixed: Setting THR LEVERS to IDLE during climb did not trigger ATHR off warningsFixed: Single PRIM fault leading to loss of GA SOFTFixed: Single PRIM fault leading to incorrect LDG PERF AFFECTEDFixed: Single PRIM fault leading to incorrect loss of AUTOLANDFixed: FCTL PRIM3 fault not shown in INOP SYS ALL PHASESFixed: ECAM: STS page recall stuck after changing to QNH, unable to remove itECAM: single SEC fault should not show LDG PERF AFFECTEDFixed: SEC1+2 fault triggering incorrect RUDDER TRIM 1+2 faultFixed:  PRIM1+2+3: GND SPOILERS listed as inop when it should not be the caseImproved: incremental thrust keybind handlingFixed: WASM exception EFIS Gauge Update - KLAX-RJTT routeFixed: WASM exception EFIS_gauge_update when rapidly loading autosavesFixed: WASM exception - Systems_gauge_update - TNCMFixed: WASM exception-  Commbus Callback - While executing DIR TOFixed: WASM exception- Commbus callback - Navigraph_FunctionResult - Entering MIQ ADF on Fixed: NAVAIDS pageFixed: BTV should not have an FMA mode change box around it when it activatesFixed: KLAX ANJLL4 STAR  - Target spd and VDS display issueFixed: VSD not showing the connecting line to WP.Fixed: Autoland at EDDLFixed: DTO modification on approach TPY plan does not show the correct informationFixed: SLS approach: channel info missing in arrival pageFixed: DOOR SD page not showing immediately when engines are shutdownFixed: RNAV SLS incorrect NAVAIDS tuningFixed: FPLN predictions: noise setting has no effect in vertical predictionsFixed: WHEEL SD: MLG door lines are too long and overlap wheel arc when openFixed: Finding quite a few missed approaches not coded correctly in blueFixed: Issue changing current approachFixed: HOLD: deleting hold from FPLN before entering generates a DISCONFixed: Selected speed not automatically crossing over to MNFixed: EO max value jumpingFixed: FCU BKUP issues including formatting, behaviour andFixed: PILOT STORED RTE - not saving SID/STAR/APPCH or DEP/ARR runway data in the routeFixed: NAVAIDS: LS display format correction when not tunedFixed: Vls too high leading to high Vapp speedsFixed: NAVAIDS: LS class shows ILS instead of GLSFixed: Mouse cursor behaviour on MFDFixed: Step alts: erasing level should delete the stepFixed: Rouge ETP circle drawing at top left corner of NDFixed: Position/monitor page tweakFixed: Active/wind page - "Entry out of Range" error when removing imported dataFixed: Small AFS CP altitude changes sometimes do not lead to ALT armingFixed: Autopilot off and descent mode should change to speed when slowing below VLSFixed: Issue when deleting HOLD as part of procedureFixed: SDL LIMIT in wrong place in F-PLNFixed: ILS ident incorrectly swaps to dep. runway's ILS ident if deviating from the flight planned routeFixed: Aggressive pitch up after TAKE OFFFixed: MAGVAR issue for display on AFS,PFD,NDFixed: Taxi camera light linked to main taxi light Fixed: MFD message EXTEND SPD BRKFixed: DTO course in, no track line while on HDG with no interceptFixed: FMS POSITION/IRS page - align on refFixed: Incorrect GD, S, F speeds in APPR pageFixed: Pulling ALT knob incorrectly engages OP CLB on groundFixed: Pulling VS on ground incorrectly engages VS modeFixed: Pulling HDG on ground incorrectly engages HDG modeFixed: Pulling SPD on ground should do nothingFixed: AFS CP Altitude&lt;accel alt, VS shows +0000Fixed: Deselecting autobrake mid flight triggering wrong aural alertFixed: Cabin Alt - Actual Rate of change not matching displayed Cabin VSIFixed: Incorrect definition, Vref should equal Vls conf fullFixed: ND: Track line should not be present on groundFixed: Unable to popout pfd/ndFixed: Unable to select MIC on HF2"Fixed: VSD bracket reverses direction brieflyFixed: HDG bug behaviour when DTO course in insertedFixed: ENG1 fail show ENG2 amber in FUEL SD pageFixed: GLS approach, AP off approach capability remained LAND1Fixed: GLS approach, AP off, LAND and FLARE modes incorrectFixed: Using LBS weight but FUEL WEIGHT DATA DISAGREE ECAM shows "KG" disagreement alertFixed: Unable to walk in walkaround modeFixed: FCU BKUP issues with function and formattingFixed: Step Climb Page behaviour when using WP drop downFixed: RTA page on ground, should show ETE/ATA at selected wptFixed: RTA page has white ALT text that should not be thereFixed: RTA/ETT, Should say ETT ISO UTCFixed: RTA, with no RTA the DELETE RTA button should be greyed outFixed: DTO course in, no track line while on HDG with no interceptFixed: SURV: can click through the confirmation box 3D Art 🎨🖌️Added: FS20 &amp; FS24: Icing effects with standalone and GSX compatibility.Added: FS24: Snow piling when cold &amp; dark panel state is loaded at gate and active weather is heavy snow.Added: Hot glowing break disc effect during high brake temps.Fixed: Engine windmill speed now wind direction dependent Fixed: Captain's window transparency different from rest Fixed: Engine covers in place but not visibleFixed: Missing cockpit texture in document rackFixed: NW: lights inside the left box are visible Fixed: NW amber lights remain lit in C&amp;DFixed: RS pitot covers not responding to windFixed: QRH reflects ground vehicle lightsFixed: Pax cabin: rain on RH pax windows moves rearwards to frontFixed: Excessive window scratches and smears post addition of rain effects - now reduced significantly.Fixed: Cabinless Variants - Cockpit avionics bay door still accessibleFixed: Right side pitot covers not responding to windFixed: Unable to pop-out Primary and Navigational flight displaysFixed: Pedal lights and first officer's flood lights appear to be switched on by default on cold and dark during gate spawnFixed: Pedestal flood light is dim vs fwd panel floodFixed: Adjusted engines windmilling logic depending on aircraft direction relative to wind for more accuracyFixed: AVNCS SMOKE annunciator doesn't light up during annunciator light testFixed: Captain's window transparency differs from the rest of the cockpit windowsFixed: A350-1000 passenger cabin window right side rain moves rearwards to frontFixed: Taxi camera light linked to main aircraft taxi light Sounds 🔊Added: New cabin packs soundAdded: New manip sounds for various squibsAdded: More varied engine noise in cabinAdded: Much more air rushing noise to reverse thrust (interior and exterior)Added: More range in ground roll noise based on speedAdded: More touchdown sound variationFixed: nose ground roll sound not tied to sound optionsFixed: FS20 aft and front engine blending Fixed: interior ambient blendingFixed: touchdown sound volumeFixed: touchdown sound v/s sensitivity Fixed: touchdown sound may not work at lower speedsFixed: some missing call chimes in FS20Fixed: FO table sound plays out of sync with animationFixed: C Chord volumeFixed: Volume adjust to misc interior manipsFixed: some FS20 interactions quiet compared to FS24Fixed: missing sounds for ecam tcas, video and recall buttonsFixed: missing sound for gravity gear handle and guardFixed: Parking brake sound inconsistencyFixed: crew supply button doublingFixed: timing of external power button soundsFixed: oxytest emergency pressure interaction would trigger test soundFixed: vertical speed knob no sound when pulled Adjusted: timing of buzzsaw transitionFixed: engine buzzsaw, new samples; sharper sound after takeoff Fixed: mix of engine post rotationFixed: dynamic range in cabinFixed: FS20 no touchdown soundFixed: APU too loud from inside with door openFixed: Exterior sound coning smoothnessFixed: Exterior engine sound distancing Improved: ambience from sound leak when doors are openImproved: nose gear touchdown noiseImproved: exterior engine mixing/levelsImproved: Oxygen tray soundFixed: Interior engine tuning on groundFixed: Engine buzzsaw sound tweaks, less 'muddy' during TO rollFixed: some hyd sounds too audible from cockpitFixed: missing sound for FADEC gnd power buttonsFixed: BAT EMER 1&amp;2 play a double click when turned offFixed: Side 1&amp;2 isol button double clickFixed: double clicking of F/CTL buttonsFixed: double clicking of mobile com buttonFixed: double clicking of landscape cam buttonFixed: APU econ mode button doubling Fixed: Fuel refuel button double clicking Fixed: door locking sys double clickFixed: ground hf datalink double clickingFixed: lack of fader for air rushing reverse thrustFixed: cabin announcements not audible through cockpitFixed: FS20 ground rolling ignores volume settings and LF gainFixed: wing anti ice button double clickingFixed: no sound for eng anti ice 1 buttonFS24 vol increase on rotation gear thumpFS20 balancing tweaks to gear up sequenceFS20 aural callouts mixing adjustmentsFS20 Tweaks to equalise engine levels internal &amp; externalFS20 ground roll volume adjusted  The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flyctb</id>
    <title>flyt Releases Afonso Pena International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flyctb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68210ebbf16c0bbcbbe7d2f6_ctb1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt has recently released their rendition of Afonso Pena International Airport (SBCT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Curitiba, Brazil, with a yearly average of 5.1 million passengers. It was built by the Brazilian Air Force Ministry in partnership with the United States Army during World War 2, although it never really served its “wartime purpose” because it was completed only in 1945, as the lights were already going out on the battlefield.  Within a year of its completion, the airport was dedicated as a civil airport, which it has consistently been. The first passenger terminal remained in use until 1959, when a replacement one was built. It remained in use for nearly 40 years, until it was replaced by a much larger one in 1996. The old terminal was then converted into a cargo terminal. The airport was upgraded in 2009 during the government’s effort to bring all the major airports up to modern standards for the World Cup (2014). The government spent 30 million BRL on enlarged aprons, new taxiways, and better parking infrastructure. It’s a focus city for Azul, and served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Gol Linhas Aéreas, JetSmart Chile, LATAM Brazil, LATAM Chile, and LATAM Peru. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom terminal interior, custom ground service equipment, an up-to-date ground layout, and much more. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $12.99 (both platforms). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ibydlf</id>
    <title>iBlueYonder Publishes Trailer for Upcoming Dallas Love Field for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ibydlf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68150eebd242e9706093cee7_yonder9.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iBlueYonder has recently published a trailer for their upcoming Dallas Love Field (KDAL) for X-Plane 12, developed in partnership with StableSystem and joshomoore (they handled the porting process, as the scenery was originally made for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020). Dallas Love Field is the 31st busiest airport in the United States, with a yearly average of 6 million passengers, opened 105 years ago as a training camp for WW1 pilots and then converted into a storage facility for surplus aircraft right after the war, where it barely saw any action for nearly ten years. It was then purchased by the city of Dallas in 1928 and opened for civilian use, with the first set of paved runways to come four years later.  The first proper terminal was built in 1940, serving 21 weekday airline departures from American, Braniff, and Delta.  World War 2 forced the airport to return to its training school roots, only ceasing after it was all over when it once again returned to being a civil airport.  With the increased passenger numbers during the late 1950s came the need for a new terminal (T3) designed by Donald S. Nelson. It would have three concourses, 26 gates, and the world’s first moving walkways.  Nowadays, the airport has a single terminal with 20 gates, with Alaska and Delta Air Lines having one each, and the remaining 18 are under Southwest’s helm. Not coincidentally, Southwest Airlines has 95.3% of the passenger market share, followed by Delta with 2.2% and Alaska with 1.7%. Houston (387,000), Denver (367,000), and Atlanta (358,000) compose the top list of busiest destinations from Love Field. While an official feature list hasn’t been revealed yet, its ported nature probably means it won’t differ much from the original, which features custom ground textures, a high-detail terminal model with its interior, hand-crafted and hand-placed signage, custom night lighting, and more. There’s yet to be any information on pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kiwsam</id>
    <title>KiwiFlightSim Releases Faleolo International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kiwsam"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6823881bc83840ff694a2260_fale1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. KiwiFlightSim has recently released their rendition of Faleolo International Airport (NSFA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Apia, in Samoa. The United States Navy built it in the 1940s on land reclaimed by the New Zealand colonial administration as an airfield and naval base. The original runway was only 1,200 meters long, but it eventually expanded to 1,829 meters in 1943 to accommodate larger fighter jets. After the war, the airport became relatively underutilized, only seeing proper traffic after an upgrade in 1957 that allowed the conversion from seaplanes to land-based aircraft. An upgrade followed in the 1970s to create a 1,700-meter-long sealed runway less vulnerable to floods (common in the region). The new addition would allow larger jets like the Boeing 737 to fly into the airport. Further upgrades followed in the mid-1980s and early 2000s to make it able to handle even larger jet aircraft. Air New Zealand, Fiji Airways, Qantas, Samoa Airways, Talofa Airways, and Virgin Australia serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D modeled main terminal and its interior (plus VIP terminal, regional terminal, and tower, all with their respective interiors), custom night lighting, custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom GSX profile, and much more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.33, requiring at least 1.39 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rsgpri</id>
    <title>RealSimGear to Slash Prices Effective Immediately</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rsgpri"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68238bd438bddc19932f45b4_rsg1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. RealSimGear has recently announced a permanent price cut on some of their products. This is due to streamlining production and consequently lowering the manufacturing costs while keeping the same build quality, allowing them to sell the products at a more inviting price tag. Products such as their G1000 suite, for example, went from $2,199 to $1,699 while retaining the same build quality and not compromising on anything. The individual unit went down from $899 to $699.  Another price cut worth mentioning is the GNS530, which is now down to $299 from its original $449.  Please refer to their store page for further information on the products and their respective discounts. It’s worth noting that the discounts do not apply to the entire product line. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/syd2d5</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Sydney Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/syd2d5"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6823a35fc4d91a1d439dde4b_sid1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyTampa recently issued an update to their rendition of Sydney Airport (YSSY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which improves compatibility with the newly released platform, provides layout updates, fixes bugs, and more. Update 2.5 brings a vast list of changes and improvements, such as the addition of new ramp parking spots as per real life, new taxiways (D and J), the reworking of certain parking spots, the remodeling of the motorway tunnels under the runway, the addition of 3D fences, new taxiway lights, performance optimization work, etc. The complete changelog follows below: According to FlyTampa's Facebook page post, the update will be available for free in the next few hours.  The scenery is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $15.21, requiring at least 1.71 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfeddv</id>
    <title>SoFly Releases Hannover Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfeddv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682607e144d0006aa59c3fb9_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly has released its highly anticipated version of Hannover Airport (EDDV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The international airport serves over 5 million passengers annually, making it the ninth-largest airport in Germany. Hannover Airport opened its doors in 1952. In 1973, it expanded with the introduction of two modern passenger terminals, A and B, which are still in operation today. The final terminal, C, was inaugurated in 1998. In the year 2000, the airport was connected by rail to the town of Hamelin through Hannover, and Paderborn was linked by rail a few years later in 2003. Today, Hannover Airport serves as a focus city for several airlines, including Corendon Airlines Europe, Eurowings, and TUI fly Deutschland. With a range of other airlines operating, the airport offers destinations across Europe, accommodating over 5 million passengers each year. The scenery comes packed with features such as interactive scenery technology, dynamic airport environment, moving ground transport, interior modelling, high-resolution texturing and modelling, and so much more. The newly released Hannover Airport is now available directly from SoFly for approximately $25.22. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/m24su2</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 2 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/m24su2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674f7277bb1f0ce33ab07974_msfs24-2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft recently released the long-awaited Sim Update 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which brings a vast list of changes, fixes, and improvements to the product. Sim Update 2 aims to enhance the simulator’s stability and performance, adding many options to reduce the encumbrance on the hardware, allowing it to run better than before. Furthermore, loading times were improved, the rolling cache can now be reduced, and many other quality of life items. Refer to the list below for more information:  There’s also a sizable list of bug fixes, encompassing a vast number of items that were affecting the gameplay experience. Refer to the list below for more information:  The update also added FSR frame generation, a GPU-agnostic technology developed by AMD, but it may induce crashing with certain Nvidia GPUs. On the green side, there’s now native support for DLSS 4.0 with Multi Frame Generation. ‍ The default aircraft also underwent changes to fix bugs and bring improvements. Refer to the changelog below: ‍ ‍ Please refer to Microsoft’s blog post on the update for further information on each updated default aircraft.    Microsoft recommends Nvidia users to update their GPU drivers to the latest (576.40) for optimal performance and stability. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kdal12</id>
    <title>iBlueYonder Releases Dallas Love Field for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kdal12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6827654e100d75a5ab17ef05_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Developer iBlueYonder has released its latest scenery for X-Plane 12: Dallas Love Field (KDAL). Situated just over 5 nautical miles from downtown Dallas, this Texan airport accommodates more than 16 million passengers annually. Opened in 1917, the airport initially served as a training base for the U.S. Army Air Service during World War I. Following the war, it continued as a military air base until the City of Dallas purchased it in 1927, marking the beginning of civilian operations, with commercial flights starting shortly thereafter. During World War II, the airport was again utilized by the military. After the war, commercial traffic at the airport saw significant growth. Over the years, the airport has undergone various expansions and improvements. Today, it operates as a base for Southwest Airlines and JSX while also serving Delta Airlines. These airlines facilitate nearly 250,000 aircraft operations each year, handling over 16 million passengers. The scenery includes features such as a complete representation of the airport, a skyline of Dallas City, a detailed terminal interior, custom night lighting, hand-placed vegetation, and more. The newly released scenery is now available from SimMarket for approximately $21.16. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/146p12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Upcoming 146 Professional for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/146p12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682777dc36ed58fea3d9941b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight has recently launched the store page for the upcoming 146 Professional add-on for X-Plane 12. This new store page officially announces and provides a preview of the add-on, which has been specifically developed for X-Plane 12 in partnership with Thranda Design. The new add-on includes an enhanced flight model specifically reworked for X-Plane 12. The artwork has been upgraded as well, featuring decal-based text on the exterior. It also natively supports rain and wiper effects. Additionally, over 40 high-quality liveries will be included, and performance has been optimised to the fullest extent. Just Flight has announced that the add-on will be available at a new, lower price. Owners of the X-Plane 11 version of the 146 Professional will receive a discount. A specific release date and price have not been announced, but the website indicates that the add-on is coming soon. You can find the full store page here. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/772516</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/772516"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published a new development update concerning the arrival of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s Sim Update 2 and what it means to their product line and upcoming updates. According to Robert Randazzo, the update caught them off guard as they were preparing an update to make the 777F compatible with 24 and another update for the newly released 777-200ER (for both platforms). They were already getting the cloud services to distribute the files, but SU2 has temporarily halted it. The new SDK changes with SU 2 introduce a bunch of auditing features that threw many warnings on their 777, which they had to spend plenty of time (until this morning) fixing. However, as they don’t want any extra surprises, it was decided that it would be best to send the update over to the testing team to make sure everything is okay before actually rolling out an update. ‍ They anticipate the 777F going live on Monday for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024; the same applies to the 777-200ER update. ‍ The 777-300ER update for MSFS 2024 is still on track for next week, even though they ran into this little roadblock with the 777F. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmrsw</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Southwest Florida International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmrsw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6829098bd5aaec989e683a71_rsw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Southwest Florida International Airport (KRSW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Fort Myers and Southwest Florida and has a yearly average of 11 million passengers. RSW was built to replace Fort Myers' former main airport, Page Field, as it was considered too small and difficult to expand due to certain constraints (like a major highway, for example), starting anew elsewhere seemed the better idea. Construction started in 1980, and the airport was inaugurated on schedule three years later. It featured an 8400-foot runway and a terminal with 14 gates on two concourses. In 1993, a 50,000-square-foot Federal Inspection facility was annexed to the main concourse, and the runway was lengthened to 12,000 feet to better accommodate international service. The terminal underwent expansion in 1998 to keep up with the region's ever-growing demand for air travel. A new wing and three additional gates were added to Concourse B. An entirely new terminal project, with three concourses and 28 gates, started in 2002. Part of the original terminal had to be demolished to make room for the new one. It's an operating base for Breeze Airways, and served by Air Canada Rouge, Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Discover Airlines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Porter Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and WestJet. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, an official GSX profile, custom high-grade aerial imagery, basic interiors for performance, and much more. It's available on Contrail for roughly $18.00, requiring at least 3.82 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/77f519</id>
    <title>PMDG’s Boeing 777F Now Available for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/77f519"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently made its Boeing 777F fully compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which is now available through the new Operations Center for 2020 owners. After a few days of struggling with SU 2 (as per their last development update), PMDG has finally managed to get the 777F working properly in the new simulator. It is the first of the pre-2024 777s to get compatibility.  Owners of the 2020 version do not need to repurchase the addon, and new purchases will grant you the two versions. Furthermore, PMDG will submit the 777F to the in-game marketplace for intake, a process that is known to take a couple of weeks. The 2020 version also got an update, as it hasn’t been updated in a while, thanks to PMDG being busy with the 777-200ER. The changes include code optimizations, flight model and fly-by-wire improvements, systems updates, and bug fixes, along with new features such as the weight and balance application, and the inclusion of the SayIntentions datalink integration to both the 777-200ER and the 777F.  The 777-300ER is currently in testing for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and might become available later this week, but that will require further evaluation, and it is possible that it will only be ready next week. Regarding their next product, the 777L is being prepared for entry into testing, and they expect that to begin by the end of May. The addon is available at their store for $54.99.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/146x12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases 146 Professional for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/146x12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682df96e16e41561e1b69d06_146-professional-xplane-12_23_ss_l_250515150628%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight, in a partnership with Thranda Design, has released 146 Professional for X-Plane 12. Based on BAe 146, its rendition features eight variants:  146-100/-200/-300, 146-200QC/QT (QC - Quick change, QT - Quiet Trader), 146-300QT, as well as CC.Mk2 and CC.Mk3 (RAF VIP and cargo configurations, respectively). The BAe 146 is a short-haul regional airliner produced by British Aerospace between 1983 and 1994, when its improved version, named Avro RJ, replaced it. 221 146s were made, with the -200 variant being the most popular one, with 116 of them built. Powered by 4 Lycoming ALF 502R-5, it could carry between 70 and 112 passengers, depending on the version (70-82 on -100, 85-100 on -200, and 97-112 on -300), up to 35,000ft, and could cruise at M0.65. Just Flight’s rendition features a detailed exterior model with PBR textures, realistic animations of the lap mechanism, passenger and cargo doors, spoilers, and the iconic tail-mounted airbrake, custom-coded systems, immersive dynamic lighting, 3D sounds, realistic flight dynamic for the each variant, custom condensation and contrails effects, several options for navigation equipment (default X-Plane FMC, custom UFMC and RXP GTN750), as well as manuals and over 40 liveries of various 146 operators across the globe. ‍ ‍MODEL‍ ‍ ‍ COCKPIT ‍ ‍ TEXTURES AND LIVERIES ‍ Included liveries ‍ The 146 Professional for X-Plane 12 comes with a variety of airline liveries from the UK, USA, Australia, Europe and more. ‍ 146-100 ‍ 146-200 ‍ 146-200QC ‍ 146-200QT ‍ 146-300 ‍ 146-300 QT ‍ CC.Mk2 ‍ C.Mk 3 ‍ ‍ SOUNDS ‍ ‍ FLIGHT DYNAMICS ‍ SYSTEMS ‍ Custom-coded aircraft systems with a high degree of complexity and depth, including: ‍ Air-conditioning and pressurisation system: ‍ ‍ Auto-flight system: ‍ ‍ Flight Management Computer (UFMC): ‍        Communication system: ‍ ‍ Electrical system: ‍ ‍ Fire protection system: ‍ ‍ Flight controls: ‍ ‍ Fuel system: ‍ ‍ Hydraulic system: ‍ ‍ Ice and rain protection system: ‍ ‍ Indicating and recording systems: ‍ ‍ Landing gear: ‍ ‍ Navigation systems: ‍ ‍ Oxygen system: Flight crew and passenger oxygen systems with valve and mask deployment controls ‍ Pneumatic system: Realistic bleed air demand from engines and APU, and pneumatic supply to air-conditioning and ice protection systems. APU: ‍ ‍ Doors and stairs: ‍ ‍ Power plant: ‍ ‍ Lighting: ‍ ‍ OTHER FEATURES ‍ The 146 Professional is available for purchase on the Just Flight store for $44.99 and requires at least 5.7GB of disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sbf522</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates SimBrief With New Planning Tools</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sbf522"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682f8512b28460b396118fa3_simbrief1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph recently issued an update to its flight planning tool, SimBrief, adding an advanced thunderstorm avoidance system, a new route calculation engine, and more. SimBrief’s latest version—subscriber-only, though—added a wealth of features that, according to Navigraph, beat real-life dispatching tools even before the update.  With their all-new route calculator, it’s now possible to avoid specific SIGMETs along the way and plan a path around the weather. Furthermore, avoiding temporary flight restriction or ETOPS areas is also a breeze. ETOPS area avoidance makes it easier for people intending to replicate certain ferry flights on non-ETOPS-certified airplanes, providing them with a realistic and safe route.  In addition to these new features, you can now easily add oceanic tracks, instantly preview the route before its generation, choose specific SIDs and STARs from a dropdown list on the route calculator, and visualize them on the interactive map before ultimately picking one. ‍ Non-subscribers have not been forgotten, and they received three new updates: a flight history overhaul, expanded aircraft options, and easier equipment editing. ‍ The update is available right now and accessible through their website or app. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxisaw</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Sabiha Gökçen International Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxisaw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6830ef392ddd872a848df044_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MXI Design has recently launched its version of Sabiha Gökçen International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Serving as Istanbul's secondary international airport, it is also the second busiest airport in Turkey, accommodating over 41 million passengers each year. The airport opened in 2001, created to accommodate the growing number of both domestic and international passengers that Atatürk Airport could no longer handle. Construction of a new terminal began in 2008 and was completed in 2009. In 2023, the airport added a second runway, and there are plans to build new passenger terminals between the two runways. Today, the airport serves over 41 million passengers annually, facilitated by more than 240,000 aircraft movements. It operates as a hub for AJet and Pegasus Airlines, while also serving airlines such as British Airways, Flydubai, Qatar Airways, and many others. The newly released scenery features high-resolution PBR textures and modelling, interior modelling, custom jetways, an up-to-date airport layout, a custom GSX profile, and much more. MXI Design's version of Sabiha Gökçen International Airport is now available on Contrail for approximately $27.28. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
