<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-07-22T18:39:26.581429+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jff71024</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes F70/F100 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jff71024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6869d32b33660add59fc8754_fukka1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently published a new development update on their upcoming Fokker 70/100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showcasing their advancements on what allegedly pushes the boundaries of what their products can deliver. The developers take us on a test flight from Salzburg to Brussels using the latest beta version of their Fokker 100 Professional. They highlight that it is still very much a work in progress, with bugs and unfinished elements to be expected (and pointed out along the way). They start by showcasing the flight deck with its sweet mixture of CRT displays and analogue gauges from the beginning of the “glass cockpit” era. The texturing was made using reference imagery of the real aircraft, and it also includes customizable elements such as different taxi light configurations and multiple panel and instrument configurations across the F70 and 100. ‍ The externals have also been based on real imagery, with hand-placed rivets, screws, and panels.  ‍ Just Flight has also paid special attention to the cabin, bringing a meticulous craft of the Fokker 100’s different passenger cabin configurations, with internal and external cargo and passenger door options, changing per livery configuration. The work on the cabin is mostly complete, with the only remaining things being fine-tuning the lighting and integrating specific cabin-to-cockpit interactions. ‍ They have been focusing a lot on performance optimization, achieving FPS figures within 5% of the default 747 and 787 in MSFS 2020 with their latest F100 beta build. Just Flight reinforces that FPS figures will vary from machine to machine, scenery to scenery, and so on. They will encourage content creators to show performance figures once they are given access to the product for their reviews. The interactive checklists were included in full, housing over 300 items, 250 of which you are supposed to check before take-off, albeit most of them are only checked during the first flight of the day after a cold and dark startup. From all the tests and stuff, they have yet to complete the annunciator test, which involves a very specific, ordered illumination of all the cockpit annunciators. They captured a slow-motion video of this test from a real Fokker, allowing them to replicate it with maximum accuracy. Their FMS (Flight Management System) is custom-coded from scratch, including features such as IRS alignment (real-time and fast align), manual IRS alignment adjustment, manual flight plan entry, automatic and manual navaid tuning, navigation and performance monitoring, custom waypoint creation, and vertical navigation. They will dive deeper into the FMS in their upcoming marketing content and operations manual. The FMS on both the F70 and F100 is said to be the most complex system they have developed so far, as it’s the heart of the aircraft, interacting with the autopilot, flight model, EFIS displays, and other systems. This complexity takes time to develop and has been the most time-consuming part so far, but they consider it feature-complete as of now.  Based on recent testing, Just Flight claims their F70/F100 add-on is within 95% of real-world data, sometimes even reaching 100% accuracy in certain phases of the climb profile. The accuracy will continue to improve as the company further develops the product. Their Fokker 100 is already able to perform a successful autoland, although they have to be “extra vigilant” due to the beta nature of their aircraft.  There is no pricing or release date information yet, but Just Flight plans to share more information soon. They are very proud of how far they have come with their most ambitious project yet in terms of sheer complexity. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfa300b4upd</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes A300B4 Professional Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfa300b4upd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6869da53572cbc6fa12f343c_hundred1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight recently published a new development update on their upcoming Airbus A300B4 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update showcases the artwork on the now fully complete flight deck based on a real airframe (F-WUAB). The flight deck will be highly configurable, with multiple possible configurations toggleable via EFB or variant-dependent. While they are currently focusing on recreating the A300B4-203 variant fitted with an INS, they will also offer the option to use the UNS-1 FMS and TCAS VSI. A full list of all the possible configurations will be shared prior to the release. The passenger cabin is nearing completion, with over 200 seats and an interior design that screams 1980s. It’s said to perfectly capture the era, except for the cigarette smoke (which they jokingly considered adding to the feature request list). A dedicated feature update on their cabin progress is coming soon. Furthermore, Just Flight can finally share external shots of the A300 for the first time in the new platform (as it was initially intended for P3D). Upon platform transition, they decided to start nearly from scratch to meet MSFS’s visual standards. ‍ The work on the exterior modeling is said to be 95% complete, and the only things remaining are the second engine variant and the wing flex. Every rivet, screw, fastener, panel line, weathered surface, and text decal was carefully hand placed on the exterior, ensuring maximum accuracy. It’s a massive undertaking for an airplane this big. Their development team has recently revisited the real aircraft to gather more high-resolution images, filling specific gaps in their photograph collection and allowing them to detect certain discrepancies in previously textured areas, which have since been corrected. Systems-wise, they have now integrated the systems code into their MSFS version of the aircraft, meaning it is now “alive” in the simulator, and their internal testing team can start evaluating it. The systems integration happened later in the development stage because most was already complete due to their original P3D development effort, meaning their first MSFS build already features a highly advanced systems suite. ‍ The aircraft’s core systems are said to be fully custom-coded, aiming to achieve maximum fidelity. They exemplify the depth by mentioning how the A300 has 10 fuel pumps – two in each fuel tank –and the fuel pressure supplied by each pump is slightly different, varying every time you load into the aircraft, replicating what you’d see in the real aircraft. ‍ Systems-wise, most of what is still being worked on is navigation-related, such as the autopilot and the INS. Work is progressing well, though, and they will share more information on those soon in future development updates. ‍ There is still no release date or pricing information, but Threshold will keep you informed as development progresses. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a092</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a092"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/686485a644b302329c4aabc2_pip1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has issued the first update for their newly released Piper Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which includes changes to sounds, systems, the 3D model, and more. Given the aircraft’s early access nature, fast-paced updates will be commonplace, and update 0.9.2 is the first of many. The complete changelog follows below: Users are instructed to redownload the installer from the store and run it, regardless of whether they want to update or perform a complete reinstall. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiyqb</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Québec City International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiyqb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/686f0a8089cfc94f97b40b1e_quebec1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels recently released their rendition of Québec City Jean Lesage International Airport (CYQB) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Québec City metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 1.7 million passengers. It was established in 1939 as a military training facility for air observers, with the first flight only taking place two years later, on September 11, 1941. It was then known as RCAF Station L’Ancienne-Lorette, and its wartime foundation laid the essential infrastructure (runways, hangars, and control tower) that would eventually be adapted for civil use. Its transition from military to civil use happened when World War 2 ended, with the Department of Transport taking over immediately. Early commercial flights connected Québec to other major Canadian cities, fostering economic growth in the region. The 1950s and 1960s saw increased passenger numbers as air travel became more popular, requiring expansion work to accommodate the ever-growing number of people. Furthermore, the beginning of the jet age also demanded slightly longer jetways and aprons. In 2006, the administration invested over 65 million dollars in increasing the terminal’s passenger handling capacity and improving the overall quality of their services. The modernization included a terminal reconfiguration, the enlargement of waiting rooms, and the complete restructuring of the baggage handling area. The process was finished 2 years later, and the airport could now handle up to 1.4 million passengers. It was expanded again in 2011—at a cost of over 200 million dollars—doubling the terminal’s size. The project took 6 years to complete and also included a new runway, new taxiways, new deicing pads, and enhanced facilities. ‍ Two years after the conclusion of the terminal expansion, further work was carried out to link the domestic and international terminals. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality models, custom ground markings, custom autogen around the airport’s area, performance-friendly optimization, and X-Plane 12’s weather textures. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.49, requiring at least 931.19 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmqbcmsfs</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Québec City International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmqbcmsfs"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/686f143ff3bd79afed96602a_qbc1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Taimodels recently released their rendition of Québec City Jean Lesage International Airport (CYQB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the Québec City metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 1.7 million passengers. It was established in 1939 as a military training facility for air observers, with the first flight only taking place two years later, on September 11, 1941. It was then known as RCAF Station L’Ancienne-Lorette, and its wartime foundation laid the essential infrastructure (runways, hangars, and control tower) that would eventually be adapted for civil use. Its transition from military to civil use happened when World War 2 ended, with the Department of Transport taking over immediately. Early commercial flights connected Québec to other major Canadian cities, fostering economic growth in the region. The 1950s and 1960s saw increased passenger numbers as air travel became more popular, requiring expansion work to accommodate the ever-growing number of people. Furthermore, the beginning of the jet age also demanded slightly longer jetways and aprons. In 2006, the administration invested over 65 million dollars in increasing the terminal’s passenger handling capacity and improving the overall quality of their services. The modernization included a terminal reconfiguration, the enlargement of waiting rooms, and the complete restructuring of the baggage handling area. The process was finished 2 years later, and the airport could now handle up to 1.4 million passengers. It was expanded again in 2011—at a cost of over 200 million dollars—doubling the terminal’s size. The project took 6 years to complete and also included a new runway, new taxiways, new deicing pads, and enhanced facilities. Two years after the conclusion of the terminal expansion, further work was carried out to link the domestic and international terminals. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground markings, realistic terminals and cargo area, realistic lighting, custom taxiways and aprons, custom jetways, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.90, requiring at least 1.42 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg713</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg713"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670074421902159c8c578804_randy5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a new development update concerning their 777 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 and provided a concrete release date for its upcoming 777LR.  While PMDG was originally planning to push out a series of 777 updates a bit before FSExpo, they claim to have underestimated the amount of work required to prepare for it, ultimately deciding to hold off on pushing the updates until the dust was settled for good, in case something went wrong with the update. ‍ They anticipate Microsoft will push out the 777 lineup update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 sometime next week (777-300ER and 777F only), bringing it up to build 116. It’s mostly a cleanup update, with no new features per se. The same timeframe applies to the update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 users, which will become free for 2020 version owners. ‍   The 777-200ER, on the other hand, is having issues with Microsoft’s intake process, and it’s unknown whether it will be available next week alongside the other family members.  ‍ Build 166 will also be available for PMDG.com customers on Tuesday, marking the first time since the airplanes were released that there is version parity between the marketplace and their own storefront.  ‍ The upcoming 777-200LR is undergoing its final testing phase and is scheduled to be released on July 15th. FSExpo has significantly delayed their progress, though, so it might be pushed to the following week. As usual, it will be made available on the website first and then in the marketplace within two weeks, assuming the intake process goes well. ‍ Furthermore, PMDG has publicly addressed some of the questions they heard at FSExpo, where they held their booth for the first time despite being a long-term major sponsor. Along these questions, the 737NG is said to be coming “asap” to 2024, the 737Max could be coming soon, and PMDG might work on a 787.  ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a350v111</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a350v111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6874609563fcf76ffdc6da39_fifty1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently updated their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing new features, bug fixes, immersive visual improvements, and more. Update v1.1.1 brings the long-awaited Collimated HUD, delivering accurate projection and dynamics right in your eye line, improving situational awareness in any weather. They have also addressed community feedback on the MFDs not being clickable in VR. iniBuilds says this is related to how mouse interaction checks occur per screen, which sometimes fail in VR frame updates. They are still investigating it. Furthermore, some users noted that both cursors disappear when a text box is active, whereas that does not happen IRL. It was a design choice to avoid mouse input conflicts. ‍ The Hydraulic system logic has been fully overhauled, correcting an issue where the outer flaps wouldn’t extend when the hydraulics were lost, despite the SD page showing they should. The logic has been reworked and now operates as required. ‍ They also addressed community feedback on the ECAM memo formatting, which they claim to be accurate and based on a realistic MSN configuration and software version they had verified access to. ‍ The visual department has seen tweaks, improving the engine blur with more transitional texture stages for a smoother animation. The metal rendering has also been enhanced, elevating the realism. 2024 users also got improved advanced weathering effects, with dents, taped areas on wings, and more. The window blinds are now visible from the outside. After months of testing, the A350 is a week away from making its debut on Xbox (MSFS 2024 only). It will include the recently released ULR variant but won’t feature the HUD yet (but it’s well underway). The 2020 version is still undergoing testing. The complete changelog for the update follows below: Systems ‍ FIXED: GA phase stuck in engine-out condition in some cases   FIXED: Derotation law now correctly disengages during go-around   FIXED: Engine display no longer incorrectly shows TOGA during reverse   FIXED: PACK/NAI/WAI indications corrected   FIXED: Engine data on ECAM now disappears automatically when expected   FIXED: "STALL" warning no longer triggered with no visual/caution indication   FIXED: Incorrect AIR ENG2 BLEED FAULT no longer triggered when APU bleed turned on   FIXED: CHECK MIN FUEL AT DEST message now behaves correctly with SEC DEST logic   FIXED: SEC DEST button logic corrected   FIXED: FMS no longer indicates FLS when FLS is deselected   FIXED: Incorrect message shown regarding GA SOFT instead of THR MCT during engine-out go-around   FIXED: Engine out after V1 now properly transitions through takeoff phase without triggering go-around   FIXED: Clock, TAT, SAT, and ISA now show "XX" when IRS not aligned   FIXED: Pilot stored waypoint clickspots no longer overlap   FIXED: Not possible to add custom pilot waypoints on FIX INFO page — corrected   FIXED: INSERT NEXT WAYPOINT from ND now correctly inserts waypoint without blanking the FPLN   FIXED: V2 lower than Vls condition in edge case resolved  FIXED: Heading preset on ground now functioning correctly   FIXED: ND manually tuned M overlap corrected   FIXED: NM unit now appears for ILS approaches on PFD FIXED: Improvements to authentication and Navigraph check code   FIXED: WASM token request logic updated to only pass token when actively subscribed   ADDED: OIS settings now show subscription status notice for Navigraph users   ADDED: ETD IFE splash screen based on user feedback   FIXED: Lav tank and water tank state now correctly retained after extended flight duration FIXED: Improvements to authentication and Navigraph check code   FIXED: WASM token request logic updated to only pass token when actively subscribed   ADDED: OIS settings now show subscription status notice for Navigraph users   ADDED: ETD IFE splash screen based on user feedback   FIXED: Lav tank and water tank state now correctly retained after extended flight duration   FIXED: Leftover elements from pilot stored waypoint remained on display   FIXED: Brake temps begin decreasing during landing roll after overweight landing   FIXED: Added time delay for brake temperatures to display on SD   FIXED: PACK 1 and 2 can be operated without bleed incorrectly   FIXED: Aircraft import airway from Navigraph reversed in direction   FIXED: Arrival runway merged incorrectly into missed approach procedure   FIXED: "REFUEL PNL DOOR OPEN" ECAM message shown twice   FIXED: ADS-C status missing “ARMED” indication   FIXED: OPEN light does not illuminate during fuel jettison   TUNED: Brake cooling logic for overweight landings   CHECKED: Speed calculations between LBS and KG units for accuracy   FIXED: Pilot stored navaids not handled properly via WASM   FIXED: Idle reverse should display ~27% N1   FIXED: Message missing when unable to select BTV with BRK MED armed   FIXED: Autopilot cannot be disengaged by sidestick due to AP disconnect protection  FIXED: DME readout clipping on PFD     FIXED: Numerous WASM crashes ‍ EFB/OIS ‍ FIXED: SD mailbox message pagination now updates correctly   FIXED: APU FU now displays in correct unit when set to LBS   FIXED: OIS unable to manually disarm slides — corrected   FIXED: FO printouts now correctly display  FIXED: HUD declutter button position corrected   FIXED: HUD arm shape geometry corrected   FIXED: HUD red breakaway indicator corrected and repositioned (CN config)   FIXED: HUD position refinements based on user feedback   FIXED: HUD size, scale, and placement adjusted from default POV    ADDED: Option for fuel panel open/close if GSX bugged out ADDED: Ability to attach printout to CPT or FO side   IMPROVED: GSX behavior now includes slide disarming to prevent automatic deployment   ‍ ART ‍ FIXED: Engine PERF mode visibility corrected when cowling open on right engine   FIXED: Pilots no longer disappear at LOD0 from external view   FIXED: Cargo door handle angle corrected   FIXED: Reduced select texture sizes from 4K to 2K for performance optimization   FIXED: A6-EXD livery issues resolved   FIXED: Iberia livery — missing wing registration corrected   FIXED: Cathay B-LXP — exit sign clipping into floor corrected   FIXED: Qatar flag orientation corrected in FS2020 version   FIXED: Emirates — winglet logo no longer extends into leading edge   FIXED: D-AIXQ, D-AIXY and other livery .cfg file errors resolved   FIXED: CX B-LXP — missing jettison GW in FMS and overhead switches FIXED: LH cabin pack – business class aisle floor covers overlapping   FIXED: ULR Cabin (SQ) – Lights disappear from walls and ceiling while moving through cabin   FIXED: ULR Cabin – Missing toilet door and flush clickspots (LOD issue)   FIXED: Qsuite – reverse textures corrected   FIXED: A350-1000 Default Cabin – PCUAs appear dark (potential code issue)   FIXED: A350-1000 Default Cabin – Lights remain ON when they should be OFF   FIXED: A350-900 Default Cabin – FWD galley emissives remain ON   FIXED: Cathay livery – forward bulkhead low-res texture   FIXED: Cabin rear right side LOD issues (final 3/4)   FIXED: Zero-thickness cockpit element above 2nd jumpseat removed   FIXED: Cabin ceiling lights remain ON after full cold and dark   FIXED: Heavy snow visual clipping into fuselage on -1000 FIXED: LH cabin pack – business class aisle floor covers overlapping   FIXED: ULR Cabin (SQ) – Lights disappear from walls and ceiling while moving through cabin   FIXED: ULR Cabin – Missing toilet door and flush clickspots (LOD issue)   FIXED: Qatar Q-Suite Cabin – reverse textures corrected   FIXED: A350-1000 Default Cabin – PCUAs appear dark (potential code issue)   FIXED: A350-1000 Default Cabin – Lights remain ON when they should be OFF   FIXED: A350-900 Default Cabin – FWD galley emissives remain ON   FIXED: Cathay livery – forward bulkhead low-res texture   FIXED: Cabin rear right side LOD issues (final 3/4)   FIXED: Zero-thickness cockpit element above 2nd jumpseat removed   FIXED: Cabin ceiling lights remain ON after full cold and dark   FIXED: Heavy snow visual clipping into fuselage on -1000   FIXED: FO side pedal disc button animation now syncs with handle    IXED:  Flap split animation ‍ SOUNDS ‍ FIXED:  Remix avionics power on sound; variety in spool sound behaviour FIXED: Packs sound mixing toned down to be less overpowering  FIXED: CTR TK feed sound fixed FIXED: Engine initial start and lightoff aft volume bump FIXED: Engine external rumble on start bump FIXED: Engine whine level dropped during takeoff roll  FIXED: Higher N1 ranges fade out less quickly ‍ The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaerostar094</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaerostar094"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6876dc32fb46d3f3e7a24e14_aerostarupdate.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently issued a new update to their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing new fixes, features, and improvements to the flight deck. Update v0.9.4 – the second so far –adds new glass to the instruments, a new animated propeller spinner, further tuning to the flight model in slow speeds, VR view adjustments, autopilot tweaks, updated engine sounds, and a wealth of minor fixes. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ - New instruments glass - New shiny and animated prop spinner - Fine tuned slow flight - Adjusted VR default view - Added A600_STEERING_SWITCH_LEFT and A600_STEERING_SWITCH_RIGHT bindings for completeness. Same as MSFS STEERING INC/DEC shortcuts, no need to rebind. - Added wingtip shakes and wing bending physics - Aligned nose wheel doors when closed - Autopilot: fixed glideslope arming logic - Autopilot: improved NAV intercept - CHT gauge illumination - Clamshell door now droops if there is no hydraulic pressure - Compass light - Deeper Landing Gear Lever cut-out on panel - EDM790 display can pop up (ALT+CLICK) - Engine levers drag&amp;drop less sensitive - Engine sounds update - Engine vibration physics - Fix for radio frequencies not loading correctly on ramp start - Fixed ambient sounds when door is open - Fixed flickering magnetos - Fixed tooltips showing throttles at 99 max - Fuel drain bottle is now hidden by default - Increased the size of the interaction volumes (WIP) - Map light range reaches floor - Oat needle gap corrected - Potential fix for NeoFly compatibility - Restored German flag on the tail with German registration - Saving ventilation switches and levers, tablet position, marker selector - Set ui_certified_ceiling to fix "Back to Fly" MSFS keybind - Slip indicator doesn't flicker - VR collision mesh corrected - Working prop heat bindings - Yoke bank max angle increased - [Tablet] "Interior error" notification logic corrected - [Tablet] Autopilot pitch UP and DN functions inverted. - [Tablet] Empty weight corrected - [Tablet] Endurance in sync with EDM790 - [Tablet] Oil level adjustments fixed - [Tablet] The EFB app doesn't update when in the pocket The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfrjqf</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces RJ QT Freighter for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfrjqf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68791ed3787b92e1403b0210_announcing-the-rj-qt-freighter-v0-z1h17lok3gdf1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a post published on Social Media, Just Flight has revealed a new RJ QT variant, part of an upcoming update to its RJ Professional series for MSFS 2020 and 2024.  In a post published on Reddit, Martyn Northall, Head of Development at Just Flight, confirmed that the new Freighter variant of the RJ will be included as part of the previously announced MSFS 2024 compatibility update. While the update’s primary focus is to ensure full native support for MSFS 2024 and the 2024 Marketplace, it will also introduce several new features across both MSFS 2020 and 2024. Although the RJ QT Freighter never left the drawing board in real life, Just Flight has brought the design to life in MSFS, initially with four liveries: the prototype livery, FedEx, DHL, and TNT.  The update, including the freighter, will be provided free of charge to all existing RJ Professional owners, with more feature announcements expected soon. For all the latest on the RJ Professional and more flight simulation news, keep an eye on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da40ng</id>
    <title>COWS Announces DA40-NG for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da40ng"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/687929d65a70e30b8d410501_videoframe_12284.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS has unveiled the DA40-NG, a new addition to its growing lineup of general aviation aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The announcement was made in a recent video, posted to the developer’s official YouTube channel. Built on the foundation of the COWS DA40-XLS, the DA40-NG brings a modernised take on Diamond Aircraft’s popular single-engine trainer. The aircraft has been designed in collaboration with real-world DA40 pilots and features a handcrafted flight model. COWS describes the result as an “exceptionally accurate” simulation of the NG’s handling and performance, particularly well-suited for student training and procedural practice. The DA40-NG introduces several other features and enhancements. These include fully modelled circuit breakers, the Engine Indicating System (EIS), and custom cylinder physics modelling. The developer confirmed that the DA40-NG will be offered free of charge, to all existing DA40-XLS owners. While the initial release will be for MSFS 2020 and 2024, a version for X-Plane 12 is also planned at a later date. Stay tuned for more flight simulation news, right here on Threshold. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/efbxvp</id>
    <title>efbX Releases New Video Preview Showcasing Upcoming Plugin Features</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/efbxvp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/687975c9e816c998381b8d26_2024BL.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. efbX has just released a new video preview on YouTube and Instagram, showcasing the user interface and upcoming features. Built by real pilots, efbX is an upcoming fully customizable, multi-platform Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) designed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, 2024, and Prepar3D. It aims to provide professional-grade features and seamless integration. At the heart of the efbX experience is the App Store, which enables users to access all their third-party flight simulation applications in one convenient location. Although most previews show efbX running on an iPad, the platform is designed as a web-based application, and will be able to run on virtually any device. efbX itself will be completely free to run; in addition, a selection of starter apps will be included; however, apps in the App Store may be paid. ‍ efbX will feature integration with key services such as SimBrief, VATSIM and GSX, and will also support live weather updates. Compatibility will initially include MSFS 2020, MSFS 2024 and Prepar3D, with X-Plane support potentially coming in the future ‍ For more details and future announcements from efbX, visit their website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/plz55m</id>
    <title>Pepelatz Releases Yak-55M for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/plz55m"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6879766220453a7b7ef517f3_4.10_optimized_200.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Pepelatz Studio has recently released its debut aircraft for XP12, the Yakovlev Yak-55M, a Soviet-era, single-seat aerobatics plane, known for its extreme manoeuvrability. Developed in close collaboration with real-world Yak-55M pilots, the aircraft promises to deliver an authentic flight experience, designed for high-precision aerobatics. Created from scratch, the aircraft includes high-resolution PBR textures, photogrammetry-based geometry, and extensive cockpit detailing. Furthermore, the addon features accurate gauge behaviour and a vibration-simulated instrument panel. The addon gives the option to choose between Cold Start or Automatic Sequential Start, metric or imperial altimeters, and 8.33 or 25 kHz VHF radios. Flight dynamics were tuned with pilot input to reflect accurate behaviour across the entire flight envelope. The addon features a fully modelled M-14P engine, custom fuel, electrical, oil, and pneumatic systems, and includes a functional smoke system with weight impact. Failures and weather-dependent engine startup behaviour are also included. Included is an EFB interface that handles weight and balance, aircraft configuration, ground equipment, as well as an interactive walk-around. The addon comes with seven liveries, VR support an an FMOD sound suite with real-life recordings. The Pepelatz Yak-55M is available now on the X-Plane.org Store for $35.00. Stay updated with all the latest in flight simulation, right here on Threshold. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a164</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a164"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a8a712346f3e8020357cc_comanche4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, focusing primarily on the 2024 port but also making some new changes to the 2020 version.  Update v1.6.4 fixes an issue with dark screens on the PMS50 GTN 750 and on the falcon71 KLN 90B GPS units, addresses saved states not being read sometimes, and a series of minor glitches with the 2024 version were also wholly mitigated. The changelog follows below: Furthermore, A2A is running a storewide sale (does not apply to the newly released Aerostar, though), with a 25% discount. It runs for two weeks from July 17.  The add-on is available for $37.49 (discounted price) in their store.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd777116</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777 Lineup for MSFS 20/24 &amp; 777-200LR Releasing Later Today</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd777116"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6879aac33c0630174c848124_1250410_20240626232728_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has issued a new update to their 777 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, as mentioned in their previous development update from a few days ago. Furthermore, they have also confirmed the release of their 777-200LR for later today. Build 116 is now available for the 777-300ER, 777F, and 777-200ER via their operations center and marketplace (MSFS 2020 only for now), while the lineup should arrive in 2024's marketplace later today (or show up for people who already own the 2020 version). PMDG also clarifies that the 777 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is not exactly the same as that of the 2020 version. They have been built using the new SDK and underwent thousands of changes to ensure stability and performance. With the 777 workload easing off, PMDG will now focus on the 737NG for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. A short video of the cockpit door being operated will come soon. ‍ The DC-6, on the other hand, is still depending on an Asobo fix, as it has suffered from an LOD issue since the advent of SU 3. ‍ The 747's development team has gained new hands since the 777 folks are now free, meaning the process might speed up significantly from now on. Both 741 and 744 are in active development, and it's a "close horse race" to see which one will be released first. ‍ The 777-200LR, the last of the 777 variants promised by PMDG, will be released later today. In Randazzo's words, it is the "true long-haul monster of the family." The marketplace release will follow sometime in August. ‍ PMDG's product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to roughly $78. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksadl</id>
    <title>MK-Studios Announces Adelaide Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksadl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/687a812534da59310e53ee8a_518247775_1162998835848402_2036539352262162792_n%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK-Studios has revealed Adelaide Airport as its next project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with a release planned for next Friday. The scenery will support both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, with a new, walkable jetway feature reserved for the newer simulator and its walkaround mode.  Based on the announcement, the package will include a modelled terminal interior, and extensive detailing across the airport environment. Adelaide Airport is the primary airport serving Adelaide, in South Australia. Located roughly 6 kilometres west of the central business district, it is the country’s fifth-busiest airport by passenger volume, with over 8.5 million travellers passing through in the 2024 financial year. Adelaide Airport accommodates domestic, international, and general aviation traffic, serving as a hub for Virgin Australia, a focus city for Qantas, and an operating base for Jetstar. The airport was first established in 1955, and operates over 250 flights daily to more than 30 destinations across Oceania, Asia, and North America. Adelaide is also equipped to handle large aircraft, including the Boeing 747 and Airbus A380. Additional details are expected in the days leading up to release. For all the latest on upcoming scenery and developer news, stay up to date with Threshold. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl309</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo &amp; neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl309"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/687ac7f98fc52b4ce72b8314_309-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently issued a new experimental update to their A321ceo and ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, focusing on increasing stability, improving visual performance, and improving the handling, among other things. Update v11.0.1.309 aims to improve performance and lower VRAM usage, ensuring better headroom for users running very high resolutions or rocking cards with little VRAM to spare. Such extra headroom should warrant better stability in video memory-constrained environments, like approaching a demanding airport on top of a photogrammetric area. They have also mitigated certain CTDs that occasionally happen with very specific TCAS traffic situations and aircraft reloads. The steps taken to mitigate those should increase the overall robustness of their code, making it much more reliable. FSLabs has also worked on correcting an issue affecting the yaw behavior during the landing roll and retuning brake effectiveness based on measured stopping distances from real aircraft. These tweaks should bring more authenticity to the post-touchdown phase. ‍ Systems were also improved, with FMGC protections added, further improvements to the NEO engine logic, ROPS behavior, and many smaller fixes.  ‍ The complete changelog follows below: AOC Service:  ‍ ‍ APU: ‍ ‍ CIDS: ‍ ELAC: ‍ FMGC: ‍ ‍ FWC:  ‍ ‍ MCDU: ‍ ‍ Neo-specific: ‍ ‍ ROPS: ‍ ‍ Systems Improvements: ‍ ‍ Model Updates: ‍ ‍ The A321ceo and neo are available in their store for $69.95 each. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
