<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-04-29T18:20:42.043337+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmazan</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Zanzibar Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmazan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644441ea8177d415a147229d_zanzi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="516707"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Abeid Amani Karume International Airport (HTZA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Zanzibar City with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  The airport was built in the 1930s by the British colonial government, primarily as a military airfield. During World War II, the airfield was used as a base for Allied forces fighting in the East African campaign.  After the war, the airport was converted for civilian use and underwent significant upgrades in the 1960s.  In 2011, the airport was renamed Abeid Amani Karume International Airport in honor of the first President of Zanzibar, who played a significant role in the country's struggle for independence from British colonial rule.  In recent years, the airport has undergone significant renovations and upgrades, including constructing a new terminal building and expanding the apron to accommodate more aircraft. These improvements have helped increase the airport's capacity and overall passenger experience.  It's the hub for ZanAir, Zanzibar's domestic airline, with flights to Arusha, Dar es Salaam, Pemba Island, Saadani, and Selous. The visitors' list includes Air France, Air Tanzania, Azur Air, Coastal Aviation, Condor, Edelweiss Air, Ethiopian Airlines, Eurowings Discover, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, and Turkish Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, an updated ground layout, custom night lighting, and custom clutter.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.39, requiring at least 114.91 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dspxen</id>
    <title>Dark Space Releases xEnviro 1.20 for X-Plane 12 </title>
    <updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dspxen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64444ecdfebe30f7ba99323b_xe1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1395797"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Dark Space has recently released the long-awaited version 1.20 of xEnviro, making it fully compatible with X-Plane 12, bringing realistic weather simulation to the newly released flight simulation platform.  ‍ xEnviro 1.20 is an adaptation of 1.18 for the new platform, with a similar feature set and improved performance: no more than 10% of the framerate is compromised once the weather engine is running (using the recommended settings), making it more performant than 1.18 was. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ ### Added - New architecture to accomodate procedural changes. ‍ ### Changed - Sound processor temporary disabled. - Visual effects temporary disabled. - Cloud shader revision. - Shaders moved to HDR rendering. - More accurate light phase with glory and fogbow. - Default X-Plane precipitation temporary enabled. - Aerodrome surface set using X-Plane runway condition. - UI colors changed to match X-Plane palette. ‍ ### Removed - Sounds settings. - Realistic aerial perspective. - Realistic night perspective. - Control water waves. - Draw wet aerodrome surface. - Draw drifting snow. - Draw snow in mountains. - Seasonal changes. - Windshield effects. - Volumetric aircraft lights effect. - Lens flares. - Diffraction spikes. - Glorious sun. - Custom rain. - Custom snow. - City lights. ‍ The developer highlights that certain features were now temporarily removed and currently relying on native X-Plane functionalities, such as the xE sounds, waves, and seasonal changes. It is also stated that they will try to re-implement the features they have removed (refer to #removed in the changelog above). ‍ Featuring industry-standard sky modeling, physics-based cloud visualization, and weather and time-dependent changes in atmospheric lighting, xEnviro aims to bring truly volumetric clouds to the world of X-Plane 12. ‍ xE 1.20 is a free upgrade for previous owners of the X-Plane 11 version. They state it will remain a free upgrade for the foreseeable future: “All updates within 2023 and likely 2024 will be free. A transition to 2.0 version would necessitate a substantial upgrade from the current capabilities of version 1.18”, stated the developer. ‍ It’s available on Threshold Store for $69.69, requiring at least a GTX 1050Ti or equivalent for the bare minimum and an RTX 2070 or equivalent for optimal performance.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2ind</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Indianapolis Executive Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2ind" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64455214ce0dc4625b14dc76_indy1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="614498"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of the Indianapolis Executive Airport (KTYQ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, located in Zionsville, Indiana, serving the city of Indianapolis with a yearly average of 41,810 aircraft operations as of 2019.  The airport started its life as Terry Airport in 1957 by the hands of Campbell Aviation. It originally had two runways (a 1018x18m bituminous runway and a 914x61m turf runway), ten hangars, and an administration building. They eventually added 26 more hangars within a couple of years.  It was sold to a new company in 1965, which made a couple of upgrades to the airport thirteen later: the main runway got lengthened and widened to 1570x23, along with the addition of high-intensity runway lighting, visual approach slope indicators, a non-directional beacon, and an instrument landing system.  After getting classified as a reliever airport to Indianapolis International Airport in the 1980s, they got funding from the government to further improve the infrastructure, adding underdrains, extra land for approach protection, and a new runway lengthening to the current 1,700 meters.  The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with a meticulous reproduction of all the buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night effects, high-detail ground service equipment, performance-friendly optimization, complete set of signs, fencing, vegetation, PBR materials, static aircraft (optional), authentic internal details and parallax internals.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.87, requiring at least 47.58 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wigper</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Perales Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wigper" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64467a9e8cba02f09a404dd8_perales1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2411836"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Perales Airport (SKIB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ibagué in Colombia with a yearly average of 74,428 passengers as of 2019.  The airport was established in 1919, during the early years of aviation in Colombia, as a grass airstrip for military and civilian aircraft.  In 1933, the Colombian government began constructing a more permanent airport facility at the site, named Perales Airport, after the local area. The airport was officially inaugurated on February 7, 1934, with the landing of a Douglas DC-2 aircraft from the Colombian airline SCADTA (now Avianca).  During the mid-20th century, Perales Airport played an important role in the development of aviation in Colombia, serving as a stopover point for commercial flights between Bogota and the country's southern regions. In 1955, the airport was expanded by constructing a new terminal building and control tower, which remained in use until the early 21st century. ‍ The airport underwent a significant renovation and expansion project in 2018, which included the construction of a new passenger terminal and extending the runway to accommodate larger aircraft.   Perales National Airport is an important transportation hub for the Tolima Department and surrounding areas. It provides easy access to popular tourist destinations such as the Nevado del Tolima mountain range, the Cocora Valley, and the Los Nevados National Natural Park.  It's served by Avianca and EasyFly, with direct flights to Bogotá and Medellin-Olaya Herrera, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail terminal and its interior, realistic ground markings, custom night lighting, and an updated ground layout.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.17, requiring at least 272.55 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shasul</id>
    <title>Shadescene Releases Sultan Mahmud Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shasul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644682b9020cdaf0fd892d58_shade1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3736156"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Shadescene has recently released their rendition of Sultan Mahmud Airport (WMKN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Kuala Terengganu in Malaysia with a yearly average of 919,829 passengers as of 2019.  The airport was established in the 1920s as a small airfield, used primarily for military purposes during World War II, serving as a base for the British Royal Air Force (RAF) and the Japanese Imperial Army.  After the war, the British colonial authorities expanded and upgraded the airport to accommodate civilian air travel. It was renamed Sultan Mahmud Airport in honor of Sultan Mahmud Al-Muktafi Billah Shah, the 16th Sultan of Terengganu.  In the following years, Sultan Mahmud Airport became an important transportation hub for the Terengganu region, connecting it with other parts of Malaysia and neighboring countries. The airport underwent several upgrades and modernizations to keep pace with the region's air travel growth.  In 2008, a major renovation and expansion project was undertaken to upgrade the airport's facilities and increase its capacity. The project included constructing a new terminal building, a new runway, and other airport infrastructure improvements.  Today, Sultan Mahmud Airport is one of the busiest airports in Malaysia, serving as a vital economic driver for the Terengganu region, supporting tourism, trade, and other industries. The airport continues to evolve and expand to meet the growing demand for air travel in Malaysia and the surrounding regions.  It's served by four airlines: AirAsia (Kuala Lumpur-International), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur-Subang), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur-Subang), and Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur-International).   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with an accurate replica of the terminal, custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, high-resolution textures, custom jetways, hand-placed taxiways, and runway light system, custom night lighting, and hand-crafted ground markings and textures.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $9.87, requiring at least 544.11 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asoatr</id>
    <title>Asobo Studio Releases ATR 42-600 / 72-600 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asoatr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64485ebf8899e6ff178e1687_atr1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="866856"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo Studio has recently released the first aircraft of their high-authenticity focused Expert Series for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the ATR 42-600 and the ATR 72-600, aiming to deliver high fidelity at a lower price bracket.  The ATR lineup is an evolution of the combined effort between two companies: Aerospatiale (now Airbus) and Aeritalia (Leonardo), aiming to build a versatile regional airplane.  The ATR 42-600 is a twin-engine, high-wing turboprop seating up to fifty passengers, introduced in late 2012. It’s an updated ATR 42, the initial combined effort between Airbus and Leonardo in the 1980s. The “42” came from the original seat count.   Being a newer airframe, the 42-600 features a  modern glass cockpit, improved fuel efficiency, and overall performance compared to the older project. It can also take off and land on relatively short runways, making it perfect for regional operations.  The ATR 72-600 is a relatively stretched version of the ATR 42-600 with a seating configuration ranging from 70 to 78 seats, with a range of 850 miles, and cruising at 320 miles per hour.  The new ATRs come with seven liveries in total:  42-600  72-600  The ATR Bundle is available on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $19.99, with a 30% discount for deluxe/premium deluxe owners. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/micwux</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XIII for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/micwux" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64486647d324857123cc82fd_wu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="417672"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released a new World Update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing visual improvements to many countries in Oceania based on the latest aerial photographs, satellite imagery, and digital elevation modeling data (DEM).   The update includes Polynesia (Hawaii and Easter Island), Melanesia (Fiji, New Caledonia, New Guinea, Indonesia’s West Papua, and the Solomon Islands), the Galapagos Islands, and key regions of Antarctica. It rounds up to 13 countries and 28 non-sovereign territories. There’s also a list of 150 points of interest made by their partner, Orbx:   ‍ Hawaii   ‍ Antarctica Bases ‍ The update includes five new hand-crafted airports and a collection of dirt airstrips in Papua New Guinea: As usual with the world updates, Microsoft has also included discovery flights, landing challenges, and bush trips: ‍ DISCOVERY FLIGHTS   ‍ 3 LANDING CHALLENGES: ‍ 3 BUSH TRIPS: The full release notes for the update follow down below: ‍ AIRBUS 310-300 ‍ AIRPORTS   ‍ NAVIGATION   ‍ SDK   ‍ DEVMODE   ‍ SCENERY EDITOR   ‍ WASM The update is available right now for Microsoft Flight Simulator users. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/insjfk</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates John F. Kennedy International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/insjfk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64395589492ea780a1a402a4_idle2.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="671016"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their rendition of John F. Kennedy International Airport (KJFK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in New York City and one of the busiest in the World.  The update fixes jetway bugs, bumps in taxiways and runways, and general fixes. The full changelog follows down below:  v1.0.1 ‍ - Fixed T8 G1 jetway not moving. - Fixed T8 G31A jetway gap. - Fixed T1 G10 jetway clipping through connector. - Fixed T5 G9 clipping default A320neo when retracted. - Fixed T1 G9 jetway being too close to parking position. - Fixed stand A79A and N parking 5F directions. - Fixed bump on taxiway B between DA and DB. - Fixed T1 AI traffic levels. - Flattened bump in runway at DB intersection. - Gates 9-17 now reaching parked aircraft. - Flattened bump in 13L/31R.   The scenery features hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life airport landside recreation, accurately modeled and positioned lighting, high-detail models of all airport buildings and objects (and surroundings), accurate taxi signage, an updated layout, custom-built jetways with variations as per real life, a fully animated JFK AirTrain between each terminal, a precise representation of the famous Canarsie Approach, LOD optimization for every model, custom static aircraft (optional), and full compatibility with the iniManager scenery configurator. It also includes a replica of the TWA Hotel with an intricately detailed interior and the Constellation aircraft in TWA colors.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $25.04, requiring at least 4.25 GB of free hard disk space to install. The developers recommend uninstalling Asobo’s hand-crafted KJFK to avoid performance issues. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfdsfu</id>
    <title>Short Final Design Updates San Francisco International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfdsfu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644898c3966e391400cd3a0b_sfo1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="190895"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Short Final Design has recently updated their rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) to version 1.1, introducing X-Plane 12 features such as weather effects, 3D trees, and custom airport vehicles with sound.   SFO is the second-busiest airport in California, with a yearly average of 57 million passengers, only behind Los Angeles International.   It’s a hub for United Airlines (44% of the market share) and Alaska Airlines (10.66% of the market share) and is visited by multiple international carriers such as Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air New Zealand, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, and WestJet.  The update adds tridimensional trees (an X-Plane 12-only feature), an A380 jetway at gate B10, custom airport vehicles with animations and FMOD sounds (X-Plane 12 only), native weather effects (X-Plane 12 only), various sheds and antennas, the addressing of minor errors with ground markings, and the replacement of GroundTraffic with LST (requires installation).  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $26.95. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwoak</id>
    <title>BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim Release Oakland International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwoak" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644afa27fe28b5af1102202d_oak1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1407818"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim have teamed up to build a rendition of Oakland International Airport (KOAK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 5th busiest airport in California with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Opened in September 1927, OAK had the longest runway at the time, at 2,140 meters of extension. It became the airport of choice for many historical flights, such as Charlie Kingsford Smiths’ US-Australia flight in 1928 and Amelia Earhardt’s world circumnavigation (gone wrong).   Commercial service started in late 1927 by the wings of Boeing Air Transport, followed by Trans World Airlines (TWA) in 1932.   During World War 2, Oakland was used by the USAF as Naval Air Station Oakland, serving as an airlift base for flights to the Pacific islands, with passenger scheduled flights being all moved to San Francisco International.  It’s currently served by thirteen airlines: Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, Azores Airlines, Contour Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, JSX, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Volotea, and Volaris El Salvador. Las Vegas, Los Angeles, and San Diego are the busiest destinations, with 671,000, 448,000, and 391,000 passengers.  It’s a cargo hub for FedEx Express, with twenty-two destinations (domestic and international).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution custom ground textures, landside buildings, parallax windows, animated BART train, and airline codes assigned to each parking spot.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.56, requiring at least 2.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Cristian Ionescu for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teiipi</id>
    <title>Teikof Studio Releases San Luis Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teiipi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644afdce57febe5a7d24560c_ipi1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1657162"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Teikof Studio has recently released their rendition of San Luis Airport (SKIP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ipiales in Colombia.   The history of San Luis Airport dates back to the early 20th century when the first landing strip was built in the area. However, it was in the 1950s that the airport was officially inaugurated and began to operate commercial flights.  Throughout its history, San Luis Airport has played an essential role in the region's development, facilitating transportation and trade between the city of Ipiales and other cities in Colombia. In particular, the airport has been crucial for the tourism industry in the area, as it provides access to popular attractions such as the Santuario de las Lajas, a Gothic-style church built on a cliff overlooking the Guáitara River.  In recent years, San Luis Airport has undergone several renovations and upgrades to improve its infrastructure and capacity.   Despite its relatively small size, the airport plays a significant role in the economic and social development of the area. It is an important asset for the people of Ipiales and the surrounding communities.  Avianca and Satena serve it with flights to Bogotá and Cali.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal building and its interior, landmarks, custom ground markings, PBR textures, updated layout, and performance-oriented optimization.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.03, requiring at least 161.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfscha</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Brussels South Charleroi Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfscha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644b02c0815e532ccea279ef_bci1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3404817"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released the second version of their Brussels South Charleroi Airport (EBCI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Belgium with a yearly average of 8 million passengers.  Also known as Brussels-Charleroi Airport, it started as a training ground for pilots in 1919, keeping its training duties to this day with three flight schools.  ‍ Charleroi wasn’t a busy commercial airport until the late 1990s when Ryanair embraced it as one of their low-cost hubs. It’s now one of their continental bases, with many destinations. It wasn’t long until other LCCs wanted a piece of the cake, such as WizzAir, which forced them to build a new passenger terminal in 2008 and 2017, increasing the passenger handling capabilities from 5 to 10 million passengers, respectively.  It’s also home to Air Belgium, a scheduled and charter airline founded six years ago, offering many holiday destinations, including Guadeloupe, Martinique, Mauritius, and South Africa.  The V2 of Charleroi features custom airport buildings, custom vehicles, runway lengthening, improved runway lighting, and AFCAD changes. It’s a free upgrade for previous owners.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.87, requiring at least 473.08 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/penx12</id>
    <title>FS Designs Releases Pensacola International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/penx12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644b074def295c6a3d35e9fe_pensa1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1580647"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FS Designs has recently released their rendition of Pensacola International Airport (KPNS) for X-Plane 12, the second-busiest airport in North Florida with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers.  Pensacola got its first passenger terminal in 1935, with commercial service to begin two years later with Atlantic and Gulf Airlines, although very short-lived due to financial issues. National Airlines took over in 1938 with flights to Mobile and Jacksonville.  World War 2 saw the airport become a US Navy training facility, granting it a new control tower and runway.   The terminal was expanded 12 years ago at $35 million, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and modernizing the infrastructure. There are talks of a new concourse and parking expansion to come shortly.  American Airlines, American Express, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Silver Airways, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. Delta tops the market share chart with 26.04%, followed by Southwest and PSA Airlines with 21.63% and 10.87%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ortho imagery, high-quality 3D modeling, PBR texturing, custom 4K ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, up-to-date layout, and wear and tear effects using the latest technology.  It’s available on their store for $14.99, requiring at least 1.74 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksphl</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Philadelphia International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksphl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644bd6a6c68c7350c035891d_phl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3132915"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Philadelphia International Airport (KPHL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 21st busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 19.6 million passengers.  Philadelphia International started its life as a training airport back in 1925. For over 15 years, it didn’t even have a terminal building built in 1940, so airlines finally abandoned Camden Central Airport for it.   World War 2 converted the airport into a First Air Force training airfield, organizing and training various fighter and air bomber groups throughout the war. It was returned to civil control in September 1945.   It was granted international status that same year and got a new terminal in 1953, with further expansion in the late 1950s. By 1957, it was served by Eastern, TWA, United, American, National, Capital, Allegheny, and Delta.  The terminals were modernized for the first time in 1970, and new terminals followed in the same decade (D in 1973, E in 1977), costing around $300 million.  Nowadays, it’s a hub for American Airlines, with 63.75% of the market share, offering a huge list of destinations, domestic and international. Frontier takes second place with 11.02%, focusing on the domestic market and Central America. Spirit, Delta, and Southwest follow with 6.59%, 6.00%, and 4.51%.  The scenery features a high-fidelity rendition of the airport, with optimized texturing, main terminal interiors modeled, custom GSE vehicles, landside buildings, compatibility with most AI plugins, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.46, requiring at least 2.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrejt</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Previews E-Jets’  Authentic FMS </title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrejt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644d0149b7a25c1c07098cb3_xc1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1357105"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Marko Mamula, X-Crafts’ founder, has made an eight-minute video showcasing the progress on their FMS for the upcoming E-Jets Family release for X-Plane 11 and 12.   The video shows a step-by-step setup of two different routes, in America (Los Angeles to San Francisco) and Europe (Glasgow to London City), showing how the FMS handles altitude restrictions, etc.   The E-Jets Family by X-Crafts aims to bring highly detailed and accurate models of the interior and exterior of the entire lineup, with an authentic flight management system, autopilot modes, and realistic systems, helped by real E-Jet pilots and instructors.  The E-Jets are a series of regional jet airliners manufactured by Embraer, a Brazilian aerospace company. The E-Jets were introduced in 2004 with the E170 and E190 models and have since expanded to include the E175 and E195 models. They are designed for short- to medium-haul flights and can carry between 70 and 124 passengers, depending on the model. They are known for their efficiency, comfort, and versatility, making them a popular choice for regional airlines worldwide.  There’s still no information on a potential release date or pricing, but you can follow the development here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/apasfm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews A330 Sounds for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/apasfm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644d0c563d5903c067e309bb_kok1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1371680"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft’s Product Manager, has posted on their forum thread about the development progress on their upcoming Airbus A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator with two videos showcasing the work-in-progress sounds for the airplane. They mention having listened to it on a high-end audio system (Edifier R1700BT speakers driven by a Topping DX3 DAC), recommending everyone to play it as loud as possible to experience the quality of the sound set. The first video showcases the sounds as is, internally and externally. The second video has the headphone simulation activated, trying to mimic the behavior of a real-life Bose A20 Aviation Headset and its noise-canceling capabilities. They claim 99% of the customers have never been inside a real flight deck, therefore lacking a frame of reference, but also reinstating it’s as close as what a pilot hears as it gets.  P. Astarto, presumably one of their beta testers, shared two screenshots of a community-made AirAsia livery on taxi and take-off: There’s still no pricing and release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
