<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-07-12T18:28:53.600268+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ppegaa</id>
    <title>PYREEGUE Dev Co. Previews Belfast Airport (EGAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ppegaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ab9f64b1aa9917b4774100_Screenshot_3.thumb.png.e4f8bdd13e4a90635c1ccabb5b7db807.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="577474"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer PYREEGUE published a short update on its upcoming Belfast/Aldergrove International Airport (EGAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. In the update, the team previews the modeling, texturing, and lighting of the airport through a series of short videos, demonstrating their progress and the new technologies being implemented on the scenery. Based on the videos, it can be concluded that the airport's terminal has been mostly completed. As the plane taxied toward the gate, we can see that the overall building, signage, small objects (ground vehicles, AC units, etc), and lighting are almost fully modeled and textured. Additionally, we can see through the building’s window into the terminal interior where everything from chairs, vending machines, and walking passengers have been modeled/animated. According to the developers, what is being shown in the videos only represent a small portion of “new crazy things” that Belfast Airport will feature. The team also hinted that the new features brought to Belfast will come to “great stuff” featured in EGAA will eventually be integrated into its other airports, starting with EGPH before moving to EGPF, EGNX and EGPD. Currently, the developers are yet to announce a release date and pricing for Belfast airport, though they did indicate that they “are not far from release”. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. For more information on the scenery, check out a previous Threshold article.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflb23</id>
    <title>AirfoilLabs Launches First Microsoft Flight Simulator Aircraft: the Bristell B23</title>
    <updated>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflb23" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ad5addf9f79bf5a4e2876c_288675244_2240065689482813_6265946275129304151_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="760363"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Traditionally an aircraft-maker for X-Plane, AirfoilLabs have made a stunning leap into the Microsoft Flight Simulator market today with the announcement and release of the Bristell B23, a light sport aircraft from the Czech Republic. Sharing the news on Facebook, the developer raved about the relatively unknown LSA brand saying that the group have flown with their B23's real world counterparts. "Today, we have a pretty different announcement to make. For over a year and a half, we have been cooperating with an LSA Aircraft manufacturer, the BRISTELL." "Airfoillabs has heard the requests many of you have been asking for and, for the first time, introduces an aircraft model for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020." The aircraft was released at the same time as the announcement was made and is available on the Microsoft Marketplace for $24.99 USD. In the comments of the social media post, community users peppered questions regarding the developer's commitment to X-Plane 11 and 12 -- to which the developer remained steadfast. "This aircraft [the Bristell B23] will not be available for X-Plane, at least not yet. But we’re working on airplanes for X-Plane 12. We will be releasing the C172 NG digital once X-Plane 12 is available to the public, as well as the NG analogue version." The steam-gauge version of the group's C172 will be exclusively available on X-Plane 12. Difficulty surrounding porting to v11 and maintaining two versions is cited as the primary reasons behind this decision. See AirfoilLabs on Facebook here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/73pmdg</id>
    <title> PMDG Publishes Development Blog for MSFS 737 Series</title>
    <updated>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/73pmdg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62760542fbf0175a9b61a988_image_15258.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712230"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, PMDG published a lengthy development blog on its website where the developers shared the future plans for their popular 737-700 and 737-600 aircrafts for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Starting off the blog, the developer indicated that the current update cycle for the -700 will only carry bug fixes and small tweaks as the team focuses on improving visual features and animations within the cockpit to improve both user experience and the plane’s overall performance. Additionally, efforts are being diverted to repair the aircraft’s trim wheel animation whose code has been “accidentally reverted” to that of the original 737nGX for P3D. This means that the part has to be completely rebuilt and retested before the update can be pushed out, a process the team hopes to complete by the middle of next week. As for the -600, the developers confirmed the beta team will soon receive the new version carrying the “new PMDG Lateral Flight Path Model (LFPM) that has been under development for two years”. The LFPM will give a far more accurate, more true-to-life lateral flight path model”, improving realism and reducing errors. The new model will be first introduced in the -600 before being implemented onto the -700. The developers have indicated that they plan to implement the LFPM into all their existing P3D aircrafts. Due to the LFPM, the team is expecting the launch of the -600 to be delayed by a few weeks and will share more information on a potential release sometime next week after the new version has been tested. Finally, the team addressed the question of when will the aircrafts be made available in the MarketPlace. Currently, the -700 are being withheld from the MarketPlace due to concern of “incompatibility between [the] product and gamepad/twist grip/dual rudder axis controllers”. The developers are hoping to resolve this issue in the next update cycle and will provide more information soon. As for the -600, there will likely be a much shorter delay between its launch on the PMDG web store and MarketPlace. 	Currently, the -700 variant can be purchased for a reduced price of $69.99. As for the -600 variant, the developers are yet to announce an exact release date and pricing. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Credits to Cristian Ionescu from the Threshold Discord for the news scoop.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsdev</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Issues Lengthy Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsdev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ad6832c576e30f5be465f2_288647332_4779790138793825_2497002483118359383_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="500377"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios are planning to hit the second half of 2022 hard and bring three more aircraft to Microsoft Flight Simulator by the end of the year, according to a new development update issued today. Firstly, addressing an aircraft that's already available for the simulator, the developer discusses work on an Amphibian variant of the Kodiak 100. "The exterior and interior models have been completed. A significant amount of time has gone in re-engineering the interior of the aircraft so that it is compatible with Asobo's submodel and attachment system." The Kodiak's interior has seen similar treatment with new support for the platform's 'submodel' feature. The developer explains that this will allow a more efficient cockpit model -- this will also find its way into the other, wheeled, Kodiak currently available. SimWorks Studios' Vans RV-14 will also see some new content in the near future, with a GNS530 radio stack being made ready for rollout on PC and Xbox.  Onto the three in-development aircraft: the RV-10, Airvan and PC-12. The four-seat cousin of the RV-14, the Vans RV-10 is said to be making 'solid progress'. The developer says that the exterior model is undergoing review at the moment, with images to come in 'the next couple of weeks'. "Regarding the PC-12, we have our WIP exterior in the simulator and are dialing in the basic geometry, electrical and engine parameters. We are nitpicking at the exterior still, as some details of the aircraft were hard to come by.  "However, thanks to Pilatus and our pilots, we have everything we need and can soon dash to the finish line and focus on the cockpit!" Finally, the Gippsland Airvan -- according to this development update, the aircraft will come equipped with steam gauges and a GNS530 plus a Bendix-King unit to comprise the radio stack. As with the Kodiak, the instrument panel will be 'moldable', allowing for user customisation. See the full development update on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rksiup</id>
    <title>Pacific Islands Simulations Posts Development Updates on Incheon/Songdo Airport (RKSI)</title>
    <updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rksiup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b14d8ab1b014932dd68bf5_289440864_3126141987634129_7456268730579559754_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="514219"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pacific Islands Simulations has recently published on its Facebook page a short update on its upcoming Incheon/Songdo Airport (RKSI) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, informing the community on the team’s progress over the past few weeks and showcasing a few new previews. According to the developers, the terminal interiors have mostly been completed. From the pictures, we can see that the team has modeled and textured everything from the escalator, the glass doom, and shops such as Dunkin Donuts in great detail.  In addition to work on the interior, the taxiways, parking lots, drainage systems, and traffic tunnels have also been added - progress that is very much evident on the previews posted. Though the team has yet to set a firm release date for the product, they teased that development has entered the “final phases” for the airport. Currently, the developers are yet to announce the pricing of the product. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. For now, check out another Threshold article. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jffk70</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Fokker 100 &amp; 70 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jffk70" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b22ba377fb9d1a175969fa_287512483_10162001953168499_8760778841413427502_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="646260"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight have added a new aircraft to their list of in development products today in the form of the Fokker 100 (and the shortened 70 variant) for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  It is the second Fokker aircraft they've got on the go at the moment, with the F28 Fellowship also in the works. Learn more about that product here. "Just like in real-life, we will be following development of our Fokker F28 Fellowship for MSFS with its younger brother, the Fokker 100 and shortened Fokker 70," the developers said on Facebook. "Built with incredible detail to take full advantage of the MSFS platform, the exterior and cockpit modelling and texturing work is progressing very well, and we are aiming for a 2023 release." The developers maintain that the aircraft is still in the early stages, saying that the 3D model and textures have a decent headstart on the code and systems for the aircraft.  We can expect the Fokker 100/70 to be added to the group's website in the near future. In the meantime. 'enjoy these initial shots,' they say.  See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfgcrr</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Lanzarote Airport (GCRR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator </title>
    <updated>2022-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfgcrr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b5438d3e068627edecec46_gcrr-lanzarote-airport_2_ss_l_220620104231.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="144502"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, Just Flight released its newest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator - Lanzarote Airport (GCRR). The scenery, utilizing the latest available technologies, brings an immersive experience for pilots who are looking for a memorable summer in the Canary Islands.	 ‍ According to the developers, the airport will feature detailed exterior models and textures for terminals, ground signages, and other facilities, as well as realistic interiors for terminals 1 and 2. Additionally, the animated objects such as palm trees, flags, and fans have been placed around the field to further improve immersion. Finally, the product supports Visual Docking Guidance System (VDGS) and supporting software for the system will be installed simultaneously with the scenery. For the full list of the features, visit the developer’s website. Just Flight has warned the users that the airport’s “custom elevation data conflicts with the amazing Lanzarote scenery of Island Creations”. To ensure that both products can work seamlessly alongside each other, the team suggests the users “please turn off [Island Creation’s] 'mesh' package by removing it from the community folder or turning it off in the content manager”. Currently,  Lanzarote Airport can be purchased on Just Flight’s webstore for $20.49 USD. The developers recommend users to have at least 456MB of free space on their hard drives in order to successfully install the product. Please note that the product is not compatible with MSFS for Xbox. Credits to REM_13 from the Threshold Discord server for the news scoop</summary>
    <published>2022-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg3p</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737-700, Now Allows 3rd Party Modifications</title>
    <updated>2022-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg3p" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b6c068a2bd3423d4467253_280406865_5341956039177470_8848590533260663753_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="500941"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Today marks the second update in the space of a month for the PMDG 737-700 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which is now on version 3.00.0024. The developers say that this patch primarily brings 'behind the panel' improvements. This is due to the forthcoming rollout of a new lateral flight path model, which was discussed at length in the group's previous development status update earlier this month -- see that here. According to PMDG lead Robert Randazzo, "we are very close to turning [this] new feature on for you." "We have also spent an enormous amount of time investigating laggy animation problems. It is a painstakingly slow process, but we think we have made good progress in stabilizing some of the laggier items such as the control columns and throttles." "One item still in the research pool is the windshield wipers. We made a small amount of improvement here, but we are finding that the wipers move so fast (even at their slow setting) that they simply don't render smoothly and we are still working to see if we cannot devise a way to make that work more effectively. Stay tuned for more there." Randazzo also notes that the trim wheel's animation and sound are seeing some work. See the full changelog here: Looking to the future, the developer says that this week will focus on control configuration problems for users. This extends to both getting rudders correctly working on some joysticks and game-pads, as well as finetuning control balancing for proper feel. Also coming with this update is a revised EULA. This was not mentioned in the primary forum post for the patch, instead, Randazzo opted to post this separately.  In short, after some disputes from 3rd party creators over PMDG's tight leash on model/texture modifications (outside of liveries) leading to a number of DMCA takedowns, the group have changed their license agreement to allow this type of mod.  It is important to note that the new EULA still states that PMDG must be contacted before distributing new 'models, sounds or other files.' See the update forum post here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukkflg</id>
    <title>UK2000 Flagstaff (KFLG) Releasing Soon</title>
    <updated>2022-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukkflg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b77f215ca00db2e9dc8a90_288834023_1841523056053190_3211437326610278558_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="501965"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The no-longer constrained UK2000 scenery group have announced that Flagstaff, Arizona will be their next airport destination. The developer began creating scenery outside of their usual scope -- these fair isles -- at the start of the year with John Wayne being released in March. The developer cited both commercial motivations and a boredom with doing very similar UK airports as the main reasons for the change-up. A number of preview screenshots were published of Flagstaff this morning via Facebook, a selection of which are attached throughout this article. Fielding some user questions in the comments section of the same post, the developer confirmed that their next product following KFLG will indeed be a UK airport -- and that Flagstaff will not be coming to X-Plane. UK2000 is exclusively a Microsoft Flight Simulator developer, having suspending X-Plane development at the start of 2021 and similarly for Prepar3D at the end of the year. See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obvtsp</id>
    <title>Orbx Phuket for Microsoft Flight Simulator Released</title>
    <updated>2022-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obvtsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b8bab7fa20ff264db50247_2-4916a7ccf996095fbc4c4eec12643be7.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="341115"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Welcoming over 16 million passengers annually -- second only to Bangkok -- Phuket International Airport is Orbx's latest destination for Microsoft Flight Simulator and first in Thailand. The airport was introduced on Friday and in typical Orbx fashion, release was swift. "There are three terminals at Phuket Airport: international, domestic, and the recently completed Siam Land Private Jet Terminal. Thai Airlines and nearly 50 other airlines, including Etihad Airways and Air China, use the airport as a hub. All these have been expertly modelled with PBR," reads the release forum post. The feature list is as follows: Orbx Phuket is available for $28.96 AUD (approx. US$20.13 | €19,06 | £16.41) from OrbxDirect.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jse120</id>
    <title>Jemma Simulations Teases Embraer E120 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jse120" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62b933f1c8c4ca443c91724a_EMBext.thumb.jpg.6299dc803e3e210dac46cd6ebfdaa4d9.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="17520"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Jemma Simulations has recently unveiled the Embraer E120 as their newest project for X-Plane. The turbo-prop, a popular aircraft for regional airlines, will feature everything from 4k textures to fully animated circuit breakers, giving users an ultra realistic flying experience. 	According to the announcement, work on the E120 has just started. It can be seen from the pictures provided that the initial exterior and interior modeling is mostly complete, though the texturing process is yet to start. The finished aircraft, the developers teased, will include fully modeled and animated 3D cabin, customized FMOD sound pack, AVITAB, and a detailed exterior model with interactive elements such as access panels and ground element. 	Additionally, the E120 will come with “lots of liveries”. Air France, American Eagle, and United are among the many liveries teased in the post. Users will also have access to the plane’s paint kit upon release and will be able to customize the “tail numbers tied to specific liveries”. 	Currently, Jemma Simulations has yet to announce an estimated release date and pricing for the E120. Threshold will keep you updated on any new developments of the aircraft. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfzbaa</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studios Releases Beijing Capital International Airport (ZBAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator </title>
    <updated>2022-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfzbaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62bd2fe906d6274cc4e16f54_Screen%20Shot%202022-06-30%20at%201.07.18%20AM-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1721145"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WF Scenery Studios, a developer who focuses on Chinese airports, has recently released the newest product in their Microsoft Flight Simulator lineup - Beijing Capital International Airport (ZBAA). The airport, which utilizes PBR textures and custom lighting, will serve as the gateway for pilots to the heart of China.  	According to the product’s store page, WF Studio’s ZBAA is furnished with animated jetways, dynamic lighting, and accurate ground markings. In addition, the airport trains that connect the various sections of terminal 3 have been modeled, textured, and animated in detail. Finally, it can be seen from the photos that customized static aircraft and interior of the control tower are also included in the scenery. ‍ 	Beijing Capital Airport, one of the two international serving the capital of China, is located 32km from Beijing. It has three parallel runways and three terminals. The airport “has rapidly ascended in rankings of the world's busiest airports in the past decade”, serving more than 80 million passengers per year. 	Currently, ZBAA can be purchased on simMarket for EUR 23.90 or USD 25.24. For users who own the P3D version of the airport, the scenery can be bought for a reduced price of EUR 12; the discount should be automatically applied to eligible simMarket accounts. Credits to buffegg from the Threshold Discord for the news scoop. For more MSFS news, check out another Threshold article.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/berxp11</id>
    <title>Tailstrike Designs and Windsock Simulations Release Airport Bergamo V2 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/berxp11" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62be82382d4ce9926440c797_298773_lime-xp_24.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="307675"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Tailstrike Designs and Windsock Simulations have recently released Airport Bergamo v2 for X-Plane 11. The airport, a leap forward compared to its original version, brings updated terminals, animated jet bridges, and redesigned surrounding details. According to the scenery’s store page, Airport Bergamo v2 will reflect the latest layout of its real life counterpart in 2021, including the new north apron. It will feature high quality PBR textures, custom made signage, and full surrounding details instead of blurry satellite images. 	Additionally, the developers have indicated that scenery will have minimal impact on the performance of the simulators, ensuring that users can have a smooth flying experience. It is recommended that users have at least 4GB of free disk space in order to successfully install the product. 	Currently, the product can be purchased on simMarket or Aerosoft’s webstore for EUR 20.13 or USD 20.91. Owners of Airport Bergamo V1 for X-Plane can purchase the new version for a reduced price of EUR 10.07. Credits to Lazerzen from the Threshold Discord for the news scoop. For more X-Plane news, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jftgr1</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases Tornado GR1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jftgr1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62c27b1f3dba37e4dfeccaeb_TOR%203.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="112172"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Last week, Just Flight announced their newest project for Microsoft Flight Simulator - the Tornado GR1. The Tornado GR1, a step up from the developer’s Hawk T1, will bring the perfect experience for pilots looking for the thrill of high speed, low altitude flying. According to the developers, the Tornado GR1 will feature 8k textures and study-level systems. Judging by the pictures provided, the exterior and cockpit of the jet have been completely modeled and textured, including moving parts such as spoilers and reverse thrust buckets. At this stage, no feature list or any additional details have been provided, though the team promised to keep the community updated on the aircraft’s progress.  Tornado GR1, a collaboration between the UK, West Germany, and Italy, is designed to be a multirole military aircraft capable of carrying out a variety of anti-ground, intercepting, and air defense suppression missions. First produced in 1979, different variants of the Tornado saw action in the Gulf War of 1991, “Bosnian War, Kosovo War, Iraq War, in Libya during the 2011 Libyan civil war, as well as smaller roles in Afghanistan, Yemen, and Syria”. Currently, the developers are yet to announce the release date and pricing of the jet aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/togamu</id>
    <title>TOGA Simulations Mitsubishi MU-2 for X-Plane Releasing Friday</title>
    <updated>2022-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/togamu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62cb51008b9d36a2a0dabd84_MU2_2_Release.jpg.827eb705b75f8863126f4fdc7d74a5c6.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="72371"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. A familiar face with an unfamiliar name will be launching the reincarnation of the Mitsubishi MU-2 for X-Plane this week, with Tom Kyler -- most notably of IXEG -- completely overhauling the now 14 year old product. The product's release will coincide with the gazetting of a new name: X-Scenery is no more and will be replaced with TOGA Simulations to better align with the products the brand makes. The Mitsubishi MU-2 has been a prominent fixture on the X-Aviation store since its creation in 2008. In fact, it was the first product ever sold on the platform according to Cameron Son, the store's owner. Speaking on the X-Pilot forum, Son made the following announcement.  "Today, we're officially announcing Friday, July 15, 2022 as the release date for v2 of this great aircraft! This isn't just an update to the existing aircraft! It's an entirely new code base, 3D model and FMOD sound simulation. It is truly a new product." A specific release time was not given, though the American-based company said they're aiming for 'the afternoon on Friday'. Further information is expected in the coming days. There's been no word of a price yet either. This will be unveiled once the product page goes live later this week. Previous customers of the MU-2 can expect a $20 discount on v2, though these coupons will only be available for 60 days.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swkodi</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Details Kodiak Improvements</title>
    <updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swkodi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62cca56fadaf9474154325e2_293382350_4845411982231640_3219375507246419653_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="360957"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Software house SimWorks Studios have come forward today with more information on a large-scale update to their Quest Kodiak 100 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The details were shared via Facebook, with today's update focusing primarily on the handling characteristics of the aircraft. "Here is an update on the Kodiak packages. A big flight model update was delivered to us this past week, which will improve the response of the aircraft," the team wrote on social media. "Many people complained that the plane was very sensitive to pitch input, something we attributed to the short travel that most desktop yokes have." "After a long time of tweaking and balancing, the next update will improve this aspect of the Kodiak's handling." The new flight model also rectifies the Kodiak's performance, giving a more accurate reflection of the American aircraft after Sim Update 8 left the high-wing somewhat underpowered. The amphibian edition of the Kodiak is also seeing some nice progress according to the developer, even given "MSFS' flight model limitations" in this area. Before release, the aircraft will see some last fine tuning and get a sign off from Quest's parent company Daher. Speaking of a release window, SimWorks have said that both the wheeled Kodiak update and new Amphibian variant should be coming out after Sim Update 10 launches in mid- to late-August. This is to take advantage of new features coming in that update. See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
