<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-10-16T18:36:39.658678+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bb757b</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations 757 for MSFS Enters Beta Testing</title>
    <updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bb757b"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e6f29c83c40b344f7382f9_Octscreenshot1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. After several weeks of quiet development, BlueBird Simulations has moved its Boeing 757 into stage one of beta testing, the first time external testers have had access to the plane. In a brief message posted to their Discord server, BlueBird confirmed that while not every system is fully implemented yet, this new phase represents a significant step forward. BlueBird also posted a beta roadmap, outlining the three planned stages of the testing phase. BlueBird explained that this initial testing stage focuses on select systems, with external feedback now helping shape the aircraft’s refinement.  The team expects all three planned beta phases to take many months, stretching well into 2026, as they continue to polish systems and ensure stability across both MSFS 2020 and 2024. An in-depth update video and further screenshots are expected either later this year or shortly after the Christmas period. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw777</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Sound Set for PMDG 777 Releasing “Within a week”</title>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw777"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e825ae36e8fa413e131714_FZgv8Jl0EfI-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. After six months of hard work, Boris Vanian, of Boris Audio Works, has confirmed that his long-awaited PMDG 777 Sound Pack is finally imminent. The trailer showcases the 777’s immense presence in detail, from the hydraulics and engines to the individual cockpit switches and air conditioning.  Streamers are already getting early access, meaning first impressions and showcases should begin appearing shortly. Boris expects the official release to follow “within a week”, though an exact date has yet to be confirmed. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/738previews2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Teases 738NG for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/738previews2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610eb67b707eee4de3d07f4_1250410_20240201232913_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has published a teaser image of their upcoming Boeing 737-800NG for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The image shows the progress on the cabin, which is “not edited in any way, straight out of the sim,” they state. As previously announced, PMDG decided to bring a fully improved version of their 737NG lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 rather than just a compatibility patch. The new version includes a proper cabin, openable cockpit windows, and an overall quality bump on modeling and texturing, while also including MSFS 2024-only niceties such as the new walkaround mode. ‍ Development has recently sped up after the developers were finally done with the 777 lineup, shifting their efforts to bring the 737NG to the new platform. Considering how prevalent the NG is in real-world operations, this is perhaps one of the most awaited updates thus far.  ‍ ‍ There is still no information on the release date or the pricing, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflf2822</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases F28 Professional Update for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflf2822"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8ced3491c2df85c132c91_fukki1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has teased the progress on their v2.2 upgrade for the Fokker F28 Professional, which will land for free (for previous owners) on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 (PC and Xbox).  While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. They will also include MSFS 2024’s pre-flight walkaround mode and a new EFB tablet model with a window-mount option. The complete 2.2 changelog and release information will be published very soon. In addition to the ongoing work on the F70/F100 and the F28, Just Flight is also hard at work on an update for the 146, which includes MSFS 2024 compatibility. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimbkordxp12</id>
    <title>Nimbus Simulation Studios Teases Chicago O’Hare Intl for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimbkordxp12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8d1e05353762223a1f1f0_kord1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has recently previewed their progress on Chicago O’Hare International Airport (KORD) for X-Plane 12, the world’s fourth busiest airport, with a yearly average of 80 million passengers. Their new O’Hare aims to fully exploit X-Plane 12’s new technologies, bringing realistic wetness, season support, detailed terminal interiors, and much more.  There is no information on the release date yet, but they say it’s getting “closer and closer”. Pricing hasn’t been revealed either. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar2020comp</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations’ Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 Now MSFS 2020-compatible</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar2020comp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8f5cb32270f9082184456_aerostar2020.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. A2A Simulations has recently released the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version of their Accu-Sim Aerostar 600, which was initially only compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. As previously mentioned on their previous development update on Discord, the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version of the Aerostar 600 doesn’t bring full feature parity with the 2024 version due to limitations, such as the walkaround system, and dynamic wear and dirt visuals, but it includes the full Accu-sim fidelity and system depth aside from that.  The optional MSFS 2020 download is already available on the store page, and it is free for owners of the 2024 version. A fresh purchase warrants access to both versions. ‍ The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/at3401</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Detail A340-600 Pro for MSFS in New Video</title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/at3401"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e958a93b0e859a60623522_Baiix3leqhI-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has initiated a developer video series for the Airbus A340-600 Pro, sharing the most in-depth look yet at the upcoming jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  In this first episode, community manager Rafi speaks with ToLiss founder Torsten Liesk, outlining how the collaboration splits responsibilities, how the flight model has been built, and what systems depth to expect. ToLiss is handling aircraft systems, avionics, custom flight and engine models, and flight logic. Aerosoft is responsible for the 3D model, visuals, and publishing. The teams say this plays to their strengths, complex Airbus systems from ToLiss, art and presentation from Aerosoft. Rather than porting code straight from X-Plane, ToLiss has spent two years creating new flight, ground, and engine models, tailored to MSFS, that behave similarly to X-Plane.  That includes workarounds for MSFS limitations, such as MSFS supporting only one aileron per wing, and a ground-handling model, developed with McGill University, to improve tyre friction, braking, and taxi dynamics. The behaviour has been validated by real-world A340-600 pilots, aiming to match the same feel of the X-Plane version. Systems are modelled at the component level, including pumps, valves, actuators, and reservoirs, so actions and failures produce natural downstream effects, rather than scripted outcomes. The team is targeting around 200–250 user-triggerable failures across hydraulics, electrics, pneumatics, flight controls, and engines. The FMS will include secondary flight plans, route offsets, temporary edits, and constraint-aware VNAV, with managed and selected modes. For long flights, a situation save/load system offers automatic saves at user-defined intervals, allowing recovery after crashes or convenient mid-route pauses.  A “jump to next waypoint” is also available, with time and fuel adjustments. Confirmed integrations include Hoppie CPDLC/ACARS and SimBrief flight-plan import. Navigraph support is under evaluation due to MSFS differences from X-Plane. Aerosoft’s video is the first in a series that will continue to show off progress, towards an eventual launch. There is no release date or pricing yet. Previously, the team also shared a video highlighting various systems and fault modes present within the A346. We will keep an eye on the weekly updates and share key developments as they land. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mpb17</id>
    <title>MicroProse Releases B-17G Flying Fortress Early Access for MSFS 2024 </title>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mpb17"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e96fa5ee2f9b4571f83890_B-17_Valor_YouTube_thumbnail_out_now.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse has released its Boeing B-17G Flying Fortress for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the first entry in the studio’s Heritage Valour Collection. The add-on is available in Early Access, with development scheduled to continue through regular updates. The package focuses on historical detail. The cockpit, crew stations, and turret positions are fully modelled, and the sound set was captured from the real B-17, Sentimental Journey. A custom flight model has also been built for MSFS 2024.  At launch, you get five liveries and an in-sim clipboard for simple crew setup. Optional modern avionics, a maintenance mode, additional liveries, and expanded crew tools are planned for the Early Access phase. MicroProse says updates will roll out on a frequent cadence, adding features consistently, ahead of the full release.  The B-17G is available now via Just Flight at an introductory price of US$32.99, rising to US$39.99 on full release. The download is about 3.2 GB. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw777sp</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases PMDG B777 Sound Pack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw777sp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e9ffe7b88b3f092b9f854a_boris1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works recently released their PMDG B777 Sound Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The pack features all three engine variants (GE90, Trent 800, and PW4000) in incredible detail, with unique tonal character and authentic ambience.  In addition to the fully re-recorded engine sets, the pack also offers authentic cockpit and cabin ambience, detailed switch, hydraulic, and environmental systems, headphone simulation, subtle differences between older and newer GE engine variants, and much more. Developed in collaboration with Dave from Fenix Simulations - known for his commendable work on Fenix’s A320 lineup -, the 777 sound set redefines the PMDG 777 experience. Customers can buy the engines separately (GE90, Trent 800, and PW4000) for $7.83 each or the full pack for $14.92. Buyers of the 2024 version get the 2020 version for free, and vice versa. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fndpmt</id>
    <title>Flyndive Simulations Announces Paramotor for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fndpmt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ed4ecdb7e0bffcf9ecf42a_videoframe_31587.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flyndive Simulations has unveiled a paramotor add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, arriving on 24 Oct. 2025 for PC. The project is the studio’s first payware release, and supports both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Built by a paramotor pilot with over 25 years of real-world experience, the aircraft focuses on true-to-life feel and handling. The flight model has been tuned for ground roll, inflation, and in-air control inputs, aiming to mirror the nuances of powered paragliding.  A fully animated pilot model is also present, with control movements and posture changes also reflected. Flyndive says the package is designed to be lightweight, responsive, and approachable, offering a low-and-slow option for sightseeing, practice, or short hops around familiar fields.  The Flyndive Paramotor will be priced at $9.99 at launch, with purchase and download via the Flyndive Simulations website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaerostar101</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaerostar101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68e8f5cb32270f9082184456_aerostar2020.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, addressing an issue with the aircraft’s physics engine that was making it slightly faster than it should be.   The first update for the newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version only addresses a physics engine issue: the airplane would climb and cruise faster than its real counterpart. This update ensures it is “nerfed” back to its real-life specifications. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyepmi</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Teases Palma de Mallorca for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyepmi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ef8c50b5fd9474f9bf6bde_563570165_18059978660547769_5826007545702491729_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. After a run of acclaimed UK releases, Pyreegue Dev Co. is headed south to the Balearics and to one of Europe’s busiest leisure hubs, having recently teased Palma de Mallorca Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The first previews hint at Pyreegue’s usual obsession with detail, promising a richly observed take on Son Sant Joan. Palma is a staple holiday destination, packed with plenty of charter and low-cost traffic in real life, and just as popular in the sim. There is no release window or price yet; however, if Pyreegue’s track record is anything to go by, expect detailed modelling, thoughtful groundwork, and plenty of atmosphere and extra nuances. We will follow development closely. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsbabp</id>
    <title>Black Square Previews Baron and Bonanza Professional for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsbabp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68efd2fff34bb8373d80eaad_561529735_1246865394147042_3516564577051242450_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square is lining up a double act for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with Baron Professional and Bonanza Professional set to release in the coming weeks. They recently released some previews through Just Flight, and the first product videos are due next week. A money-saving bundle covering both aircraft will be available at launch. If you already own the Steam Gauge editions, look for an email confirming a 20% discount.  The respective product pages are also up, in both single and bundle deals. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaerostar102</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaerostar102"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has released updates to the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 versions of the Accu-Sim Aerostar 600, fixing various bugs in both and adding GPS unit real-time detection (2024 only).  Update v1.0.1 (MSFS 2024) adds the aforementioned GPS unit real-time detection, the noise cancellation device tooltip now shows its battery state, the right magneto bindings were fixed, the rare autopilot initialization issue was wholly mitigated, and some typos were addressed. Update v1.0.2 (MSFS 2020), on the other hand, fixes a problem with the GPSS not tracking the magenta line correctly and addresses the autopilot pitch reference bindings. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilyr</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Svalbard Airport Longyear for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilyr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f0d927cac4ddc2c4d92544_ForumBannerSceneryENSB.png.42eb0ead74d2c18b0b303897758efe4f.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds is heading far north, with a detailed rendition of Svalbard Airport, Longyear (ENSB), for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Billed as one of the world’s northernmost commercial airports, this Arctic outpost will arrive pretty soon, with a launch price of $13,42, excluding sales tax. Operationally, ENSB links Svalbard to mainland Norway, with scheduled flights to Oslo and Tromsø, as well as seasonal and charter services that support tourism and research. iniBuilds says the package captures the isolation and atmosphere of “polar” aviation, with custom ground textures across the airfield, bespoke night lighting, and carefully modelled landside areas, even including the famous Global Seed Vault on Platåberget. Terminal interiors feature parallax and bespoke assets, and the airside environment is modelled with accurate ground clutter, signage, and static aircraft, including helicopters and a C172. The area surrounding the airport is also modelled. A custom GSX profile is included, and all models have LODs incorporated. Set against a collection of steep mountains, sea ice, and rapidly changing weather, Longyearbyen is the perfect place for fun approaches. We’ll keep you updated on its release. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xce210</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Updates E-Jets Family With Live Weather Radar, Shares Roadmap</title>
    <updated>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xce210"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f0f3e811054ee098a5057b_E-Jets-Family-X-Crafts-Weather-Radar-Update-02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. X-Crafts has just released version 2.1.0 of their E-Jets Family for XP12,  a free update that brings a fully integrated weather radar, a string of fixes and some quality-of-life tweaks.  Tied into XP12.3’s new precipitation data, the radar paints real returns on the PFD and MFD. v2.1.0 also smooths flight director behaviour after take-off, adds new HSI modes, including full compass, arc, and an arc-with-flight-plan option, and lets you hide the missed approach from the map. Cabin lighting bleed-through at night has been fixed, EFB crashes have been addressed, and overall compatibility with XP12.3 has been confirmed.  Looking ahead, X-Crafts is planning a free E-Jets 3.1 update, with the same radar tech and further map improvements, a new, from-the-ground-up ERJ Family 2.0 for XP12, and the next-gen, E-Jets Family 3.0. What’s New in v2.1.0 You can download v2.1.0 via SkunkCrafts or by re-downloading from your store account. New customers can purchase the E-Jets in various single and bundle deals, ranging from $74.95 to $149.95. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
