<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-11-08T18:29:07.891570+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oxfs24</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases an Update on FS2024 Product Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oxfs24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67227fc503596d64b591900b_Header2.png.80d4236c4db10cdc5155de38183ae3b1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. As the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 release is scheduled to be in a little less than 21 days, Orbx has released a statement on the compatibility of their products with the upcoming simulator.  Even though existing FS20 addons should work out-of-the-box in FS24, the new simulator will bring loads of new features that many developers may want to utilise. One of them is Orbx. In the forum post, they stated that the product transition will be smooth, but will take some time. The most recent and popular sceneries will be the priority during the transition. ‍ Another detail that was mentioned in the statement was the upgrade fee. In case the product update will take some advantages of the FS24, the customers may expect a small upgrade fee.  ‍ As always, Threshold will keep you updated with all new information about FS2024! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/h8kcab</id>
    <title>Hangar Studios 713 Releases Super Decathlon 8KCAB for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/h8kcab"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6722921a08695077ddbdd620_670c9b225add7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Hangar Studios 713 has released previews of their upcoming aircraft for MSFS - Super Decathlon 8KCAB. Designed for flight training, this two-seat taildragger is capable of withstanding G-forces between +6G and -5G.  Designed by the Champion Aircraft Corporation, the 8KCAB was based on the Citabria, another aircraft designed by the same manufacturer, although with higher resistance to the negative G forces, allowing it to perform more acrobatic manoeuvres. Powered by a single Lycoming IO-320, it can cruise at altitudes up to 15,800ft, with a cruise speed of around 125kts and a maximum range of around 420nmi. Hangar Studios 713’s rendition of Super Decathlon features an authentic flight model, detailed 3D texturing and modelling, a smoke system for airshows, and interactive elements such as a modelled engine and animated doors and windows. ‍ The Super Decathlon 8KCAB is available for purchase at Hangar Studios 713 website, as well as Orbx Direct for roughly 19,99 $. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold fore more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ediraq</id>
    <title>DCS Iraq Map Available for Pre-purchase</title>
    <updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ediraq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67229e95f2ee5ca8719d29c6_Screenshot%202024-10-30%20214806.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has just released another Middle-eastern map for pre-ordering: Iraq. One of the most important parts of the world for air combat in the 20th and 21st centuries finally received its own map. It will cover more than 1,820,000km² Three versions of this map are available for purchase: Iraq, Iraq North and Iraq South.  The map division is the same as with the previous maps, such as Afghanistan. For example, if one buys Iraq North, they will receive the whole map, however, only the northern part of the map (the blue area in the picture) will be of higher detail. The same can be applied to to Iraq South map. The full version of the map will include more detailed areas of both the North and South(green and blue areas), while the rest will be of lower detail. The Iraq North map will cover more than 321,700km² of the detail area with 17 highly detailed airfields, some of them being: Baghdad Intl’, Erbil Intl’, Sulayimaniyah Intl’, Kirkuk Intl’, K1 Base, H2/3 Base, Mosul and other. It will cover mostly the territory of Iraq, with smaller parts of Iran and Syria.  Its counterpart, the Iraq South map on the other hand covers around 491,500km² of detailed area with 14 detailed airfields: Kuwait Intl’, King Fahd Intl’ (Dammam), Bahrain Intl’, Doha Intl’, King Abdulaziz (air base near Dammam), Jubail Naval…  Unfortunately, the Iraq South Map will not be available for pre-purchasing or early access. The pricing of the maps during the pre-purchase period (ending in Q4 2024) is as follows: After the pre-purchase period ends, the early access -20% discount will only apply to the Iraq map, as the Iraq North map EA price will be the same as the full release price. Eagle Dynamics has released a trailer for the upcoming map on their YouTube channel. If you have any more questions about the Afghanistan map, you may find your answers here. ‍ The Early Access release is expected for Q4 2024, but as always Threshold will keep you updated with new info about the map! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fb380a</id>
    <title>FlyByWire Simulations Releases Airbus A380 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fb380a"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672403756f57fd8552c33ac1_a380-01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlyByWire Simulations recently released their long-awaited rendition of the Airbus A380 for Microsoft Flight Simulator in an open alpha stage. It has enough operability for A to B flights, but many systems are still under development.  Their goal is to enable access to outside contributors and developers, provide the community with an early look, and actively work on further developing it over time with more features and tweaks. Due to the aircraft's sheer complexity and its current open alpha nature, performance is significantly more demanding than that of most payware aircraft. It requires at least an RTX 4080 Super for 1440p@60 at ultra and at least a GTX 1060 6 GB for 1080p at 30 fps on low settings. The current release (subject to change in the future as it is an early alpha) features a custom flight management system based on their updated fms-v2 implementation, with support for all ARINC424 leg types, holding support, and more. Furthermore, it accurately represents the primary flight display, navigation display, engine and warning display, and system display, with precise MEMOs for numerous systems and integrated checklists for normal and abnormal procedures. It also includes a comprehensive simulation of the core aircraft systems and 140 potential failures, although full simulation is not guaranteed at this development stage. Other features include realistic flight control surfaces, dynamic wing flex, Brake to Vacate capabilities, Runway Overrun Warning/Protection, and OANS (Onboard Airport Navigation System), which aids situational awareness by displaying a virtual airport map.  ‍ Regarding future MSFS 2024 compatibility, FlyByWire has stated that it won't be available for the new platform as soon as it is out due to the significant amount of effort required due to differences in system requirements and 3D model optimizations, among other things. They will not be sticking to any specific timeline at the moment. ‍ The A380X is available for free on the FlyByWire installer. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kfsrar</id>
    <title>KiwiFlightSim Releases Rarotonga International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kfsrar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6724080eba7a9a50472d80d8_raro1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. KiwiFlightSim has recently released their rendition of Rarotonga International Airport (NCRG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Avarua in the Cook Islands, with a yearly average of 350,000 passengers. Built in 1944 by the United States Army Air Forces to support their Pacific campaign, establishing a vital link in the Allied supply chain by facilitating the transportation of troops and supplies to the frontlines, it marked a significant milestone in Rarotonga’s development, opening up the island to the outside world. The 5000-foot-long airstrip remained operational after the war, serving as a stopover point for trans-Pacific flights. It was not until the 1970s that it underwent a major overhaul to properly embrace the jet age and its steeper runway length and ground infrastructure requirements.  Twenty-one years ago, the terminal, departure, and check-in areas were heavily revamped to meet modern standards, and six years later, the terminal was reconstructed and expanded to accommodate the new passenger traffic demands. It’s a hub for Air Rarotonga, and Air New Zealand, Air Tahiti, Hawaiian Airlines, and JetStar also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, custom ground markings, five detailed interiors, detailed surrounding buildings, custom night lighting, custom runway textures, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.29, requiring at least 1.82 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p74710</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup and Previews Upcoming Boeing 747</title>
    <updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p74710"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660b6ad17d5c0c0dd40fa5d2_1250410_20231128215337_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently issued a new update to their Boeing 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update brings further stability fixes to the Universal Flight Tablet and fixes the broken pushback module from the previous build. The update is already available via the Operations Center for PMDG.com customers, whereas marketplace owners must wait until it goes through Microsoft's intake process. No changelog was provided with the update because of its tiny nature. They have also provided further information on their upcoming Boeing 777F for MSFS 2020 and 2024. As previously mentioned during their last development update, PMDG is unaware of how many changes will be required to function correctly in the new platform. As they waited for that to become clear, they sorted out issues related to the main deck cargo system and thoroughly tested items such as lighting and cargo door controls. It's said to be in great shape regarding operability, but they are taking their time to improve gameplay features they consider essential. In Randazzo's own words, streamers will receive their copy of the upcoming product "shortly." While part of their team works hard on the new triple seven variant, their 747 team is also hard at work on their new project, the Boeing 747-100 (and the -400). PMDG claims to have unprecedented access to a broad range of expertise, which will help make the 747 for MSFS their "lifetime project." They plan out on covering the entire 747 product line for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with the initial entries being the aforementioned 747-100 and the 747-400, but other variants such as the 747SP are also in the plans, and even some special projects like the RA001, Air Force One, and the original test-flight bird. ‍ It is intended to be a love letter to the iconic aircraft, with an enormous amount of effort being put into making it happen. Below is a work-in-progress image of the overhead panel: Their product is available on PMDG.com and in the Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/twdnar</id>
    <title>TearWearDesigns Releases Northwest Arkansas Regional Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/twdnar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672412239d5400fbc8e34135_na1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TearWearDesigns recently released their rendition of Northwest Arkansas Regional Airport (KXNA) for X-Plane 11 and 12. The airport serves Bentonville, Fayetteville, Springdale, and Rogers in Arkansas and has a yearly average of 1.9 million passengers. It opened in late 1998 to replace Fayeteville’s Drake Field as the region’s main airport, as the latter was deemed too small to accommodate the ever-growing passenger traffic demand. After nine years, the airport was expanded for the first time by constructing a new concourse, which increased the number of aircraft parking positions from twelve to twenty. In the 2010s, it was further expanded with an additional 4,700 square meters and twelve upper-level gates, which cost the administration around $21 million. A new concourse project was approved a few years ago. It will allow the airport to use the gates more efficiently and handle a higher passenger traffic volume. The cost estimate for the undertaking is around $35 million to $50 million. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, 3D vegetation, hand-placed night lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.98, requiring at least 1.04 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniinn</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Innsbruck Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniinn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672503c496a3c5fca79f85d7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iniBuilds has released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator (both 2020 and 2024), featuring Innsbruck Airport (LOWI). This airport, known for its challenging approach, serves the Austrian city of Innsbruck, which is nestled between the Alps. Each year, Innsbruck Airport welcomes over 900.000 passengers. The airport opened in 1925 with the goal of connecting the city to Munich by air. However, it soon became evident how challenging it was to land and take off in an airport surrounded by mountains. The airport played a significant role during the Winter Olympics held in Innsbruck in 1964 and 1976. Over the years, the airport has undergone various upgrades and improvements, enhancing both its capacity and safety for travelers. Today, it offers a range of both year-round and seasonal routes, supported by airlines such as Austrian Airlines, easyJet, and Eurowings, among others. Last year, the airport served 900.000 passengers. The new rendition of Innsbruck Airport features hand-crafted ground textures, an authentic airport landside, dynamic lighting, highly detailed airport buildings, an official GSX profile, and much more. The scenery requires a total of 5.41 GB of storage space and is available for $19.48 on the iniBuilds Store.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfrjre</id>
    <title>Just Flight RJ Professional Release Imminent </title>
    <updated>2024-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfrjre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672933f0d151142928d69b1e_465288144_962022285964689_7810937860046070195_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight has just confirmed on their social media accounts that the long-awaited RJ Professional for MSFS will be released soon! The pre-release coverage by streamers has already begun, and a couple of popular flight sim streamers have already received it.  The RJ Professional is based on Avro RJ, a modernised version of BAe 146, a 4-engined regional airliner that usually saw usage at smaller airports around the globe. With 387 numbers built, it was the most successful British-made civil aircraft. It has also received its rendition in the simulator by Just Flight. Along with pre-release streams, Just Flight has also started posting more details about the RJ, such as the guide to differences between RJ and BAe 146. Unfortunately, no news about the release date or the pricing has been revealed, but as always, Threshold will keep you updated! Stay tuned to Threshold for more news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/linxp2</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Publishes New Development Update for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/linxp2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67297fe1a12555018842ecab_lineage1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts recently published a new development update concerning their upcoming Embraer Lineage 1000 add-on, a 50 million dollar ultra-large business jet variant of the popular Embraer 190 with an 8500 km range. Cabin texturization is nearing completion. They will next animate the window blinds, cabin doors, and all tables, add customizable lighting throughout the cabin, create a custom fuel system with additional tanks, and add new EFB stuff. Their custom interior will include different zones made with ultra-high resolution materials and heavy optimization work to warrant smooth performance despite the level of detail. Regarding cabin accuracy, the developer claims to have access to a real Embraer Lineage, allowing them to capture each nook and cranny of the aircraft as realistically as possible, with precise dimensions, accurate furniture, and more. While there is no release date yet, X-Crafts expects it to be ready within a few months for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Owners of the complete E-jets Family will receive the new plane for free, whereas new owners can buy it separately. There’s also an upgrade path for owners of any individual E-Jet, which warrants access to the whole family for $67.45. Refer to their blog post for further information on the matter and purchase links. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navuix</id>
    <title>Navigraph Releases SimBrief Dispatch for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navuix"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6729856646dc65696c3f4105_dispatch1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Navigraph has recently released a new tool for Microsoft Flight Simulator, allowing users to fully utilize SimBrief within the simulator for flight planning, thus removing the necessity to access SimBrief from a web browser. The new integration allows access to most of SimBrief’s flight planning features right from the simulator. It maintains a layout similar to that of the online version, retaining familiarity and ease of use. SimBrief dispatch is free to use and install. It is available through Navigraph Hub for Navigraph customers and through the SimBrief dashboard for all users.  Designed to create a seamless and straightforward workflow, the new tool can be launched straight from Microsoft Flight Simulator’s world map through a button that reads “Simbrief” above the “Fly Now” button. Clicking it will open a SimBrief window within the simulator, where you are then prompted to put in your login details and presented with a familiar interface (translated to Microsoft Flight Simulator’s User Interface design language), where you can generate your flight plan. Navigraph customers will benefit from updated navigational cycles, which will ensure the best possible data match for their flight plan generations. ‍ After the planning stage, users can also launch the SimBrief UI at any moment during their flight by clicking on its toolbar icon. This will display the same interface, allowing for quickly booking a return leg or calculating take-off performance. ‍ Navigraph has also mentioned that a Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version is in the works. This version is planned to be integrated into the sim’s global electronic flight bag. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxsha</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Showcases Upcoming Sharklets Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxsha"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad36ef2cdccb6b9a18c44_sharklets12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations has published an in-depth development update showcasing the upcoming sharklets update for their A320 family lineup (except for the A319). As promised in the past, it is said to be released "this week" for all customers at no extra cost. While the A320 and the A321 will be getting the sharklets from the get-go this week, the A319 will take a while. Fenix Simulations claims it's been a bit tricky to obtain reliable data on it, as not many exist in real life.  The sharklets are more than just a visual thing. Airbus went the extra mile to warrant similar handling and overall behavior between both variants, mostly on the "software" side of things, making it hardly noticeable if one doesn't look closely enough. Fenix Simulations claims to have accurately replicated the subtle system differences and flight dynamics behavior, warranting a realistic experience. The flight model has been adjusted to the sharklets, with a bit more lift on the wings, less drag, and extra energy on flare, which is said to be subtle but noticeable if you pay close attention. Regardless, the fly-by-wire system should make the overall handling feel relatively homogeneous across all variants, as in real life. As previously mentioned, there are also software changes, with upgrades to the two elevator and aileron computers, three spoiler elevator computers, and the two flight augmentation computers, as well as less significant changes to the ECAM, fuel, FMGC, and more.  Among these ELAC changes, Fenix Simulations highlights the Load Alleviation Function, which alleviates wing structure loading, as the extra weight of the sharklets also means more strain on the wings, making them bend more aggressively in extreme conditions. The LAF system rapidly deploys ailerons upwards while in-flight or spoilers 4 and 5 to prevent that. The FBW system was also tweaked to accommodate the new system and its inherencies. Ground physics also underwent improvements. The tiller mapping from the real A320 was applied to their add-on, adding a bit of extra weight to the taxi phase across their entire range of aircraft (wingtips included). They have also built a custom wingflex model to accommodate the more obvious sharklet wingflex, taking into account a lot of factors such as localized forces, fuel tank level, etc. It has also been backported to the wingtip fences. They also reinforce that it's mostly a work in progress and might not be perfect initially. The ADIRS model has been upgraded to the newer version, applying to both aircraft. The old one has been ultimately retired as it's rare in currently flying A320s anymore. The ACP was also upgraded, and the old one was phased out. They plan on bringing both the old ADIRS and ACP as options in the future. The new digital standby instrument has also been added as an integral - and forced - part of the sharklets modernization, complete with the correct degraded displays and its functions. At long last, the ACT tanks were also added to the A321, allowing for realistically operated transcontinental flights and routes like Finnair's HEL—PMI. The presence of the ACTs also means less space in the cargo compartment, which is also modeled. The lights were heavily tweaked to match the configuration of most A320SLs, featuring a full LED suite across the aircraft. Regarding liveries, they have painted 106 unique liveries so far, with accurate cockpit configurations, ACTs (A321 only, of course), and more. The expected rollout date is sometime this week, and the discount on the full bundle will end once that happens. They conclude with a statement on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024: "Unfortunately, we were not permitted access to the DevAlpha (though we did ask Microsoft), which means we still don't have an answer for you on compatibility and timelines for adjusting to this new platform. Our intent will be to bring compatibility and stability first and foremost, then at a later time assess the new feature set and see what makes sense." Therefore, they found themselves unable to make any promises regarding dates, viability, or anything for that matter. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflmax</id>
    <title>Airfoillabs Announces Boeing 737 Max for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflmax"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672add2f860c5eec1bcd5b73_ma1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airfoillabs has recently announced the development of a high-fidelity Boeing 737 Max for X-Plane, featuring realistic flight dynamics, a detailed 3D cockpit environment, cockpit builder friendliness, and more. The development process will be completely transparent, with the developers providing frequent development updates on their X-Plane Org forum thread delineating every step taken into building the add-on. The updates will occur every month with detailed progress reports, media (screenshots and videos), technical deep dives, and clear milestone tracking with real-time progress indicators. They have already come up with an expected feature list for each release: alpha, beta, 1.0, and the future beyond that. The alpha release will implement the core flight dynamics, a detailed 3D cockpit environment, basic systems, and a relatively basic flight model. The beta release, on the other hand, should bring comprehensive aircraft systems, advanced autopilot functionality, initial FMS implementation, and the integration of the core systems. For 1.0, the aircraft should fully integrate all its systems,  a custom EFB, a professional-grade sound environment, and complete documentation and manuals. ‍ The aircraft should get regular updates based on community feedback, enhanced functionality releases, ongoing systems refinement, and advanced feature implementations post-release. ‍ What they claim sets their 737 Max apart is that it's explicitly built for X-Plane's flight model engine, with a deep systems simulation focused on professional-grade accuracy. Thus, it's a potential platform for cockpit-building enthusiasts. ‍ The development updates will start next Friday, with an in-depth look at their cockpit modeling progress. In the coming weeks, a real-time development tracker will be added to their website, where potential customers will be able to see its current development state. ‍ Refer to their announcement post for further information on the matter. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzawan</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases Wanaka Region for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzawan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672c356b8f0c30410d5c981b_wanaka1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. NZA Simulations has recently released their rendition of Wanaka Airport (NZWF) and its surroundings for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring over 5000 square kilometers of enhanced terrain, nine airports, and more. Wanaka Airport serves the town of Wanaka, in Otago, New Zealand, with a passenger average circling around the 5 digit mark (exact numbers are not available).  It was built in 1984 on top of a pre-existing private airstrip owned by Tim Wallis, a Kiwi businessman and aviation entrepreneur, ultimately replacing Mount Iron Aerodrome, which used to be Wanaka’s only airport and deemed too small for their plans back then. Air New Zealand started scheduled services in 2004, canceling them after only nine years due to low demand (which would only peak during airshow weekends). Local businesses rapidly stepped in to fill the gap, albeit unsuccessfully.  ‍ In late 2020, SoundsAir started a scheduled service route to Christchurch airport, which is currently the airport’s only commercial traffic.  Other than the airport itself, the package also offers a 5000 square kilometer coverage around its surroundings, with nine airports in total, four helipads, 20+ mountain huts, 3D models, PBR texturing, high-resolution aerial imagery, 3D interiors for the main airport, Skydive Wanaka Hangar &amp; Customer area, Whare Kea Chalet Hut, Aspiring Helicopters, and Makarora Hangars. Below is a map with all the airports, airstrips, and landmarks included: It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $21.72, requiring at least 4.19 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sharks</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases Sharklets Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sharks"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad40126a28c4a9b738d5a_sharklets20.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations has recently released the long-awaited sharklets update for their Airbus family lineup (except for the A319) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, at no extra cost and with a wealth of new features. While the A320 and the A321 will be getting the sharklets as of right now, the A319 will take a while. They claim it's been a bit tricky to obtain reliable data on it, as not many exist in real life.  The sharklets are more than just a visual thing. Airbus went the extra mile to warrant similar handling and overall behavior between both variants, mainly on the "software" side of things, making it hardly noticeable if one doesn't look closely enough. Fenix Simulations claims to have accurately replicated the subtle system differences and flight dynamics behavior, warranting a realistic experience. The flight model has been adjusted to the sharklets, with a bit more lift on the wings, less drag, and extra energy on flare, which is said to be subtle but noticeable if you pay close attention. Regardless, the fly-by-wire system should make the overall handling feel relatively homogeneous across all variants, as in real life. As previously mentioned, there are also software changes, with upgrades to the two elevator and aileron computers, three spoiler elevator computers, and the two flight augmentation computers, as well as less significant changes to the ECAM, fuel, FMGC, and more.  Among these ELAC changes, Fenix Simulations highlights the Load Alleviation Function, which alleviates wing structure loading, as the extra weight of the sharklets also means more strain on the wings, making them bend more aggressively in extreme conditions. The LAF system rapidly deploys ailerons upwards while in-flight or spoilers 4 and 5 to prevent that. The FBW system was also tweaked to accommodate the new system and its inherencies. Ground physics also underwent improvements. The tiller mapping from the real A320 was applied to their add-on, adding a bit of extra weight to the taxi phase across their entire range of aircraft (wingtips included). They have also built a custom wingflex model to accommodate the more obvious sharklet wingflex, taking into account a lot of factors such as localized forces, fuel tank level, etc. It has also been backported to the wingtip fences. They also reinforce that it's mostly a work in progress and might not be perfect initially. The ADIRS model has been upgraded to the newer version, applying to both aircraft. The old one has been ultimately retired as it's rare in currently flying A320s anymore. The ACP was also upgraded, and the old one was phased out. They plan on bringing both the old ADIRS and ACP as options in the future. The new digital standby instrument has also been added as an integral - and forced - part of the sharklets modernization, complete with the correct degraded displays and its functions. Lastly, the ACT tanks were added to the A321, allowing for realistically operated transcontinental flights and routes like Finnair's HEL—PMI. The presence of the ACTs also means less space in the cargo compartment, which is also modeled. The complete changelog follows down below: Avionics and Systems The update is available right now via Fenix Installer. The full bundle (A319/A320/A321) is available on their website for roughly $103.87. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avrorj</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Avro RJ Professional for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avrorj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672e4d368f3171d57da27d35_erejota1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight has recently released their rendition of the Avro RJ for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, bringing a high fidelity simulation of all three variants (RJ70, RJ85, and RJ100) of the popular short-haul regional airliner manufactured by British Aerospace. ‍ The RJ is objectively an upgraded BAE 146, featuring a modern cockpit (for the early 1990s), and newer engines featuring FADEC and digital avionics. Their revamp allowed the model to remain relevant in times when the 146 was getting too old for modern-day aviation due to its analog systems, and other manufacturers already had their own “future-proof” alternatives. The add-on features an accurate rendition of the airplane, with all three variants created from real-world aircraft plans and comprehensive photography of the real thing, sporting a highly detailed passenger cabin and galleys customized for each variant, custom-modeled ground equipment, high-resolution textures, a custom-coded GNLU-910A FMS, and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ VARIANTS ‍ All three variants of the RJ are included: ‍ ‍ MODEL ‍   COCKPIT ‍   LIVERIES ‍ The RJ comes with a variety of liveries representing the aircraft's numerous operators from all around the world:   RJ70 ‍ RJ85 ‍  RJ100 ‍  A PSD Paint Kit is also available to download, allowing for the creation of custom livery and cabin textures. ‍   SYSTEMS ‍ RJ Professional features fully custom-coded aircraft systems with a high degree of complexity and depth, including:   Air-conditioning and pressurisation system ‍ APU ‍ Auto-flight system ‍ Communication system ‍ Doors and stairs ‍ Electrical system ‍ Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) ‍ The aircraft is equipped with a tablet EFB for controlling various aircraft options and payloads, including: ‍ The EFB can also be used for flight planning and monitoring: ‍ FDE and effects ‍ Fire protection system ‍ Flight controls ‍ Flight Management System ‍ Fuel system ‍ Hydraulic system ‍ Ice and rain protection system ‍ Indicating and recording systems ‍ Landing gear ‍ Lighting ‍ Navigation systems ‍ Oxygen system ‍ Passenger cabins ‍ Pneumatic system ‍ Power plant ‍ Sounds ‍ ‍ OTHER FEATURES ‍ The add-on is available in their store for $69.99 (or in a bundle with the 146), requiring at least 2.6 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
