<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-02T18:23:35.806743+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssda50</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Previews DA-50RG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssda50"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a6da424e97843527b0932_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyward Simulations has recently previewed its first project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the Diamond DA-50RG. The DA-50RG is a modern single-engined aircraft, powered by a 300HP turbodiesel engine. The sleek airframe is made of carbon fiber, which sets a new bar for aircraft construction. The aircraft can fly at 20,000 feet at a speed of 180 knots. Together with great fuel consumption, these features make the DA-50RG one of the best modern general aviation aircraft. According to Skyward, The DA-50RG will feature an accurate 3D model, true-to-life definition textures, Custom-coded systems, ground idle function simulation, accurate flight model, integrated WortkingTittle G1000NXI, hand-made liveries, and immersive custom sounds by Boris Audio Works.  The addon will cost around 16.12 USD, but as of the publishing of this article, the release date is yet to be announced. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a150</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a150"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a8a5b47035b5699933700_pa24.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing small improvements to the PC version of the add-on. Update 1.5.0 fixes an SU15 beta issue that would happen on engine run-ups with brakes or chocks applied, improves battery performance at very cold temperatures, adds more telemetry variables for force feedback hardware, and more. The changelog follows below: The update will also be available in the marketplace at a later date. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/haliv2</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Halifax Stanfield International Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/haliv2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a9519d18669c7d7ef9b2c_halifax1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently released their upgraded rendition of Halifax Stanfield International Airport (CYHZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Halifax Regional Municipality with a yearly average of 3.6 million passengers as of 2023. ‍ Construction started in 1955, and the airport was inaugurated five years later, costing the administration $18 million.  The first couple of years in operation were rather successful, leading to a complete renovation of the passenger terminal in 1966 and a 5,000-square-meter extension a decade later. By 1990, the airport was already averaging 2.5 million passengers a year. It was further renovated in the early 2000s, with slight expansions and improvements, which happened again between 2018 and 2019. It’s a focus city for Air Canada and Porter Airlines and served by Air Saint-Pierre, Air Transat, American Airlines, American Eagle, BermudAir, Canada Jetlines, Condor, Delta Connection, Discover Airlines, Flair Airlines, Icelandair, Sunwing Airlines, United Express, and WestJet. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout (as of March 2024), significant performance improvements, an improved interior model, new ground poly, custom taxi signs, an improved terminal model, and more. ‍ The V2 Update is available as a free upgrade for previous owners, and new owners can find it on OrbxDirect for roughly $19.19. It requires at least 5.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tekola</id>
    <title>Threshold Exclusive: Orbx Kola Map Previews</title>
    <updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tekola"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662b9980524bd60b8b0c37c3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Threshold has received exclusive screenshots for the upcoming major release of Orbx's Kola map for DCS. The release has been teased on their YouTube channel, and now Threshold is the first to share these exciting images. The Kola map is a geographical representation that spans over 550,000 km2 of land across northern Scandinavia and northwestern Russia. It also includes large sections of the Norwegian Sea and Barents Sea for naval operations. Upon release, this map will showcase various airbases such as Bodø, Bardufoss, Evenes, Rovaniemi, Luleå, Vidsel, Monchegorsk, Olenya, Severomorsk-1 and -3, and many more. Additionally, the map will feature test ranges, naval bases, radar sites, storage sites as well as a complete network of railroads and roads. The Kola map will feature various civilian points of interest, such as key buildings, bridges, hydro dams, power plants, port facilities, and vertical obstructions. The region's beautiful coastline will be enhanced by dramatic fjords, glaciers, and numerous islands. The taiga forests dotted with lakes and the arctic tundra will add to the natural beauty of this area. There will be both Summer and Winter versions of the Kola map available. Orbx collaborated with experienced DCS campaign creators Baltic Dragon and Reflected Simulations to create engaging campaigns featuring F/A-18C and F-16C at launch. The map's release is imminent, so if you want to be the first to know when it is available, register your details at Orbx's website. Currently, there is no confirmed release date, but the trailer has a hidden Morse code message that says "Coming Soon." ‍ The next previews will show more terrain, so remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brnwax</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases North Weald Airfield for XP11 and XP12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brnwax"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662bb63635fa337836882bbc_11.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has released their rendition of North Weald Airfield for X-Plane 11 and 12, a small General Aviation airfield in Essex, UK. Opened in 1916 as Royal Flying Corps Station North Weald Bassett Aerodrome by the Royal Flying Corps (predecessor to the Royal Air Force), and in 1918 it became a Royal Air Force airport. This airfield played an important role in defending British skies during WWII. Hawker Hurricanes stationed in North Weald Airfield saw action in Dunkirk and the Battle of Britain. Later on in the war, Norwegian squadrons were reassigned to this airfield. Between the 1940s and 60s, this aerodrome was used for RAF glider training. The last combat unit left North Weald in 1958, while the RAF completely withdrew in 1964, and since then this aerodrome has been classified as civilian. Today, North Weald sees over 40,000 movements on average per year and is home to a collection of vintage and veteran aircraft such as the P-51 Mustang, Hawker Hurricane, Supermarine Spitfire, Douglas Dakota, Curtiss Kittyhawk, as well as early jet aircraft such as Hawker Hunter, de Havilland Venom, de Havilland Vampire, Folland Gnat and BAC Jet Provost. North Weald Airfield will feature up-to-date orthophotos, 4K PBR airport buildings, 3D Forrest (XP12 only), 3D vegetation, 3D volumetric grass, Custom night lighting, realistic HD static aircraft, accurate ground markings including cracks and wear &amp; tear, dynamic weather effects (XP12 only) and accurate airport layout based on latest charts. You can buy this scenery on the Boundless store for $13.75 USD. It requires around 970MB when installed. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/g15mya</id>
    <title>GATE15Scenery Releases Miyako Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/g15mya"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663133f74227e68d0af480a9_miyako1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GATE15Scenery has recently released its rendition of Miyako Airport (ROMY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Miyakojima, Okinawa Prefecture, and has a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers. It opened in 1943 as an Imperial Japanese Navy airbase, and civilian operations only took place for the first time in 1956. The airport sports a single terminal building with five gates and three extra stands for mid-sized aircraft. All Nippon Airways, ANA Wings, Japan Airlines, Japan Transocean Air, and Ryukyu Air Commuter serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, a basic interior model, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.01, requiring at least 391.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skyvat</id>
    <title>Sky-Additions Releases Paris-Vatry Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skyvat"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663136e2e8954cc558351816_vatry1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Sky-Additions has recently released their rendition of Paris-Vatry Airport (LFOK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It serves the champagne region in Northeastern France and is close enough to Paris (135km) to be considered by Ryanair as one of the Parisian airports. As of 2018, the airport had a yearly average of 61,826 passengers. It was built as an air base in 1953, housing fifty fighters in three large hangars. When France withdrew from the integrated NATO structure in 1967, the Americans left the base, leading to its closure. The French Air Force then used it for training until the early 2000s, when it was sold to civil interests and converted into a civilian airport. Besides handling occasional passenger traffic, it’s also a training pilot site for many airlines, such as Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, KLM, Transavia, Transavia France, and Swiss. Airbus has also used its relatively long runway for aircraft testing. It’s served by Ryanair, with flights to Marrakech and Porto.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, a custom GSX profile, detailed environmental elements, realistic airport vehicles, custom ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.64, requiring at least 120.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vueiva</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Ivato International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vueiva"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66313a8e0cc90a5e00caa2e2_ivato1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Ivato International Airport (FMMI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Antananarivo, the capital of Madagascar, with a yearly average of 845,000 passengers. Since the 1960s, this civil and military airport has served as Antananarivo's main airport. It features two terminals, one for domestic operations and the other for international operations. It's the main hub for Air Madagascar, the nation's carrier, taking passengers to South Africa, France, China, and nearby French islands. Air Austral, Air France, Air Mauritius, Airlink, Corsair International, Ethiopian Airlines, Kenya Airways, Tsaradia, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery accurately depicts the airport, with a highly detailed main terminal and its interior, custom runway materials, accurate night lighting, LOD optimization for optimal performance, an up-to-date layout, and much more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.92, requiring at least 301.76 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftsydx</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Previews Sydney Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftsydx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66314ed3b936dadb3d37e191_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlyTampa has recently revealed its newest scenery, Sydney Airport for X-Plane 12. The team has shared screenshots on Facebook and a trailer on YouTube, and the scenery is expected to be released soon. The team has shared some of the features and previews of the upcoming Kingsford Smith Airport rendition for X-Plane 12. The airport has been fully customized with custom mesh, custom night lighting, SAM and LST integration, and an Ortho4XP patch. Additionally, there are many more features that have not yet been revealed. As the busiest airport in Australia, Kingsford Smith Airport is a highly anticipated addition to X-Plane 12. Although FlyTampa has not announced the pricing and release date, they have confirmed that the airport is coming soon. We will update you with more information as soon as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxkm</id>
    <title>Orbx Kola Map Previews and Features</title>
    <updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxkm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66321d2ea471ee5009516050_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Threshold recently received exclusive screenshots of the upcoming Kola Map for DCS, and today, we have three more exclusives to share with you. The community has highly anticipated the new Kola Map, which will cover large parts of Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia. As of now, the project is listed as "coming soon," with the release of the early access version imminent. The Kola Map will first be available for early access and will be feature-packed with a multitude of airports. There will be two airports in Finland, five in Russia, two in Norway, and three in Sweden. Additionally, early access ensures a complete base terrain, highly detailed topography for the entire map, and lots of POIs, road and railroad networks, night lighting, and many landmarks to explore. Although early access will be available first, many future features have already been planned. Winter textures are scheduled to ensure the representation of the cold and harsh climate up North. A multitude of military airfields like Bardufoss and Kirkenes and a variety of civilian airports, including Tromsø and Luleå, are also planned. Also, general improvements to landscape features have been scheduled. The official store page for the Kola Map is now available on Orbx. Be sure to check it out for more information and screenshots. ‍ We will update you with more information as soon as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thnlx</id>
    <title>Threshold Newsletter going live</title>
    <updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thnlx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663299e7db7880a89ef3635e_2023-06-04%2016_41_26-X-System.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The first-ever Threshold Newsletter is now live! Our new monthly newsletter is here to stay, and we'll provide you with a roundup of all the biggest flight simulation news, as well as the editorial of the month. You can find the April newsletter on our website and sign up now to receive future newsletters. 2024 has been an outstanding year for us at Threshold, as we have been committed to delivering the highest quality content to you. Our team has written a remarkable 223 news articles and 18 full-length articles, covering a diverse range of topics and providing valuable insights to our audience. We are proud to have achieved a new record this year, and we look forward to continuing to provide exceptional content to our readers in the future. ‍ ‍ The Newsletter will evolve over time and we encourage you to give us feedback in our Discord on how what you would like to see published. This is new to us too =) ‍ The entire team at Threshold would like to express our gratitude to everyone who has joined us on our journey thus far. We hope that this newsletter will continue to help us grow and remain a go-to destination in our community. Thank you! ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mjcupd</id>
    <title>Majestic Software Posts Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mjcupd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633a13adbc1928e7050a1ab_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Majestic Software recently posted an update on their forum regarding the progress of their aircraft development for Microsoft Flight Simulator. According to the post, the team has completely reworked the EFIS screens and custom flight dynamic for MSFS. They are also adding a new EFB, which will be included in not only the MSFS version of the aircraft but also the current Prepar3D version. Majestic Software has announced its intention to bring both the Q400 and Q300 for MSFS, and the Q200 is also highly likely. However, the team hasn't shared a specific timeline for the project yet. They hope to complete the plane by 2025 if everything goes according to plan.  We will keep you updated when the team shares more information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ahhawk</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Releases Hawker Hurrican Mk.1 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ahhawk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633a7639ed49c1fd0c01774_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aeroplane Heaven has recently released its version of the Hawker Hurricane Mk.1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a British fighter aircraft that first flew in 1935. The single-seater plane was built by Hawker Aircraft Ltd. and was initially used by the Royal Air Force (RAF). The aircraft was introduced in 1937 and a total of 14.487 planes were built between 1937 and 1944. Although it initially flew for the RAF, it was also used by other countries such as Australia, Belgium, Greece, Poland, and more throughout its lifespan. The new add-on comes with a range of features, including high-fidelity models, detailed features, animations, accurate flight dynamics, a variety of liveries, and more. The add-on requires 2.81GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $28.85. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xejets</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Updates Free E-Jets for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xejets"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633b28dcd8ab9aec417e180_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts have released an update for their freeware E-Jets, bringing the plane to version V3.0. This new version is compatible with X-Plane 12 and comes with many improvements and new features. The previous version (V2.5) remains compatible with X-Plane 11. The Embraer E-Jet family consists of a multitude of Brazilian-made narrow-body airliners. The project was initially revealed by Embraer in 1997, but it was not officially unveiled until two years later. In 2002, the first E-Jet had its maiden flight. The E-Jet family comprises of four commercial airliners, including the E170, E175, E190, and E195. The free E-Jets series by X-Crafts includes both the E175 and the E195 models. The new X-Plane 12 version of the E-Jets comes with a range of new features, such as an enhanced flight model, improved modeling, updated lights, cockpit fixes, and more. The new version is now available for download on the X-Crafts website. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inprmm</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Freeware Milwaukee Mitchell International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inprmm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633b8599606ada829410cf4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has provided a sneak peek of its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport in question is Milwaukee Mitchell International Airport (KMKE), which will be released for free to the community. As the busiest airport in Wisconsin, KMKE boasts over 160 destinations to explore from the airport. The freeware package will include a multitude of features such as hand-made ground textures, custom ground decals, vegetation, dynamic lighting, highly detailed models, an up-to-date airport layout, a GSX profile, and much more. The developer has announced that the update will be available tomorrow, and the store page is now live on the iniBuilds Store.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777bpr</id>
    <title>FightFactor Releases Beta Pre-Release Version of 777v2 for Invited Members</title>
    <updated>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777bpr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6633bf3190d08942b64aadcf_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has just released a beta pre-release version of their 777v2 airplane for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. This version is only available to invited members, who are not allowed to post any information or screenshots outside a dedicated forum. While the store page for the airplane is up, the official price for the airplane has not yet been revealed, and the $9.999 price tag currently shown is not the normal price. The store page offers a detailed description of the aircraft, along with plenty of screenshots. The 777v2 boasts a range of features, including an accurate flight model, 3D modeling, accurately simulated systems, ground services, custom sounds, failure model, EFB, and much more. FlightFactor has not yet announced when the 777v2 will be available to the public, nor what the price will be, so stay tuned for updates on that front. In the meantime, you can check out the current store page over at the X-Plane.Org Software Store. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
