<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-09-18T18:34:51.076118+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a0912</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a0912"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4e305e7104aacb1bc8bf9_aerostarnew.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing new refinements, fixes, additions, and more. Update v0.9.12 of their Aerostar 600 is nicknamed “Little Bits Part 2”, bringing many fixes, further refinements, new additions such as noise-canceling headphones and a functional Hobbs meter, among many other things. The complete changelog follows below: Change log v0.9.12: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ubbb12</id>
    <title>Azrsim Releases Heydar Aliyev International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ubbb12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c565b01ab5b66a4fc40f63_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After releasing their Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 versions of Heydar Aliyev International Airport (UBBB) a few weeks ago, Azrsim has now launched the X-Plane 12 version of the airport. Located in Baku, the capital of Azerbaijan, the airport serves over 7.5 million passengers each year. The airport began operations in 1933. In 1964, a new passenger terminal complex opened, increasing the facility's capacity. A new runway was inaugurated in 1998, followed by the opening of Terminal 2 in 1999. The following year, a new air traffic control (ATC) tower was constructed. In 2004, a new domestic passenger terminal was introduced, and the Baku Cargo Terminal (BCT) was launched in 2005. Additionally, an extra runway was built in 2012, and Terminal 1 was inaugurated in 2014. ‍ The airport accommodates numerous airlines that operate both domestically and internationally, including Azerbaijan Airlines, IrAero, Pegasus Airlines, and Utair, among others. Consequently, the airport facilitates the movement of over 7.5 million passengers annually and manages nearly 60,000 flights each year. The scenery package includes features like accurately recreated terminals, hangars, and additional buildings, detailed interiors, high-resolution ground textures, detailed apron layouts, and much more. The newly released version of Heydar Aliyev International Airport for X-Plane 12 is now available on SimMarket for approximately $23.47. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssmok</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Molokai &amp; Kalaupapa Airports for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssmok"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c5e01b23f35de1cd89d99b_43.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Northern Sky Studio has released a twin-pack for X-Plane 12, featuring Molokai Airport (PHMK) and Kalaupapa Airport (PHLU), giving island-hoppers two richly crafted airports in one go.  Both airfields feature custom ground textures, detailed airport objects and vehicles, weather effects, new lighting, PBR materials, and 3D vegetation. For night operations, you can tune COM1 to 125.7 to switch on the runway lighting, like at a real pilot-controlled field. The package integrates with new X-Plane 12 features, supports World Traffic 3, and is compatible with Ortho4XP and the default mesh, ensuring it should fit into most Hawaii setups without issue. Molokai’s two asphalt runways and central-plateau sets the contrast nicely with Kalaupapa’s coastal strip, making this a versatile pair for commuter, air taxi, or GA flying. Expect high-resolution building and ground textures, realistic reflections on glass, shaded and baked details, plus animated ground traffic, courtesy of the LST plugin. As always, you can read the full feature list below: Features: The Molokai &amp; Kalaupapa Airports pack is now available from Orbx, priced at about $19.20.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vdlebb</id>
    <title>Virtual Design 3D Releases Bilbao Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vdlebb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c7e354f792befcb6d5731c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Virtual Design 3D has just launched its rendition of Bilbao Airport (LEBB) for X-Plane 12. Situated just 5.6 miles from the city of Bilbao, this international airport serves over 6.3 million passengers annually, facilitating travel to and from the Basque Country in northern Spain. The airport opened its doors in 1948, with the terminal beginning operations two years later in 1950. At that time, the airport featured one asphalt runway, one earth runway, a passenger terminal, an air traffic control tower, and a taxiway. In 1955, a taxiway was added to connect the runway to the parking stands and terminal. Between 1964 and 1965, an Instrument Landing System (ILS) was installed, along with an extension to the runway and apron.  ‍ In 1977, the airport underwent several expansions, including an extended parking stand, a link road, an upgraded ILS, and a new runway. During the 1980s, further improvements were made, including the expansion of the passenger terminal and parking facilities, as well as the addition of a cargo terminal and a fire service building.  ‍ Since the 1990s, the airport has continued to grow, acquiring a new taxiway, a new aircraft parking apron, a new air traffic control tower, and a newly designed terminal area featuring a new terminal building and a north apron. In 2009, an expansion of the terminal building was announced, originally expected to be completed in 2014; however, it has faced delays of at least five years. ‍ Today, the airport serves a wide range of destinations through various airlines, accommodating over 6.3 million passengers and nearly 50,000 aircraft movements annually. The scenery features highly detailed terminals and buildings, custom animated jetways, custom runways, HDR lighting, customized 3D vegetation, detailed surrounding areas, and much more. The newly released Bilbao Airport for X-Plane 12 is now available at the X-Plane.Org Software Store and is currently on sale for $14.93. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cowsep</id>
    <title>COWS Updates Diamond Aircraft, Introduces DA40-NG for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cowsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c89364aeda392855e269a1_DA40DA42_Update%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS has recently rolled out a major update across its Diamond line of products, bringing the entirely new DA40-NG, alongside refinements to the DA40-XLS and DA42 TDI/VI. These changes arrive as two distinct product updates, each with its own feature set and improvements. The Diamond family of aircraft is a familiar sight at many flight schools and academies around the globe. The DA40 XLS, being the oldest of the three variants, offers a traditional Lycoming piston setup, while the newer DA40 NG introduces a more modern, AE300 engine. Stepping up, the DA42 takes the DA40’s platform, adding twin turbodiesel engines, retractable gear, and enhanced stability, making it a popular bridge into multi-engine training. The DA40-series has been updated to version 1.1.0, with the headline addition of the new NG variant. Built on the XLS platform, the NG comes with a reworked flight model, designed to replicate training manoeuvres with more accuracy. On the systems side, the aircraft now features a fully custom electrical system, that models bus voltage, alternators, and battery behaviour down to details, such as overnight discharge, if the cabin light is left on.  Other highlights include refinements to engine dynamics, autopilot, priming assist, as well as an expanded G1000 feature set, with wide flight plan view, nearest airport auto-set, endurance calculations, and additional reset options. The DA42 also sees a significant refresh, now at version 1.2.2. Developed in parallel with the DA40 update, it benefits from the same electrical system overhaul and G1000 improvements. Changes extend into the powerplant model, with FADEC adjustments, turbo response tuning, and cooling airflow simulation. Other systems, such as de-ice and auxiliary fuel tanks, are now also influenced by aircraft acceleration. A long list of fixes touches on lighting, visuals, state saving, and failures, rounding out the update. As always, you can read the full changelog(s), for both updates, in the following section: ‍ V1.1.0 15/09/25 Powerplant/Flightmodel Engine friction changes and tuning Oil and CHT warm up a little faster New cooling airflow simulation (More natural behaviour with winds and prop discing) Automixture: Mixture lever now sets a target mixture like a conventional FS mixture lever Increased oil pressure drop from propeller governor Fixed engine alternate air bug Added rudder deflection from trim tab Systems Autopilot tweaks RPM sensor is now simulated Added temperature offsets to gauges Fixed stall horn on the ground in high winds Standby gyro reacts to system voltage Fully custom electric system: - Simulated electrical buses, diodes, component power draw, circuit breakers, batteries and alternators - Simulated alternator field voltage, voltage regulators - Simulated battery voltage, resistance and temperature - Battery charge is statesaved and battery will self discharge over time - Leaving the cabin light on will discharge the battery - Battery can be recharged in the G1000 engine page menu and emergency reset procedure (check tips in checklist) G1000 Updated Navigraph plugin Added wide Flightplan view Added Priming assist Added nearest airport being set as the origin Updated the MFD data fields to use the totalizer for fuel and endurance calculations (FOB, FOD, END) Updated the Engine Page Menu with more reset failure options Updated the fuel calculator range and endurance to use the avionics computer state Fixed the endurance field showing as failed when toggling the electric master Fixed the PFD bottom info data styling to be compatible with the HSI map and other configs Added "timer expired" voice alert Added a delay to displaying the CAS Reversionary mode fixes Total Time in Service is now activated when the aircraft becomes airborne Other: Separated package into FS20 and FS24 specific versions (G1000v2 mod no longer required, currently Orbx only) Fixed Parking brake on/off commands Tweaks to: Lighting, Visuals, Sounds, Statesaving, Failures, Standby instruments Added some new tips to checklist FS24: Fixed lighting bloom Added DA40NG ‍ V1.2.2 15/09/25 Powerplant/Flightmodel FADEC improvements Increased turbo response New cooling airflow simulation Oil cooling improvements Improved fuel system behaviour Ecu error detection is paused shortly after slewing Reduced steering angle at high speeds Systems Autopilot tweaks De-ice fluid is now affected by aircraft acceleration Removed unusable de-ice fluid Aux tanks are now affected by aircraft acceleration Added temperature offsets to gauges Standby gyro reacts to system voltage Fully custom electric system: - Simulated electrical buses, diodes, component power draw, circuit breakers, batteries and alternators - Simulated alternator field voltage, voltage regulators and temperature - Simulated battery voltage, resistance and temperature - Battery charge is statesaved and battery will self discharge over time - Leaving the cabin light on will discharge the battery - Battery can be recharged in the G1000 engine page menu and emergency reset procedure (check tips in checklist) G1000 Updated Navigraph plugin Added wide Flightplan view Added nearest airport being set as the origin Updated the MFD data fields to use the totalizer for fuel and endurance calculations (FOB, FOD, END) Updated the Engine Page Menu with more reset failure options Updated the fuel calculator range and endurance to use the avionics computer state Fixed the endurance field showing as failed when toggling the electric master Fixed the PFD bottom info data styling to be compatible with the HSI map and other configs Added Blue and Red line airspeed markers Added "timer expired" voice alert Added a delay to displaying the CAS Reversionary mode fixes Total Time in Service is now activated when the aircraft becomes airborne Other: Separated package into FS20 and FS24 specific versions (G1000v2 mod no longer required, currently Orbx only) Set fuel tank priority, main tanks are refilled first Fixed Parking brake on/off commands Tweaks to: Lighting, Visuals, Gear physics, Sounds, Statesaving, Failures, Feathering, Deice system, Fuel selectors, Xfer pumps, Standby instruments Added some new tips to checklist FS24: Blocked prop lever inputs triggering ECU errors FS24: Fixed lighting bloom Both the DA40 and 42 are offered as separate purchases, priced at $26.85 and $30.85 respectively. You can find them both on OrbxDirect. Owners of the DA40-XLS receive the NG variant as part of the package, at no extra cost. Updates are available now through Orbx Central, with Marketplace releases to follow. Be aware, COWS has noted that neither aircraft is currently compatible with the new SU4 beta. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflsep</id>
    <title>Airfoillabs Shares 737 MAX 8 Systems Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c8a834f77a283762009dfc_AFL737MAX8-2025-08-1600_01_41.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After a string of progress reports, Airfoillabs has taken to social media, sharing the latest on its 737 MAX for X-Plane 12. The update focuses on systems work, cockpit modelling, and the steps toward a custom Autopilot and Autothrottle, providing insight into how the ambitious project is shaping up. Starting off, the FMS has seen a round of quality-of-life tweaks since the last update. The Arrivals page now streamlines STAR and transition selection, while constraint checks have been refined to be more straightforward and less error-prone.  We also saw previews of the Vertical Situation Display, adding various practical cues, such as destination runway on profile, approach glideslope and minimum-altitude gates, plus a cleaner terrain picture, to support descent planning. Meanwhile, the PFD/HSI are reported to be close to feature-complete. Airfoillabs says the suite now renders the core symbology used in normal ops, including validity flags and annunciators, with edge cases tuned. Hence, the flags appear, and clear, in a more predictable way. The 737 MAX will also support third-party navigation data, with Airfoillabs noting ongoing work with Navigraph. This integration brings worldwide procedures and navaids into X-Plane 12, updated with each AIRAC cycle. This means cleaner routing, with fewer gaps, particularly on complex SIDs and STARs. Ultimately, this work should ensure consistency with other Navigraph-enabled tools, and a more predictable experience, when flying published procedures. Two cockpit art milestones are also in place. The aft overhead panel now has all animations and manipulators implemented, with guards, detents, and backlighting, tuned for consistent interaction, in 2D and VR.  Animations and UI logic for the Mode Control Panel are also complete, including a custom-built font, with this work serving as the front-end for the custom AFDS, currently underway. That AFDS, the Autopilot and Flight Director System, is currently moving through intensive development. Airfoillabs explains that they are developing a custom system, complete with an integrated autothrottle.  Planned functions include LNAV, VNAV, Level Change, V/S, localiser and glideslope capture, dual-channel autoland, speed protections, and go-around logic. The team describes this process as iterative, with captures, transitions, and reversions being expanded over multiple passes, with the eventual goal of offering study-level realism. Looking ahead, Airfoillabs plans to refine the AFDS further, focusing on smoother LNAV and VNAV captures, approach handling, and system protections. Work is also underway on expanding the autothrottle, adding mode safeguards, and improving throttle lever behaviour.  Alongside this, the team continues quality checks on navigational data, as well as polishing cockpit details, such as backlighting and switch feel, to ensure consistency across both 2D and VR. For the full details, you can read Airfoillab’s numerous blog posts on the X-Plane.Org Forum, and visit the product page here. No release date has been announced, however progress seems to be moving along nicely.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barreirinhas</id>
    <title>flyt Simulations Releases Barreirinhas Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barreirinhas"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c8d3993c6b84b8d8850327_maranhao1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt Simulations has recently released their rendition of Barreirinhas Lençóis Maranhenses Regional Airport (SSRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Barreirinhas, Maranhão, Brazil. It opened only four years ago, replacing the older facility, which has been closed since then.  Easaero operates it, and there are no scheduled flights to Barreirinhas as of yet. It's mainly used for panoramic flights of the Lençóis Maranhenses National Park, one of the UNESCO World Heritage sites due to its exceptional beauty and overall uniqueness. There's nothing quite like it anywhere else in the world. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality 3D buildings, custom clutter, and much more. It's available in the Marketplace for $5.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol113</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates Volanta Flight Tracker to v1.13.0 </title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol113"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9870ee32b1aa1f00cdeb2_social.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated its popular Volanta Flight Tracker to v1.13.0, introducing a mix of new features, quality-of-life tweaks, and perhaps some rather unexpected additions.  At the centre of this update is support for MSFS 2024’s walk-around mode, which allows player movement outside of the cockpit to be tracked by Volanta, just like in the air. When stepping out of the cockpit to explore, you will now see your path logged as blue lines, recorded alongside your flights in purple. A new kind of aerocache has also been introduced, available only in walk-around mode. These hidden collectables are marked by orange circles on the map and, for now, are exclusive to Orbx’s new Jurassic World: Archipelago scenery, off the coast of Costa Rica.  That pack adds nine airfields, 12 helipads, and more than 550 square miles of terrain to explore, and yes, dinosaurs are included. Read more about it here. Elsewhere, Volanta gains a new map layer for points of interest (POIs), designed to highlight locations worth visiting, with more detailed map data. Flight cards have also been given themed styles, when departing or arriving at Jurassic World airports. Behind the scenes, Orbx has released an entirely new plugin for MSFS users. The installer has been simplified, bugs such as auto-selecting aircraft have been ironed out, and overall performance impact has been reduced. This plugin supports all the latest features of v.1.13.0, including the new avatar tracking. For those who would prefer to keep things strictly realistic, the fictional Jurassic content can be disabled via a toggle, available for all Volanta users, as of the latest patch. You can read the full changelog of v1.13.0 here: Enhancements (As of version 1.13.2, Premium is no longer required to disable fictional content) Volanta v1.13.0 is available now as a free update. The program can be downloaded free of charge from the Volanta website, supporting virtually every simulator out there, from DCS and Aerofly, to Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ft43se</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates F406 Caravan II &amp; T-33 Jet Trainer for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ft43se"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9dcd1196a963bc2883ece_image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has issued maintenance updates for two of its Microsoft Flight Simulator aircraft, with the F406 Caravan II moving to v1.0.4, and the T-33 Jet Trainer updated to v1.0.6. The focus is squarely on visual polish, small avionics corrections, and a targeted fix for the T-33 in MSFS 2024. On the F406, v1.0.4 tidies a number of long-standing visual quirks. Texture artefacts around the fuselage, windows, and exhausts have been corrected, clipping inside the exhausts has been resolved, and floating decals have been corrected. Missing pilot models now also appear as expected.  In the cockpit, orphaned text on the WT Garmin unit, plus background issues on OBS2 TO/FROM flags, have been cleaned up. As for the T-33, it has recieved a single change: a canopy LOD fix, specific to MSFS 2024, improving how the canopy displays at varying distances.  Both updates are available now via the iniManager. New customers can purchase both the F406 package and the T-33 for $27, sold separately on the iniBuilds store. For all the latest news and updates, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ktwsep</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Previews Katowice Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ktwsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9f9101e168e1067f557ca_548888828_18072700433159309_390960243165974347_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently shared some fresh previews of its in-development Katowice Airport (EPKT), showing steady progress on both the airside and landside.  The main terminal remains the headline focus, while Terminal A is also now underway, rounding out the passenger facilities. Around the ramps, work continues on Hangars 3 and 4, with the GA area also taking shape. The team also showcased development on cargo operations, including a dedicated high-loader for wide-body aircraft like the 777, 767, and 747. Furthermore, we get a preview of a new technical building in the parking area, a second radar installation, and rows of container-style office units. The on-site hotel is complete, with curbs and sidewalks in place, traffic islands and parking canopies installed, and custom signage appearing across the frontage. Spotter platforms, a local favourite, have also been built and positioned.  Lighting has advanced, with apron masts across the movement area, red obstruction lights on key structures, and custom streetlamps in the car parks, while access roads to the GA hangar, Hangar 3, and Hangar 4 are also finished. Interior terminal work now includes custom information boards, and ground equipment is being populated at each stand. LOD optimisation is progressing in parallel, to keep frames steady. For more details, visit Drzewiecki Design’s Instagram page. For all the latest news and updates, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b25jah</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Announces B-25J Mitchell for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b25jah"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cabea35455feadf03b5fca_547337499_1465656791594562_7642901538470120385_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aeroplane Heaven has confirmed its next project for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the B-25J Mitchell. Following the Lancaster, the developer is building the base J model, with the 8-gun nose “strafer”, also in scope. No release window has been given, with the team only saying “soon”. Platform plans are clear for the first step. The aircraft is coming to MSFS 2020 for now, with a console release "more than likely", on Xbox. Aeroplane Heaven adds that this project focuses solely on the B-25J, so do not expect other Mitchell variants at launch. The B-25J was the final production model of the Mitchell, blending traits of the earlier B-25D and B-25H, into what became its most formidable form. Built in Kansas City, the J rolled off the line in huge numbers, over 4,300 airframes, making it the most produced of all Mitchell variants.  While it was originally fitted with a glass nose, many were quickly adapted with a solid “strafer” nose (J2), crammed with forward-facing guns, with this variant also in development by Aeroplane Heaven. In fact, most of its 14–18 machine guns pointed ahead, including those from the dorsal turret, mounted further forward than on earlier models. The Royal Air Force operated 316 of them under the name Mitchell III, cementing the J’s reputation as both a bomber, and a rugged gun platform, in the closing years of the war. Threshold will keep you updated on all the latest regarding Aeroplane Heaven! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdc172</id>
    <title>Carenado Teases Classic Cessna 172 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdc172"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68caccbc5160e2aae8006100_547907150_1205990311568770_2091384684421266241_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has just teased their next aircraft release, hinting at a classic, steam-gauge Cessna 172.  The screenshot shows a polished, early-production airframe, at golden hour, captioned “Carenado 172 Oneseventytwo”, which strongly suggests a recreation of an early 172 model, rather than a later, Skyhawk-branded airframe. Carenado added that they hope we can “enjoy it in a couple of days”, though there is no firm date or feature list yet. From the cues on show, this looks like the original 172 that debuted in the 1950s. That aircraft evolved from the Cessna 170B, with tricycle landing gear. If confirmed, it will sit apart from the default 172S, found in MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024.  The modern Skyhawk uses a 180-horsepower, fuel-injected Lycoming IO-360, carries the aerodynamic refinements of later production, and typically tops out at 30 degrees of flap. The early 172 ran a carburetted Continental O-300 six-cylinder engine, offered up to 40 degrees of flap for short-field work, and is often noted for friendly, low-speed handling. Carenado has not shared pricing or platform details yet, but their aircraft usually arrive via the in-sim Marketplace.  Threshold will keep you updated on all the latest. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsptds</id>
    <title>Black Square Updates Piston and Turbine Duke, Adds MSFS 2024 Support</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsptds"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68caf240acef932422703b09_black-square-turbine-duke-msfs-13_1600x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has rolled out v0.1.2 for both the Piston Duke and Turbine Duke, bringing full MSFS 2024 compatibility, a raft of new interactions, and a long list of fixes. The headline addition is an expanded pre-flight walk-around for 2024, complete with collision models and clickspots for chocks, pitot covers, doors, and baggage bays. Both aircraft gain a new headphone simulation, with adjustable attenuation, refreshed interior lighting, new magnetic compass effects, GTNxi 750/650 bezels, support for TDS GTNxi Advanced Crossfill, and quality-of-life tweaks across the tablet, legacy radios, and animations.  Black Square has also implemented a workaround for MSFS 2024’s dynamic registration quirk, restored cockpit precipitation sounds, improved oxygen logic in pressurised scenarios, and provided a batch of avionics and systems fixes. The Turbine Duke receives further love, with a smoother prop governor model, an “Instant Beta on Touchdown” option for reliable beta entry after landing, new engine-driven fuel pump failure logic, faster torque indication changes, and additional polish to the cabin visualiser.  The Piston Duke received new oil-pump failure and engine-seizing physics, along with custom toe-brake animations, that play nicely with the parking brake. Across both packages, numerous niggles have been addressed, from reversed glideslope sensing on the copilot side to tablet refresh delays to oddities in heater blower behaviour on hot days, aiming for cleaner ops in both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Updates and corresponding changelogs are available through the Contrail app. New customers can purchase both aircraft for $50.89 separately, or together in a bundle, for $72.10, also through Contrail. For all the latest in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini100</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Impulse 100 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini100"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc254362a96576bcc40424_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has announced its latest upcoming addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the Impulse 100. Nicknamed the “Pocket Rocket”, it is a high-performance aircraft known for impressive speed and sharp handling. The addon will feature a highly accurate 3D model, a detailed electrical system, realistic lighting, an accurate simulation of the Allison 250-C20R engine, a custom-designed fuel system, custom system simulations, and much more. While a specific release date has not been announced, the team states that it is coming soon. The store page for the aircraft is now live and reveals that it will be priced at $16.37. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mig29e</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Releases MiG-29A Early Access</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mig29e"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc277c0a88b80202d63ea9_546152110_1171185158390354_2885748911819553500_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. The long-awaited MiG-29A Fulcrum has finally been released in early access form! One of the most popular fighter jets of all time, with over 1,600 units built, has been brought to DCS by Eagle Dynamics. Developed by Mikoyan and Gurevich Design Bureau during the 1970s, along with the Sukhoi Su-27, it was built to oppose the American F-15 and F-16. Originally designed as an air superiority fighter, the Fulcrum has slowly transitioned to a multirole fighter throughout its service life, with many of them being retrofitted to use air-to-surface and precision munitions. Today, the MiG-29 is used by 25 air forces around the globe. The Eagle Dynamics’ rendition of this fighter jet features a fully interactive cockpit based on 3D scanning and photogrammetry, a highly detailed external and pilot model, high-fidelity aircraft systems, fully-developed navigation system with multiple modes (POINT-TO-POINT, RETURN, LANDING, TRAFFIC RE-ENTRY), realistic modelling of RWR, flare dispenser system, FIre Control Radar, basic IFF (Identity Friend or Foe), Early Access Guide, Training Missions, as well as a full russian cockpit, with an option for a cockpit and technical inscriptions in English. At the final release, the module will also feature Ground Control Intercept (GCI) command system, a fully modelled IFF, a complete flight manual, a campaign by Eagle Dynamics, and a larger number of liveries and missions. ‍ The full feature list is as follows: The MiG-29A Fulcrum module is currently on an Early Access sale, and is available for purchase at the DCS E-Shop for $63.99, with the price increasing to $79.99 after the sale’s end (keep in mind that this module is incompatible with the Steam version of DCS!), and requires at least 2.64GB of free disk space. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b17sep</id>
    <title>MicroProse Previews B-17 Flying Fortress for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b17sep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc3cebf03642f58b1e0490_microprose-msfs-b-17-g-the-queen-02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse is bringing one of aviation’s most legendary aircraft to Microsoft Flight Simulator, and recently shared a new update on the project. The B-17 Flying Fortress is now deep in development, for both MSFS 2020 and 2024. A trailer shared on YouTube gives us a closer look at the project, which is being built in partnership with Hangar Thirteen and the 100th Bomb Group Foundation. The aircraft is part of MicroProse’s Heritage Valor Collection, a series focused on recreating iconic warbirds, with the highest possible fidelity. According to MicroProse, the B-17 will feature a detailed flight model, authentic sound recordings from surviving aircraft, and hand-crafted 4K PBR textures, that show every rivet, scuff, and patch of wear. The team is also promising a faithful recreation of the bomber’s complex systems, from electrical power, to crew operations, all designed to immerse simmers in what it was like to fly one of these heavy bombers, as close as possible. For many, the B-17 needs little introduction. It was the backbone of the USAAF’s daylight bombing campaign over Europe, famed for both its firepower, and durability. Now, MicroProse wants to capture that same spirit in the virtual skies, bringing the Flying Fortress back to life, for a new generation to enjoy. The project is still in development, with no firm release date yet, but MicroProse has confirmed it will be available through the in-sim Marketplace, once complete. For more information about the project, you can visit this link. Threshold will keep you updated on MicroProse’s B-17! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
