<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-01-09T18:41:12.950052+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaccu25024</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Releases Native Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaccu25024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694f09f57c89041e08b3844c_manche1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently released a native build of their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, including new 2024-only features such as the new EFB apps, dirt accumulation, and more. ​ The upgrade brings native 2024 gauges, a native 2024 EFB with charts and other apps, a full walkaround system using 2024’s standards, dirt accumulation on the exterior, dual PMS/TDS GTN 750/650 configuration, time compression support, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: It’s available in their store for $49.99, and owners of the MSFS 2020 version can upgrade for a discounted price ($14.99). The upgrade is not mandatory, and the previous version will continue to work in 2024, albeit without the new features. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/l73v2r</id>
    <title>LevelUp 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 Set for Dec. 30 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/l73v2r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695032e07ab2038b76a39d1a_Available-Now%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The LevelUp 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 appears set to release on Dec. 30, quietly revealed via its download page, with a short note simply stating, “See you on the 30th”. The update marks the long-awaited first stage of the V2 refresh for X-Plane 12, delivering a comprehensive visual and audio overhaul years in the making.  Stage 1 focuses on exterior and cabin upgrades, pairing a rejuvenated 3D model with brand-new 8K textures, optimised geometry, and a modular visual architecture, designed to keep file size small. The V2 package brings the complete five-member 737NG family, spanning the -600 through -900ER, all powered by Zibo systems, and all benefiting from a reworked cabin, improved exterior modelling, and a wide range of configuration options, from split scimitar winglets to eyebrow windows. Sound has also been a significant focus, with a revamped FMOD 2.0 soundset, professionally recorded material, improved performance, and far greater depth across both interior and exterior audio, including a more authentic CFM56 sound profile. Following the release of Stage 1, Stage 2 will introduce a fully reworked cockpit, flight model improvements and more.  We’ll keep you updated on any future developments, leading up to release day. For more information, you can check out the official LevelUp Discord server. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mgoatr</id>
    <title>Mango Studios Announces ATR 72-500 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mgoatr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69504c4feec84d0e916e5bcf_600347200_877109611962696_5780293440335014144_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In a surprise announcement, Mango Studios, perhaps a name more commonly associated with audio addons than aircraft, has revealed its first-ever aircraft project, the ATR 72-500 for X-Plane 12. The project is stated to have been in development for around nine months and is being created in partnership with Alsie Express, alongside volunteer contributors from across the flight simulation community.  According to Mango Studios, the goal is to deliver a highly authentic, deeply researched ATR simulation, built using real-world photographic references, pilot feedback, and extensive technical study. Planned features include a fully custom FMOD sound set, bespoke aircraft systems, a detailed 3D model with high-resolution textures, an integrated electronic flight bag, and custom animations throughout. While the aircraft remains firmly work-in-progress, early screenshots have already been shared, offering a first look at the external modelling and surface detail. You can read more about that here. No release window, pricing, or development roadmap has been announced at this stage, and Mango Studios has been clear that the project is still in its early phases, which the pictures so far also represent. You can read more about the project on the X-Plane.org forums. We will keep you updated as development continues. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mgmtdc</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Teases Major Hardware Refresh</title>
    <updated>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mgmtdc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69517398eec84d0e91a16508_602974703_122215487966063585_8627058572866468407_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Meridian GMT has recently teased that a major product update is just days away, with its official website set to receive a complete refresh on Dec. 30. This will include new product pages, several previously unseen features, and an expected launch window for its upcoming hardware lineup. The update was previewed in a short video teaser, where the team has promised a steady drip-feed of information.  Each day leading up to Dec. 30, Meridian GMT says it will highlight a new or updated feature on its Facebook page, with live answers to questions in the comments.  As part of the post, Meridian GMT confirmed a reset of its product naming, dropping the earlier phonetic system in favour of clearer, brand-led names.  Under the new structure, yokes will be grouped under the Horizon Series, while throttle quadrants will carry the Latitude branding, beginning with the Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant. Carrying on, as part of their daily feature highlights, Meridian GMT has also showed off two core pillars of the upcoming hardware refresh.  The first is "Quantum Leap", a new 16-bit TMR sensor system, borrowed from aerospace and industrial applications, designed to deliver higher resolution, lower noise, and more consistent, centre precision than traditional Hall-effect sensors. These are deployed selectively on axes where accuracy matters most, including roll, throttle, and trim.  Alongside this sits "ModulAIR", Meridian’s modular control architecture, built into both Horizon Plus and Latitude Plus, allowing pilots to expand and upgrade their setups over time, without replacing entire units. This is achieved while still maintaining mechanical and electrical compatibility across future generations, supporting a more flexible, long-term hardware ecosystem.  For more information and teasers, check out Meridian’s Facebook page.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/340dec</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Shares Full A340-600 Pro Test Flight</title>
    <updated>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/340dec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695189c49517d8d65b230c98_69XntUbTIcU-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has delivered a pleasant surprise for fans of the A340, releasing a whole, uncut test flight video of the upcoming A340-600 Pro, showcasing the aircraft on a full Frankfurt–Boston sector. The footage, shared by the Aerosoft Flight team, offers an extended look at the aircraft’s current state, including system operation, flight dynamics, EFB interaction, sounds, and exterior visuals. The A340-600 Pro is being developed as a collaboration between Aerosoft and ToLiss, combining ToLiss’s systems and flight modelling expertise, with Aerosoft’s visual and artistic work.  The aircraft is planned for release on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, although it remains firmly in development for now.  As always, keep in mind that this is still a work-in-progress build, and does not necessarily represent the final product. As of the latest, you can expect release sometime in 2026. For more information and teasers, you can check out Aerosoft’s Discord server.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrfterjdec</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Posts Development Update for the ERJ Family 2.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrfterjdec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69525d539ee102ae2394925a_ERJ-FAMILY-2.0-FULL-SYSTEMS-SIMULATION-PREVIEW_12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts has provided an update on the upcoming ERJ Family 2.0 for X-Plane, confirming that the aircraft will not be released in 2025 as previously announced. The X-Crafts ERJ Family 2.0 will not be released in 2025, as the company has chosen to prioritise quality over meeting that deadline. They indicated that the main reason for the delay is that they have pushed their development efforts further than ever before. According to X-Crafts, their real ERJ pilot testers can fly the aircraft just like they would in real life, and 99 percent of all cockpit buttons are operational. The only exceptions are circuit breakers or buttons that cannot be realistically simulated in a flight simulator. Marko Mamula, founder of X-Crafts, states that all systems, including flight controls and an authentic FMS with holding patterns, have been implemented. A detailed systems showcase has also been posted. AirComms is a new on-screen interface designed to assist you in flying the aircraft. It will feature interactive tutorials, offer tips on when to perform specific actions, and provide warnings if certain tasks are overlooked. AirComms looks to be aimed at users who are less familiar with the ERJ Family, helping them to quickly get up to speed. X-Crafts has not provided an updated release date, but the aircraft is largely complete. They have mentioned that the main things still needed are documentation, website resources, screenshots, and other materials. ‍ For more on the ERJ Family 2.0, check out Marko Mamula’s blog post. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lvl737</id>
    <title>LevelUp Releases 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lvl737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6952fc3b056ada59f5b3f1b1_ForXP12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After the long wait, LevelUp has finally released the 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 update for X-Plane 12!  The new update brings new FMOD sounds, 8K exterior textures and new models, a remodelled cabin interior, as well as the newest ZiboMod systems update. Both the exterior and the interior have received big upgrades, with higher poly counts on the exterior - winglets, engine cowlings and gear tyres, which will make them look smoother compared to the older version. Along with the new 3D models, textures were also a part of the update, as all the above-mentioned items now have 8K textures. Meanwhile, the cabin has received a refresh, with the new models that are closer to the seats mostly used in today's aircraft. Another big part of the update are the new sounds. Using the 2.0 FMOD, it features an entirely new soundset, with plenty of new and improved sounds, such as stick shaker rattle, bleed air rush after shut-down, HUD handling sounds, improved environment sounds, cabin chatter, touchdown sounds, as well as improved touchdown sound logic. The LevelUp 737NG Series V2 update is available for download on the Threshold forums and the OrbxDirect for free, and requires just 0.94GB of free disk space. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/newgmt</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Website Relaunch Goes Live, Reveals Full Hardware Line-Up</title>
    <updated>2025-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/newgmt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69559d21c030d96f3ecf5e9c_latitude-product%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Meridian GMT has officially launched its redesigned website, marking a significant milestone for the studio and putting its long-teased hardware ecosystem in the spotlight. This follows the initial announcement made by Meridian on Christmas Day. The updated product pages are now available at MeridianGMT.com, showcasing various imagery, specifications, and feature breakdowns for the Horizon Plus Flight Controls, Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant, and the X-Ray Handheld FlightDeck. At the centre of the line-up is the Horizon Plus Flight Controls, Meridian’s flagship yoke system, designed around a modular architecture that allows pilots to tailor the setup for airliner or general aviation operations.  The system combines a full-range roll axis with a deliberately asymmetric pitch mechanism, providing precision during rotation, approach, and landing. At the same time, modular avionics bays on either side allow panels to be swapped, as flying styles change. Sitting alongside it is the Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant, a highly configurable throttle solution, with interchangeable lever sets and magnetic faceplates. This allows for quick transitions between various Boeing, Airbus, and GA configurations. Rounding out the ecosystem is the X-Ray Handheld FlightDeck, a compact controller designed for couch and casual flying, with magnetic faceplates, tactile controls, and a strong emphasis on accessibility.  Full information on X-Ray compatibility, particularly for console use, will follow once licensing processes are completed in January. ‍ The website relaunch also confirms Meridian’s move away from its earlier phonetic naming scheme, with product names now aligned directly to the brand’s identity, a change founder Nicki says represents a clean break from the company’s past, and a renewed focus on its own design language.  According to the published roadmap, a non-binding pre-order sign-up for the Horizon Plus Flight Controls is planned to open on Jan. 20, 2026, serving as a system and demand test, with full pre-orders expected from Feb. 1, 2026. The Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant will follow shortly after. They also plan to showcase hands-on prototypes at FSWeekend in Lelystad and at FlightSimExpo 2026 in Saint Paul, Minnesota, ahead of beta units and wider pre-orders rolling out during the second quarter of 2026.  Pre-orders will, however, only open once production timelines are formally locked in with manufacturing partners. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shsbud</id>
    <title>SkyHigh Studios Announces Budapest Liszt Ferenc for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shsbud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6958fb2bb20f890dcc5375aa_607485218_1430484399080870_653525041141878838_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SkyHigh Studios has announced that it is developing Budapest Liszt Ferenc International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, marking the studio’s first confirmed project for the new platform.  The announcement was shared alongside a small selection of early in-sim screenshots, offering an initial look at the airport’s terminal areas, surrounding buildings, and parts of the cargo complex. Liszt Ferenc, named after the famous Hungarian composer Franz Liszt, is Hungary’s primary international gateway, and a significant hub for Central and Eastern Europe.  It has a strong presence from Wizz Air, alongside numerous cargo and long-haul operators, also previously hosting the now-defunct Hungarian flag carrier, Malév. SkyHigh Studios has not yet shared detailed feature lists or technical specifications. However, the previews suggest a focus on details, including terminal interiors, landside structures, and airport-adjacent scenery, all of which are still clearly in early development. No release window has been confirmed at this time. SkyHigh Studios says more information will be shared as development progresses.  We’ll keep you updated. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atmo10</id>
    <title>REX Simulations Releases Atmos Core Technical Update 1.0</title>
    <updated>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atmo10"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690157e70cff0654c089ed7e_68b206df44ac00c5f59ecd96_atmos-core-hero.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. REX Simulations has released Technical Update 1.0 for REX Atmos CORE, delivering a wide-ranging update focused on stability, compatibility, and weather rendering improvements for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The headline change is full compatibility with Sim Update 4, addressing multiple integration points affected by the update, including environmental data offsets and API communication, ensuring Atmos Core continues to inject weather and atmospheric changes reliably.  Alongside this, REX has resolved long-standing issues with custom weather rendering across METAR, Simple, and Advanced modes, rebuilding the internal hooks to improve multi-layer atmospheric rendering, cloud behaviour, and lighting synchronisation. Several usability and reliability fixes are also included, such as corrected UI validation that previously blocked preset saving, improved reading of the local settings.json file, and minor interface clean-ups. The update also introduces a new startup log system, designed to verify application processes during launch, as well as simulator runtime validation, which confirms that the simulator is running before Atmos Core initialises, reducing the risk of errors or failed startups. REX notes that this is a full version release, and strongly recommends uninstalling all previous versions of Atmos Core before installing build 8.1.2025.1210.  For the full release notes, visit REX's Discord server, or click here.  You can also read Threshold’s hands-on review of REX Atmos Core here.  ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hbhm</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Birmingham–Shuttlesworth for X-Plane 11/12</title>
    <updated>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hbhm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695915ee884343ea80e9fdbe_371406_Cessna_172SP_-_2025-12-27_22.57.02_copy%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Fly2High has released Birmingham–Shuttlesworth International Airport (KBHM) for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12, bringing Alabama’s primary commercial airport to the platform. Located just northeast of downtown Birmingham, Birmingham–Shuttlesworth International Airport serves a mix of airline, cargo, and general aviation traffic, making it a versatile place for regional and domestic operations. The scenery features custom-modelled terminals, realistic PBR textures across buildings and ground surfaces, hand-placed night lighting, and an accurately reproduced airfield layout, all tuned to remain performance-friendly.  Additional touches include modelled terminal interiors, custom mesh, detailed vegetation, 3D grass, and a faithfully recreated area of the Alabama Air National Guard. KBHM Birmingham–Shuttlesworth is available now for $16.99 on the X-Plane.org Store, and is also on sale via SimMarket. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ss220u</id>
    <title>Synaptic Simulations Shares A220 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2026-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ss220u"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695adcf09a00a32183e5de53_image1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Synaptic Simulations has shared a brief end-of-year development update on its upcoming A220, offering a snapshot of where the project stands as it heads into 2026. Over the past year, the team has made steady progress across the aircraft’s core systems, including engine control, fly-by-wire, and autoflight logic, as well as a significant rebuild of the flight management system, to support deeper system integration.  System complexity has continued to grow, with the EICAS now featuring more than 100 messages. At the same time, ongoing revisions to both the engine and flight models aim to further refine the aircraft’s handling and performance.  Looking ahead, Synaptic says testing will ramp up in the coming months, with a focus on LNAV behaviour across global procedures, VNAV integration, and ensuring that performance data is adequately respected by guidance and engine systems. A handful of remaining systems, including pressurisation and autobrakes, are still being finalised.  While the A220 did not release in 2025, the team reiterated that the extra time is being used to deliver a more complete, polished product, with further updates expected, as development continues into the new year.  Read the full update on Synaptic's Discord. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsaw26</id>
    <title>Vote Now: Community Nominations Open for Flightsim Awards 2026</title>
    <updated>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsaw26"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695be909ac215d8654456993_FLIGHTSIM_AWAR_Black_Background.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The community survey for the Flightsim Awards 2026 is now live, marking the opening of the official nomination phase for next year’s awards.  The survey allows simmers to nominate projects, developers, creators, and long-term contributors they believe made a meaningful impact on the flight simulation scene in 2025. The nomination phase plays a key role in shaping the final shortlist, covering a wide range of categories across aircraft, scenery, tools, freeware, hardware, innovation, and community contributions.  Participants are free to nominate in as many or as few categories as they wish, with no requirement to complete the entire form. All submissions will be reviewed and passed on to the Flightsim Awards organising board and jury, alongside nominations gathered from invited content creators and media outlets. The goal is to ensure that the final voting slate reflects a broad community sentiment, rather than a curated selection. All entries are evaluated according to shared principles: The survey is being distributed jointly by Threshold, FSElite, and Cruiselevel, who together organise the Flight Sim Awards. Public voting will follow later in the process, with a jury step only used in cases of ties or irregular results. Nominations are open until the published deadline, with eligibility limited to products and projects released or significantly updated in 2025.  The winners will be revealed during the Captain’s Dinner at FlightSimWeekend 2026, on Friday, March 20.  ‍ Take the nomination survey here.  You can read more on the Flight Sim Awards website. Tickets to FlightSimWeekend 2026 and the Captain's Dinner can be found here. ‍ Join the Flight Sim Awards Discord and be a part of the Awards community! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsogaleo2</id>
    <title>FSoares Shares New Galeão International Airport Previews </title>
    <updated>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsogaleo2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695c3b3230f0a76c32a4119e_rio1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSoares has recently teased the development progress on his Rio de Janeiro/Galeão International Airport (SBGL) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is the main airport serving Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with a yearly average of 14.5 million passengers. It was opened in 1952 on top of a pre-existing Brazilian Air Force base that was utilized by international long-haul flights, which were too heavy and too large for SBRJ’s (Rio’s domestic airport) 1,300 m runway. With the ever-increasing international demand, they finally built a passenger terminal, which was progressively expanded until 1977. A new terminal building was opened that year, and all scheduled passenger traffic was transferred there. It’s still in use today as Terminal 1. Terminal 1 was first renovated in 1991 in preparation for the United Nations Earth Summit (held in 1992), and its annual capacity increased to 7.5 million passengers. Eight years later, Terminal 2 was opened, featuring 24 jetways and a capacity of up to 7.5 million passengers per year. ‍With the imminence of the World Cup and the Olympic Games in 2014 and 2016, respectively, Infraero (the airport’s former manager) unveiled a $431 million upgrade and expansion plan for Galeão, including the renovation of Terminal 1, the completion of Terminal 2, and the expansion of the parking lots. The new concessionary revised the plans and included a new pier with 26 jetways, a new apron for 97 aircraft, and 2640 parking spaces. The $400 million sum quickly jumped to $800 million instead. Aerolíneas Argentinas, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, Azul, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Flybondi, Gol, Iberia, ITA Airways, JetSmart Argentina, JetSmart Chile, KLM, Latam Brasil, Latam Chile, Latam Perú, Lufthansa, Paranair, Sky Airlines, TAP, and United Airlines serve it. There is no information on features, pricing, or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbt267</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Targets 2026 for 757 Release</title>
    <updated>2026-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbt267"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695dcaa617a27011d5d4fb98_610642515_1180738477521565_5941258756545479178_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. BlueBird Simulations recently took to Facebook to announce that they are planning to release their 757 in 2026. The initial release will include a version of the plane compatible with both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This will be followed up with a native 2024 version of the 757. The latter will be provided free of charge for those who purchase the initial release version. The team has promised that a ten to twenty-minute video update will be posted by the end of January. After releasing the video update later this month, the team plans to do one more pre-release video. This final video will detail the full features of the simulation and provide a specific release date for Bluebird Simulation’s 757.  Along with the 757 news, Bluebird Simulations has announced that they’ve committed themselves to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 only for all subsequent releases.  ‍ Finally, Bluebird Simulations has announced that its Discord will be open later this year. This will support the 757 release and all the various free updates the team has planned. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lirfv2</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Rome Fiumicino V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lirfv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695fe8c0782a7ec1a7f24ed5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has just released Rome Fiumicino V2, their latest scenery package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This package offers an intricately detailed recreation of Rome Fiumicino Airport (LIRF), which is the eighth-busiest airport in Europe. The original version, Rome Fiumicino V1, was released in 2022, and now, three years later, V2 has been introduced, enhancing and expanding upon the features of the previous version. The airport opened its doors in 1961, originally featuring only two runways. A third runway was constructed shortly after during the 1960s. Over the years, the airport has undergone various improvements and expansions, including terminal upgrades and the construction of new terminals. Today, the airport welcomes almost 50 million passengers annually, with airlines such as ITA Airways, easyJet, and Neos operating flights to and from destinations around the globe. Rome Fiumicino V2 features high-quality 3D models and textures, modelled terminal interiors, an up-to-date ground layout, custom-designed jetways, immersive lighting, and more. The newly released Rome Fiumicino V2 by MK Studios is now available from Contrail for $21.41. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
