<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-04-01T18:20:21.735561+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbroc</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Rockhampton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbroc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641ee7e3d5928070e16588f3_rock1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2027019"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Rockhampton Airport (YBRK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a major Australian regional airport serving the city of Rockhampton. It’s the 17th busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 634,913 passengers (as of 2014-2015).  The airport opened in March 1930 as Rockhampton Aero Club flying field after many years of collective effort to find a suitable site in the city to build an aerodrome. It was built on top of a former racecourse, Connor Park, acquired by some aspiring aviators and adapted for airplanes. The first passenger aircraft to touch Rockhampton’s runway was a Fokker monoplane during the opening ceremony.   Between 1938 and 2021, Rockhampton Airport hosted a meteorological office providing proper weather observation for airplanes and general purposes. It was closed two years ago after generating a lot of discussion between the locals.  The airport saw its first upgrades during World War 2, with its total land size doubling, and a new 1,250-yard bitumen runway was built to reduce the dust being stirred up by the propellers and causing discomfort to passengers and interfering with the meteorological station. The Australian Royal Air Force moved in shortly after, establishing an Aeradio station that survived until 1992.   Due to its proximity to the Fitzroy River, the airport is prone to closures when the river floods, which caused it to close many times over in 1954, 1991, 2011, and 2017, which eventually prompted a proposal to relocate the airport.   Rockhampton was redeveloped in 2008 at the cost of 8 million Australian dollars, which included a complete renovation of the terminal, removing an old viewing deck, a new café/restaurant, relocation of offices and check-in counters, and a customs screening point for international flights, along with new air conditioning equipment and improved lighting.   Recently, the airport saw a new upgrade, with a 41 million dollar refurbishment that included new body scanners and body screening equipment, private airline lounges, a FIFO hub, additional retail and hospitality businesses, and a slight update on existing amenities. Work progressed further than expected because it coincided with the pandemic in 2020 and 2021.  It’s currently served by four airlines: Bonza (Sunshine Coast, Townsville), QantasLink (Brisbane, Cairns, Mackay, Townsville), Skytrans Airlines (Cairns and Proserpine), and Virgin Australia (Brisbane).  The scenery features a detailed rendition of Rockhampton Airport with ultra-high-resolution textures, custom groundpoly, taxiway lighting, military and GA static aircraft, interior terminal modeling of the departure area, terraformed runways, drainage channels, taxiways, and aprons, and crisp 15cm aerial imagery.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.39, requiring at least 1.17 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfs12</id>
    <title>MSFS Update 12 Brings New Features</title>
    <updated>2023-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfs12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641f119feb63762abe961aa6_MicrosoftTeams-image-4-1536x864.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="652058"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has released sim update 12. This update includes multiple bug fixes as well as some new features. Big features include WASM support for Xbox users and new controls for turbulence. The biggest release as a part of this update is WASM support. WASM is the core script to Microsoft Flight Simulator and is attributed to the lack of support for addons in the Xbox edition. With this script being added to the Xbox edition, we will begin to see add-ons that were only available for PC move into the Xbox edition.  Along with the WASM support, numerous general fixes were made, and several improvements were also made to the navigation/ traffic system. Live weather also received a big update with new controls for turbulence. The Garmin G3000 and G5000 systems received updates to improve functionality and accuracy.   Finally, several aircraft received fixes and improvements, with the A310, Cessna Citation Longitude, and the Cessna Citation CJ4 receiving the most updates.  ‍ For a full list of improvements and more information on how to install this update, please visit the Microsoft Flight Simulator Forum for more details.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/azu160</id>
    <title>AzurPoly Tease New C-160 Transall for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/azu160" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6420481b17d5d466c7cee835_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="805228"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Azur Poly has released a video trailer of their upcoming C-160 project for Microsoft flight simulator. Although the trailer reveals little about how far along the project is or an expected timeframe for release, we do get to see the aircraft and some of its features.  The Transall C-160 is a military transport aircraft developed by a combination of German and French aircraft design companies, the main ones involved being: Aerospatiale, Fokker and Messerschmitt-Bölkow-Blohm. The aircraft was first built in 1965, with production ending for the most part in 1985. Although this aircraft proved vastly popular throughout its career, it is now being phased out in favour of more modern and advanced replacements.  It is unclear as to when the C-160 will release for MSFS, but according to Azurpolly, it's coming soon! </summary>
    <published>2023-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini7we</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Spartan 7W Executive for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini7we" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6420db7baddeff4f99537c14_image.thumb.png.d6f874ebd599aab7625ce4197cb563f7.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="214786"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds have announced the next project in their CLASSIC aircraft range, the Spartan 7W Executive. This project is still in the early stages of development so stay tuned to Threshold for further updates.  The Spartan 7W Executive is a late 1930s aircraft built for the fledgling executive market. The aircraft featured an all-metal construction with fabric flight controls. Production started in 1936 but was halted shortly after due to World War II. Production never resumed after the war and only 36 examples were built over several models.  The iniBuilds project will focus on the most popular 7W model, with 34 built. This edition of the aircraft featured a spacious cabin and was powered by a single 400Hp Pratt &amp; Whitney R-985 radial engine. Although the aircraft had a short production run, 17 examples are known to exist, with several in airworthy condition.  No official release date has been announced yet, but stay tuned to Threshold as development continues. You can also find more information on the iniBuilds forums.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sivtuu</id>
    <title>SIMMAN releases Ubon Ratchathani Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sivtuu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6420e3c615d455af6ab503e1_315907_37.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3061887"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer SIMMAN has released Ubon Ratchathani Airport (ICAO: VTUU) for MSFS. VTUU is the main airport for the Ubon Ratchathani Province in Northeastern Thailand. The airport serves both civilian and military uses.  The airport, which opened in 1921, was first used for humanitarian purposes during a smallpox epidemic. In 1955 the airport began its military use when it became Ubon Royal Thai Air Force Base to support operations during the Vietnam War.  In 1975 the airport opened for commercial traffic with flights initially operating on international routes to Vietnam. International flights from the airport did not last long, the airport now serves domestic traffic only. Airlines such as; Nok Air, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Lion Air now serve destinations throughout Thailand, with the most popular destination being the capital city of Bangkok. The airport is still home to an F-5E fighter squadron.  This airport can be purchased for MSFS from the iniBuilds store and will require 1.42GB of storage space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more news. </summary>
    <published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rans6s</id>
    <title>FlyBoy Simulations Releases the Rans S6S Coyote II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rans6s" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6420ea0544163de37d973e95_315080_1.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="362552"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyBoy Simulations have released its first aircraft for MSFS, the Rans S6S Coyote II. This backcountry aircraft is one that many enthusiasts may way to take a look at. The Rans S6S Coyote II is a lightweight backcountry kit plane built by the popular backcountry aircraft designer Rans. The S6S has been in production since 1988 and comes as a “kit plane”, meaning the owner/pilot will assemble the aircraft themselves. This allows for heavy customization by the builder and the Rans kits can be built in as little as 500 man-hours.  The Ran S6S Coyote II also known as the “Super Six” comes with a 100Hp Rotax 912 engine and two different wing options. In real life the aircraft can be configured with either a nose wheel or a tail wheel, the FlyBoy release comes on both versions of the aircraft. Other features of the aircraft include: This aircraft is available from SimMarket for $15.03 USD and will require 1.94GB of disk space to install, stay tuned to Threshold for more news.</summary>
    <published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdsver</id>
    <title>Token Design Releases Vernon Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdsver" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64219d0178ea3358a1da4806_vernon1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="680681"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Token Design has recently released their rendition of Vernon Regional Airport (CYVK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a non-towered airport serving the city of Vernon, in Canada.  The origin of the airport dates back to the end of WW2 when Vernon relocated their airfield from the south of the city to the farmlands of Okanagan Landing, where it initially sported a single grass field that is half today’s length. For 20 years, the Vernon Flying Club was the sole tenant - with four aircraft - and responsible for paving the 1,200x12 runway with two inches of asphalt.  During the early 1950s, Vernon Regional got a hangar, which progressively increased the aircraft capacity and traffic at the airport, with up to eighty airplanes at one point, 20 years later down the road. Such extra traffic motivated a new runway expansion to 2,200 feet while keeping the same width.   For over 18 years, the airport remained unchanged until the late 1980s when The Vernon Flying Club and the Tri-Lake Flight Centre financed the construction of a new runway.   It’s an important airport in the region for skydivers, as it happens to be the only airport in the Okanagan Valley that allows it, given all commercial operators have to provide written consent to the skydiving company that desires to offer such service, which makes it rather unfeasible on bigger and busier airports.  The scenery features over 30 hand-modeled 3D buildings throughout the airport, an accurate replica of the main airport building terminal, the Okanagan College Aerospace Campus hangar, a custom runway with correct aprons &amp; night lighting, multiple static aircraft parked at the right areas, hand-modeled &amp; textured fuel tanks, custom taxiway signs, 4K high-detail PBR textures, and the CYVK rose compass texture on the ground.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.25, requiring at least 198.61 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdxbo</id>
    <title>PMDG Anticipates 737 Release and DC-6 Re-Release for MSFS on Xbox</title>
    <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdxbo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6421c58ad54dbf78e2755f30_Gallery_6__16156.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="137882"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After the release of sim update 12 for MSFS, many developers have announced their return to Xbox. PMDG has announced that both the 737 and DC-6 will become available on the Xbox platform soon.  PMDG has been able to accomplish this through the implementation of C++/WASM for Xbox. Many developers such as PMDG rely on this script for their aircraft to function, with the addition of this script to Xbox will allow developers to release aircraft for both platforms.  This update is a major improvement to conforming both platforms, PMDG has finalized updates for the DC-6 and expects it to become available on March 30th with the 737 expected to be complete by the end of April.  More information about the update can be found at the PMDG Forum, ad the updates will be available through the in-game marketplace. Stay tuned to Threshold for more news. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkudub</id>
    <title>MK-Studios Teases Upcoming Dublin Airport v2 Release for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkudub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64238c919961218669f047cc_d1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2031213"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK-Studios has recently teased their upcoming rendition of Dublin Airport (EIDW) v2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator with a trailer video produced by AviationLads, showcasing many of its new features.  Dublin Airport is the busiest airport in Ireland, and the 12th in Europe, averaging 30 million passengers yearly. It hosts their flag carrier Aer Lingus, the low-cost carrier beast Ryanair, and TUI Airways, with a significant route network that encompasses most of Europe and some key cities in North America.   The second version of their Dublin scenery will feature a high-fidelity rendition of the airport, built from the ground up, with crisp textures throughout all buildings and structures, detailed interiors on pier one, four, and on the control tower, recent and hand-corrected orthoimagery, detailed, true-to-life aprons, surfaces, lines and paint markings, the addition of runway 28R/10L, realistic VDGS implementation, landside buildings and significant points of interest near the airport, compatibility with most AI traffic plugins, and optimized for PC and Xbox.  While the pricing is not available yet, the product page for the scenery on OrbxDirect mentions a 2.38 GB install size.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mv2dub</id>
    <title>MK-Studios Releases Dublin Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mv2dub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6424616558d57b346ba9bfd0_mks1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2115413"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK-Studios has recently released their updated version of Dublin Airport (EIDW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding the new runway (28R/10L), improved models and textures, and more! ‍  Averaging 30 million passengers a year and holding the crown of being the busiest airport in Ireland (and 12th in Europe), Dublin Airport is the gateway to the leprechaun land, housing their flag carrier Aer Lingus with their significant international and intra-European route network, the low-cost carrier giant Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Many carriers come from all over on either fixed or seasonal basis, including Air France, American Airlines, British Airways, Emirates, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, and United Airlines.   Dublin V2 features a high-fidelity rendition of the airport built from the ground up, with crisp texturing on models and ground, detailed interiors on pier 1, 4, and on the control tower, performance-friendly optimization, recent (and color-corrected) orthoimagery, detailed aprons, true-to-life ground markings, realistic VDGS implementation, landside buildings and significant points of interest, compatibility with most AI traffic plugins and the inclusion of the brand new runway 28R/10L.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.70 (with a 30% discount for V1/P3D version owners), requiring at least 2.38 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inijfk</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces John F. Kennedy International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inijfk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6424874e3696888342456a91_jfk1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3513815"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of their next mega-hub for Microsoft Flight Simulator: John F. Kennedy International Airport (KJFK), the primary airport serving New York City and the busiest of the lot, with over 60 million passengers per year.   Opened 74 years ago as New York International Airport, or Idlewild Airport, after the homonymous golf course that it displaced in the early 1940s, it originally featured a single 7,365 square meter terminal (expanded to 20,021 square meters in 1949) and six runways.   The current naming was only adopted after John F. Kennedy’s assassination in 1963 as a tribute. It was also back when the airport took the crown as New York’s busiest, with more take-offs and landings than LaGuardia and Newark combined, and even managed to be the second busiest in the country with nearly 404,000 airline operations. With LaGuardia’s eventual expansion, the figures evened out by the 70s, with similar flight counts.   As a curiosity, KJFK was the first airport in the United States ever to receive a commercial A380 flight in March 2007. The first regularly scheduled commercial flight to ever land on JFK happened a year later, by the wings of Emirates (Dubai - JFK route). The list of A380 operators with a regular schedule goes way beyond that, with Singapore Airlines, Air France, Korean Air, and Etihad Airways. It was also the first American airport to receive a commercial A350 flight in 2015.  The busiest international gateway to the United States is served and visited by over 90 airlines, covering all the inhabited continents around the globe. JetBlue tops the market share chart, with 28.8% or 15,624,961 passengers, followed by Delta Air Lines and American Airlines, with 28.4% (15,390,437) and 14.5% (7,870,971), respectively. From foreign operators, Air France leads the way with 1.9% of the total market share or 1,025,339 passengers.  The scenery will feature highly detailed models of all airport buildings, objects, and surroundings, with hand-crafted ground poly, crisp textures, accurately modeled and positioned dynamic lighting, custom static aircraft, custom jetways (10+), true-to-life airport landside recreation, realistic taxi signage, up to date airport layout, fully animated JFK AirTrain between terminals, LOD optimization for optimal performance, use of the latest MSFS SDK features, and full iniManager compatibility to configure the scenery for the best performance possible. They also highlight an accurate rendition of the TWA Hotel with an intricately detailed interior and the Constellation aircraft in TWA colors.   There has not been any information on the release date, pricing, or install size. Stay tuned to Threshold for further details on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/snjfuk</id>
    <title>Snj Sim Releases Fukuoka Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/snjfuk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6425e289b61fa71ecd058a34_rjff1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1088644"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Snj Sim has recently released their rendition of Fukuoka Airport (RJFF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 4th busiest airport in Japan with a yearly average of 24 million passengers. It was built during late WW2 by the Imperial Japanese Army Air Force as Mushiroda Airfield and later occupied by the USAF as Itazuke Air Base from 1945 to 1972. It was the largest USAF airbase on the island of Kyushu until its closure due to budget cuts and the gradual reduction of US Army presence in Japan. The airport saw civilian air service for the first time in 1951, with a Japan Airlines service from Fukuoka to Osaka and then Tokyo. JAL followed suit ten years later with a flight from Fukuoka to Tokyo. The first international flight only happened in 1965, to Busan in South Korea. Air Siam and Air France tried to offer international services in 1975 but it didn’t last long. As one of the busiest airports in the country, Fukuoka gets visited by many domestic and international airlines, including Air Busan, All Nippon Airways, Asiana Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Cebu Pacific, China Airlines, EVA Air, Hawaiian Airlines, Japan Airlines, Jeju Air, Jetstar Japan, Korean Air, Peach Aviation, Singapore Airlines, Thai Airways, United Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines.  The scenery features a detailed rendition of Fukuoka Airport, with surrounding buildings, custom autogen, animated jetway models, custom airport groundpoly, realistic night dynamic lights, custom static vehicles, and AI traffic plugin compatibility (tested with FSLTL). They mention an eventual update once the work on the second runway and taxiways reaches completion. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.73, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lvf320</id>
    <title>Latin VFR Release A320 CEO</title>
    <updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lvf320" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6427360d02503df5dbed7282_332239360_1345118569675623_4454289404156924450_n.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="268772"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Popular aircraft and scenery developers LatinVFR have recently released the latest addition to their ever-growing fleet of Airbus aircraft for MSFS. The A320 ceo has an impressive 90 liveries based on real-world operators and has engine options for both the CFM and IAE variants. The aircraft also comes with the option of the Airbus Sharklets rather than the standard Airbus wing tip devices.  The aircraft is the first of the LatinVFR fleet to feature their new EFB which provides an easy way to control the ground handling equipment which is modelled with the aircraft. The developer has noted that this EFB will eventually be implemented on their entire fleet.  Although the A320 appears to lack slightly in system depth when compared to the FlyByWire or Fenix options, there seems to be a real improvement on previous aircraft., LatinVFR appear to be marketing the A320 ceo to a market more suited to the casual sim pilot and to those using MSFS on games consoles.  The aircraft can be purchased through the MSFS marketplace for both XBOX and PC at the price of $24.99 ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/banf12</id>
    <title>Banff National Park UHD Released for XP12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/banf12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64273b04cb17ba373e62eeea_33.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="983118"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The talented Frank Dainese has just released his latest masterpiece for the X-Plane platform, Focusing on the Banff National Park region this stunning scenery will provide pilots with a fantastic place to fly their virtual aircraft and enjoy the stunning views that Alberta’s rocky mountains have to offer.  The scenery package includes over 13 airfields, water strips and helipads for pilots to fly from, along with 1500 square Kilometers of stunning 4K national park.  The scenery can be purchased from the Xplane.org store for $24.95 ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dditnn</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Tallinn Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dditnn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64275698381fc1e6616367af_eet1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2242922"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Tallinn Airport (EETN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Estonia’s largest and busiest airport with a yearly average of 2,700,000 passengers.   The airport’s conception dates back to 1931 when the construction work began. Completion and the official opening happened five years later, despite being operational four years before, with LOT Polish Airlines flying a Fokker F.VIIb/3m.   During World War 2, the airport was first occupied by the Soviets (1940), then by Germany (1941-1944), and later under the Soviet helm again, with Aeroflot being the sole operator for 44 years. During that period, the airport got a new terminal, designed under Stalinist architecture, and finished in 1954. As the years went by and the traffic figures increased significantly, there was a need for a newer terminal, built between 1976 and 1980, just in time for the 1980 Summer Olympics sailing event held in Tallinn. The new terminal was designed by Mihhail Piskov, taking inspiration from traditional Estonian housebarn architecture, and Maile Grünberg designed the interior.    Recent work included the construction of a cargo terminal in 1997 and a passenger terminal modernization in 1999, increasing the passenger capacity and improving the infrastructure. It was expanded again in 2008 to 35,000 square meters, the current standard. The expansion included 18 new gates, ten new check-in desks, a new restaurant and cafes, and separate lounges for Schengen and non-Schengen flights.   There are plans to expand the airport by 2035, bringing the total capacity up to 8 million passengers per year, 85,000 square meters of expanded area, and 26 gates.   The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom clutter, custom ground textures, custom jetways, interiors on all terminal buildings, static aircraft, GSX Pro compatibility, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.86, requiring at least 1.95 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tpskit</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Robert L. Bradshaw Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tpskit" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6427603aa6c4e3d257aadb16_kit1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1087999"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released their rendition of Robert L. Bradshaw Airport (TKPK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Basseterre on the island of Saint Kitts in the West Indies.  The airport was built in the 1940s as an airfield to serve the needs of the Royal Air Force during World War II. After the war, it was turned over to the local government and became a civilian airport. Over the years, the airport underwent several upgrades and expansions, including the construction of a new terminal building in the 1990s and a major renovation between 2004-2006, at the cost of 17 million USD.  With a yearly average of 400,000 passengers, St. Kitts Airport is served by ten airlines: Air Canada Rouge, Air Sunshine, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, InterCaribbean Airways, Silver Airways, Sky High, Trans Anguilla Airways, and United Airlines. Interestingly, the American Airlines service between St. Kitts and Miami/New York has been going on since 1979.   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with full night illumination, native MSFS dynamic lighting, seamless integration with the default scenery, full use of the SDK, up-to-date ground layout, custom ground markings, terminal interior, and 3D passengers.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.78, requiring at least 1.36 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
