<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-12-03T18:30:47.087735+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siaban</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Bang Phra Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siaban"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673fa0e6530024a565ee4305_bang1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SiamFlight recently released their rendition of Bang Phra Airfield (VTBT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Due to its surrounding geography, this airfield is one of the most challenging in Thailand. Located about 3 kilometers east of Bang Phra, a small village in Thailand, the airfield is home to the Thai Flying Club, the country's first and oldest club. The club is highly committed to developing and promoting General Aviation in the area. With a mountain on one end and power lines obstructing the approach on the opposite end, Bang Phra is known as one of the trickiest airfields in Thailand. It requires great dexterity with airplane controls. The scenery accurately depicts the airfield, with custom ground textures, hangars, village landmarks, a custom windsock, custom night lighting, a sloped runway, high power tension lines, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $7.38, requiring at least 7.12 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf2024</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Update on MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673fe163ad892655e82bbbe2_jr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight recently updated the community regarding their plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and eventual upgrades to include the new features made possible with the newly released platform.  Their development team has begun evaluating their in-house aircraft in the release build, with promising results in terms of visuals and performance. They plan on bringing their fleet to MSFS 2024 as soon as possible. Asobo has addressed many of the compatibility issues previously found, and they have successfully completed full flights in their newly released RJ Professional, the most complex aircraft in their fleet. However, some compatibility issues still exist and will be worked on. Considering the sheer size of their MSFS fleet, consisting of nine airplanes, the porting process might take a while to complete. Still, Just Flight will keep everyone updated through regular development updates. They also remind users that until the official compatibility update is released, they will not offer support for adventurous users trying to run their 2020 builds in 2024.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/afl737</id>
    <title>Airfoillabs Publishes 737 MAX Development Updates </title>
    <updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/afl737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674068dae54a24aec3f3888e_image-1731963660340.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airfoillabs has released a couple of development updates for their upcoming 737 MAX for X-Plane, just weeks after announcing it.  ‍ The first part of the update covered the progress of 3D development. The modelling team has fully finished the texturing of the upper overhead panel, with a focus on precise geometric accuracy and mechanical detail. The developers have also implemented a custom shader, which they claim has improved visual fidelity. Meanwhile, the flight systems have also received progress, as the engine performance and aerodynamic model have been polished to match real-life behaviour (a video of the flight model in action can be found here). An interesting part of the update is the progress made on the Electronic Flight Bag (EFB). Thanks to the new Web API available for X-Plane, the developers will be able to provide a highly functional EFB.  The last part dealt with display rendering. The previously mentioned custom shaders also enhanced the instrument displays. The displays that received development were the Primary Flight Display (PFD), Navigational Display (ND) and Engine Indication System. The video of the current state of displays can be seen here. As always, Threshold will keep you updated with all development updates and progress of AFL 737 MAX! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fir321</id>
    <title>FlightSimLabs Posts First A321 Video</title>
    <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fir321"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674229141bb7f09ce4fc9e6f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightSimLabs has recently released its first video showcasing the upcoming FlightSimLabs A321 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The video highlights the appearance of icing and demonstrates the de-icing process on the new aircraft. The team has also confirmed that the A321 will be compatible with both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and will offer a free upgrade for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The video and its descriptions provide a wealth of information about the icing and de-icing features of the aircraft. It will offer realistic environmental interactions in conjunction with the weather engine from Microsoft Flight Simulator. The short video showcases some of the enhanced immersion that the upcoming aircraft will feature. The video does not provide a specific release date but mentions "coming soon," which suggests that the aircraft's arrival is hopefully imminent. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/whale1</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/whale1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67428686aadfc99ec3353245_whale1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published a lengthy two-part development update regarding their plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the upcoming Boeing 777F, and their ongoing work on the 747 Classic (with pictures). The first part is very similar to their previous statement on their plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with their plan to rebuild their product line in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s SDK and feature all the new niceties still in place:  ‍ ‍ Their position regarding pure compatibility without the 2024 niceties is still the same. The compatibility claim made by Asobo didn’t prove to be true, with the airplanes not functioning as they should in the new simulator. They have been working together with Asobo to figure out a potential fix that would allow the straightforward drag-and-drop compatibility to work. ‍ The second part concerns their upcoming products (777F, 747 Classic) and further information on their issues with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s SDK. It lists some of the “blockers” that have been making their lives slightly harder and draws a parallel with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020’s initial period and its initial lack of development tooling.  ‍ The 777F remains under beta testing in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, with the latest beta build featuring small fixes, a completed simulation of the cargo deck lighting systems, operational controls of the cargo deck door, safety nets, and “other fun features within the main deck cargo area,” in Randazzo’s words. They have also included further integration with FSDT’s GSX, allowing the software to seamlessly manage their doors, entries, cargo loading, and unloading.  ‍ Their best-case scenario plan was to release it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 only if the release went well enough, which did not happen. Thus, they are moving ahead with the release for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020.  ‍ They anticipate another beta cycle, “likely earlier next week or the early following week,” and then “she will roll out of the hangar to support your cargo hauling adventures.” PMDG will let people know when they have the release date set. ‍ The work on the upcoming 747 Classic continues to roll forward, with code-side preparation for the 747-400 reaching an advanced stage of readiness. As the code is running within MSFS 2020 for now, they are beginning mapping changes that will be required to make it MSFS 2024 compatible, making for a “truly magnificent simulation of this airliner.” ‍ ‍ On the other hand, the 747-100 Classic Whale is shaping up nicely, with feature sets mapped up that will “open this product line up to a greater swath of users.” “After all, while navigating via fixes defined by their lat/lon positions was revolutionary back in 1971, it can be intimidating and confusing for folks who don’t understand how the process works or who might not be inclined to take the time to learn it just for their weekend simming experience”, justified Randazzo. Their 747 Classic will come with the CIVA triple INS system—fully modeled to a high degree of detail—with a built-in flight engineer ready to assist the user should they struggle with its sheer complexity. Hardcore pilots will have the option to handle it all by themselves if they so desire. In addition to the CIVA INS, they will also offer a relatively more modern option: a Honeywell FMS, which equipped many 747-100s later in their service cycle. ‍ They anticipate it will be the “most detailed classic airliner yet produced for desktop flight simulation.” ‍ PMDG’s lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fuf24c</id>
    <title>Fenix Updates A320 Series for MSFS24 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fuf24c"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674369b7a42c6b89513c8803_livery_6.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Developers at Fenix Simulations have recently updated their Airbus A320 series, originally developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, to bring compatibility with the newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, among other updates. In a blog post on their website, Fenix founder and director Aamir Thacker announces the update, as well as their plans for MSFS 2024. Thacker says that this new update is “not simply the 2020 version ported”, and that they “rebuilt the package with the 2024 SDK…[and] have taken advantage of several of the new features present in 2024”. This includes adding experimental support for 4x SimRate, changes to support MSFS 2024 walkaround mode, and more. The update also brings improvements to the aircraft itself, with a rebuilt airmass temperature simulation, rewritten fuel flow and estimated fuel onboard (EFOB) math, and various improvements to the flight model. Thacker provides a disclaimer that the support for MSFS 2024 is “entirely experimental at this stage and DO NOT consider 2024 compatibility an ‘advertised’ feature” due to MSFS 2024 being unstable, and they “do not want to begin taking customers’ money on this basis while being unable to guarantee a smooth experience”. He continues to say that Fenix “will not be considering refund requests on the basis of MSFS 2024 experiences/issues”, and they “will not be accepting customer support tickets in the 2024 environment at this time”. Additionally, Thacker mentions that they know of certain issues with the aircraft in MSFS 2024, but most of them are related to simulator-level issues which are not necessarily specific to the A320 series. Finally, Thacker adds that Fenix is not yet done with MSFS 2024, stating that “Once we’ve all had more time with the new platform and a few of the bigger issues are resolved, we’ll be back to really sink our teeth into new items”. The full changelog can be found in their blog post. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews! Join our Discord and follow us on social media to never miss another article!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tds024</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Publishes Statement on MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tds024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674640e9f7e37afd7741b387_tds1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TDS Sim Software recently announced to its Discord community the current state of their product's compatibility (TDS GTNXi) - or lack thereof - with the newly released simulator. According to TDS, their original plan was to provide compatibility within hours of the simulator's official release, with everything prepared on their side to warrant the smoothest process possible, a critical bug with the loading of external WASM gauges rendered that compatibility impossible for the time being. They reinforce that it's not a TDS-exclusive bug but an issue that affects all packages containing WASM gauges. Asobo has been informed, and the company confirms that the issue exists and that they are working on mitigating it.  TDS eagerly awaits the bug's resolution so it can release their product for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The TDS GTNXi Pro is available on their website for roughly $68.21 ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfl126</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes A300B4 Professional Development Update for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfl126"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6746460bd816149160d57716_ovh1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight has recently published a development update on their progress with their upcoming Airbus A300B4 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, showcasing the airplane’s upper flight engineer’s station and its many switches and lights.  They claim every single object has been recreated from high-resolution imagery of a real A300B4 based at the Aeroscopia museum in Toulouse, France; meaning all fonts and scales of the gauge backgrounds and annunciator lights are “as accurate as you can get in any simulator.” The showcase begins with the left-hand column, showing where pilots manage passenger and crew oxygen, hydraulics, and fuel.  Then, they skip over to the systems related to the landing gear, brakes, and fire detection, with the APU control panel lying at the very bottom and its three vertically stacked gauges for parameter monitoring, a bank of fault annunciators, switches for fuel pumps and starting, and it’s dedicated fire shut-off handle.  The upper right section houses the magnetic annunciators, which display a trefoil pattern when a piece of equipment or its circuitry shows some fault. Underneath lies the air conditioning and pressurization system, arranged from the bottom up and following on from the air bleed section. Its sheer size is explained by the dual pressurization systems for redundancy and the separate temperature controls and displays for the six passenger and cargo compartments. The last column features the panels for the flight data recorder, probe heat, and a large metal guard covering the fuel jettison switches, efficiently protecting it from accidental operation. Just Flight also mentioned on their Facebook page that the A300B4 is a MSFS 2020 product for now, and MSFS 2024 compatibility hasn’t been looked at yet. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aslimc</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Announces Release Date for Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aslimc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67477af908984b9cbc357485_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Aerosoft has just released the official trailer and announced the release date for their upcoming rendition of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport is set to be available tomorrow, and while it is initially designed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, a version compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will be available later at no extra cost. Although the pricing has not yet been announced, we will learn more about it tomorrow at the release. Aerosoft has, however, revealed the key features of the new scenery. These include an accurate representation and updated layout of the airport, detailed terminal buildings, high-quality custom structures, realistic nighttime lighting, and much more. We will keep you updated as soon as the scenery is released and available. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asmxpr</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asmxpr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67484e8088b8fa00e0945b51_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Aerosoft has recently launched its version of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. As the second busiest airport in Italy and the largest in northern Italy, it serves the city of Milan. The airport welcomes approximately 26.1 million passengers each year. Aviation activities have been taking place in the area of the current airport since 1910. In the early years, the airfield served both general and military aviation. It was not until 1948 that Milan Malpensa Airport began commercial operations. Over the years, the airport has undergone various expansions and continues to develop. In 1998, the Italian airline Alitalia relocated its main hub from the country's largest airport, Rome Fiumicino, to Milan Malpensa. Today, the airport welcomes over 26 million passengers annually, handling approximately 187.000 aircraft movements. It serves as a base for airlines such as easyJet, Neos, and Ryanair, while also accommodating a variety of other airlines that offer destinations around the world, including Rome, Amsterdam, and Singapore. David Rosenfeld has developed the newly released version of Milan Malpensa Airport, featuring an accurate and up-to-date representation of the airport, detailed terminal buildings, high-quality custom objects, realistic night lighting, and more. The add-on requires 3.4 GB of storage space and is available on Aerosoft for approximately $24.21. It's worth noticing that MSFS 2024 compatibility will be available for free in the coming weeks. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdpdud</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Posts Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdpdud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6748571a4fc14894e2191251_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently provided an update on their Discord regarding their current products and future plans. The team announced that they have entered the sustaining phase of their lifecycle, which means they will continue to support their existing projects. However, their capacity to start new projects is limited. The focus will be on v2 updates for their current projects. If they do take on any new projects, these will likely be smaller airports, similar in size to Gold Coast Airport. Next year will be dedicated to these v2 updates, although it is possible for a new project to emerge, none are currently planned. The team has provided updates on their current projects. EGLL is making steady progress, with a significant update expected in the first half of 2025, likely to include T5A.  ‍ The ZDP Library v1.2 update is nearly complete and is scheduled for release before the end of the year. ‍ RKSI will receive a v2 update featuring an updated taxiway layout, a new runway, new aprons, new buildings, and new ground textures.  ‍ MDPC is also set for a v2 update, which will include new ground textures, new vegetation, updated ortho, an updated taxiway layout, an updated apron layout, and completely redone buildings. ‍ The team intends to provide RJAA with a v2 update featuring new ground textures, ortho, vegetation, and more. However, this is a substantial task, and no timeline has been established for its completion. ‍ As for KSDF, PANC, EGNR, KCLL, and YBCG, no updates are currently planned.  ‍ Lastly, the EDHI project is unfortunately no longer active due to a lack of cooperation from iniBuilds concerning the Beluga Halle. Additionally, the source files were lost due to a hard drive failure. Consequently, the team has determined that reviving this project is not feasible at this time. The team has stated that they are monitoring the development of X-Plane 12 and the release of next-generation scenery. If any compatibility issues arise from these developments or releases, they will pause their current projects to focus on updates. As a result, the team's plans may be affected and are subject to change. ‍ We will keep you informed as soon as the team shares more information or releases any updates. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx532</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx532"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad36ef2cdccb6b9a18c44_sharklets12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update to their A320 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, focusing on stability and code infrastructure. Update 2.3.0.532 fixes an issue where the aircraft's systems would not load or unload correctly, a bug with the CAB ALT gauge not showing the correct value and a few crash fixes. The model was also improved for MSFS 2024, with a cockpit blend mask fix across ambient occlusion, metalness, and roughness.  Their installer was also updated, and it now automatically cleans up old log files when installing a new product. MS Store is preferred over Steam if both are installed, as well as additional data logging and more. The full changelog follows below: The complete lineup (A319, A320, A321) is available on their website for roughly $114. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inibbn</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Brisbane Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inibbn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6748ed0df5b2a6430f3c2c5f_bris1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently announced the development and imminent release of Brisbane Airport (YBBN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Brisbane Airport is the largest airport in Australia by land area and the third busiest in passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 23.2 million passengers. The airport’s construction started in 1980. Built by Leighton Contractors, it cost 400 million dollars and opened eight years later. It initially had a domestic terminal and two runways. Nearly a decade later, in September 1995, the international terminal was inaugurated, bringing in further passenger traffic. In 2007, the government approved the construction of a new parallel runway, which was expected to take eight years to build on swamp land 2 kilometers west of the terminal area. The unexpectedly long construction time was due to the settling period of the 13,000,000 cubic meters of sand gathered from Moreton Bay to cover the swamp. Work was completed in 2020, costing $1 billion and taking precisely eight years from start to finish. It’s a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia. Air Canada, Air Niugini, Alliance Airlines, American Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, EVA Air, Fiji Airways, FlyPelican, Jetstar, Korean Air, Link Airways, National Jet Express, Nauru Airlines, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Skytrans Airlines, Solomon Airlines, United Airlines, VietJet Air, and Virgin Australia also serve it. ‍ There’s no information regarding pricing or features yet, but Threshold will keep you informed.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777612</id>
    <title>PMDG’s Boeing 777F Release Date Confirmed, 737 Lineup Update, and More</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777612"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6748f61a71e1eca5334fa74f_777f1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG has published yet another development update, bringing further information on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 add-on compatibility, the release date of their upcoming 777F, and a micro-update for their 737 Lineup, bringing it to full parity with the marketplace version. The 737NG lineup has been updated to version 3.00.0108, matching the marketplace version to be made available in early December (according to Randazzo's predictions). It's mostly a micro-update, removing "some cruft that was determined to be unneeded in the release build of the product" at the request of the Marketplace's intake team. In their previous development update, they mentioned that the 777F would get a release date once they had issued a few cleanup builds to their beta testers. This has happened, and now they have a date in mind: next Friday (06/12), during the evening, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Pricing will be announced at release. The add-on will feature accurately modeled supernumary controls and functions, main deck lighting systems, manual or automatic operation of the main deck cargo door, safety guards, and more. They have also increased the GSX compatibility by allowing FSDT's plugin to control the doors, loading process, etc. Their take on MSFS 2024, compatibility-wise, is still the same as that of the previous development updates: they have not yet been able to fully gauge the amount of work required because the new simulator does not yet provide the required tooling. Randazzo shared PMDG's thoughts on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024: "My answer remains optimistic. I have been exploring the new sim while flying the PMDG DC-6 which is not yet fully compatible, but overlooking the dim displays and some font issues, gives a very good representation of what it will be like once we get the fleet compatible with the new platform". "MSFS24 is to my eye more convincing visually than any simulation platform we have ever seen [...] It offers more opportunity to engage in interesting flying, varied degrees of flying, community participation and engaged learning than any simulation platform we have had access to in the short 40+ years I've called myself a simmer", he concluded. PMDG's aircraft lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fslweb</id>
    <title>FSLabs Launches New Website with Further A321ceo Details Included</title>
    <updated>2024-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fslweb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674a405ea755e614a14d347b_labs1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Flight Sim Labs recently launched their new website design, featuring a landing page for their upcoming A321ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and a selection of screenshots, details, pricing information, and more. The company rose to fame in 2016 after releasing the first high-fidelity Airbus A320 add-on. This add-on allowed Microsoft Flight Simulator X and Prepar3d users to experience the day-to-day operation of one of the most popular airliners, one that had not yet been developed to such standards (which quickly changed within five years). Described as “the most advanced Airbus A321ceo simulation for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020”, FSLabs’ upcoming bird is said to bring a combination of cutting-edge technology with unrivaled attention to detail, featuring immersive cabin operations, custom MEL (minimum equipment list) systems, next-generation visuals, enhanced systems, dynamic effects, realistic operational hazards, and real-world navigation obstacles such as GPS jamming, based on real-world data.  The add-on will retail for $69.99 and feature two engine options (CFM56 and IAE V2500), wingtip fences and/or sharklets, totaling up to four variants included in the package. They have also announced the development of an A321neo next, which is still being worked on but is said to “follow shortly behind” the release of the current engine option variant. Owners of the ceo between its release and the Neo’s release will be eligible for a discount. Refer to their website for further information on the upcoming product(s). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmzbad</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Beijing Daxing International Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmzbad"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674c4bddb5e54ac15b98b97d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Taimodels has recently launched its rendition of Beijing Daxing International Airport (ZBAD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This airport, which serves the capital of China alongside Beijing Capital International Airport, opened just five years ago. It accommodates nearly 40 million passengers each year. After years of proposals, the construction of the new airport was officially approved in 2014. Following five years of construction, the airport opened its doors on September 25, 2019, with its first commercial flight occurring the next day. The airport serves as a hub for six airlines: Air China, Beijing Capital Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, China United Airlines, and XiamenAir. Additionally, it is a focus city for Hebei Airlines. However, the airport is not limited to these carriers; it accommodates numerous airlines from around the globe, offering flights to various destinations, including Hong Kong, Amsterdam, Doha, and many more. The newly released version of Beijing Daxing International Airport includes realistic terminals, airport buildings, PBR ground markings, realistic lighting, custom jetways, and other features. The scenery requires 4.54 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for about $23.44. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
