<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-06-22T18:32:48.777511+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inirho</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Rhode Island T.F. Green International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inirho"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6848c21fb73891b4af4d1d51_pvd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently released their rendition of Rhode Island T.F. Green International Airport (KPVD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which serves Providence with a yearly average of 4 million passengers. It was dedicated in 1931 as Hillsgrove State Airport, and its first passenger terminal was only built in 1933. Its original layout consisted of three 910-meter-long concrete runways. It was used for flight training by the United States Army Air Force during 1942 and 1945, hosting the 435th Army Air Force Base. The WW2 occupation period led to several upgrades, including runway extensions (300 meters each) and slightly improved infrastructure. In the 1960s, a new terminal was built, as the old one was not large enough to handle a metropolitan area with over a million people.  It wasn’t until 1996 that it would see another upgrade, entirely replaced by a new passenger terminal with 18 gates. Four extra gates were added in 1997. It’s a hub for Wiggins Airways and an operating base for Breeze Airways. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, BermudAir, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a true-to-life landside, realistic dynamic lighting, custom jetways, real-world signage, LOD-optimized objects, and much more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $13.51 (introductory price), requiring at least 3.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vpibog</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases El Dorado International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vpibog"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6848cb0873eb6eb8d8d2b3a1_bog1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. V Pilot Designs has recently released their rendition of El Dorado International Airport (SKBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Bogotá and its surrounding areas with a yearly average of 45.8 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in Latin America. The airport was conceived during General Gustavo Rojas Pinilla's government as part of his intent to modernize Colombia. Construction started in 1955, and it opened its doors for passengers within four years. It ultimately replaced Techo International Airport, Bogota's former main airport. By 1973, the airport was already handling over 3 million passengers, leading to concerns about over-congestion in the near future, which led to plans for a new runway. The second runway only came to be in 1998, much to the dismay of the locals, as that meant more noise. In 2017, the airport's Terminal 1 was significantly expanded, going from 173,000 square meters to 235,000, and can now handle up to 43 million passengers annually. Two years ago, plans were made to expand the airport further, bringing its capacity up to 60 million passengers annually. The project, funnily enough, was named El Dorado Max. It's a hub for Aerosucre, Avianca, Avianca Cargo, Avianca Express, Copa Airlines Colombia, LATAM Colombia, LATAM Cargo Colombia, and SATENA, and an operating base for AerCaribe, Central Charter de Colombia, Clic Air, Helicol, SADELCA, SAEP, and Wingo. Aerolineas Argentinas, Aeroméxico, Air Canada, Air Europa, Air France, American Airlines, Arajet, Avior Airlines, Copa Airlines, Delta, Emirates, Gol Linhas Aéreas, Iberia, JetSmart, KLM, Lufthansa, Spirit, Turkish, United, Viva, and Volaris also serve it. The scenery was rebuilt from scratch for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, featuring an up-to-date ground layout, high-resolution PBR textures, performance-friendly optimization, highly detailed terminals, custom jetways, and much more. It's available in the MSFS 2024 Marketplace for $21.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsrdss</id>
    <title>Black Square Announces Release Date and Pricing for the Starship for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsrdss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684955697bbd27a5f2469b47_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has announced the release date for its highly anticipated Starship for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The aircraft is scheduled to be released on June 19th, just over a week from now. The upcoming Starship is being promoted as one of the most advanced aircraft simulations available for the simulator. It will feature an accurate recreation of the Collins avionics suite, a sophisticated pressurisation and cabin temperature simulation, and over 230 potential failure scenarios. Additionally, a new tablet interface will allow users to configure all options, manage payloads, control failures, monitor engines, and more, all from one convenient location. A complete list of features can be found on the product page. The aircraft will be available exclusively on the Just Flight website initially, with plans for releases on both the marketplace and other third-party websites to follow. The highly anticipated Starship from Black Square is set to launch with a price tag of around $54.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/chrlsv</id>
    <title>Cardinal Horizon Relaunches SimVector With New Data Platform</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/chrlsv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6849feb5e6fc0d79b38e79ea_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Cardinal Horizon has recently released SimVector, a subscription-based platform designed to provide affordable, dynamic schedule data for the flight simulation community. ‍ First launched in 2019 as a live VATSIM map, SimVector has been reworked to address the growing need for up-to-date airline schedules. Today, many virtual airlines rely on static spreadsheets, which are prone to falling behind real-world changes, such as new routes or equipment swaps. ‍ “For many months, the communities that use our products have complained about stagnation in the market, data quality, and more with existing schedule offerings”, said Taylor Broad, owner of Cardinal Horizon. “SimVector is our answer. We want to provide data and products that allow our customers and their staff to focus on building communities, and not the minutiae of maintaining these datasets on their own.” The platform's standout feature is SimVector Direct Delivery, available on the Plus plan, allowing purchased data to be synced directly with a user’s phpVMS v7 installation. This removes the need for manual downloads or uploads, keeping schedule data current with minimal user intervention. ‍ Data is formatted for phpVMS v7, and available in CSV and JSON formats. Pricing follows a points-based model, where the number of points required per airline is proportional to the cost of acquiring the data. This results in notable cost savings compared to traditional providers. For example, a dataset for Delta Air Lines costs $4.32 under the Plus plan, versus $20.31 on a competing platform. ‍ The Basic plan includes 50 points for $10 per month, while the Plus plan offers 250 points for $29 per month and unlocks Direct Delivery.  A general aviation apron model is also provided, with potential for more features as development progresses. ‍ Although the platform currently focuses on flight schedules, Cardinal Horizon has confirmed the development of additional datasets in the future. ‍ You can learn more by visiting simvector.net. ‍ For more updates on SimVector and the latest in flight simulation, keep an eye on Threshold. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737m24</id>
    <title>iFly Releases Experimental 737 Max Compatibility Patch for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737m24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684a682255cee2412867f4a9_ifly1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iFly has recently issued an experimental compatibility patch to their 737 Max for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with an addendum that there are still issues with it, hence the “experimental” tag. “The changes introduced by Asobo have been difficult for developers to deal with, and we want to say up front there are remaining issues due to the base sim still being work-in-progress by Asobo,” warns iFly. They also add that people are welcome to try it if they want, but it’s an experimental release, if anything. They complement, “There are still multiple, unresolved compatibility issues remaining. Any future progress by us depends on Asobo supplying the complete backward compatibility they promised.”  iFly believes that despite the many issues, it’s already possible to fly from A to B with their 737 Max and have fun. Some features, such as the airport maps and RAAS, do not work due to the way everything is now streamed, but these options will be made available again at a later date. Running iFly Manager 1.0.4.0+ is required to install the update, which appears once you select “MSFS 2024” within it. ‍ The add-on is available on their store for $69.95, requiring at least 5 GB of hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wkbo24</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases El Dorado International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wkbo24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684a6b769c774a16da1e214b_boggers1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. WingSim has recently released their rendition of El Dorado International Airport (SKBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves Bogotá and its surrounding areas and has a yearly average of 45.8 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in Latin America. The airport was conceived during General Gustavo Rojas Pinilla's government as part of his intent to modernize Colombia. Construction started in 1955, opening its doors to passengers within four years. It ultimately replaced Techo International Airport, Bogota's former main airport. By 1973, the airport was already handling over 3 million passengers, leading to concerns about over-congestion in the near future, which led to plans for a new runway. The second runway only came to be in 1998, much to the dismay of the locals, as that meant more noise. In 2017, the airport's Terminal 1 was significantly expanded, going from 173,000 square meters to 235,000, and can now handle up to 43 million passengers annually. Two years ago, plans were made to expand the airport further, bringing its capacity up to 60 million passengers annually. The project, funnily enough, was named El Dorado Max. It's a hub for Aerosucre, Avianca, Avianca Cargo, Avianca Express, Copa Airlines Colombia, LATAM Colombia, LATAM Cargo Colombia, and SATENA, and an operating base for AerCaribe, Central Charter de Colombia, Clic Air, Helicol, SADELCA, SAEP, and Wingo. Aerolineas Argentinas, Aeroméxico, Air Canada, Air Europa, Air France, American Airlines, Arajet, Avior Airlines, Copa Airlines, Delta, Emirates, Gol Linhas Aéreas, Iberia, JetSmart, KLM, Lufthansa, Spirit, Turkish, United, Viva, and Volaris also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, custom jetways, rebuilt interiors for MSFS 2024, and much more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $8.00, requiring at least 1.08 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prjeff</id>
    <title>Propair Releases Rocky Mountain Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prjeff"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684a74dfdc14765c5a7ad5d6_jeff1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Propair has recently released their rendition of Rocky Mountain Airport (KBJC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, serving Denver, Colorado, with a yearly average of 262,000 aircraft movements. The airport’s history stretches back to the late 1950s, when the increased demand for private air travel required something beyond Stapleton International Airport (Denver’s former main airport), as that one was operating at capacity. The idea was to create an airport dedicated to general aviation, offering a convenient alternative for private aircraft, corporate jets, and flight training operations that were increasingly constrained at a large hub such as Stapleton. The airport has experienced exponential growth through the 1960s and 1970s, thanks to the rise of corporate aviation. Its strategic location close to Denver and Boulder made it extremely attractive and way easier to access than Stapleton ever could. In 1995, with Stapleton’s closure, Rocky Mountain Airport (then Jefferson County Airport) rode their first high wave, as Denver International Airport had no intent whatsoever to be general aviation friendly, meaning JeffCo would take all of the GA traffic that was once meant for Stapleton. Many investments were made during that period to ensure the infrastructure was always up to the highest standard. In the early 2000s, the airport’s administration decided to be more than just a general aviation airport and embrace regional tourism, changing their name to “Rocky Mountain Metropolitan Airport” and solidifying its role as the gateway to the Rocky Mountains.  JSX currently serves it, with flights to Burbank, Dallas—Love Field, Las Vegas, and Scottsdale. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, PBR materials, custom night lighting, custom ground poly, animated people, and much more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.14, requiring at least 2.66 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/321303</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/321303"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68462848149bf830100ab516_1250410_20250605190233_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently issued an update to their A321ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, improving the compatibility with the latter, fixing a lighting issue on sharklet aircraft, and more. Update v11.0.1.303 is now available via the experimental channel in their Control Center, improving the compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, fixing a magnetic variation issue that was only present in the new platform, wing strobes and nav lights are now visible on sharklet aircraft, the ATSU loadsheet &amp; cargo door logic were improved, and more. The complete changelog follows below: Simulator Platform Magnetic Variation Lights ATSU/AOC EFIS / FCU Effects ELAC Sounds Others The FSLabs A321ceo is available in their store for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777324</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 777-300ER for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777324"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6700743a43d6279dcc6fba41_randy3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently made their Boeing 777-300ER compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the last remaining member of their 777 lineup that was still only available in MSFS 2020. Furthermore, they have also updated the 777-200ER and the 777F for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 with build 113, bringing version parity across the entire aircraft family. Regarding the Marketplace debut, PMDG doesn’t know when the 777 updates will arrive in MSFS 2020 nor when the planes will appear for purchase in 2024’s marketplace, as they are still working through some data sent by the Microsoft team overlooking the intake process. The instruction sets provided by Microsoft conflict with PMDG’s method of doing things, and they are working out a way to settle that properly. The 777-200LR is set to enter beta testing this weekend, and they plan to release it by the end of the month. PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfse25</id>
    <title>Threshold at FlightSimExpo 2025: What to Expect</title>
    <updated>2025-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfse25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684eead05fdddd6bccb40fe2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FlightSimExpo returns this month, bringing one of the world’s largest flight simulation events to Providence, Rhode Island. With more than 3,000 attendees expected and over 70 exhibitors confirmed, FSExpo 2025 is shaping up to be one of the biggest gatherings yet for enthusiasts, developers, and aviation professionals alike. ‍ Threshold will once again be on-site to provide live coverage throughout the event. From June 27 to 29, our team will share real-time updates, breaking announcements, and hands-on insights from the show floor via our social media channels. Expect frequent posts across Bluesky, Instagram and Facebook, as well as video content directly from the exhibit hall. We will be streaming a special event on our YouTube channel, covering the biggest announcements and product reveals from #FSExpoFriday. As with last year, we will be speaking with major developers, creators, and exhibitors, bringing you exclusive video interviews and insights from the event. If you prefer to catch up at your own pace, don’t worry, we will publish daily roundup articles to summarise the key news and releases from each day. Attending in person? Feel free to say hello to Magnus and Drew on the show floor, they will be around all weekend and would love to meet you, whether you’re a long-time reader or just discovering Threshold! ‍ From product debuts to engaging conversations, we’re excited for what FSExpo 2025 has in store.  ‍ Be sure to follow Threshold for all the latest updates! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mslgsk</id>
    <title>Mango Studios Releases Skiathos International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mslgsk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684f823e8a3d6ac3b711c010_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Mango Studios has recently released its version of Skiathos International Airport (LGSK) for X-Plane 12. Known for its challenging approach, this Greek airport welcomes over 550,000 passengers annually. Skiathos International Airport first opened its doors in 1972. In 1998, the airport added a passenger terminal and a new control tower. However, this terminal was closed due to a minor earthquake in 2001, and a new terminal was inaugurated just a year later, in 2002. Since 2019, the airport has operated with two terminals: one for international flights and another for domestic flights. Currently, the airport can accommodate aircraft as large as the Boeing 757-200. It serves a variety of airlines, including easyJet, Jet2.com, Olympic Air, Ryanair, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air, among others. These airlines help the airport handle over 550,000 passengers each year, supported by more than 5,000 annual aircraft movements. The scenery features 4K PBR terminals and airport buildings, a fully modelled car park and waterfront, custom runway textures, realistic GSE, a pre-made ortho tile, and much more. The newly released Skiathos International Airport is now available from the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $17.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/750css</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Releases Crossfill for GTN 750Xi/650Xi Units</title>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/750css"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68523601998401abc0b9a01c_gpslol.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. TDS Sim Software has updated their GTN 750Xi add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and X-Plane. The update adds crossfill between the two units, allowing them to talk to each other and exchange data. Contrary to popular belief, Garmin’s crossfill function does not only synchronize the active flight plan between two units; it also crosses over fourteen items, such as the flight plan catalog, user waypoints, user-defined frequencies, missed approach acknowledgment, nearest airport criteria, CDI scale, and more. Their crossfill implementation fully replicates the real unit’s behavior, using the same protocols as in real life, ensuring ultimate immersion and fidelity.  ‍ For crossfill to work, one must use an aircraft with two GTN units, be it two 750Xi, one 750Xi and a 650Xi, two 650Xis, and so on. It’s also possible to turn it off if the user wants individual flight plans on each. ‍ To get the functionality working, you should be on the Trainer’s V20.42 version or higher, 1.3.0.0 or higher of the TDN Pro for MSFS 2024, and 1.0.0.4 or higher for X-Plane. ‍ Furthermore, the GTN 750Xi/650Xi is now available in select default MSFS 2024 airplanes, as part of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s SimAttachments feature. Thanks to a mod created by one of their community members, their GPS unit canm now be part of the default Cessna 185 Skywagon, Cessna 404 Titan, and also on the Cessna 172 Skyhawk Classic. ‍ Work is underway to support even more default aircraft in the future: DA40, PC6 Gauge version, DV20, C152, Twin Otter, C207, V35B Bonanza, and H125. ‍ Please refer to their official website for further information. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ham618</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Hamburg Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ham618"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68536e1c6b7e0adbea6a1073_perle1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft recently released their rendition of Hamburg Airport (EDDH) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Hamburg metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 14.8 million passengers, making it the fifth-busiest airport in Germany. It opened in January 1911, making it the oldest International airport in operation in the world and the second oldest in Germany after Tempelhof, which is now closed. It was given its current name – Hamburg Airport – during the British occupation of Hamburg starting in 1945. Its importance was proven in 1948 when it was an essential part of the Berlin Airlift, where allies carried supplies to West Berlin after the Soviets had blockaded every land access, effectively cutting their supply lines. It was Lufthansa's hub in the mid-50s, although Frankfurt eventually replaced it due to growth constraints that couldn't be overcome. While this did not affect the airport's potential as a non-hub, it could not meet Lufthansa's expectations as a large hub.  It wasn't long until the government started discussing the construction of a new airport away from the city and thus not suffering from any potential growth constraints. While the idea seemed nice on paper, they quickly dismissed it due to how bad it was back in the 1960s to have your airport away from the city (transport infrastructure was far from efficient at the time). Thus, they settled with what they had, which could not grow much but was at least within the city's heart and easily accessible.  Furthermore, Lufthansa had already moved to Frankfurt, so the traffic demands were not justifiably high anymore. The 1990s saw extensive modernization work at the airport, including a pier extension, a new terminal, and an airport plaza between the terminals. It's a focus city for Condor, Eurowings, Ryanair, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air Cairo, Air France, Air Serbia, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, Croatia Airlines, Emirates, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, TAP, Tunisair, Turkish, Volotea, and Vueling also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, realistic 3D ground, custom aerial imagery, detailed airport buildings, seasons support, 3D vegetation, custom animated vehicles, custom animated jetways, and more. It's available on their shop for $19.99, requiring at least 2.6 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsa321n</id>
    <title>FSLabs Releases A321neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsa321n"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68540e8ed866ddc50457ee02_fslneo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs recently released their rendition of the Airbus A321neo, the largest and most capable member of the A320 family, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024.  Airbus introduced the A321neo in 2010 as the next generation of their very popular A321. It features newer—and more efficient—engines, aerodynamic enhancements, and higher passenger capacity, making it a solid choice for airlines wishing to transport passengers efficiently on high-density routes. FSLabs’ rendition attempts to capture the full range of technological and operational advancements that define the new generation of Airbus narrow-body aircraft. Engine behavior, extended range capabilities, and fuel management logic were all modeled to reflect the real counterpart as closely as possible.  The rollout will be done in two phases, with the first (current) focusing on the A321-251N and A321-251NX equipped with CFM LEAP-1A32 engines, the A321-252N and A321-252NX featuring the LEAP-1A30 variant, and the A321-253N and A321-253NX with the LEAP-1A33. The second phase will follow shortly and include the A321-271N and NX, powered by Pratt &amp; Whitney 1133G-JM engines, and the A321-272N and NX, powered by the 1130G-JM engine. They split the development phase to streamline development, testing, and delivery. The second phase will be provided at no extra cost. The complete feature set includes all the aforementioned variants with their respective performance profiles, startup behavior, thrust response, and fuel efficiency. It also accurately depicts the standard and ACF cabins with their peculiarities. The DRAIMS (Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System) is also included, featuring seamless integration with VHF radios, audio selectors, intercom functionality, and PA systems. The full feature list follows below: ‍ A321 NEO LR Support with Additional Centre Tanks (ACTs): ‍ DRAIMS – Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System: ‍ High-Fidelity Flight Performance Model: ‍ Custom Engine Sound set: ‍ Advanced ELAC L103 (Elevator Aileron Computer): ‍ ‍ Updated FADEC with engine cooling: ‍ Realistic ground handling: ‍ ROPS / ROW Integration (Runway Overrun Protection / Warning): ‍ GSX Pro Full Integration: ‍ Fully Integrated ATSU/AOC Functionality: ‍ A321ceo owners are eligible for a discount coupon, which needs to be redeemed here. The offer is only valid until September 15, 2025.  The add-on is available in their store for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsrsss</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Starship for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsrsss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68546092a5ad2bba524cd835_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has released the highly anticipated Starship for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This aircraft was developed in partnership with the owners of the real Starship to ensure the most realistic recreation possible. Development of the Starship began in 1979, and after ten years, in 1989, the first production model took to the skies. Although a total of 50 Starships were built, only six remain airworthy today. The aircraft was groundbreaking for several reasons: it was the first certified canard wing aircraft, the first all-composite structure business aircraft, the first certified twin pusher turboprop, and the first general aviation aircraft to feature an all-glass cockpit. Additionally, it is one of only three civilian turboprop aircraft with a service ceiling of 41,000 feet. The Starship was truly ahead of its time. The aircraft is equipped with numerous features, including an accurate recreation of the Collins avionics suite, a sophisticated pressurisation simulation, and an advanced cabin temperature simulation. It offers 230 potential failure scenarios, a new tablet interface, and much more. These various features contribute to its promotion as one of the most advanced aircraft simulations available for the simulator. The newly released Starship by Black Square is now available from Just Flight for $54.99.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bs757p</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Shares 757 Pricing and Beta Plans in Latest Video Update</title>
    <updated>2025-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bs757p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685829e71757547af85458c1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a new YouTube video, the owner and CEO of BlueBird Simulations, Shervin Ahooraei, has shared a June update on the team’s upcoming Boeing 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update confirms pricing details and outlines the aircraft’s multi-phase beta roadmap. While development progress is steady, Ahooraei emphasised that a release remains several months away. The passenger variant of the 757, including both the -200 and -300 models, and multiple engine options, will be priced at $80. The aircraft will be compatible with both MSFS 2020 and 2024. It will be available for PC through Just Flight and BlueBird’s website. The Xbox version is expected several months after the initial release. ‍ “Just because we're comfortable announcing a price doesn't mean we're close to release”, said Ahooraei in the video. “We're still months away from the next stage of testing”. Ahooraei also outlined a three-phase beta program, beginning with a small group of testers with extensive experience with the 757. Stage two, described as the most critical, depends on completing the flight management system (FMS), which Ahooraei acknowledged is still several months away due to its complexity. The final stage will open for broader testing, allowing access for all users. Recent development efforts have focused on a comprehensive rework of the pneumatic system, enabling a more authentic engine start process and failure simulation. BlueBird has implemented functional air-ground logic and the 757’s engine electronic control (EEC) computer, while completing significant work on flight controls, using custom code. Over 450 custom sound samples are now integrated into the cockpit, and although the virtual cabin is beta-ready, additional cabin features are not currently a priority. Looking ahead to FlightSimExpo 2025, BlueBird Simulations will exhibit for the first time, with a fully equipped 10x20 booth showcasing the 757. Attendees can try the aircraft hands-on using a dedicated hardware setup, featuring peripherals from Thrustmaster and WinWing.  ‍ Ahooraei reiterated the team’s long-term vision and commitment to quality: “The goal is to be a top-tier developer, and the 757 is just the beginning.” BlueBird also reaffirmed work on its Boeing 767, beginning with the -300ER variant. Handled by a separate team, the project doesn’t impact 757 development, but draws from shared resources and an established codebase, which is expected to speed up development. No release date has been announced, and Ahooraei was clear in managing expectations: “We’re here for the long haul. We’re not going anywhere.” FlightSimExpo 2025 begins on 27 June in Providence, Rhode Island.  ‍ For all the latest updates, be sure to follow Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
