<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-01-15T18:22:25.015919+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniu36</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniu36"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658e3ce4907680bdcf3367a3_inia3003.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated their newly released Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing various issues ranging from VNAV tweaks to CTD mitigations.   Version 1.0.1, the first patch for the A300 so far, brings a substantial list of fixes and improvements to their brand-new release for MSFS. The changelog follows below:   The airplane is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.55, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sayinai</id>
    <title>SayIntentions.AI Receives Launch Date and Updates on Pricing</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sayinai"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65902e79129400a37b98b792_Untitled-1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Several months ago, we covered a potentially game-changing AI Air Traffic Control (ATC) system activated and controlled using your voice. SayIntentions.AI enables users to employ natural language and phraseology commonly used in real-world aviation communications. The primary goal is to provide users with a lifelike, interactive communication experience, making SayIntentions.AI ideal for those new to learning aviation radio communications. The team behind SayIntentions.AI, (formerly known as SmartSky.AI) plans to launch the product on January 15th, 2024. Their vision is to "create something that is not only comprehensive but also undeniably more enjoyable to use than flying solo," while addressing the challenge of making live ATC less intimidating. ‍ Since the initial announcement, the team has made significant progress. SayIntentions.AI can now support Class B, C, and D airspaces, providing services such as flight following, radar services, traffic advisories, closed traffic pattern work, Air Traffic Services (ATS), Terminal Radar Approach Control (TRACON), Air Route Traffic Control Center (ARTCC), Visual Flight Rules (VFR) transitions, routes, and flight plans for every airport in the United States. Sayintentions.AI works with both X-Plane and Microsoft Flight Simulator with flexibility across both sim platforms. ‍ Additional features include custom voices for specific airports, and controllers will possess their own personalities, adding uniqueness to certain areas. The team outlined various procedures in a Reddit post, including noise abatement procedures and guided directions to specific landmarks as well. ‍ SayIntentions.AI also includes a student pilot mode designed for learning the ropes, with more patient controllers allowing users to ask questions, prompting ATC to provide assistance. The team is fine-tuning the last five percent to achieve the perfect finished state. Pricing details are still in progress, set with a subscription-based service at a monthly rate of possibly $15-20. A trial version will be available around the Lake Tahoe Reno, Nevada area, allowing users to "try before you buy."To learn more about SayIntentions.AI see the Reddit post, website, SayIntention.AI's Discord and check out the demo YouTube video below. You can also sign up for the wait list via SayIntention.AI's website! ‍ ‍ Of course stay tuned to Threshold for more news and updates on SayIntentions.AI!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxbl2</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Previews Upcoming A320 Block 2 Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxbl2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6592d24222a5204134d84e6d_iaewen1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has broken the silence on New Year's Eve about their long-awaited Block 2 update for their A320 add-on, showcasing the IAE engines, cockpit improvements, new night lighting, and some of the new features that will be part of the update. They have worked around most of the issues they ran through during the development phase, with only weeks separating it from an official release after an eleven-week delay concerning the predicted initial release date.  The new cockpit shows a new - thinner - center window pillar, side windows, and new configuration options, such as the absence of DCDUs, which is typical in North and South America. They have entirely remapped the cockpit textures, cutting the memory footprint in half. Externally, new wings, wingtips, nose, and landing gear are expected, along with a new soft-body physics system for the tires, showing actual compression that will vary with the aircraft's weight.  Physics-driven weathering will also be present in Block 2, with an accurate simulation of the dirt accumulation around the engine and its surroundings.  ‍ The already showcased shadow-casting lights make a return in today's update, showing how it looks with the new V2500s and the many improvements made to the night environment experience inside the cockpit. A deep dive into the new systems and simulation aspects is coming soon.  There's no release date available for the update yet. Threshold will keep you informed on the matter!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da42vi</id>
    <title>COWS shows off the upcoming DA42-VI for MSFS and X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da42vi"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6592f5aa9a3b5154f6bba82f_BANN.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. COWS, the development team responsible for the upcoming DA42 aircraft in Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12, has recently unveiled a teaser, showcasing their latest project. The trailer provides a glimpse into the noteworthy visual features that COWS has meticulously focused on. COWS is aiming to deliver the most accurate DA42 TDi experience for both flight simulators. According to the team, the COWS DA42 promises the ultimate multi-engine experience through its emphasis on precise flight modeling, detailed systems modeling, and the implementation of an in-house COWS NXi COWS G1000 replica. This replica will boast numerous screen configurations and menu operations, complemented by the inclusion of RAIM prediction. The detailed operational experience has been carefully crafted to cater specifically to students, offering a platform to practice critical procedures and maneuvers. The entire project is built by the hands of DA42 pilots and student pilots to ensure accuracy in both Microsoft Flight Simulator/FS2024 and XP12. Originating from the late 1990s brainstorming sessions, the DA42 has undergone numerous iterations during its 24-year production span. The latest iteration, the DA42-VI, has gained popularity among consumers as a luxurious four-seater featuring modern construction, materials, and cutting-edge avionics. Additionally, the DA42 has made significant inroads into the flight training market, serving as a robust twin-engine trainer utilized globally to prepare pilots for complex multi-engine aircraft types.Renowned for its efficiency, the DA42 offers unique engine options, such as aerodiesels co-designed with Mercedes-Benz and Austro Engine GmbH. The Austro diesels contribute to a remarkable 46% improvement in fuel efficiency compared to the gasoline models. COWS is currently putting the finishing touches on the project, indicating an imminent release within the next few weeks. While no details regarding pricing or specific vendors have been disclosed at this point, anticipate the release of such information as the project approaches a confirmed launch date. Keep an eye on Threshold for additional updates regarding the release of the COWS DA42-VI!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/para42</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases a free new utility for Microsoft Flight Simulator.</title>
    <updated>2024-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/para42"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6595adc63c4cf7f2e3a204ea_Main.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently released Simstaller for FS2020. The software is designed to detect add-on conflicts and installation issues related to the complexity of installing modifications to the simulation. It is a lightweight standalone application that runs in the background of Windows. Initially, Parallel 42 planned to offer the utility as a payware product but later realized that it was a must-have for users who download from community sites like flightsim.to.   The Virtual File System (VFS) scans and detects issues, alerting you to packages that override critical core operations or unintended game modifications. With Simstaller, you can identify who or what is overriding the functions of the simulation. Simstaller provides welcome relief for individuals fatigued by the constant need to troubleshoot errors and pinpoint the root causes of issues within Microsoft Flight Simulator's community folder. ‍The Parallel 42 Simstaller app is available free on parallel42.com. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hcar</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Cartagena Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hcar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65972ccc02552f718f5db512_cartagena.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Rafael Núñez International Airport (SKCG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Cartagena, Colombia, with a yearly average of 7.2 million passengers.  It was built in 1946 as Crespo Air Field, with TACA Colombia being the first airline to serve the city, albeit very briefly, as they went under a year later, with LANSA taking the remaining slots.  By 1979, the airport averaged around 99 flights a week, which was not enough in terms of touristic volume for the local hotels, leading to pressure for an airport redevelopment in 1982: a new passenger terminal and a runway extension, allowing for bigger aircraft. It is now the fourth busiest airport in the country.  It’s a hub for Avianca and served by Air Century, American Airlines, Arajet, Avianca Costa Rica, Clic, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Edelweiss Air, JetBlue, KLM, Latam Colombia, Latam Peru, Spirit, Wingo.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, high-detail buildings, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.37, requiring at least 1.21 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kissar</id>
    <title>Kiss Simulation Releases Sarajevo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kissar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659731c1f041642de77632a0_sara.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Kiss Simulation has recently released their rendition of Sarajevo International Airport (LQSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Sarajevo in Bosnia and Herzegovina with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers.  It was built in 1966 and opened for traffic three years later, although domestically. International operations only started a year later, with Frankfurt being its first international destination.   The first renovation happened nearly 20 years later for the 1984 Winter Olympics, with a new terminal building, a runway extension, and navigational system improvements.  The terminal was expanded in 2017, with a new 10,000-square-meter building able to handle up to 2 million passengers a year.  Its mountainous terrain and unpredictable weather have led to multiple financial losses over the years, with the most memorable one dating back to December 2015, when over 40% of the flights were canceled. The only way they could fix it would be by moving the threshold an additional 200 meters, which would shorten the runway, which is not ideal given that it’s already relatively short at 2,600 meters.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with the new terminal extension, custom runway profile, real-world ILS profile, custom-made ground textures, up-to-date ground layout, runway weathering, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.18, requiring at least 792.15 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini102</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini102"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659886bafbae95c3795e4091_a300update.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a substantial list of fixes and changes to the flight model, systems, sounds, and more.  Update v1.0.2, the second A300 update and the biggest so far, brings a massive changelog encompassing a multitude of fixes and improvements. The changelog follows below:   The add-on is available on the iniManager Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cph100</id>
    <title>Cockspur Releases PH100 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cph100"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6581875cba258cbc09117127_411476662_346824141428470_4464571675854412464_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur has announced the release of their PH100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Known for their light business jets and general aviation aircraft in MSFS, Cockspur has now unveiled the PH100, an rendition of the Embraer Phenom 100. Their recent release of the Cessna Citation Mustang garnered popularity from the Microsoft Flight Simulator community, and anticipation for the PH100 has been building steadily. This project started as a side endeavor right after the Mustang release but was kept under wraps until an intriguing teaser trailer was unveiled in early December 2022. Recent beta testing, marked by live streams offering glimpses of the development progress and features, has further stoked the excitement. The PH100 has become one of the most eagerly awaited aircraft in the MSFS community, with Cockspur teasing its release date via their Facebook page just this week. In the real world, the Embraer Phenom 100 is a significant player in the corporate jet market. Manufactured by the renowned Brazilian aircraft manufacturer Embraer, the Phenom 100 is classified as a VLJ (Very Light Jet), with its larger sibling being the 300E. The Phenom 100 made its maiden flight on July 26, 2008, and has since achieved immense success, becoming one of the most popular light jets on the market. A new configuration of the Phenom will set you back approximately $3 million, and with over 400 units produced, it boasts a strong presence in the aviation world. Cockspur has recreated this popular aircraft within Microsoft Flight Simulator, offering a plethora of features that faithfully replicate its real-world counterpart. These features include Garmin G1000NXi avionics with a custom FADEC system, meticulously replicated switches, and authentic functionality to provide a true-to-life piloting experience. Dynamic systems bring the experience of managing and operating the Phenom's unique systems, closely mirroring the real-world aircraft. Flight dynamics have been finely tuned based on feedback from actual Phenom pilots, enhancing the overall immersion of flying the PH100. The visual modeling is equally impressive, with accurate 3D modeling, animations, and texturing that add to the overall authenticity. The PH100 package includes 11 liveries, with support for FS2020's dynamic registration system. Additionally, a paint kit is included, allowing users to create their custom liveries or recreate their favorite designs. To ensure a smooth download experience, Cockspur recommends using a download manager, especially during high server loads. Additionally, they suggest utilizing the recently released Simstaller by Parallel 42 (//42). The PH100 is available for purchase through the Cockspur store, priced at 26.99 € / 29.48 $. To find out more information regarding the release and features see the product page here. For support and further information on the PH100 visit Cockspur's Discord or Facebook.  ‍ As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!  </summary>
    <published>2024-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skylab</id>
    <title>VSKYLABS Aerospace Simulations Releases Robinson R44 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skylab"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6598a0fc6bfd855983d32fa9_vskylabs-r44-v3.0-011.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VSKYLABS Aerospace Simulations, well-known for introducing unique niche aircraft to the X-Plane flight simulator, has recently launched the release of their Robinson R44 Raven II project. This release follows VSKYLABS' previous introduction of the iconic SR-71, a supersonic spy plane from the Cold War era. Showing an continuing commitment to delivering iconic aircraft, the VSKYLABS team has updated the R44 in a significant release, aligning it with compatibility for the latest version of Laminar Research's  X-Plane 12.0.08, complete with refined flight dynamics and more.R44, a four-seat rotor-wing aircraft made by Robinson Aircraft in Torrance, California, evolved from earlier models like the R22, boasting a larger cabin and improved performance. With over 5,000 deliveries, it's one of the best-selling GA helicopters, finding use in various applications from sightseeing to government operations. Over the past several weeks, the team has diligently worked on various aspects of the update. Their primary focus has encompassed deep-tuning the drive train simulation, enhancing aircraft performance and handling qualities, and improving auto rotation and landing skid dynamics, all while enhancing engine power gradient accuracies. This substantial update also introduces graphical improvements, including an all-encompassing PBR setup to align with X-Plane 12's rendering engine. Additional default liveries were also added to the package for more variety. Furthermore, the update addresses sound by converting FMOD sound packs to v2.0x and introducing physics-based blade angle slap sounds. This update is available to existing customers of the VSKYLAB R44 package through the auto-updater. VSKYLABS recommends downloading the store build package to "bridge the gap between the user-end progressive version and the base build version." You can access the complete update log and purchase the Robinson Raven on the VSKYLABS website at www.vskylabs.com. The project is also accessible via the x-plane.org store website. As usual, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgbra</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgbra"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659b2c4c68bfcd1c9cfde99b_bra1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has shared more previews of their upcoming Brasília - President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR), the third busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. The airport was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. A proper terminal building was inaugurated in 1971, designed by Tércio Fontana Pacheco, a Brazilian Air Force architect. The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more, divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The upcoming scenery is said to feature animated moving walkways, an up-to-date ground layout, terminal interiors, custom jetways, detailed landside, and more.  There’s no release date yet, but it’s said to be “almost there.”Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniapw</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews PW Update for Airbus A300-600R </title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniapw"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659c11fb9bb2494c2f1d6997_pw.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently teased the progress on the Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D engines for their recently released Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with info on a new bugfix update (1.03).  The Airbus A300-600 is an extended version of the A300B2 and B4, with two additional rows of seats, powered by two General Electric CF6-80C2/Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D engines, and making use of the A310 cockpit, with no need for a flight engineer like the older A300s. 313 A300-600s were sold between its inception and 2007, when production stopped.   iniBuilds claims to be working hard on update 1.03, which will bring more fixes and EFB updates, set to be released at one point this week.   The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simtha</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Nakhon Si Thammarat International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simtha"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659d8f49ec4ffc74ad0d4a83_tha1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Nakhon Si Thammarat International Airport (VTSF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the municipality of Nakhon Si Thammarat in Thailand with a yearly average of 1.2 million passengers.  It opened in 1998, replacing Cha-ian Airport as the main airport for Nakhon Si Thammarat residents, with a 7,985 square meter passenger terminal handling a maximum of 2,504 daily passengers.  A new passenger terminal was built recently, with three stories, the first for arrivals, the second for departures, and the third for shops and restaurants. It has been in operation since September 2023. The total area is around 30,600 square meters, accommodating up to a thousand passengers per hour.  Nok Air, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Lion Air serve it with flights to Don Mueang International (Bangkok).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a realistic passenger terminal model and its interior, custom ground textures, custom jetways, and an up-to-date ground layout.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.86, requiring at least 3.18 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xomhar</id>
    <title>Xometry Design Releases Harrisburg International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xomhar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659d92b1e511c1fc19a38f09_har1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Xometry Design has recently released their rendition of Harrisburg International Airport (KMDT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, with a yearly average of 1.1 million passengers.  The airport dates back to 1898, when the Signal Corps of the US Army was stationed there, building what would become Olmsted Field and having its first planes landing in 1918.  It was used almost exclusively for military purposes up until 1969 when the Middletown Air Depot closed, and airline flights moved from the nearby Capital City Airport to Olmstead State Airport, renamed Harrisburg International Airport in 1973, which was also when the passenger terminal reached full completion, designed by architect William Pereira.  Thirty-one years after the passenger terminal’s inauguration, a new 360,000 square-foot terminal was built, costing around $120 million and designed by the Sheward Partnership.  Allegiant, American, American Eagle, Delta, Delta Connection, Frontier, United, and United Express serve it, connecting the city to their most prominent hubs.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, high-resolution ground textures, PBR, realistic wear &amp; tear, custom mesh, custom night lighting, and custom jetways.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.28, requiring at least 2.24 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ontx12</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Ontario International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ontx12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659d9a888ab8e6c3467199ac_ont1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Ontario International Airport (KONT) for X-Plane 12, serving the cities of San Bernardino, Riverside, and Greater Los Angeles with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1941 as an Army Air Corps aircraft training and operation base. After the war, it became a large storage, sale, and scrapping center for Army Air Forces aircraft.   Shortly after, in 1946, the airport was renamed from “Ontario Municipal Airport” to “Ontario International Airport” because of outgoing trans-Pacific cargo flights. The first international passenger flight happened that same year, a Pacific Overseas Airlines flight from Shanghai to Ontario, inaugurating round-trip air passenger service between the United States and the Orient. Western Airlines began operating at the airport three years later, followed by Bonanza Air Lines in 1955.  A new terminal was opened in 1998, discontinuing the old terminals, which now function as the administration and the USO. There are 26 gates total, with 12 on T2 and 14 on T4. Terminal 2 hosts Alaska Airlines, Avianca El Salvador, China Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, United Airlines, and Volaris. Terminal 4 hosts American Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, and Southwest.  It’s a FedEx and UPS Airlines cargo hub, transporting cargo all over North America and Asia (UPS). Amazon Air, Ameriflight, Amerijet International, Asia Pacific Airlines, and Kalitta Air also serve it. Ontario International is the ninth-largest cargo airport in the United States.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with brand-new XP12 weather maps, accurate cargo ramps, an up-to-date ground layout, HDR lighting, PBR texturing, SAM jetways, LOD optimization, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.50, requiring at least 1.61 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/joemoe</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Development Progress on Oslo Gardermoen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/joemoe"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a1c4ff26983e141b4abff7_engm1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Jo Erlend has published a new batch of screenshots showcasing the development progress on his rendition of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM), to be distributed by Aerosoft. It’s the busiest airport in Norway, with a yearly average of 30 million passengers.  It is the main airport serving Oslo, located approximately 47 kilometers northeast of the city center. It opened in 1998 to replace the outdated Fornebu Airport, which had been operating since 1939. It was built to modernize and expand Norway’s airport infrastructure and improve accessibility to the capital city, quickly becoming the Main hub for domestic and international travel in the Country.   The new previews focus on ground service equipment, some of the detail work on the airside part of the terminal, and a short video demonstrating the night light effects.  There is no price or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you updated!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
