<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-08-17T18:25:32.942387+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a162</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a162"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b6a667d03737a221cfd962_comanche.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently issued a micro-update to their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding an accurate weight option for users wishing to fly with animal companions.  ‍ Update 1.6.2 also fixes the to/from flags in GPS OBS mode, a small area of protruding mesh when the stabilator tips are fitted, and updates the tail number font logic for their new livery pack (available in the Marketplace). The complete changelog follows below: The Accu-Sim Comanche 250 is available in their store for $49.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kolaud</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates DCS Kola Map</title>
    <updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kolaud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b74a3d1764368d8b095c2c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Orbx has recently released a new update for its DCS add-on, Kola Map. The update includes a variety of new features and several improvements. It adds three new airfields and reduces the total size of the installed map by about 12 GB. The new update introduces three new airfields: Kirkenes (ENKR), Kallax (ESPA), and Vidsel (ESPE). Additionally, cities, towns, and infrastructure have been added around the new airfields. In addition to the new features, several fixes and updates have been implemented. Some noteworthy fixes include adjustments and revisions to the ILS at Bodo airfield (ENBO), improved ground imagery at new airfields, and a reduction of the installed map size by approximately 12 GB. The updated add-on is presently available on Orbx for $55.91 during early access and will increase to $69.99 upon full release. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/adta3v</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Posts First "Discover the Aerosoft A330" Video</title>
    <updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/adta3v"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b76fd99e2499b6330c941e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has released a new video showcasing its upcoming Airbus A330 CEO and NEO products. This video is the first in a series called "Discover the Aerosoft A330". In this video, the team focuses on the 3D model of the aircraft. The video previewed the exterior of various upcoming aircraft variants. According to the video, the different variants being made are the A330-302 (GE), A330-323 (PW), A330-343 (RR), and the A330-941 (NEO). There was also a quick glimpse inside the cockpit. The video created by AviationLads does not provide any information about a release date or potential price. However, we will keep you updated as more information becomes available.‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hase</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Aspen/Pitkin County Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hase"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ba15f1130f595c749b78c3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has just released its version of Aspen/Pitkin County Airport (KASE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The US airport serves the city of Aspen, Colorado and has an annual average of just over 625.000 passengers. In 1946, a private gravel airstrip was opened at the current location of the airport. The airstrip was open to the public. In 1956, the pavement of the runway began, and it has been expanded a total of four times since, with the latest expansion occurring in 2011. The airport is served by the following airlines: American Eagle, Delta Connection, and United Express. These three airlines offer flights to various destinations, including Chicago, Los Angeles, and San Francisco. The scenery includes various features such as an accurate representation of the airport, hand-made ground textures, dynamic airport lighting, highly detailed models, and more. Aspen/Pitkin County Airport is now available on Orbx for $7.91 and takes up around 1.77 GB of space on disk. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddswaw</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Previews Warsaw Chopin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddswaw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bba9ea238ab41cb91c47f1_warsaw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design recently previewed their upcoming rendition of Warsaw Chopin Airport (EPWA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Warsaw Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 18.5 million passengers, roughly 40% of the country’s total air passenger traffic. Urban development in the mid-1920s led to air traffic complications around Warsaw’s former aerodrome, leading to the need to build a new airport elsewhere. A decade later, a new airport was finally ready to roll, built near the village of Okecie. It featured a ticket office, customs post, police station, newspaper kiosk, restaurant, and viewing terrace—state-of-the-art infrastructure for early 1930 standards.  Right after the civilian infrastructure was considered ready, they began developing its military potential with the construction of a Polish Air Force base, an Institute of Aviation building, an aircraft-building plant, and other military-related structures. In the late 1930s, the airport was equipped with radio navigation equipment to aid pilots during low-visibility conditions.  World War 2 wholly destroyed the airport, which happened to be a battleground between the Germans and the Polish Resistance. It was a bombing target from day one and was occupied by the Luftwaffe as soon as Germany took the country over.  The Germans built their first concrete runways and taxiways, which remained undamaged until the final days of the war when they were deliberately destroyed to prevent the enemies from using them. ‍ After the war, LOT Polish Airlines resumed operations at what used to be the airport, kicking off the reconstruction efforts. In two years, they have built a new terminal, a new control tower, and many aircraft parking stands, making it ready to serve people again. ‍ The airport’s terminal was reconstructed between 1964 and 1969 after LOT transferred its maintenance rights to state administration. By 1970, it already hit the one millionth passenger mark. It made them realize that their new terminal was already too small, leading to the construction of a temporary arrival hall, and a pre-war structure was used for domestic operations. ‍ While passenger numbers slightly declined in the early 1980s, the mid-80s and beyond were the opposite, urging the administration to expand the airport even further.The expansion plans from the late 1980s only got started after the fall of communism in the early 1990s. The new terminal was finally brought to life at the cost of 300 million German marks, using 164 subcontractors and 24 months of work. With a maximum capacity of 3.5 million passengers, it could handle 3.5 more people than the previous terminal, which was more than enough at the time. A new terminal (North Hall) was built in 2008, featuring a considerably larger footprint. It now handles arrivals for Star Alliance and Oneworld Airlines. ‍ It’s a hub for LOT Polish Airlines and a focus city for Enter Air, Smartwings Poland, SprintAir, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Air China, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, Ethiopian Airlines, Finnair, flydubai, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Qatar Airways, TAP Air Portugal, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery will feature custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom ground service equipment, custom landside buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but it’s said to be “turning base” (coming soon!).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1212</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.1.2 Beta </title>
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1212"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bbb05bcf9b6765b4297ce9_beta1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research recently issued a new X-Plane 12 beta build, which brings new boats, fresh custom airports, double jetway support, new cameras, bug fixes, and more.  New boats were added to the X-Plane world, increasing the immersion when flying around islands and coastal areas. Ships feature region-specific accuracy, warranting that extra bit of realism. The number of boats shown will depend on the World Objects Density setting within the graphics setting.  They have also added three new hand-built airports in the Caribbean, with custom buildings and ground textures: Princess Juliana International Airport (TNCM), Juancho E. Yrausquin Airport (TNCS), and Gustaf III Airport (TFFJ).  This update also represents a major milestone for their Scenery Gateway, as the simulator now ships with 20 thousand 3D airports built by the community. Additional camera commands were also added, with General Aviation pilots in mind. The first two commands allow you to tilt the cockpit view by 45 degrees to the left and right, and executing them again will tilt it by another 45 degrees. Commands to look up and down were also added. The camera tilts 30 degrees upon execution, and executing them again will make you look 60 or 90 degrees up or down. By popular demand, Laminar has added dual jetway support, making widebody operations much more realistic. Aircraft and airport authors can now update their products to use this feature.   Lastly, new items were added to their general airport library, such as passenger stairs, airport buses, and a ground power unit. The remainder of the changelog follows below: Support for VirtualFly Hardware Included with 12.1.2 is support of four additional products VirtualFly in X-Plane: - Switcho Engines Ignition - Switcho Engines Electrical - Switcho Lights - Switcho Trims ‍ Fixes and Enhancements ‍ Replay System We have focused effort on improving the stability of our replay system for this release. What good is a butter landing if you can’t show it to your friends later? ‍ Local Web API When the WebServer cannot bind to port 8086 a warning will be shown to the user, but X-Plane will continue to start normally. ‍ Scenery We updated the Eiffel Tower in Las Vegas. ‍ Aircaft ‍  General We fixed a problem regarding rain drops on windshields (XPD-15751).  Cirrus Vision SF50 We fixed an engine behavior bug in the Cirrus VisionJet. Previously, if you started the engine, shut it down and then immediately tried to start it again, nothing happened.  Beta ALIA VTOL The ALIA 250 now has gauges for all four batteries on its display. ‍ Refer to their blog post for further instructions on installing the beta.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwigrb</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Green Bay-Austin Straubel International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwigrb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bbb76360940db710480e30_austin1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios has recently released their rendition of Green Bay-Austin Straubel International Airport (KGRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Green Bay metropolitan area with a yearly average of 657,000 passengers.  The airport started its early life as Blesch Field, and it wasn’t until 1948 that it became a de facto airport, then named after the County where it is located: Brown County Airport.  A new passenger terminal was built in 1965 to meet the ever-rising passenger traffic demands, reflecting its importance as a regional air traffic hub.  The FAA now categorizes it as a non-hub primary commercial service facility, although 68% of its traffic corresponds to general aviation. Commercial service accounts for 15% of it, and air taxis take the remaining 16%. American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features custom ground textures, custom jetways, a custom terminal interior, custom ground clutter, and more. It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $10.84, requiring at least 4.37 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/scr111</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Publishes Summer Development Update for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/scr111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bbbde97b061e914012e3e2_E-JETS_FAMILY_BY_X-CRAFTS_E175_027.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts recently published a new development update concerning their E-Jets Family for X-Plane, covering the beta release of the second release candidate for the long-awaited 1.1.0 update. Now available in early access, update V.1.1.0-RC2 brings many new features, improvements, and fixes, including ILS autotune, which is demonstrated in the video below: The new feature list also includes climb performance fine-tuning for the E170 and E175 - which now closely matches the real-world figures, FMS speed stability enhancements, VNAV recalculation improvements, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍  Fixed: There was a green edge on the cabin windows. This has been fixed ‍ ‍ Refer to their blog post for instructions on how to get early access builds.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/astorc</id>
    <title>Astralis Studios Releases Ocean Reef Club Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/astorc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bbd034158f178bc7d3eef3_ence1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Astralis Studios has recently released their rendition of Ocean Reef Club Airport (07FA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a private-use airport serving Key Largo, Florida. The Ocean Reef Club opened for business in 1951 on top of what used to be the Dispatch Creek Fishing Camp. The former structure consisted of four cabins, several docks, and a small harbor. It was then transformed into a proper club, accessible via land, sea, and air. Once upon a time, the airport even had scheduled passenger air service, with Ocean Reef Airways flying passengers to Miami, Fort Lauderdale, and Charters. It was successful at first, with route expansions throughout the 1970s. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date airport layout, custom buildings, custom houses, custom ground markings, Select Club facilities, and handcrafted airport surroundings. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $12, requiring at least 493.5 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rjdevu</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Development Update for RJ Professional</title>
    <updated>2024-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rjdevu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bc9f2062ed5345342643d4_RJ%20Cabin%20InDev%205_KNVXh7f9J.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight have released another development update on their website for an upcoming product for MSFS - RJ Professional. ‍ The newest update focuses on the cabin and all the differences in cabins between BAe 146 and RJ. The cabin in RJ is also modelled in a 3-3 seat layout, although with grey leather seats, compared to the blue fabric seats in the 146 version.  The cabins are custom-modelled for each variant of RJ (RJ70, RJ85 and RJ100), and take all the small differences between them into account, such as blanked-out windows, smaller stowage bins where the wing structure and fuel tanks are located, as well as reduction of seats in rows as the fuselage starts narrowing at the rear. As usual, Just Flight developers have modelled and coded the smallest details in the cabin - both forward and aft galleys are interactive, cabin-to-cockpit communication, and of course, the beloved “study-level” coffee-maker.  The changes in the galley were also made. The bulky communication panel that can be found in 146 Professional is replaced with a simple handset in RJ Professional. Using the headset, you can call the rear or forward galley, cockpit, or passenger cabin. Chimes and annunciators are also included at each station. On the right-hand side of the cabin, the attendant panel can be found. It is used to check the status of the doors, turn on/off seatbelts and no smoking signs, and connect the cabin with the electrical power supplied by the GPU. The layout of this panel is different in RJ, as there are two additional switches that control the cabin lighting. If you aren’t a big fan of getting involved in the passenger simulation, developers have you covered! The EFB will include an option named “Auto Cabin Crew”, and when enabled, the virtual cabin crew will automatically take care of all cabin duties, while you prepare the aircraft for the flight. Speaking of the cabin duties, the boarding and deboarding music will be played via the cool little digital player, which is also in 146 Professional. It allows you to play one of seven default tunes, while you can add your own custom music if you fancy full immersion while flying real-world flights, or just want to relax in the cabin during the cruise with your favourite songs. According to the developers, the rest of the product is finished and has entered the “polishing” phase, where RJ will undergo intensive testing and ensure that it is ready for release. Unfortunately, no information about the release date or pricing has been released, but as always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/319321</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Publishes Introduction to A319/A321 Expansion for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/319321"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66be4843f29db92c859ea0b2_fenixcover1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations recently published an in-depth blog post about their upcoming A319/A321 expansion package for Microsoft Flight Simulator, covering historical bits, differences, catches, flight model changes, and more. The first few paragraphs explain why the Airbus A320 came to be and who it was trying to compete against. They then eventually delve into the length differences of each airframe and the many challenges encountered during development, spanning from wingspan to engine thrust and even noise restrictions.  From there onwards, they also went on in detail about the flight model differences between both, with the A321 suffering to slow down and the A319 slowing down far too much, and how that differs from what one would expect based on their experience flying the A320.  The differences don’t stop there, though, with the A321 demanding an entirely different landing technique due to its weight and length, significantly increasing the risk of a tailstrike in case of an overflare, and the A319 being the exact opposite due to its 13.5-degree tailstrike clearance.  While the A319 and A320 share the same fuel system, the A321 has an entirely different layout, using a single, large tank per wing instead of the split-wing design on the smaller siblings. The electrical center tank pumps were replaced by transfer jet pumps, using motive flow to extract fuel from the center tank and move it to the wing tanks. Such a difference makes it so the fuel logic is far from being the same, which they exemplify in a pretend failure scenario, with the A321 being able to have its pumps working - gravitationally -  even in case of an electrical supply failure, whereas the A319/A320 would not. The ECAM, which is the central nervous system of a modern Airbus, is also objectively different across the variants. Fenix has gone through extensive documentation to ensure accurate ECAM behavior with every possible variant, as certain combinations are exclusive to each type. ‍ The ELAC (Elevator and Aileron Computer), SEC (Spoiler and Elevator Computers), and FAC (Flight Augmentation Computers) were also altered for A319/A321 conformity, as they are also intrinsically different. ‍ Their cabin announcement system was changed to support the upcoming expansion, making type-specific cabin announcements possible. ‍ Fenix has also fed their systems with new data, warranting accurate green dot, VLS computation, and performance application updates to provide proper takeoff and landing distance calculations. ‍ Each airframe will accompany its own GSX profile, ensuring compatibility with FSDT’s Ground Service X from day one. ‍ The flight model has undergone massive changes, with a rewritten control translation system that is faster, more performant, and more accurate, running literally 100x faster than before. The “delay” on control input that many users complained about is now a thing of the past. That tweak led them to retune the fly-by-wire logic entirely, with changes to the Alpha Protection PIDs, a complete autopilot rework, and some of the code had to be altered to accommodate the new changes. When flying the aircraft by hand, the outcome is a more natural, direct, and “connected” feel. ‍ Their flare logic has also been given attention, with the ground effect completely externalized. This gives Fenix Simulations full control over the landing dynamics, ensuring the aircraft’s behavior on the landing and flare portion is closer to the actual thing. ‍ They highlight that the handling upgrades will also be made available for the A320 on launch day instead of an open-ended promise to back-port the new features “eventually.”  ‍ The new engines will also follow their XEM (external engine model) system, with all airframes having unique engine variants and thrust ratings. The A319 will feature the CFM56-5B6 engines for the -112 variant and the IAE V2524-A5 SelectOne for the -132. The A321, on the other hand, will feature the CFM56-5B2 engines for the -213 variant and the IAE V2533-A5 SelectOne for the -231. Their new flight model was built on hundreds of hours of telemetry data fed by their beta team and then compared with real-world performance data, yielding a “wonderfully accurate” result with convincing drag, lift, thrust, flap settings, geometry, fuel flow, ground handling, and gyroscopic precision.  ‍ They have also solved an issue where their Airbus would lose stability when fully configured and flying close to VLS, often “dropping a wing.” That has since been addressed, and one should be able to fly an extremely heavy A321 fully configured in a tight visual circuit without having a wing drop anymore. These improvements will also be applied to the A320 on launch day. ‍ There’s no information about the release date yet, but their next development update will showcase some new liveries for the upcoming birds. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/honcha</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Shop Publishes Honeycomb Charlie Pedals Update</title>
    <updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/honcha"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66be5e00d9df4bd18ee6b6e7_pedals1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Aerosoft Shop has published a brief status update on the Honeycomb Charlie Pedals stock situation. The product is currently being shipped to Hamburg and is set to arrive in early October. As Honeycomb’s official distributor in Europe, Aerosoft has thoroughly tested the Charlie Pedals from the latest production run, attesting to its build quality, realistic feel, and performance that their customers have come to expect from their previously released products. People can track the cargo ship carrying the pedals here. It’s expected to arrive in Hamburg by late September, and then it will take another week for the containers to go through customs and the delivery process to Aerosoft’s warehouse, where they will be ready for immediate delivery.  Charlie Pedals pre-orders will warrant a 30 euro voucher for your next order on the Aerosoft Shop (codes will be emailed separately as soon as they start shipping the pedals).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/splibd</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Bari Karol Wojtyła Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/splibd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bf777fd7e2f9b4dc325850_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimPixel has recently released their version of Bari Karol Wojtyła Airport (LIBD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located in the Italian city of Bari, about 5 miles from the city center. In 2023, the airport handled just under 6.5 million passengers, making it the 10th busiest airport in Italy. The airport was originally built as a military airfield and opened in the 1930s. It was seized during the Second World War and began receiving civil flights in the 1960s. Alitalia was one of the first airlines to fly to the airport, offering routes to Rome, Catania, Palermo, Ancona, and Venice. In 1981, a new passenger terminal was built, and in 1990, the airport underwent a runway extension and terminal upgrade. Another renovation took place in 2000, resulting in the construction of a new passenger terminal, which was completed in 2005. Today, the airport serves as a hub for various airlines including easyJet, Ryanair, and Volotea, offering a wide range of destinations across the world. With approximately 6.5 million passengers and 50.000 aircraft movements yearly, the airport continues to be a vital transportation hub. The newly released version of Bari Karol Wojtyła Airport boasts a range of features, such as high-resolution textures, custom 3D models, dynamic lighting, detailed interiors, static aircraft, ground vehicles, and more. The add-on requires 2.94 GB of storage space and is available on iniBuilds for around $16.7. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwitre</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Announces Trenton-Mercer Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwitre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bfa7fb66a9852f1acfe6e7_trenton1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios recently announced the development of Trenton-Mercer Airport (KTTN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This joint civil-military airport serves Trenton in New Jersey and has a yearly average of 917,000 passengers. The airport’s history is more than a century old. Its first airplane landing was in 1907 when it was just a small airfield on Alfred Reeder’s farm. It was opened to the public in 1929 as Skillman Airport. It was used for aircraft testing during World War 2 when a nearby General Motors factory switched from building cars to Grumman TBF Avenger torpedo bombers for the United States Navy. The facility was greatly expanded to accommodate the testing needs. After the end of the war, it was returned to the county and renamed Mercer County Airport. However, it remained partially military, with a Naval Air Warfare Center, which only closed in 1997. The airport’s name was changed again in 1995 to its current name (Trenton-Mercer Airport), after the city of Trenton, which is the state capital and county seat of Mercer County. Many plans were made to replace the old terminal, which residents along the flight path opposed. As a compromise, they renovated it in 2013, bringing it up to standard.  An eventual replacement was finally drafted in 2021, considering environmental concerns, and with 125,000 square feet of total area instead of 24,780 from the old one. FAA approved the project a year later, and the terminal was set to reach completion by mid-to-late 2024, but construction had yet to start by May 2024.  It’s served by Frontier Airlines, with flights to Atlanta, Fort Lauderdale, Orlando, and Tampa.  ‍ The scenery will feature custom ground textures, custom buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  There’s no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hgpt</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Gulfport–Biloxi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hgpt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c08231815ba3daf9cd8447_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Gulfport–Biloxi International Airport (KGPT). Situated in Gulfport, Mississippi, the airport serves the Gulfport-Biloxi metropolitan area and accommodates just over 685.000 passengers annually. In 1942, the airport opened as a training field for the United States Army Air Forces. Originally named Gulfport Army Airfield, it served as a training field until 1946, when it was placed into reserve status. In 1949, the airport was transferred to the City of Gulfport to be used as a civil airport. Passenger and cargo services started in the early 1950s. Since the transformation into a civil airport, the facility has been operated by a variety of airlines, including American Eagle, Breeze Airways, and others, offering flights to destinations such as Las Vegas, Tampa, and Atlanta. The airport handles just over 50.000 aircraft movements annually. The scenery includes an accurate airport representation, hand-crafted ground textures, dynamic lighting, highly detailed models, and more. The newly released scenery is now available on Orbx for approximately $12.33 and requires around 2.40 GB of disk space. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/1921rw</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Announces Release Window for A319 &amp; A321 Expansion</title>
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/1921rw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c0d7894ca0c3305ad044b4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After their recent introduction of the upcoming Fenix A319 &amp; A321 expansion, the team has just released a new post featuring a variety of liveries and art previews. The developer has also provided details about the release window for the new expansion. The team has rebuilt the fuselage textures from the ground up for the new expansion. For example, the A319 will now have stronger skin deformation on the airframe due to being in a higher pressurisation cycle state. The team has also provided a screenshot clearly showing these changes both below and above the cockpit windows on the A319. Additionally, the team informed us about their decision to offer both dual overwing exit and single overwing emergency exit options on the A319. This choice was made to provide users with the most realistic experience, allowing them to replicate real-life aircraft configurations used by specific airlines. Implementing this new option required the team to update reflections on the ECAM, cabin artwork, wing layout, and other related aspects. When it comes to the A321, the team had to make a decision. This time, the choice was between a two-class or single-class layout for the A321. Again, the team decided to include both layouts and the option to change between them, similar to the A319's overwing exit option. The team has confirmed that the new window textures are included, along with the unique double-slotted flaps on the A321. Additionally, they have shared a video comparing the full TOGA on the various aircraft versions with their respective CFM versions. As of now, the livery manager boasts a total of 450 liveries, with even more on the way. Lastly, the team has announced that the highly anticipated A319 &amp; A321 expansion will launch next week. Once more information is available, or the expansion has been released, Threshold will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
