<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-06-24T18:24:04.912944+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbmel</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Melbourne Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbmel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649056e45095ca885fb0ea99_melb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="719386"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Melbourne Airport (YMML) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Melbourne in Australia with a yearly average of 25 million passengers. It is the second busiest airport in the country!  Built in the 60s and opened in 1970, it replaces Essendon Airport (Orbx’s home) as the city’s main airport due to its relatively short runways, small terminals, and its expansion limitations that were a consequence of the urban development around the area.   During its first year of operations, Melbourne only handled international traffic, handling 155,275 international passengers that year and six airlines.   It originally featured three connected terminals, an international at the center, a terminal for Ansett to the south, and one for Trans Australia Airlines to the north. It could withstand 8 Boeing 707s and a rate of 500 passengers per hour, with expansion work three years later to comport the Boeing 747.  It wasn’t long until the passenger figures increased drastically, forcing further expansion: the Ansett terminal, domestic, got bigger, followed by an upgrade to the international terminal in 1993 and the opening of a new three-level concourse in 1995, with ten additional jetways.  In 1997, Melbourne was privatized, on a 50-year long-term lease, followed by a series of upgrades and improvements, including the construction of a multi-story carpark with 3,100 parking spaces, a 276-room hotel, and the expansion of the Qantas domestic terminal with a second pier and nine additional stands.  In 2005, the airport underwent more construction work to become A380-ready, with a runway widening, the addition of dual jetbridges, a terminal extension, and a subsequent expansion of terminal 2 in 2006 and 2008, massively increasing its passenger handling capabilities.  The airport has 68 gates, 53 used for domestic operations and 15 for international.   The airport is a hub for Jetstar (Adelaide, Auckland, Ayers Rock, Ballina, Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Brisbane, Busselton, Cairns, Canberra, Christchurch, Darwin, Denpasar, Gold Coast, Hamilton Island, Hobart, Ho Chi Minh City, Honolulu, Launceston, Newcastle, Perth, Phuket, Proserpine, Queenstown, Singapore, Sunshine Coast, Sydney, Townsville), Qantas (Adelaide, Alice Springs, Auckland, Ballina, Brisbane, Broome, Cairns, Canberra, Christchurch, Dallas/Fort Worth, Darwin, Delhi, Denpasar, Gold Coast,  Hamilton Island, Hobart, Hong Kong, Jakarta–Soekarno-Hatta, London–Heathrow, Los Angeles, Perth, Queenstown, Singapore, Sunshine Coast, Sydney, Wellington), Rex Airlines (Adelaide, Brisbane, Burnie, Canberra, Devonport, Gold Coast, King Island, Merimbula, Mildura, Mount Gambier, Sydney, Wagga Wagga), and Virgin Australia (Adelaide, Ballina, Brisbane, Cairns, Canberra, Darwin, Denpasar, Gold Coast, Hamilton Island, Hobart, Launceston, Nadi, Newcastle, Perth, Queenstown, Sunshine Coast, Sydney). The visitor list includes Air China, Air India, Air New Zealand, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, LATAM Chile, Singapore Airlines, United Airlines, and more.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR texturing, interior terminal modeling of departure lounges, VDGS, custom traffic animations, crisp satellite imagery, custom ground clutter, custom POIs, LOD optimization, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $23.92, requiring at least 6.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navwxr</id>
    <title>Navigraph Implements Weather Layer Feature in Charts 8</title>
    <updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navwxr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649065f47d1d65462b3f7a13_wxr1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="161058"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has recently added Weather Layers to their Charts 8 application, allowing users to fetch real-time weather information, including precipitation, winds, turbulence, METARs, cloud coverage, and more.  With an array of dynamic weather layers, pilots will have a comprehensive meteorological insight, with a set of different layers that will help with flight planning and decision-making for VFR and IFR simmers. The complete feature list follows below:  Radar – Monitor real-time precipitation and storm activity. The weather radar also supports a 2 hour playback to facilitate the anticipation of weather conditions for your flight. ‍ AIRSIGMET / CWA (AIRman’s METeorological Information / SIGnificant METeorological Information / Center Weather Advisory)  – Stay informed about significant weather hazards and hazardous flying conditions such as thunderstorms, turbulence and icing across your route. ‍ METAR (METeorological Aerodrome Report)  – Display real-time meteorological aerodrome report information such as temperature, dewpoint, wind and ceiling to gauge current weather conditions at airports around the world. ‍ Turbulence – Identify regions of potential turbulence along your flight path to ensure a smoother journey.  ‍ Icing (Severity) – Understand the severity of icing conditions in different regions and adjust your flight plan accordingly. ‍ Reflectivity – Gain insights into precipitation by visualizing areas of precipitation and their severity. ‍ Cloud Cover – Evaluate cloud coverage and make informed decisions based on ceiling conditions displayable from FL20 up to FL500. ‍ ISA (International Standard Atmosphere) Temperature – Gain a better general understanding of the regional temperatures and plan your flights more accurately by incorporating International Standard Atmosphere temperature variations. ‍ Tropopause – Identify the upper limit of the troposphere to gain a better understanding of weather at high altitudes. ‍ Convective Cloud Top Level – Visualize the top levels of convective clouds to assess the potential for severe weather. ‍ High Cloud Top Level – Identify the altitude of high-level clouds, allowing for a better understanding of high altitude weather. ‍ Visibility – Display regions with low visibility to ensure safe and efficient navigation. ‍ MSL (Mean Sea Level) Pressure – View mean sea level pressure to understand the regional atmospheric conditions. ‍ Jet Streams – Discover the location of jet streams at different altitudes and plan your flights accordingly. ‍ Wind Barbs – Observe wind directions and strength with wind barbs at different altitudes for increased situational awareness and accurate flight planning.  Navigraph also adds that a 24-hour forecast is available for all layers except AIRMETs/SIGMETs, METAR, and radar; A 6-hour playback is available for all layers but AIRMETs/SIGMETs and METAR, while the radar offers a 2-hour playback.  They have attached a video showcasing some of the weather layers in action:  The new feature is available right now for Navigraph Ultimate subscribers. Click here to subscribe! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrcfrc</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update II France &amp; Local Legend 09 Latécoère 631</title>
    <updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrcfrc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64906cd180725061b6e7ca32_fr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="878399"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Microsoft Flight Simulator team has unveiled an exciting new update through a video on their youtube channel. City Update II: France is here, and it brings with it the breathtaking beauty of five iconic French cities: Amiens, Angers, Nantes, Nîmes, and Reims. To add to the excitement, this update coincides with the prestigious Paris Air Show and includes the highly renowned Paris–Le Bourget Airport (LFPB) in both standard and festival configurations. Each city featured in this update has its own unique charm and historical significance. Let's take a closer look at what makes them so special. To further celebrate French aviation heritage, the Microsoft Flight Simulator team is launching the Local Legend 09: Latécoère Model 631 aircraft. This impressive flying boat, designed and manufactured by France's Latécoère Corporation, represents a source of great national pride. The Model 631, an all-metal, high-wing, six-engine aircraft, took its maiden flight on November 4, 1942, and held the distinction of being the largest flying boat in the world for several years. Its elegant design and significant role in trans-oceanic travel make it a must-have addition for aviation enthusiasts. ‍ The Latécoère Model 631 comes with 16 liveries and will be available for purchase at $14.99. With its unique blend of beauty and historical significance, this aircraft perfectly complements the City Update II: France. ‍ To embark on this virtual journey through France and experience the wonders of City Update II, ensure that your Microsoft Flight Simulator is updated to version 1.32.7.0. Once updated, download the City Update II for free and prepare to be amazed by the stunning sights that France has to offer. ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsrop</id>
    <title>New SimWorks Studios update, regarding RV-10/14, Okavango delta and PC-12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsrop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6491e89107e81c253a2348d8_sws1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="959919"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Developer Simworks Studios, renowned for their rendition of the Kodiak 100 for MSFS has recently provided a development update on their Discord and Facebook regarding the RV-10/14, Okavango delta, and their PC-12. ‍ In light of the recent Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 announcement, SimWorks Studios has stated that as their existing add-ons follow the guidelines of the MSFS SDK, they believe that they will work fine in FS2024. They will update the installers to give users the option between MSFS2020 and MSFS2024 and users should be able to use the existing products without any paid upgrades. However, it's worth noting that if an add-on takes advantage of the new features exclusive to FS2024, such as the ability to perform specialized tasks, SimWorks Studios may choose to charge extra for such expansions. For example, if an aircraft like the Kodiak 100 requires additional work to enable the dropping of parachutists, an expansion product might be introduced with an associated cost. Nevertheless, if the existing add-ons continue to function flawlessly in FS2024 without any modifications, users can enjoy the enhancements without any additional charges. ‍ In other news, developers have announced updates for the RV-10 and RV-14 aircraft, addressing minor code bugs and compatibility issues. The RV-10 update specifically focuses on resolving problems with the PMS50 GTN650 and GTN750, while the RV-14 update improves ground handling for the taildragger variant in the Microsoft Store version. These updates are expected to be available next week, benefiting both Microsoft Store and other vendors. ‍ Furthermore, the much-anticipated update for Okavango Delta is set to arrive next week. This update brings a total of 14 new airstrips to the region, including Chitabe FBME, Delta FBDT, Kanana FBKK, Khwai FBKR, Mapula FBND, Ntswi FBND and camp, Pom Pom FBNO, Rann FBMQ, Sanctuary FBMB, Seronga FBSH, Shakawe FBSW, Shindi FBMJ and camp, Xaxaba FBXB and camp, and Xugana FBXG. Alongside the new airstrips, the update introduces hundreds of traveling animals, which exhibit realistic behavior, including running away if approached too closely. Additionally, minor fixes have been made to existing camps and airstrips, as well as improvements to animal LOD switching. ‍ A sneak peek at the PC-12 interior textures has been unveiled, showcasing the level of detail and customization options available. The textures for both the cockpit and cabin are being refined and improved, allowing for a fully customizable experience.  ‍ Repainters will appreciate the flexibility provided, as changing a few small textures will completely refurbish the cabin's look. The advantage of this approach is that it doesn't require large 4k textures for every livery, keeping the package size manageable. The cabin has already undergone significant changes, with a new kind of wood and carpeting, demonstrating the level of customization available to users. The developers have put great effort into ensuring that the textures and details of the PC-12's interior are of the highest quality. Turning our attention to the exterior of the aircraft, the model has undergone a final cleanup to add missing details and correct placements of various items. Flap actuators have been remodeled and animated, further enhancing the realism of the aircraft. The exterior is currently undergoing a final pass to ensure all aspects meet the highest standards and is expected to be completed by the end of this month. ‍ So far no release date has been announced for the highly anticipated PC-12 however when we find out we will inform you here at Threshold.  ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/c182ms</id>
    <title>Carenado Releases C182 RG II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/c182ms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6491e98484aaf86b50ac421a_182-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1126676"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has taken to their Facebook page to announce the release of their latest aircraft, the Cessna 182RG II for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Cessna 182RG II is a variant of the popular Cessna 182 Skylane aircraft. The Cessna 182RG II is a single-engine, four-seat aircraft with retractable landing gear. It is part of the Cessna 182 series, which has been in production since 1956 and is one of the most successful general aviation aircraft models. ‍ It's powered by a horizontally opposed, air-cooled engine. It typically uses a Lycoming IO-540 engine, which provides ample power for cruising and climbing. The aircraft has a maximum cruise speed of around 170-175 knots (196-201 mph) and a maximum range of approximately 900 nautical miles (1,035 miles) with standard fuel tanks. You can now pick it up from the In-Sim Marketplace for $19.99 at the time of writing.</summary>
    <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpg747</id>
    <title> Hype Performance Group Suspends Sales of the 747 Supertanker</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpg747" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6491ea74072011765bd5aac9_tanker1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="669089"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has taken to their Twitter page to announce the suspension of sales regarding their recently released 747 Supertanker.  The Hype Performance Group 747 Supertanker which was released just a few days ago, allowed users to take control of the 747 Supertanker and put out wildfires and help resolve an array of other disasters such as maritime oil spills. The aircraft was built upon the default MSFS Boeing 747 and had its own mission generator which randomised locations of the mission targets.  The suspension of sales is effective immediately and the aircraft is no longer available for purchase in the store. Hype Performance Group stated that they are unable to fully address the community’s questions and concerns regarding this. Those of you who have bought the addon and would like a refund should contact Hype Performance Group directly and their team will assist you with your request. Hype Performance Group will provide further details in an upcoming announcement through all their social media channels. ‍ We will keep you informed of the future announcement when it becomes available. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simrea</id>
    <title>SimCoders releases Reality Expansion for Super Cub in X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simrea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6491eae7561c512700538526_plane1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="873302"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After months of anticipation and hard work, the Reality Expansion Pack (REP) for the X-Plane 12 Piper Super Cub has finally arrived! This highly anticipated expansion pack is here to enhance your flying experience and take your virtual piloting skills to new heights. What's more, it is fully compatible with the existing free Super Cub mod by taildragging68. Let's take a look at some of the exciting highlights of this Reality Expansion Pack: ‍ ‍ For the full feature list, do check out their product page. These are just a few of the highlights that the Reality Expansion Pack for X-Plane 12 Piper Super Cub has to offer. From VR support to interactive pre/post-flight checks, a custom towing system, and much more, this pack aims to provide an unparalleled level of realism and immersion for X-Plane enthusiasts. ‍ It is now available on the X-Plane.org store for just $19.99. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sams3d</id>
    <title>SamScene 3D Releases Tibet Lhasa Gonggar for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sams3d" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649334cea89e500f0a5bbf00_image_2023-06-21_123509932.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="605992"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SamScene has taken to their Facebook page and Youtube channel to announce the release of their latest addition to Microsoft Flight Simulator, Tibet Lhasa Gonggar Airport. ‍ Lhasa Gonggar Airport (ZULS) is situated 11,800 feet above sea level high up in the Tibet Autonomous Region in southwestern China. Lhasa Gonggar Airport is one of the highest airports in the world. Recently the airport unveiled its brand new third terminal in 2023, offering modern amenities and an enhanced travel experience for visitors.  ‍ ‍ Lhasa Gonggar Airport is very well connected to other major cities in China, notably, Beijing, Chengdu, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Hong Kong, Chongqing, Xian, Xining, Kunming, Diqing, and the Chamdo Region. ‍ ‍ The airport features two runways, 09L and 27R. Runway 09L, although a non-ILS (Instrument Landing System) runway, provides a visually striking approach for pilots. On the other, hand Runway 27R offers the convenience of ILS navigation to allow a more convenient approach. ‍ ‍ Lhasa Gonggar Airport and its surrounding scenery are now available to purchase on their webstore for $14.95 at the time of writing.</summary>
    <published>2023-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/h55nan</id>
    <title>Hunter555 Releases Nan Nakhon Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/h55nan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6493444c98e4d60622914d77_vtnc1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3983939"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hunter555 has recently released their rendition of Nan Nakhon Airport (VTCN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Nan in Thailand with a yearly average of 380,000 passengers.  The airport was inaugurated in 1980, originally consisting of a single-story passenger terminal, a parking lot, and an administration office. It wasn’t until 2014 that Nan Nakhon got a modern passenger terminal, built near the old one, with 5,750 square meters of total area, accommodating up to 300 passengers per hour and 864,000 people per year.  It’s served by Nok Air, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Lion Air with flights to Bangkok (Don Mueang).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D model of the passenger terminal, custom ground textures, a custom GSX profile, custom night lighting, custom autogen for the city, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.92, requiring at least 75.67 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflab4</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Airbus A300B4 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflab4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649364803b78a4d68ad5fa4d_a300-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="280375"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently uploaded a YouTube video announcing the development of an Airbus A300B4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator and teasing some of the already finished work.   The upcoming add-on will feature highly detailed exterior models with two engine variants, cargo and passenger configs, realistic animations (dynamic wingflex, flaps, and spoilers), and more.  The systems (hydraulic, electrical, fuel, and pressurization) will be custom coded based on the aircraft’s manual, and the navigation systems will include a custom INS and FMC, and options for an AFCS (Automatic Flight Control System) panel and the A300’s N1 limit computer and autothrottle.  The cockpit will feature all three positions (pilot, first officer, and flight engineer), realistically reproduced, texturized (4K and 8K), and modeled with animated and functional switches, knobs, and levers.  The A300B4 was the long-range version of the A300, which became the first ETOPS-compliant aircraft in 1977, just two years after its launch, becoming an interesting option for overwater routes and quickly becoming a favorite of many Asian airlines.  There’s no release date or pricing information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksbol</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Bologna Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksbol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6494b6f84e86849d126d6ccb_bologna1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1414398"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Bologna Airport (LIPE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Bologna in Italy with a yearly average of 8.5 million passengers.  Opened in 1933, the original airport sat 500 meters west of the current building. With the advent of the jet age in the 1970s and the subsequent traffic boom, it was deemed too cramped and replaced by the present building soon after.  The “new” terminal was expanded between 2011 and 2013 to 36,100 square meters, sporting 24 departure gates, none of which have jetways.   It’s a hub for Ryanair (Alghero, Amman–Queen Alia, Athens, Barcelona, Bari, Beauvais, Berlin, Billund, Brindisi, Bucharest–Otopeni, Budapest, Cagliari, Catania, Charleroi, Cologne/Bonn, Copenhagen, Crotone, Dublin, Edinburgh, Eindhoven, Fès, Fuerteventura, Gran Canaria, Kraków, Lamezia Terme, Lanzarote, Lisbon, London–Luton, London–Stansted, Madrid, Málaga, Malta, Manchester, Marseille, Nuremberg, Palermo, Paphos, Porto, Prague, Santander, Santiago de Compostela, Seville, Sofia, Stockholm–Arlanda, Tel Aviv, Tenerife–South, Thessaloniki, Trapani, Valencia, Vienna, Warsaw–Modlin, Wrocław, Zaragoza) and Neos (Marsa Alam, Sharm El Sheikh, Tenerife–South), and visited by a comprehensive list of carriers such as Aegean, Air France, British Airways, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, and more.   The scenery features a high-fidelity rendition of the airport, with an accurately modeled terminal and its interior, landside buildings, custom GSE vehicles, performance-friendly optimization, and compatibility with most AI traffic plugins.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.20, requiring at least 1.09 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse2023</id>
    <title>A2A's Scott Gentile demos the upcoming Accu-Sim Comanche 250 at FSExpo23 </title>
    <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse2023" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d2daee83e88a379f1b44bc_a2a-1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="420712"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations announced their first new add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the Accu-Sim Comanche 250. Friday product announcements  FlightSim Expo 2023 included the Comanche 250, demoed featuring a unique approach to flight model feel and realism. A2A's owner, Scott Gentile, highlighted the details of the nearly finished aircraft in an interview with Two Tone Murphy during the convention; the interview was also published to their Youtube channel.  The big takeaway is the engine's wear, tear and scheduled maintenance requirements. Further highlights detail engine physics, friction, temperature simulations of internal components, and much more. A2A aims to keep each flight of the Comanche unique through wear and tear experienced through ownership of an aging general aviation piston. Scott also provides an explanation of the "feel" of the aircraft's aerodynamics while flying over New England. The setting then transitions to the simulator, demonstrating the feel of flying an light piston are well recreated. The also video shows the dynamics of flight animated  as the aircraft moves through chop. The video then shifts focus to showcase the impact of aerodynamic effects and fuel loads on the airframe, as demonstrated by the left wing's reaction to changes in airflow. In addition the sound recording processes are also highlighted in the video above, make sure to check it out its worth the watch! ‍  A2A has a release aimed for this July. Of course, keep an eye on Threshold for more information on this upcoming release and continued coverage of FlightSim Expo 23. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/released-microsoft-flight-simulator-famous-flyer-six-the-ford-tri-motor</id>
    <title>Released: Microsoft Flight Simulator Famous Flyer Six, The Ford Tri Motor </title>
    <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/released-microsoft-flight-simulator-famous-flyer-six-the-ford-tri-motor" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64964e2e6d29e8408196d73d_MSFS_FordTrimotor_NoSnipe_NoLogo_NoText.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3220634"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo has recently announced the launch of the Ford Trimotor for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This aircraft is a significant piece of aviation history, with about 200 built in total and made its first flight in June 1926. Even today, approximately 6-8 of the Trimotors are still flying, one offering rides during EAA Airventure Oshkosh. Its unique design features a corrugated metal fuselage for added strength and rigidity, along with three radial engines, making it easily recognizable in the skies. The Trimotor can accommodate up to 12 passengers and can cruise at around 100mph. The Trimotor's three engines were a safety feature, ensuring redundancy and building public trust in flying as a mode of transportation. The team has done an excellent job recreating this iconic aircraft, as showcased in their release trailer on the Microsoft Flight Simulator YouTube channel. Asobo is giving this one away free June 23 to June 30!! From the Asobo team. Available now! The Microsoft Flight Simulator team is thrilled to release a new aircraft in the "Famous Flyers" series of planes. The Ford 4-AT Trimotor is an aviator’s dream machine: an all-metal, high-wing, three-engine passenger, and cargo aircraft. Built ruggedly, it can operate out of some of the world’s most austere airfields, and due to its renowned forgivingness in the air, the Trimotor elevates pilot confidence to new heights.For the next week, this classic is available for FREE to simmers! From June 23 to June 30 at 11:59 PM PDT, it can be downloaded at no charge from the in-sim Marketplace. From July 1 onward, it will be available for USD $14.99.Explore the world from the cockpit of this iconic aircraft that has been rendered in exquisite detail – the sky is calling! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia36</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases Airbus A300-600 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia36" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649706e0792c5b9089468bc4_a3-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="567950"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Yesterday, iniBuilds revealed their “ultimate airliner experience” to the world, initially teased in early June with an in-game screenshot of an engine. The mystery airplane is an Airbus A300-600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring realistic 3D models, true-to-life systems, full ACARS/CPDLC simulation, and more.  They claim to have completely re-created the exterior model, using 4K and 8K PBR textures with realistic decals, wear and tear, and dirt.   The detail also extends to its interior, with a fully modeled cockpit and cargo compartment and an extensive range of cargo loads varying from boxes to horses.   The airliner will feature a comprehensive systems simulation with a realistic flight model, full ACARS/CPDLC simulation, Navigraph charts compatibility, multiple liveries, a custom WWise sound set, and two variants: freighter and passenger—the first to come on release and the latter after the release.  They also plan to include the Primus Epic suite later down the line, with further updates on that to come in the future.  The Airbus A300-600 is an extended version of the A300B2 and B4, with two additional rows of seats, powered by two General Electric CF6-80C2 engines, and making use of the A310 cockpit, with no need for a flight engineer like the older A300s. 313 A300-600s were sold between its inception and 2007, when production stopped.  There’s still no pricing or release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swmuc2</id>
    <title>Sim-wings Releases Munich Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swmuc2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64971ae2cd1bd07e1e0e63d0_muc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="459657"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Sim-wings has recently released the second version of their Munich Airport (EDDM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a complete rework of the previous version from late 2020 with new buildings, improved aerial imagery, and more.  Munich Airport is the 9th busiest airport in Europe, with a yearly average of 47.9 million passengers, serving the city of Munich and Upper Bavaria.   It opened in 1992, replacing Munich-Riem Airport, which served Munich from 1939 to 1992. It was deemed hard to expand because of the growing number of inhabitants around its proximity, leading to the desire to move the airport to a completely different location.   Construction work started in 1980 on the small village of Franzheim, whose 400 inhabitants were moved elsewhere. Operations began on 17 May 1992, with Riem closing the night before.  It’s one of the main hubs for Lufthansa, flying worldwide. Condor, Eurowings, Eurowings Discover, and TUIfly Deutschland also use the airport as their bases.  The scenery features a high-detail rendition of Munich, with custom color-matched aerial orthoimagery, custom terraforming, detailed taxi lines, accurate replicas of the terminal and landside buildings, custom dynamic lighting, PBR texturing, custom ground textures, animated jetways, and VDGS compatibility.   It’s available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $24.99, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners are entitled to a free upgrade. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cldmac</id>
    <title>Cloudsurf Asia Simulations Releases Mactan-Cebu International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cldmac" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6497212fde248421b34a9010_cebu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1009384"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cloudsurf Asia Simulations has recently released their rendition of Mactan-Cebu International Airport (RPVM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Metropolitan Cebu in the Philippines with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  The airport started as an emergency landing strip for USAF’s Strategic Air Command bombers in 1956. It wasn’t until 1966 that Mactan became a commercial airport, replacing the closed Lahug Airport that couldn’t be expanded due to physical limitations.   Mactan-Cebu has two terminals, with Terminal 1 occupying a floor area of 38,525 square meters, and Terminal 2 occupying 65,600 square meters, yielding a combined capacity of 12.5 million passengers per year.  It’s a hub for Cebgo (Bacolod, Busuanga, Butuan, Cagayan de Oro, Calbayog, Camiguin, Caticlan, Davao, Dipolog, Dumaguete, General Santos, Iloilo, Legazpi, Manila, Naga, Ozamiz, Pagadian, Puerto Princesa, Siargao, Surigao, Tacloban, Zamboanga), Cebu Pacific  (Caticlan, Clark, Davao, General Santos, Hong Kong, Iloilo, Manila, Puerto Princesa, Seoul–Incheon, Singapore, Taipei–Taoyuan, Tokyo–Narita, Zamboanga), PAL Express (Bacolod, Baguio, Borongan, Busuanga, Butuan, Cagayan de Oro, Caticlan, Clark, Cotabato, Davao, Iloilo, Manila, Puerto Princesa, Siargao, Tacloban, Zamboanga), and Philippine Airlines (Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Manila, Seoul–Incheon, Tokyo–Narita).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom objects, fully modeled terminals and hangars, full PBR texturing, custom animated jetways, hotels and resorts around the Mactan island, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.38, requiring at least 695.93 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
