<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-10-24T18:23:08.136097+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfratm</id>
    <title>Got Friends Releases AviTar Series for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfratm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65274c2469e45fd170052d81_Screenshot%202023-10-11%20at%209.30.02%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2032520"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Got Friends, developers of well loved aircraft and pilot avatars, has released another foray into avatar development for Microsoft Flight Simulators, the AviTars Series for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  ‍ This release builds on their very popular freeware “Man's Best Friend” mod, and adds more advanced technology and higher detailed character models to the simulator. The models integrate with the IK Chain animation system, and work with the MSFS core, so they are able to grab and move the yoke, rudder pedals, throttles, and mixture on any aircraft that has used the animation system. Many addons are already compatible, such as the popular Comanche 250 by A2A Simulations, and many aircraft from developers like Flying Iron Simulations and Touching Cloud. The Got Friends’ AviTar Series includes three avatar packs. The first pack is a re-launch of the popular Man’s Best Friend pack, including integration with the AviTar system, and includes eight new cats, and one new dog, The next pack, dubbed “Valor” includes six warbird pilots to take out on missions. The third pack includes many of the community’s favorite Twitch streamers, including TwoToneMurphy, TheDukeNewComb, WestCoastWilly, BurstixTV, FordorLearnToFly, and OohCando. The Valor pack is a payware product, and can be acquired in the Got Friends store for $4.99 USD. The Valor and Man’s Best Friend packs are both free. The inital release will be for PC only, but Got Friends is planning on a Marketplace and XBOX release sometime in the future ‍ For more information about Got Friends’ amazing AviTar series and to get them for your sim, visit the Got Friends Store. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthtus</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Tucson International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthtus" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65286384c896130c9806f772_tus.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1482961"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Tucson International Airport (KTUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Arizona with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers. ‍ It was built in 1948, replacing the former airport (Tucson Municipal), the first municipality-owned airport in the United States (circa 1919). They used three hangars that were utilized by WW2 manufacturing companies as the base infrastructure, along with a wooden control tower from the same era.  ‍ A proper control tower was built a decade later, and commercial operations started two years prior with American, TWA, and Frontier.  ‍  A new terminal was inaugurated in 1963, with an international inspection station. It had already been operating internationally two years before, with Aeronaves de Mexico flying to Hermosillo. It was remodeled twice in the 60s and 70s.  ‍ Twenty years later, the administration expanded the main terminal from 150,000 square feet to 300,000, rebuilding the concourse into separate structures with jet bridges. Further renovation happened in 2005, adding 82,000 square feet to the terminal and renumbering the gate layout. ‍  Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR texturing, custom animated jetways, custom ground poly, improved lighting, hand-placed ground clutter, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.68, requiring at least 695.96 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inipsp</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Palm Springs International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inipsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6529bf75cd04126ce0527b35_psp.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1940922"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of Palm Springs International Airport (KPSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Palm Springs area in California with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. It was built by the US Army as an emergency landing field in 1939, later improved to serve as a staging field during World War 2. It was then sold to private buyers in 1946 and purchased by the City of Palm Springs in 1961 to become Palm Springs Municipal Airport. Airline service started with Western Airlines in the mid to late 40s, followed by Bonanza Air Lines a decade later.  Palm Springs was transformed into a dual runway airport in the 1990s and expanded with a new concourse in 1999, increasing its passenger handling capacity.  The pandemic aftermath brought record growth, thanks to the arrival of Southwest Airlines with year-round flights to Oakland, Phoenix, Denver, and Vegas (the latter started a year later).  Air Canada, Air Canada Rouge, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Flair Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet currently serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, highly detailed models, custom night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, LOD optimization, and more. It will be released next Friday (Oct 20) for roughly $18.17. Media previews will begin two days prior.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pricgh</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Releases São Paulo-Congonhas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pricgh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6529cdc7bc22a0f97c694b8a_cgh.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="254252"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Paulo Ricardo Scenery Designer has recently released their rendition of São Paulo - Deputado Freitas Nobre Airport (SBSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 18 million passengers. Although initially planned in 1919, it only opened in 1936, with a 300-meter-long dirt runway, serving as an alternate airport to Campo de Marte, São Paulo’s first airport. Commercial service began that year with a flight to Rio de Janeiro, served by VASP.  ‍ Twenty years later, Congonhas was the third busiest airport in the world for air cargo while also serving all international flights to and from São Paulo, as the runways were long enough to accommodate the aircraft from that time period, which was no longer the case in the 60s and 70s, with the advent of passenger jet aircraft, which led airlines to look for an alternative (Viracopos Airport, in Campinas). ‍ The late 50s marked the creation of the famous air shuttle between Congonhas and Rio de Janeiro (SBRJ), with regular departures every half-hour. It used to be an agreement between three airlines (VASP, Varig, and Cruzeiro do Sul), with Transbrasil joining the partnership in 1968. The deal was dissolved in 1999 after airlines decided to operate their shuttle flights independently. ‍ It was São Paulo’s main airport until 1985 when Guarulhos Airport was officially opened, and restrictions were imposed to limit CGH’s daily flights. Even with all the restrictions, Congonhas still manages to be the most popular domestic airport in the city because of its convenience (Congonhas is closer to the city’s heart).  ‍ The airport lost its international category in 2008 after multiple restrictions were imposed regarding aircraft size, landing weight, etc. The Airbus A320 and the Boeing 737-800 are the largest aircraft allowed to operate in Congonhas, while it had previously dealt with DC-8s, 767s, and A300s. Accidents such as the TAM Airlines Flight 3054 (17/07/2007) made it more restrictive. ‍ AENA has recently won a 30-year concession to operate the airport, which had been previously owned and operated by Infraero, a government-owned company. ‍ It’s currently served by Azul Brazilian Airlines, Azul Conecta, GOL Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, true-to-life landside, multiple city landmarks, a detailed terminal interior, custom ground clutter, custom weathering, and more. It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for $16.99, requiring at least 5.8 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwa340</id>
    <title>X-Works A340 For XP12 Released</title>
    <updated>2023-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwa340" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/652aafb8590043936a41ece3_A342_-_2023-10-04_00.44.11.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1657656"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular X-plane freeware Developers X-Works have released their latest Airbus Creation for X-Plane 12. The new Freeware A340 will bring the avid Airbus flight sim captain a delightful smile.  Initially, today, there was some trouble from a few community members who decided to keep pressuring the development team into announcing a release time. Much to the backlash of some in the community,  X-Works postponed the release of the aircraft in an attempt to put out the fire that was burning in their Discord. I’ll leave it to those in the community to decide whether this helped.  The aircraft is loosely based on the Default A330 Platform but V1 will include the following additions and changes: ‍ After a controversial and far from smooth release day, however, the A340 is finally here, and Sim pilots can now enjoy the four-engined beast in all her glory.  The aircraft can be downloaded via a link in the X-works Discord server.  ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a34060</id>
    <title>LatinVFR announces new Airbus widebody addons!</title>
    <updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a34060" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/652d3b86696ed3416d59c00d_391621024_1030570411425585_3996768700227810381_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="295083"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LatinVFR has recently announced the upcoming release of new Airbus widebody addons for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the A330/A340, as shared in a Facebook post. According to the post, the A330neo will be available this(possibly Thursday, according to comment replies) week, while the A340-300/200 will be released in the coming weeks. LatinVFR also confirmed that they would launch the A330-200CEO and A340-600 addons next year. The team states that these upcoming addons will be of the "middle ground" tier, featuring custom systems and avionics, among other features that surpass the default systems and standards. The addons will be available for XBOX users as well! LatinVFR is known for their A320, A319ceo A318, and sceneries like San Diego Int for Microsoft Flight Simulator. You can check out LatinVFR's products on their website, the Contrail app, or the Microsoft Addon store within the sim. ‍ ‍ Check out the release trailer and preview shots here or more here! As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more new regarding these upcoming releases! </summary>
    <published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taicar</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Cairns Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taicar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/652f7f1eba1640e3fc6aa018_cairns.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="588650"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Cairns Airport (YBCS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Cairns in Queensland, Australia, with a yearly average of 5 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1936 on 162 hectares of land bought by the Cairns City Council, originally sporting three runways made of cinders, red earth, weathered rock, and sand. Then, in the early 1940s, the Australian Government purchased the airport to adapt it for RAF use, paving and lengthening the main runway to comport larger aircraft. ‍ Twenty years later, the airport was upgraded to receive jet aircraft, with an expansion and a runway extension followed by extensive flattening. ‍ With the ever-growing passenger traffic figures, there was pressure in the late 1970s to expand the passenger terminal, which went on to happen in 1982. Finished two years later, it was just the first stage of three. The whole ordeal ended in 1997 with the conclusion of a three-story Airport Administration Center. ‍ In 2007, the domestic terminal was redeveloped, costing the administration around 200 million Australian Dollars.  ‍ The last upgrade started in 2019 and was completed a year later, increasing the departure hall area and adding dining and retail facilities. It’s part of their plan to prepare the airport for handling up to 6 million passengers annually from 2027. ‍ In early 2023, they announced the first major upgrade to the international terminal, rolling out in stages to minimize passenger disruption. ‍ It’s a hub for QantasLink and Skytrans Airlines, and served by Air New Zealand, Air Niugini, Airnorth, Alliance Airlines, Asia Pacific Airlines, Bonza, Hinterland Aviation, Jetstar, PNG Air, Qantas, Rex Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Virgin Australia. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made PBR ground markings, custom terminals, realistic lighting, up-to-date taxiways, performance-friendly optimization, and custom jetways. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.01, requiring at least 736.46 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsibu</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Sibu Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsibu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/652f84863b135309793370f1_sibu.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="722727"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Sibu Airport (WBGS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Bintangor, Sarikei, Kapit, and Sibu in East Malaysia, with a yearly average of 569,000 passengers, making it the 11th busiest in the country. ‍ It opened in 1994, replacing Sibu’s former airport, which was demolished to make way for the Laila Taib College (its runway can still be seen, albeit partially).  ‍ It underwent a massive expansion project in 2010, upgrading the terminal building and car park at a total cost of RM130 Million. With the upgrade, the airport could handle 1.8 million passengers per year. ‍ AirAsia, Batik Air Malaysia, Malaysia Airlines, and MASwings serve it. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout (2023), custom jetways, AI traffic compatibility, and custom ground textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.63, requiring at least 28.81 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kokefb</id>
    <title>PMDG Teases Upcoming EFB for 737 Lineup </title>
    <updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kokefb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65305d2b150d777ee563d827_1250410_20231010221817_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1486655"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mathijs Kok from PMDG has made a forum thread showing a quick sneak peek of their upcoming Electronic Flight Bag for their 737 lineup on Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with a date to look forward to.  ‍ While the teaser itself does not say much (aside from the preview), Mathijs has shared that Robert Randazzo will publish a feature list, more images, and a release date sometime this weekend. ‍ It will be a free micro-update for PMDG.com and Marketplace users, but the latter will take longer because of Microsoft’s intake process. They estimate around 2-3 weeks from the release on their official website, and it’s just guesswork based on the average time it takes, according to their empirical data.  The 737 lineup is available on PMDG.com or via Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atcsky</id>
    <title>SmartSky brings us natural voice interaction with in sim ATC</title>
    <updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atcsky" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6531ea011b3cbe750aefb13a_Screenshot%202023-10-19%20213358.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="233585"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Recent advancements in AI have changed the world over the past year or so. It's undoubtedly one of the most significant advancements we've made over the recent decades, leaving Sundar Pichai to insist that the AI revolution is more significant than the invention of fire. Some may think that's a little farfetched, but in a way, he is not too far off. The AI boom will have a profound impact on many industries around the world. Some industries will be impacted wholly and others less rapidly. ‍ Simply put, let the computer do the heavy lifting and leave the humans to supervise. Aviation will be affected by AI quite a bit on the non-pilot side of the industry. Data processing, calculations, route, and frequency planning and processes could change significantly due to AI. The industry desperately needs ATC controllers; maybe AI could solve this problem over the next decade. But instead of waiting for the next decade, we could glimpse the future using our regular old home-based simulation. But first, before we do that, we have to find a creative person who's willing to tackle the problem of Microsoft's horrendous AI ATC (can we even call I Ai?)  The stock sim's ATC is worse than a group of kids playing Red Light Green Light, but there looks to be hope on the horizon, thanks to SmartSky.ai  ‍ We recently discovered their post on Reddit of their very promising Ai ATC controller that's voice-activated. It currently uses ChatGPT as a framework for listening and providing instruction. The excitement comes from the naturality of Ai's voice. Unlike MSFS and other ATC add-ons, you aren't teleported into your grandma's talking 1984 Chrysler LeBaron. Your DoOR is AJAR. SmartSky.ai leaps ahead with phonetics and phraseology you recognize. SmartSky achieved this by studying ATC communications to match the many voices you would hear flying in real life. This dedication gives the user hundreds of unique voices throughout the software experience. These voices give Smart Sky its uniqueness. You can also respond in regular English with a normal talking speed as you would in real life. Allowing you to respond to ATC requests without using clunky menus or trigger words to acknowledge instructions. ‍ Smart Sky states they are focusing on general aviation VFR, the more difficult phraseology for the AI to master. IFR General Aviation will follow sometime next year. From their Reddit post, "It Assumes you have a level of how ATC works." There are no pop-up menus to interact with; you speak into your headset as you would in real life. This natural interaction is where this idea shines; I can see this being an excellent training tool for student pilots wanting to touch up their ATC communications offline from VATSIM, etc. So far, it only covers the United States and all major airspace classes B, C, D. Clearance Ground Tower, Departure, Center, Unicom, and more. ‍ According to the team, they're just about ready for their initial release after ironing out the bugs. To help smash the bugs faster, they're offering a beta sign-up version allowing early adopters to test the features to help perfect the first release for free.  ‍ To sign up for the beta check this link out on their website! ‍ Of course stay tuned to Threshold for more news and updates on SmartSky.Ai!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inkpsp</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Palm Springs International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inkpsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6532a5a832ff1653fb920ed6_inipsp1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="566644"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Palm Springs International Airport (KPSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Palm Springs area in California with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. Built by the US Army as an emergency landing field in 1939, it was later improved to serve as a staging field during World War 2. It was then sold to private buyers in 1946 and purchased by the City of Palm Springs in 1961 to become Palm Springs Municipal Airport. Airline service started with Western Airlines in the mid to late 40s, followed by Bonanza Air Lines a decade later. It was transformed into a dual runway airport in the 1990s and expanded with a new concourse in 1999, increasing its passenger handling capacity. The post-COVID period brought record growth, thanks to the arrival of Southwest Airlines with year-round flights to Oakland, Phoenix, Denver, and Vegas (the latter started a year later). Air Canada, Air Canada Rouge, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Flair Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet currently serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, highly detailed models, custom night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, LOD optimization, and more. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.19, requiring at least 3.57 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737uft</id>
    <title>PMDG Reveals Planned Release Date for Upcoming Universal Flight Tablet</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737uft" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65343e6b65baf3b73849208c_uft.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2640684"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo from PMDG has made a new announcement concerning their long-awaited Universal Flight Tablet for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with many preview images, features, and a release date.   ‍ They begin with an explanation of why it took relatively long to develop, with a bit of backstory on their pre-existing regulatory Electronic Flight Bag that was available for their P3D line of products between 2016 and 2022 and the decisions that led to developing a completely new tool from scratch, with a different approach and scope.  ‍ PMDG highlights that the Universal Flight Tablet is not an EFB, as EFBs are tightly tailored toward flight planning and management tasks with a fairly limited scope. They wanted to offer more than just that this time, which other developers have also been offering and has become the market standard as of late. Thus, the different naming.  ‍ Asobo’s SU13 removed one of their biggest limitations regarding communication with an external server, making it easier for PMDG to send data back and forth from the user’s aircraft to their server infrastructure and eliminating the need for the complex workaround method they had previously been utilizing.  ‍ One of the things that was not previously mentioned is that their tablet will be compatible with sim-enhancement tools from either themselves or partners, meaning it will provide an ecosystem for applications that will run inside that environment. They refer to it as the “garden.”   Upon release, which is scheduled for October 30, the application suite will be as follows:  Flight Plans/SimBrief Integration - Importing flight plans from SimBrief. - Download weather for the flight plan route. - Flight plan/weather sharing between tablet/aircraft. - Display of Operational Flight Plan. - Display of real time METAR information (native or simplified format)  Charting: - Navigraph Charts (Requires Navigraph Subscription) - Georeferenced aircraft on displayed charts where appropriate. - Flight centric chart selection/pinning of desired charts.  Performance Computation: - T/O, Diversion, Landing computations. - Data Import from flight plans or from the aircraft itself. - Reduced runway length computations. - Graphic display of displaced threshold data.  Plans for upcoming applications were already laid out, including ways to manage aircraft options, functions, and failures.   While more features are yet to be announced, they claim to have coordinated with other developers to include access to their applications from the tablet, bringing an entirely seamless integration.  The core functionality includes data entry via keyboard or on-screen, metric/imperial units, day/night setting, and independent tablets (pilot/co-pilot).   Their upcoming 777 will feature the tablet from the beginning, while the 737 Lineup will get the update on October 30, as previously mentioned.  The 737 lineup is available on PMDG.com or via Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dddwro</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Copernicus Airport Wrocław for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dddwro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653447d22a5e93a42af6888e_wroclaw.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1604694"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Copernicus Airport Wrocław (EPWR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an international civil-military airport serving the city of Wrocław, in Poland, with a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers.  ‍ It was built by the Germans for military purposes in 1938 when the city was still part of Germany. It used to host a military aviation school, the Lufkstriegskule 5.   ‍ After a brief post-war Soviet occupation, it saw civil use as early as 1945, with four domestic service routes.  ‍ International service started in 1993 with a flight to Frankfurt, followed by many airport upgrades, including a new international departures terminal in 1997 and a domestic terminal in 1998. ‍ Further expansion happened in 2005, along with a name change: from Wrocław Airport to Copernicus Airport Wrocław, after the famous astronomer. The passenger terminal had been expanded to accommodate up to 750,000 passengers a year, and they soon had to increase the terminal’s size again because the airport’s yearly average had neared a million passengers by 2007.  ‍ In the mid-2000s, the administration contracted the architectural firm JSK to design a major expansion for the entire airport, including a larger terminal and apron, runway improvements, and more. The first stage opened six years later, bringing the passenger handling capabilities up to 3.5 million passengers a year. ‍ The airport is one of the Polish hubs for Ryanair (Buzz), flying passengers all over Europe. Enter Air, European Air Charter, Eurowings, Finnair, KLM, LOT, Lufthansa, Swiss, and WizzAir also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a performance-friendly design, custom-animated people and vehicles, modeled interiors, custom-animated jetways, high-quality static aircraft, city landmarks, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.89, requiring at least 1.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fleha2</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fleha2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65344c7d27c83b0010461bdf_update.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="270835"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has recently issued a new update to their rendition of Amsterdam Airport Schiphol (EHAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a list of new bug fixes and improvements.  ‍ Version 1.2, the second update so far, brings updated AI parking codes, taxiway layout updates, multiple fixes, lighting improvements, and more. The changelog follows below:  V1.2 (19 Oct 2023) -updated AI parking codes -taxiway layout update based on latest changes -fixed jagged shorelines -minor 3D and texture fixes -optmised taxiing over elevated taxiways -added more grasspads -added custom animated apron traffic -optimised highway lighting ‍  ‍ ‍ The scenery is available on their website for $21.99, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vuevia</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Velana International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vuevia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6536ed85c758d5b6c39bfc08_velana.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1277622"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Velana International Airport (VRMM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport in the Maldives, serving its Capital city, Malé.  What once started as a small strip of land in the early 1960s became a proper airport only four years later, when the government and its people gathered together to build an asphalt runway: four city districts competed for who could be the fastest. Two years later, the runway was opened and ready for commercial action.  ‍ The upgrade to International status happened a decade after the initial tourism boom, with its official inauguration as Malé International Airport in 1981.   ‍ A few years ago, the administration expanded the airport with a new runway (that was serving as a taxiway until 2022 because there was an old seaplane terminal near it that was too close). They have also been building a new passenger terminal, a long-term project scheduled to reach completion by 2025. It features an area of around 78,000 square meters, serving up to 7.3 million passengers a year instead of its current capacity of only 1 million. ‍  It’s a hub for Maldivian and Trans Maldivian Airways. Aeroflot, AirAsia, Air France, Air India, Austrian Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, British Airways, China Eastern Airlines, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Gulf Air, ITA Airways, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Turkish Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and WizzAir visit it. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with its new passenger terminal (and interior), updated runway, custom taxiways, custom night lighting, LOD optimization, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.88, requiring at least 415.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdch7p</id>
    <title>PILOT'S GesmbH announces the upcoming release of the Dash 7</title>
    <updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdch7p" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6537def75eaeb757d29960be_NNOSE.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="374149"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Today PILOT'S GesmbH announced the imminent release of their long-awaited Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Known for their scenery and utility addons for FSX and P3D, they'll add the Dash 7 to their lineup soon. The Dash 7 is a rugged four-engine turboprop developed and manufactured by de Havilland Canada. It is known for its STOL performance, which gives it more destination options in rugged terrain and unpaved landing surfaces. Making its first flight in March of 1975, approximately 113 were built. The DHC-7 is powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney PT6A-50 engines producing around 1,100 shaft horsepower, allowing it to cruise upward to 230 knots. Its STOL capabilities allow it to operate out of runways as little as 2,000 feet long. This capacity makes it useful for passenger service and cargo. ‍ ‍ According to a recent Facebook post by PILOT'S GesmbH, you will soon be able to experience the STOL performance of the DHC-7 this weekend. The addon will include real-world liveries and equipment, such as the Working Title GNS 530 and a specific model supporting the GTNXi. Additionally, custom sounds are engineered for the Dash 7 with assistance and input from Air Tindi. There are many operational quirks modeled after the real Dash 7"One such unique feature is the nose wheel gear doors slowly opening after engines shut down with the subsequent hydraulic pressure drop". ‍ The Dash 7 will be available on their web store at www.pilots.shop this weekend. Make sure to create an account for purchase.   As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
