<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-01-19T18:41:01.605275+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ss220u</id>
    <title>Synaptic Simulations Shares A220 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2026-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ss220u"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695adcf09a00a32183e5de53_image1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Synaptic Simulations has shared a brief end-of-year development update on its upcoming A220, offering a snapshot of where the project stands as it heads into 2026. Over the past year, the team has made steady progress across the aircraft’s core systems, including engine control, fly-by-wire, and autoflight logic, as well as a significant rebuild of the flight management system, to support deeper system integration.  System complexity has continued to grow, with the EICAS now featuring more than 100 messages. At the same time, ongoing revisions to both the engine and flight models aim to further refine the aircraft’s handling and performance.  Looking ahead, Synaptic says testing will ramp up in the coming months, with a focus on LNAV behaviour across global procedures, VNAV integration, and ensuring that performance data is adequately respected by guidance and engine systems. A handful of remaining systems, including pressurisation and autobrakes, are still being finalised.  While the A220 did not release in 2025, the team reiterated that the extra time is being used to deliver a more complete, polished product, with further updates expected, as development continues into the new year.  Read the full update on Synaptic's Discord. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsaw26</id>
    <title>Vote Now: Community Nominations Open for Flightsim Awards 2026</title>
    <updated>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsaw26"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695be909ac215d8654456993_FLIGHTSIM_AWAR_Black_Background.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The community survey for the Flightsim Awards 2026 is now live, marking the opening of the official nomination phase for next year’s awards.  The survey allows simmers to nominate projects, developers, creators, and long-term contributors they believe made a meaningful impact on the flight simulation scene in 2025. The nomination phase plays a key role in shaping the final shortlist, covering a wide range of categories across aircraft, scenery, tools, freeware, hardware, innovation, and community contributions.  Participants are free to nominate in as many or as few categories as they wish, with no requirement to complete the entire form. All submissions will be reviewed and passed on to the Flightsim Awards organising board and jury, alongside nominations gathered from invited content creators and media outlets. The goal is to ensure that the final voting slate reflects a broad community sentiment, rather than a curated selection. All entries are evaluated according to shared principles: The survey is being distributed jointly by Threshold, FSElite, and Cruiselevel, who together organise the Flight Sim Awards. Public voting will follow later in the process, with a jury step only used in cases of ties or irregular results. Nominations are open until the published deadline, with eligibility limited to products and projects released or significantly updated in 2025.  The winners will be revealed during the Captain’s Dinner at FlightSimWeekend 2026, on Friday, March 20.  ‍ Take the nomination survey here.  You can read more on the Flight Sim Awards website. Tickets to FlightSimWeekend 2026 and the Captain's Dinner can be found here. ‍ Join the Flight Sim Awards Discord and be a part of the Awards community! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsogaleo2</id>
    <title>FSoares Shares New Galeão International Airport Previews </title>
    <updated>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsogaleo2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695c3b3230f0a76c32a4119e_rio1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSoares has recently teased the development progress on his Rio de Janeiro/Galeão International Airport (SBGL) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is the main airport serving Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with a yearly average of 14.5 million passengers. It was opened in 1952 on top of a pre-existing Brazilian Air Force base that was utilized by international long-haul flights, which were too heavy and too large for SBRJ’s (Rio’s domestic airport) 1,300 m runway. With the ever-increasing international demand, they finally built a passenger terminal, which was progressively expanded until 1977. A new terminal building was opened that year, and all scheduled passenger traffic was transferred there. It’s still in use today as Terminal 1. Terminal 1 was first renovated in 1991 in preparation for the United Nations Earth Summit (held in 1992), and its annual capacity increased to 7.5 million passengers. Eight years later, Terminal 2 was opened, featuring 24 jetways and a capacity of up to 7.5 million passengers per year. ‍With the imminence of the World Cup and the Olympic Games in 2014 and 2016, respectively, Infraero (the airport’s former manager) unveiled a $431 million upgrade and expansion plan for Galeão, including the renovation of Terminal 1, the completion of Terminal 2, and the expansion of the parking lots. The new concessionary revised the plans and included a new pier with 26 jetways, a new apron for 97 aircraft, and 2640 parking spaces. The $400 million sum quickly jumped to $800 million instead. Aerolíneas Argentinas, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, Azul, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Flybondi, Gol, Iberia, ITA Airways, JetSmart Argentina, JetSmart Chile, KLM, Latam Brasil, Latam Chile, Latam Perú, Lufthansa, Paranair, Sky Airlines, TAP, and United Airlines serve it. There is no information on features, pricing, or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbt267</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Targets 2026 for 757 Release</title>
    <updated>2026-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbt267"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695dcaa617a27011d5d4fb98_610642515_1180738477521565_5941258756545479178_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. BlueBird Simulations recently took to Facebook to announce that they are planning to release their 757 in 2026. The initial release will include a version of the plane compatible with both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This will be followed up with a native 2024 version of the 757. The latter will be provided free of charge for those who purchase the initial release version. The team has promised that a ten to twenty-minute video update will be posted by the end of January. After releasing the video update later this month, the team plans to do one more pre-release video. This final video will detail the full features of the simulation and provide a specific release date for Bluebird Simulation’s 757.  Along with the 757 news, Bluebird Simulations has announced that they’ve committed themselves to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 only for all subsequent releases.  ‍ Finally, Bluebird Simulations has announced that its Discord will be open later this year. This will support the 757 release and all the various free updates the team has planned. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lirfv2</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Rome Fiumicino V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lirfv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695fe8c0782a7ec1a7f24ed5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has just released Rome Fiumicino V2, their latest scenery package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This package offers an intricately detailed recreation of Rome Fiumicino Airport (LIRF), which is the eighth-busiest airport in Europe. The original version, Rome Fiumicino V1, was released in 2022, and now, three years later, V2 has been introduced, enhancing and expanding upon the features of the previous version. The airport opened its doors in 1961, originally featuring only two runways. A third runway was constructed shortly after during the 1960s. Over the years, the airport has undergone various improvements and expansions, including terminal upgrades and the construction of new terminals. Today, the airport welcomes almost 50 million passengers annually, with airlines such as ITA Airways, easyJet, and Neos operating flights to and from destinations around the globe. Rome Fiumicino V2 features high-quality 3D models and textures, modelled terminal interiors, an up-to-date ground layout, custom-designed jetways, immersive lighting, and more. The newly released Rome Fiumicino V2 by MK Studios is now available from Contrail for $21.41. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a340vip</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces A340 VIP Update for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a340vip"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696194174d46a75b24ded75e_a340vipcover.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently announced the development and imminent release of a free VIP package for their A340 Airliner, which was released in 2025 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024.  The new VIP configuration will include a brand-new passenger cabin with custom ambient sounds, adjustable light dimness, lighting controls via the flight attendant panel, customizable mood lighting, and custom cabin animations. The developers have not provided any concrete information regarding the release date, but it’s said to be “coming soon”. It will be a free update for A340 owners. The A340 Airliner is available in the MSFS Marketplace for $59.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vvtsv2</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Tan Son Nhat International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vvtsv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696265c69df71fd60f7609f8_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. DominicDesignTeam has just released the V2 version of Tan Son Nhat International Airport (VVTS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport, located in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, serves around 40 million passengers each year. The airport has its origins in the early 1920s when it began as a small airfield. Over the years, it has expanded and developed into what it is today. Currently, the airport features two parallel runways, three passenger terminals, a cargo terminal, and a 230-foot tall air traffic control tower. It serves as a hub for both Vietnam Airlines and Vietnam Air Services Company, as well as accommodating a variety of other airlines that provide flights from around the world. The V2 version of the scenery is packed with features, including PBR textures, dynamic lighting, realistic ground markings, custom jetways, and more. The newly released Tan Son Nhat International Airport by DominicDesignTeam is now available on SimMarket for approximately $26.17. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwslgb</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Announces Long Beach Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwslgb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6962d5220d13a767adaaec96_lgb1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. XWind Studios has recently announced the development of Long Beach Airport (KLGB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Greater Los Angeles with a yearly average of 4.1 million passengers. The airport was built on the same site as the world’s first flight school (created in 1919 by Earl S. Daugherty), after he managed to convince the city council to transform the structure into a municipal airport in 1923. The passenger terminal building was built in 1941, designed by William Horace Austin and Kenneth Smith Wing.  During its first few decades of commercial operations, the only destinations were Los Angeles, San Diego, and Catalina Island. It wasn’t until 1962 that the route network expanded to San Francisco, and eventually to Las Vegas and Oakland, with the advent of jet aircraft in the late 1960s. The early 1990s were disastrous for the airport’s traffic figures, with multiple airlines ending service to it. Further blows came in the early 2000s and mid-2010s, when American Airlines and Alaska Airlines ceased service, respectively. It’s served by Delta Airlines, Delta Connection, Hawaiian Airlines, and Southwest Airlines. ​ The developers claim to have spent the last nine months learning, researching, and working their way through the production of the scenery, which is approximately 70% complete and is expected to be released within the first quarter of the year. ​If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfdimd11101</id>
    <title>TFDi Design’s MD-11 MSFS 2024 Update to Release in 2 Days</title>
    <updated>2026-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfdimd11101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6962d86ea77b76278e485855_mcd1.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TFDi Design has recently published a trailer unveiling their long-awaited Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 compatibility update, which brings many new features, including Pratt &amp; Whitney engines, extended simulation, and more. The new update will bring a highly detailed cockpit with multiple customer options and subtle variances between variants, a meticulously modeled exterior with a strong emphasis on mechanical details, and a high-fidelity representation of the aircraft’s systems including all manual and automatic control modes and advanced flight management system/auto-flight systems, high-quality sounds, an interactive passenger cabin with working in-door controls, lavatories, overhead bins, window shades, and seat-back trays, and integration with many third party software and hardware options. The add-on is available in their store, starting from $69.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfdimd112024new</id>
    <title>TFDi Design Releases Major MD-11 Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfdimd112024new"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69657661180c6e8d2a5fefdb_md1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TFDi Design has recently released their long-awaited MD-11 update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024, bringing massive improvements to the aircraft’s 3D model, many bug fixes and tweaks, a new engine variant, and full compatibility with Microsoft’s latest flight simulator. The new update will brings a highly detailed cockpit with multiple customer options and subtle variances between variants, a meticulously modeled exterior with a strong emphasis on mechanical details, Pratt &amp; Whitney engines, and a high-fidelity representation of the aircraft’s systems including all manual and automatic control modes and advanced flight management system/auto-flight systems, high-quality sounds, an interactive passenger cabin with working in-door controls, lavatories, overhead bins, window shades, and seat-back trays, and integration with many third party software and hardware options. The complete changelog for the update follows below: The add-on is available in their store for $74.99 (either the passenger or freighter variant, with the option to purchase the other for an additional $9.99). The extended simulation package can be obtained for an additional $4.99.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a340107</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a340107"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69694761d21c8739ea43cbf2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released an update for their A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing the aircraft to version 1.0.7. This update includes the addition of the VIP variant of the A340 Airliner, along with various other changes, fixes, and improvements. The aircraft is now available at the iniBuilds Store, whereas it was previously only accessible through the Marketplace. The new VIP variant of the Airliner is packed with features, including a controllable Flight Attendant Panel, ambient multi-colour cabin lighting, and animated faucets, showers, and toilets. The latest version includes a comprehensive changelog, which can be found below: ‍ V1.0.7 SYSTEMS ⚙️ FIXED ND ETP not drawing on ND consistently   FIXED Electrical system behavior with BAT only on ground   FIXED AOC WX request showing invalid data when CPDLC source set to BeyondATC   FIXED MCDU ATSU/ATC page formatting refinements   FIXED Issues with along-track waypoints   FIXED ENG ECAM page, Engine 1 N2 vibration   FIXED Live PLD/ZFW too high on spawn   FIXED Long press of the CLR button not clearing the entire scratchpad   FIXED Brake fans operating with gear up   FIXED FPLN A page SID name missing above departure runway   FIXED PFD track diamond offset   FIXED AOC free-text send triggering incorrect received message reply   FIXED HDG bug missing in PFD   FIXED ACARS TO PERF message corrections   FIXED BRK fan pushbutton not displaying HOT   FIXED Direct to clearing flight plan causing WASM crash FIXED Replicable WASM crash when entering LAT/LONG coordinates into MCDU stored waypoints page FIXED Default camera views not aligned FIXED TO PERF invalid altimeter import values when using SYNC WX in inHg FIXED Side quickviews not aligned to 90 degrees from pilot POV FIXED TO PERF below MTOW limits shown on EFB but inconsistent after changing units FIXED Inserting DIR TO wiping flight plan ‍ ART 🎨 FIXED Passenger windows overly tinted   FIXED Horizontal stabilizer dihedral angle   FIXED Net texture inverted   FIXED Curtains clipping in forward galley   FIXED Wall ambient occlusion striping   FIXED Removed clickspot for crew rest door near 3L (Cabin and Freighter)   FIXED LOD issue with exit signs in the cabin   FIXED Icing effect transparency at ~50% intensity   FIXED Strobe effects missing physical double-flash   FIXED Clickspots for door 4L/R added to FA panel   FIXED Snow accumulation heavy-snow visibility threshold   FIXED Snow on wings texture shading   FIXED Cabin door handles inhibited in-flight   FIXED Pilot model not visible in exterior view FIXED VIP crew bunk floor gap FIXED VIP Door 4L/R curtain clickspot too large, preventing door handle access FIXED FC seat small screens incorrectly affected by color scheme routine ‍ EFB💻 FIXED Options not persisting across future simulator loads   FIXED GPS jamming option not saved   FAP Door status indications not matching actual door state ADDED Full FA Panel Simulation  ADDED VIP variant SimBrief profile ‍ SOUNDS🔊 FIXED Missing “five” altitude callout   FIXED GPWS audio tweaks   FIXED No smoking sign missing tone ADDED VIP cabin interactive sounds The latest update is available for all current owners or can be purchased through the Marketplace or the iniBuilds Store for approximately $59.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inihau</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Haugesund Airport Karmøy for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inihau"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696a9d883db36feaed6c5d55_ForumBannerSceneryENHD.thumb.png.a5eca005a8be4897627cf2ee58226c7f.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released Haugesund Airport, Karmøy (ENHD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Developed by Jakub Lukaszewski in collaboration with iniBuilds, the scenery is available now. Located on the island of Karmøy, Haugesund Airport is known for its challenging coastal approaches, rapidly changing weather, and proximity to the North Sea.  The scenery leans heavily into that identity, surrounding the airport with rocky terrain, detailed coastal formations, and authentic vegetation. On the ground, ENHD features custom ground textures across the entire airport, detailed terminal interiors, and a carefully recreated landside area, using bespoke models.  iniBuilds has also included fully custom night lighting, custom taxiway signage, Norwegian-specific airside clutter, static aircraft, and high-resolution textures, all optimised with Level of Detail (LODs), to maintain strong performance. A 10 cm CGL further enhances terrain fidelity around the airport. ENHD supports a mix of regional airline operations, offshore, and general aviation, making it well-suited to turboprops, helicopters, and short-haul jet flights alike.  Haugesund Airport (ENHD) for MSFS 2024 is available now via the iniBuilds store for for $13,36, and you can read more here. As always, we'll keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw73724</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases PMDG 737NG Sound Set for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw73724"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696ae8aceb3db727c924c883_borisng1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works has recently released their long-awaited sound set for the PMDG 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The set brings meticulously engineered sound captures from the cabin, engines, environment, and more. Recorded with state-of-the-art audio equipment from a real 737NG airplane, Boris Audio Works’ latest product promises a comprehensive audio package with a clear engine, cabin, fans, pack, ground roll, buttons, hydraulic pump sounds, and cabin chatter for extra immersion. ​ Furthermore, the package includes a headphone simulation with noise cancellation for those seeking a more realistic audio experience during their virtual journeys. ‍ The complete feature list follows below: ‍ ‍ MSFS 2024-only additions:  ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $10, requiring at least 108.38 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddradom24</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Warsaw-Radom Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddradom24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696aeeb4d221e2f6ed06f3ac_radom1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their freeware rendition of Warsaw-Radom Airport (EPRA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Radom, Poland, with an average of 112,610 passengers per year. It was built in early 1929 as a training facility for Poland’s first civilian pilot training school, and was eventually handed over to the military in 1932, which greatly expanded the facility by buying additional land and building hangars, barracks, and a shooting range. It then became a training facility for military pilots and paratroopers. As soon as World War 2 started, the base was heavily damaged by bombings, completely destroying the aircraft based there, some of the hangars, and forcing the crew to evacuate. The Germans took over the airport and used it to train and prepare their pilots for combat on the Eastern Front.  By the end of the conflict, the airport was once again heavily damaged and mined, requiring extra effort from the Polish Army to get it back into shape, which they have done rather promptly. They have been conducting pilot training sessions continuously since mid-1945. In mid-2006, Radom’s municipal administration established Port Lotniczy Radom S.A., with a hefty budget, to operate as a civilian airport. It wasn’t until the early 2010s that the necessary work was carried out to prepare the airport for such a task, though. In 2012, they bought Lodz’ airport's former terminal (disassembled) and reassembled it the following year, completing it a year later.  AirBaltic and Czech Airlines were the first to embrace the new airport with scheduled services, albeit quickly giving up after yielding suboptimal traffic numbers.  In the late 2010s, the administration decided to repurpose Radom as a low-cost airport, which initially drew strong opposition, especially given that the region already had two major airports (Modlin and Chopin).  The new terminal building was completed in 2022 and inaugurated in mid-2023. ​ It’s served by Enter Air, LOT Polish Airlines, Mavi Gök Airlines, and Wizz Air. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom 3D models, custom ground service equipment, performance-friendly optimization, an up-to-date ground layout, and much more. ​ It’s available for free on Contrail, requiring at least 2.41 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcs26r</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Outlines DCS World Roadmap for 2026 and Beyond</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcs26r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696c1b0419e861478f69cebc_In_Dev2%20(3).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has published a comprehensive set of newsletters, detailing what’s ahead for DCS World in 2026 and beyond, combining a forward-looking technical roadmap with a look back at recent campaign releases and what’s still to come. At the core of the 2026 plans is continued work on the long-awaited Dynamic Campaign, with development now heavily focused on strategic and tactical AI behaviour, ground force interactions, and the supporting user interface.  Eagle Dynamics says internal testing is already underway, across multiple maps and force compositions, with tools planned to allow players to interact with Air Tasking Orders, objectives, and mission data in far more depth than before. Another major pillar is the transition to the Vulkan API, described as being in late-stage development. The move is expected to unlock modern rendering features, such as improved frame generation support, expanded DLSS and FSR options, cockpit ray tracing, and better VRAM management.  Alongside this, further performance work, visual effects upgrades, and expanded multi-threading on the simulation side remain in progress. Beyond core engine work, Eagle Dynamics highlighted improvements to weather, explosions, and visual effects, a new navmesh system for better AI ground pathfinding, and a complete overhaul of ATC and radio communications. Mission State Save, introduced in 2025, will also continue to expand, with additional waypoint and AI behaviour data planned to be preserved between sessions. On the content side, 2026 will see continued support for existing aircraft and maps, completion of the Afghanistan and Iraq terrains, and progress on new modules, including the free Flaming Cliffs-level Su-25, alongside longer-term projects, such as the F-15C and F-35A.  The Pacific Theatre of Operations remains a major focus, with the F6F Hellcat, A6M5 Zero, a dedicated WWII Marianas map, and a large PTO assets pack, all forming the foundation for 1944-era operations. Eagle Dynamics also published an extensive campaign retrospective for 2025, highlighting a strong year for single-player content across multiple eras and aircraft, from WWII to modern combat. Looking ahead, a wide range of new training, historical, and story-driven campaigns are already in development for 2026 and beyond, as the ecosystem of third-party campaign creators continues to grow.  Further details are expected in upcoming updates. You can read Part 1 of the roadmap here, Part 2 here, and the Campaign Retrospective here.  As always, we’ll keep you updated. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asevs3</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Mt. Everest Airports Vol. 3 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asevs3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/696c232ca5c920998325a3b5_XlTYwNdEyiI-HD%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has released Mt. Everest Airports Vol. 3 – Namche Bazaar to Basecamp for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, continuing its high-altitude scenery series with a focus on helicopter and specialist mountain operations. The third volume centres on the Khumbu region of Nepal, featuring a detailed recreation of Syangboche Airstrip, the highest fixed-wing airstrip in the area, and the final runway before Everest.  From there, the package shifts its attention to rotary-wing flying, adding a highly detailed Namche helipad, 18 additional helipads, and an extensively modelled Everest Base Camp area. Aerosoft has placed particular emphasis on terrain and elevation accuracy, with upgraded data for the Khumbu Glacier and Icefall, improved valley terrain, and an enhanced Mount Everest summit.  Other features include custom villages, suspension bridges, and a “living world” layer with people and animals. Mt. Everest Airports Vol. 3 is now available from the Aerosoft Store for $13.60 (excluding VAT), with an official trailer also available on YouTube. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
