<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-09-19T18:32:54.811210+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barreirinhas</id>
    <title>flyt Simulations Releases Barreirinhas Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barreirinhas"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c8d3993c6b84b8d8850327_maranhao1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt Simulations has recently released their rendition of Barreirinhas Lençóis Maranhenses Regional Airport (SSRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Barreirinhas, Maranhão, Brazil. It opened only four years ago, replacing the older facility, which has been closed since then.  Easaero operates it, and there are no scheduled flights to Barreirinhas as of yet. It's mainly used for panoramic flights of the Lençóis Maranhenses National Park, one of the UNESCO World Heritage sites due to its exceptional beauty and overall uniqueness. There's nothing quite like it anywhere else in the world. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality 3D buildings, custom clutter, and much more. It's available in the Marketplace for $5.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol113</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates Volanta Flight Tracker to v1.13.0 </title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol113"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9870ee32b1aa1f00cdeb2_social.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated its popular Volanta Flight Tracker to v1.13.0, introducing a mix of new features, quality-of-life tweaks, and perhaps some rather unexpected additions.  At the centre of this update is support for MSFS 2024’s walk-around mode, which allows player movement outside of the cockpit to be tracked by Volanta, just like in the air. When stepping out of the cockpit to explore, you will now see your path logged as blue lines, recorded alongside your flights in purple. A new kind of aerocache has also been introduced, available only in walk-around mode. These hidden collectables are marked by orange circles on the map and, for now, are exclusive to Orbx’s new Jurassic World: Archipelago scenery, off the coast of Costa Rica.  That pack adds nine airfields, 12 helipads, and more than 550 square miles of terrain to explore, and yes, dinosaurs are included. Read more about it here. Elsewhere, Volanta gains a new map layer for points of interest (POIs), designed to highlight locations worth visiting, with more detailed map data. Flight cards have also been given themed styles, when departing or arriving at Jurassic World airports. Behind the scenes, Orbx has released an entirely new plugin for MSFS users. The installer has been simplified, bugs such as auto-selecting aircraft have been ironed out, and overall performance impact has been reduced. This plugin supports all the latest features of v.1.13.0, including the new avatar tracking. For those who would prefer to keep things strictly realistic, the fictional Jurassic content can be disabled via a toggle, available for all Volanta users, as of the latest patch. You can read the full changelog of v1.13.0 here: Enhancements (As of version 1.13.2, Premium is no longer required to disable fictional content) Volanta v1.13.0 is available now as a free update. The program can be downloaded free of charge from the Volanta website, supporting virtually every simulator out there, from DCS and Aerofly, to Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ft43se</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates F406 Caravan II &amp; T-33 Jet Trainer for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ft43se"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9dcd1196a963bc2883ece_image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has issued maintenance updates for two of its Microsoft Flight Simulator aircraft, with the F406 Caravan II moving to v1.0.4, and the T-33 Jet Trainer updated to v1.0.6. The focus is squarely on visual polish, small avionics corrections, and a targeted fix for the T-33 in MSFS 2024. On the F406, v1.0.4 tidies a number of long-standing visual quirks. Texture artefacts around the fuselage, windows, and exhausts have been corrected, clipping inside the exhausts has been resolved, and floating decals have been corrected. Missing pilot models now also appear as expected.  In the cockpit, orphaned text on the WT Garmin unit, plus background issues on OBS2 TO/FROM flags, have been cleaned up. As for the T-33, it has recieved a single change: a canopy LOD fix, specific to MSFS 2024, improving how the canopy displays at varying distances.  Both updates are available now via the iniManager. New customers can purchase both the F406 package and the T-33 for $27, sold separately on the iniBuilds store. For all the latest news and updates, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ktwsep</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Previews Katowice Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ktwsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9f9101e168e1067f557ca_548888828_18072700433159309_390960243165974347_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently shared some fresh previews of its in-development Katowice Airport (EPKT), showing steady progress on both the airside and landside.  The main terminal remains the headline focus, while Terminal A is also now underway, rounding out the passenger facilities. Around the ramps, work continues on Hangars 3 and 4, with the GA area also taking shape. The team also showcased development on cargo operations, including a dedicated high-loader for wide-body aircraft like the 777, 767, and 747. Furthermore, we get a preview of a new technical building in the parking area, a second radar installation, and rows of container-style office units. The on-site hotel is complete, with curbs and sidewalks in place, traffic islands and parking canopies installed, and custom signage appearing across the frontage. Spotter platforms, a local favourite, have also been built and positioned.  Lighting has advanced, with apron masts across the movement area, red obstruction lights on key structures, and custom streetlamps in the car parks, while access roads to the GA hangar, Hangar 3, and Hangar 4 are also finished. Interior terminal work now includes custom information boards, and ground equipment is being populated at each stand. LOD optimisation is progressing in parallel, to keep frames steady. For more details, visit Drzewiecki Design’s Instagram page. For all the latest news and updates, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b25jah</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Announces B-25J Mitchell for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b25jah"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cabea35455feadf03b5fca_547337499_1465656791594562_7642901538470120385_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aeroplane Heaven has confirmed its next project for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the B-25J Mitchell. Following the Lancaster, the developer is building the base J model, with the 8-gun nose “strafer”, also in scope. No release window has been given, with the team only saying “soon”. Platform plans are clear for the first step. The aircraft is coming to MSFS 2020 for now, with a console release "more than likely", on Xbox. Aeroplane Heaven adds that this project focuses solely on the B-25J, so do not expect other Mitchell variants at launch. The B-25J was the final production model of the Mitchell, blending traits of the earlier B-25D and B-25H, into what became its most formidable form. Built in Kansas City, the J rolled off the line in huge numbers, over 4,300 airframes, making it the most produced of all Mitchell variants.  While it was originally fitted with a glass nose, many were quickly adapted with a solid “strafer” nose (J2), crammed with forward-facing guns, with this variant also in development by Aeroplane Heaven. In fact, most of its 14–18 machine guns pointed ahead, including those from the dorsal turret, mounted further forward than on earlier models. The Royal Air Force operated 316 of them under the name Mitchell III, cementing the J’s reputation as both a bomber, and a rugged gun platform, in the closing years of the war. Threshold will keep you updated on all the latest regarding Aeroplane Heaven! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdc172</id>
    <title>Carenado Teases Classic Cessna 172 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdc172"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68caccbc5160e2aae8006100_547907150_1205990311568770_2091384684421266241_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has just teased their next aircraft release, hinting at a classic, steam-gauge Cessna 172.  The screenshot shows a polished, early-production airframe, at golden hour, captioned “Carenado 172 Oneseventytwo”, which strongly suggests a recreation of an early 172 model, rather than a later, Skyhawk-branded airframe. Carenado added that they hope we can “enjoy it in a couple of days”, though there is no firm date or feature list yet. From the cues on show, this looks like the original 172 that debuted in the 1950s. That aircraft evolved from the Cessna 170B, with tricycle landing gear. If confirmed, it will sit apart from the default 172S, found in MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024.  The modern Skyhawk uses a 180-horsepower, fuel-injected Lycoming IO-360, carries the aerodynamic refinements of later production, and typically tops out at 30 degrees of flap. The early 172 ran a carburetted Continental O-300 six-cylinder engine, offered up to 40 degrees of flap for short-field work, and is often noted for friendly, low-speed handling. Carenado has not shared pricing or platform details yet, but their aircraft usually arrive via the in-sim Marketplace.  Threshold will keep you updated on all the latest. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsptds</id>
    <title>Black Square Updates Piston and Turbine Duke, Adds MSFS 2024 Support</title>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsptds"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68caf240acef932422703b09_black-square-turbine-duke-msfs-13_1600x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has rolled out v0.1.2 for both the Piston Duke and Turbine Duke, bringing full MSFS 2024 compatibility, a raft of new interactions, and a long list of fixes. The headline addition is an expanded pre-flight walk-around for 2024, complete with collision models and clickspots for chocks, pitot covers, doors, and baggage bays. Both aircraft gain a new headphone simulation, with adjustable attenuation, refreshed interior lighting, new magnetic compass effects, GTNxi 750/650 bezels, support for TDS GTNxi Advanced Crossfill, and quality-of-life tweaks across the tablet, legacy radios, and animations.  Black Square has also implemented a workaround for MSFS 2024’s dynamic registration quirk, restored cockpit precipitation sounds, improved oxygen logic in pressurised scenarios, and provided a batch of avionics and systems fixes. The Turbine Duke receives further love, with a smoother prop governor model, an “Instant Beta on Touchdown” option for reliable beta entry after landing, new engine-driven fuel pump failure logic, faster torque indication changes, and additional polish to the cabin visualiser.  The Piston Duke received new oil-pump failure and engine-seizing physics, along with custom toe-brake animations, that play nicely with the parking brake. Across both packages, numerous niggles have been addressed, from reversed glideslope sensing on the copilot side to tablet refresh delays to oddities in heater blower behaviour on hot days, aiming for cleaner ops in both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Updates and corresponding changelogs are available through the Contrail app. New customers can purchase both aircraft for $50.89 separately, or together in a bundle, for $72.10, also through Contrail. For all the latest in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini100</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Impulse 100 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini100"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc254362a96576bcc40424_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has announced its latest upcoming addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the Impulse 100. Nicknamed the “Pocket Rocket”, it is a high-performance aircraft known for impressive speed and sharp handling. The addon will feature a highly accurate 3D model, a detailed electrical system, realistic lighting, an accurate simulation of the Allison 250-C20R engine, a custom-designed fuel system, custom system simulations, and much more. While a specific release date has not been announced, the team states that it is coming soon. The store page for the aircraft is now live and reveals that it will be priced at $16.37. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mig29e</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Releases MiG-29A Early Access</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mig29e"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc277c0a88b80202d63ea9_546152110_1171185158390354_2885748911819553500_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. The long-awaited MiG-29A Fulcrum has finally been released in early access form! One of the most popular fighter jets of all time, with over 1,600 units built, has been brought to DCS by Eagle Dynamics. Developed by Mikoyan and Gurevich Design Bureau during the 1970s, along with the Sukhoi Su-27, it was built to oppose the American F-15 and F-16. Originally designed as an air superiority fighter, the Fulcrum has slowly transitioned to a multirole fighter throughout its service life, with many of them being retrofitted to use air-to-surface and precision munitions. Today, the MiG-29 is used by 25 air forces around the globe. The Eagle Dynamics’ rendition of this fighter jet features a fully interactive cockpit based on 3D scanning and photogrammetry, a highly detailed external and pilot model, high-fidelity aircraft systems, fully-developed navigation system with multiple modes (POINT-TO-POINT, RETURN, LANDING, TRAFFIC RE-ENTRY), realistic modelling of RWR, flare dispenser system, FIre Control Radar, basic IFF (Identity Friend or Foe), Early Access Guide, Training Missions, as well as a full russian cockpit, with an option for a cockpit and technical inscriptions in English. At the final release, the module will also feature Ground Control Intercept (GCI) command system, a fully modelled IFF, a complete flight manual, a campaign by Eagle Dynamics, and a larger number of liveries and missions. ‍ The full feature list is as follows: The MiG-29A Fulcrum module is currently on an Early Access sale, and is available for purchase at the DCS E-Shop for $63.99, with the price increasing to $79.99 after the sale’s end (keep in mind that this module is incompatible with the Steam version of DCS!), and requires at least 2.64GB of free disk space. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b17sep</id>
    <title>MicroProse Previews B-17 Flying Fortress for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b17sep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc3cebf03642f58b1e0490_microprose-msfs-b-17-g-the-queen-02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse is bringing one of aviation’s most legendary aircraft to Microsoft Flight Simulator, and recently shared a new update on the project. The B-17 Flying Fortress is now deep in development, for both MSFS 2020 and 2024. A trailer shared on YouTube gives us a closer look at the project, which is being built in partnership with Hangar Thirteen and the 100th Bomb Group Foundation. The aircraft is part of MicroProse’s Heritage Valor Collection, a series focused on recreating iconic warbirds, with the highest possible fidelity. According to MicroProse, the B-17 will feature a detailed flight model, authentic sound recordings from surviving aircraft, and hand-crafted 4K PBR textures, that show every rivet, scuff, and patch of wear. The team is also promising a faithful recreation of the bomber’s complex systems, from electrical power, to crew operations, all designed to immerse simmers in what it was like to fly one of these heavy bombers, as close as possible. For many, the B-17 needs little introduction. It was the backbone of the USAAF’s daylight bombing campaign over Europe, famed for both its firepower, and durability. Now, MicroProse wants to capture that same spirit in the virtual skies, bringing the Flying Fortress back to life, for a new generation to enjoy. The project is still in development, with no firm release date yet, but MicroProse has confirmed it will be available through the in-sim Marketplace, once complete. For more information about the project, you can visit this link. Threshold will keep you updated on MicroProse’s B-17! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baysim-scenery-releases-grand-teton-national-park-for-msfs-2024</id>
    <title>Baysim Scenery Releases Grand Teton National Park for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baysim-scenery-releases-grand-teton-national-park-for-msfs-2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc76c414bfbb426c7ed67d_365521_Screenshot_390-1%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Baysim Scenery has released a native build of its Grand Teton National Park package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a hand-crafted recreation, of one of the United States’ most dramatic mountain ranges.  Centred on Jenny Lake, the update adds far denser detail across the visitor hub and shoreline, with bespoke models, for the visitor centre, store, trail bridges, park signage, boat docks, and the Jenny Lake Lodge entry, plus improved parking layouts, lighting, and ground clutter, for a lived-in feel. Expect more than 100 custom objects, dozens of unique landmarks, and hundreds of animated visitors, spread around the car parks, trails, and piers. The docks at the south and west shores feature ferries and small craft, the Cottonwood Creek crossings are modelled, and night effects are included after dusk.  The scenery is confirmed compatible with MSFS 2024 SU3, and is designed to slot neatly into your bush-flying or sightseeing routes, across Wyoming’s 40-mile Teton Range. As always, the full feature list follows below: ‍ Scenery Features Baysim Scenery's Grand Teton National Park is available now on simMarket, for $13.25, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssu27</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Previews Super27 Expansion for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssu27"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cc92651f76e09c34cd7489_S27-Focus1-header.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlightSim Studio has recently previewed its upcoming Super27 expansion for the Boeing 727, building upon the original base package, with more modern equipment and several new additions. The Super27 expansion was first announced back in June. Since then, the team has posted two detailed updates, titled "Focus #1" and "Focus #2", that sketch a clear picture of what this retrofit will bring to the table. The first post set the scene with visuals and core changes. The 727 receives the real-world Super 27 treatment: uprated JT8D-217C pod engines, with clamshell reversers, plus a centre JT8D-17A upgrade. They are larger, quieter, and give the jet its distinctive Super27 silhouette. New operator liveries are included for both freighter and passenger variants, and you can adapt existing paints easily, as the exterior textures are largely unchanged, beyond of course, the new powerplants. Inside the cockpit, the flight engineer’s fuel gauges move to digital readouts, according to the new avionics layout. A combined digital VSI, with integrated TCAS, arrives, paired with a new transponder.  There is also an Apollo MX20 moving map, that can replace the weather-radar dummy.  The headline tease is a retrofitted Collins EFIS, EADI and EHSI, with matching control panels, plus an accompanying autopilot, and VNAV (descent) support. The EFIS is optional, and can be toggled on the clipboard, for those who prefer the classic six-pack. The second post dives deeper. That TCAS-equipped VSI and its transponder can be enabled in the base 727, once the Super27 is installed. An auto-spoiler arm feature is also included in the upcoming package. Radio-nav fans get dual DME recievers, enabling proper cross-bearing fixes, without a map. The EFIS fit is specified as a Rockwell Collins EFIS-86C. The EADI provides flight-director commands, mode annunciations, speed cues, and deviation scales. The EHSI, meanwhile, offers a compass rose, expanded, and map-with-route views, with ranges up to 600 NM, and selectable data such as wind and groundspeed. Tying it together is a Collins APS-85 autopilot, available with the EFIS, and dual GNS-XLS FMS. Mode selection sits on the glareshield, with sensible fallbacks, to roll hold and vertical speed. Lateral capability runs from heading and NAV tracking to CAT II approaches. Vertically, expect pitch and VS modes, SPEED, with IAS/Mach logic, altitude hold and capture, VNAV path following from the FMS, and a yoke-triggered go-around mode.  The Super27 expansion is an add-on to the existing 727. You need the base package, and the expansion covers passenger and freighter variants you already own. FlightSim Studio furthermore says video previews are imminent. A release window has not been given. For the full details, visit this link, for Focus #1, or this link, for Focus #2. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgbelzonte</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Belo Horizonte International Airport v2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgbelzonte"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ccd6a469d3072fda647ce0_belzonte1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Brazil Land Games recently previewed their progress on their upcoming Belo Horizonte/Confins Tancredo Neves International Airport (SBCF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil, with a yearly average of 12.3 million passengers. It was built in the early 1980s by Infraero, a state-owned airport management company. At the time, the airport’s main purpose was to help lessen the congestion at Pampulha Airport, which used to be Belo Horizonte’s only airport. It was operating at 120% of its capacity, with no possibility of expansion. Its slightly inconvenient location did not help with the passenger figures at first: while they assumed it would hit the two million passenger mark by 1990, that only happened 22 years after its inauguration. Pampulha Airport was still fairly more convenient for the locals. It wasn’t until 2005 that the government decided to “nerf” Pampulha with a restriction: planes with more than 50 seats could not operate there anymore, forcing it to become a regional-only airport. Over 130 flights were transferred to Confins that year, and the traffic figures went from 300,000 to 3 million passengers in the blink of an eye. The government did try its best to mitigate the accessibility issues by improving the highway that links the city to the airport, significantly reducing the time needed to reach the airport.  A new terminal—Terminal 2—was built in 2015, 31 years after Terminal 1’s inauguration. The new infrastructure can handle up to 22 million passengers annually, giving SBCF some breathing room for many years. It’s a hub for Azul Linhas Aéreas and Gol Transportes Aéreos. Copa Airlines, Latam Brasil, Latam Chile, Sky Airline, and TAP Air Portugal also serve it. The scenery promises an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom ground service equipment, high-detail buildings, custom jetways, a custom terminal interior, and more. ‍ There’s no information regarding availability and pricing yet. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/c172cr</id>
    <title>Carenado Releases Cessna 172 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/c172cr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cadf31b0d19b05605aa8e7_548422664_1206653604835774_5649167629880773778_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following last week’s teasers, Carenado has released its classic, steam-gauge Cessna 172, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Carenado's rendition models the very original, early-production lineage from 1956, which pre-dates the modern Skyhawk.  Expect a cabin full of round dials, a period interior, and short-field friendly flap travel, which sets it apart from the default 172S in MSFS 2024. The aircraft comes in several variants, including with and without wheel covers. If you enjoy steam gauges, pattern work, and low-and-slow sightseeing, this looks like a nice addition. Carenado’s classic Cessna 172 is available on the MSFS 2024 Marketplace, for $14.99. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwbpdc</id>
    <title>WINWING Releases Boeing-Style EFIS Panels: 3N PDC &amp; 3M PDC Now Available</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwbpdc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cd76901b39b38b3b7854b1_QmT9QWUFUXB86692sPgCZML2g2EbB6fF7WEC1qQS5WHqHp.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Winwing’s new 3N PDC and 3M PDC panels are now available to buy, bringing a new, Boeing-style EFIS to your desktop.  They slot neatly on either side of the already released PAP 3 Autopilot Panel, for a full 737-style glareshield, and can also be used standalone. The product range has been split into two variants, to mirror the real aircraft: The 3N PDC covers the 737 NG, meaning it has no Vertical Situation Display button, as well as a labelled range scale, with eight detents on a 210-degree selector, numerical markings, and the expected mode and baro interactions. Meanwhile, the 3M PDC (737 MAX-style) features a dedicated VSD button, a detent-free 360° encoder, with simple minus/plus direction marks, and revised labelling, to match the IRL MAX. Both products ship with left and right glare shields in the box, allowing you to swap between captain and first officer layouts. Additionally, both support the multi-panel backlight sync feature, through SimAppPro.  Furthermore, the centre (CTR) push switch is correctly inhibited in PLN mode, matching the real limitation. You’ll get full-structure moulded faces, with sharp 3D detailing, individual switches for MINS RST, BARO STD, CTR, and TFC, plus authentic auto-reset logic on MINS and BARO selectors. Each unit connects over its own USB and can be used standalone, paired together NG/MAX, or integrated with the PAP3 autopilot panel, for a complete Boeing-style glareshield. As for compatibility, Winwing lists native or active development support. Included for MSFS 2020/2024 are; the PMDG 737, 777, Asobo/Working Title 747 and 787, and the iFly 737 MAX. On the X-Plane-side, Winwing so far supports the Zibo 737, Laminar 737-800 &amp; 747-400, and FlightFactor 777.  Further aircraft, including classic jets, like the FSS 727-200 Advanced, and Aeroplane Heaven 707, are flagged as upcoming.  The products went live earlier today, and global listings are live with limited stock, with regional pricing being published as follows, for a single unit: Note that regional sites may adjust prices for exchange rates, and shipping or tax may apply to the global store. For all your 737 adventures, these PDCs complete the picture, modelling the respective differences between the NG and MAX, standalone or in combination with the PAP3 MCP. You can find them both on the Winwing store, available together in a combo for $175.00, or sold separately, for $87.50. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t320ra</id>
    <title>ToLiss Announces Airbus A320ceo Release Date</title>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t320ra"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68cd9c4b874d424ab014fe5b_TOPOST---a320-2025-09-1910_09%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After releasing the A320neo for X-Plane in 2023, ToLiss has announced that the much-loved A320ceo will soon join the line-up, coming for X-Plane 12 next Friday, as an expansion package. First launched in the mid-1980s and entering service with Air France in 1988, the A320ceo was revolutionary for introducing all-digital, fly-by-wire controls to the airliner market. The family grew to include the A318, A319, and A321, and became a workhorse for airlines across the globe. The ToLiss A320ceo will come with both the CFM56-5B4 and IAE V2527-A5 powerplants, and will require the ToLiss A320neo base package to run. ToLiss has confirmed that pre-release copies of the A320ceo expansion will be going out to streamers and reviewers very soon, so expect full previews, walkthroughs, and performance showcases in the coming days. ToLiss hasn’t confirmed which platforms it will release on just yet, but going by past launches, you can expect to see it available through the X-Plane.org Store, Aerosoft , and Simmarket. For the full post, visit this link. The ToLiss A320ceo is releasing Friday, Sep. 26. The expansion will be priced at $29.95.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
