<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-08-25T18:28:25.360398+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc12ca</id>
    <title>Carenado Publishes PC-12 Screenshots</title>
    <updated>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc12ca" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62e8ae7cfa7f39830db544f5_292071041_5216927795050659_1988621114253456010_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="66362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has recently showcased various screenshots of their upcoming visual rendition of the Pilatus PC-12 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This comes after a period of tight-lipped silence from the developers. Carenado did express an apologetic state, as they have experienced unexpected delays in the release of this aircraft to the public. They do hope to surpass these setbacks and move forward with the release aircraft. In the screenshots posted to their Facebook page, they showcased working GTNXi by TDS, and the in-house EX600 Suite. With these operational, Carenado hopes to move forward with development and an eventual release. Be sure to follow Threshold for more updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t208gc</id>
    <title>Thranda Releases Free Expansion Pack for C208 Grand Caravan</title>
    <updated>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t208gc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62eb32157b64ff81adee4fa2_unknown.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="277119"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Last week, developer Thranda announced via the X-Plane forum the release of a new expansion pack for its C208 and C208B Grand Caravan. The best part: this pack is completely free and can be downloaded from the X-Plane.org store! The feedback on the forum is very positive. Users seem to be delighted with this free and well-developed initiative. But what exactly does this pack contain? First of all a seaplane version of the Grand Caravan equipped with floats. ‍ For the landplane version, the pack offers tundra tires and mud flaps, enabling operations in rough terrains. The package also offers changes to the interior of the aircraft such as an integrated G1000. The seats will also be removable via presets, allowing the aircraft to serve either as a passenger or cargo plane. These features will be available for both the amphibious and landplane models. Currently, users who already purchased the plane can download the expansion pack together with the new version. Those who are looking to pick up the aircraft can purchase it on the X-Plane.org store for $44.95, ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jff28u</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker F28 Fellowship Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jff28u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ec9b05681fa0dbd328e67a_1000_Air_France_srxkHMBHR.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="89426"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer Just Flight published a brief update for its upcoming Fokker F28 Fellowship for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The short blog focused on the work being done on the aircraft’s interior modeling/texturing and cockpit lighting. Announced just over a year ago, Just Flight’s Fokker F28 has seen extensive work being done on it over the past few months. Since the last update, the developers have been making “extensive upgrades to the cockpit”. Due to the great variations in cockpit design that exist between the F28 variants operated by different airlines, the team chose to base their design on the real F28 they visited in Fokker Technical College. With the layout finalized, the developers are working to improve the visual fidelity of the cockpit while testers, including  “F28 flight, engineering, and training crew”, are checking and rechecking every detail. Apart from cockpit modeling, progress has also been made in cockpit lighting. Just Flight has included a few pictures in the update to showcase the night lighting of the Fokker’s instruments, annunciator, and warning lights. Currently, Just Flight is yet to announce the release date and pricing of the aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Shout out to Joe from the official Threshold Discord server for the news scoop. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniadu</id>
    <title>iniScene Publishes August Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniadu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f09df44826b824a9cb2609_Screen%20Shot%202022-08-08%20at%201.23.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2821738"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer iniScene published its development update for the month of August. The brief blog touched upon the team’s plan for the coming weeks and unveiled two new sceneries - Ibiza Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator (LEIB) and Buffalo Airport (KBUF) for X-Plane. 	Starting off the update, the developer announced Ibiza Airport for MSFS and confirmed that the scenery will be available for purchase later this month. Though the team is yet to release further details on the airport, it can be seen from the trailer that it will feature everything from terminal interiors and PBR textures to animated vegetation and custom night lighting. ‍ 	Apart from Ibiza, the developer also announced Buffalo Airport for X-Plane. The scenery will feature hand-made ground polygons, realistic ground equipment, and dynamic lighting, and high quality textures. iniScene confirmed that the airport will be fully compatible with upcoming X-Plane 12 and teased that a few more X-Plane scenarios will be released later this year.  Currently, the developers are yet to announce a firm release date for either Ibiza or Buffalo airport. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Shout out to MJ from the official Threshold Discord for the news scoop.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfosfd</id>
    <title>ShortFinal Design Releases KSFO Definitive for XP11</title>
    <updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfosfd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f09d0e1ca43f55577d226d_a350_xp11%20-%202022-08-04%2013.25.45.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="238302"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Known developer for X-Plane 11, ShortFinal Design (aka MisterX6) has released his long-awaited KSFO Definitive Project for X-Plane 11. With many updates from the previous rendition, this visual rendition of San Francisco International impresses one and all, with new techniques used by the developer. MisterX6 released his first and only freeware rendition of KSFO back in 2015, and it underwent updates till he moved to payware projects. Since then, the San Francisco area received no love from developers, till SFD announced he was revisiting the area and had started from scratch on the project. This rendition has a vast inclusion list that has been provided. Starting off, the usage of SAM for jetways and airport operations has been used to add realism and life to the airport. The airport layout shipped is the current layout of KSFO as of 2022. Various animations of airport vehicles, workers, and passengers have also been included. The usage of PBR textures is present throughout the scenery package. For the complete feature list, you can view it on the X-Plane.Org Store This rendition of KSFO is now available on the .Org Store and sells for $26.95. If you are interested in other packages developed by ShortFinal Design, you can view his payware catalog on the .Org Store as well. If you are interested in his freeware catalog, you can have a look over on his forum page.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc12ca2</id>
    <title>Carenado Finishes PC12 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc12ca2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f68cc569f22508515e2486_298795014_5315779201832184_7004121334989087429_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="303487"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has announced that development work and testing are complete on their upcoming PC12, meaning that it is now ready to fly under the command of virtual pilots! The aircraft has been a long-awaited addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator and from what we can see visually in the teasers, it looks stunning.  In a recent press release on their Facebook page, the developers said: “dear friends, we are very happy to inform you that the PC12 project was finished and handed over to Microsoft to be uploaded to the simulator marketplace, Microsoft recently told us that this will happen in the first days of September, we appreciate all the shows of support and understanding setbacks in the development of this project, thank you all very much and we hope you have fun with this wonderful plane!” Judging by the post, it looks like fans of Carenado and the PC12 can expect to take off for the first time in the Pilatus early in September.  Though the developers are yet to announce a precise release date for the PC12, it is certain that we only have a few more weeks to wait! Threshold will keep you updated on any news regarding the aircraft. For now, check out a previous article on the PC12  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inikbuf</id>
    <title>iniScene release Buffalo Niagara KBUF scenery for X-Plane 11 </title>
    <updated>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inikbuf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f68e8e7904d06ceed85d21_22_24069982-7921-4e4f-b57a-28f78a2b1b40.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="555864"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has released its anticipated Buffalo Niagara scenery for X-plane 11. KBUF is located in Buffalo New York, the airport serves Buffalo and the surrounding area, as well as the southern golden horseshoe region of Ontario Canada. Interestingly KBUF is the third busiest airport in New York. It serves as a hub for; United Airlines, American Airlines, Delta, Jet Blue, and various other airlines on top of being a relatively large hub for FedEx Express and UPS.  The developers have teased that the scenery boasts  You can find the full feature list for KBUF here Currently, Buffalo Niagara Airport is available for the reasonable price of £16.99 on the iniScene Store. The developers recommend users to have at least 2.94GB of free space on their hard drives to successfully install the product. Be sure to follow Threshold for more updates on the latest scenery and aircraft for MSFS and X-plane 11.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inkadl</id>
    <title>IniBuilds Announces Dallas Love Field for MSFS and Partnership with iBlueYonder</title>
    <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inkadl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f9e09e2ad68d9da820e3ad_unknown.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="982644"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IniBuilds has announced its partnership with iBlueYonderpour to develop its upcoming Dallas Love Field (KDAL) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. After complimenting the CEO of iBlueYonder, Bill Womack, IniBuilds revealed that it has already started development on KDAL. However, neither developers have disclosed any details on either the scenery or the partnership. Though IniBuilds is well known within the community, iBlueYonder may be a less familiar face to some. In reality however, iBlueYonder is very experienced in the creation of sceneries for P3D, X-Plane, FSX, and MSFS. More details on the developers can be found here. But why choose KDAL? Though Lovefield is often overshadowed by Fort Worth, it is located much closer to Dallas city center and serves as a main hub for Southwest Airlines, a well-known low cost airline that operates an all 737 fleet. Southwest, Delta and Alaska also flies a few flights to select destinations per day. ‍ The IniBuilds forum post ends with the announcement of a trailer about this airport that will be available soon. Currently no release date or pricing had been disclosed. Threshold will keep you updated on this front.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/v35msf</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Beechcraft Bonanza V35 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/v35msf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ff1dba33c3ef3001b9e82c_Screen%20Shot%202022-08-19%20at%201.20.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3575534"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, the developers of Microsoft Flight Simulator announced the release of its newest aircraft - Beechcraft Bonanza V35.  The Bonanza, developed by Carenado and published in partnership with Microsoft, is the third aircraft in MSFS’s new Famous Flyers series. The plane is powered by a 6-cylinder Continental IO-520B piston engine and has a 900 mile maximum range. It also features an iconic V-shaped tail that works as “a hybrid of a rudder and an elevator”. Unfortunately, neither Carenado or Microsoft released a feature list for the Bonanza. However, a trailer is available to those who are trying to catch a glimpse of what the aircraft has to offer. Currently, the V35 can be bought in the ingame Marketplace for $14.99 USD. Microsoft has teased that the next aircrafts of the Famous Flyers series will be coming soon. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Shout to themsmyshoes from the Official Threshold Discord for the news scoop. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd738</id>
    <title>PMDG 737-800NG at “Top of descent”</title>
    <updated>2022-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd738" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6302b517d3a4b32950df5104_Screen%20Shot%202022-08-21%20at%205.43.15%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1393334"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG, developer of the popular 737 series add-ons for P3D and MSFS, has announced that the next aircraft of their 737 series, the -800, for Microsoft Flight Simulator is at the “top of descent”. Adding to this latest update from the team, the team also revealed a host of new enhancements for their current series of aircraft. The official post can be read over on the PMDG forums. Firstly, PMDG teased that they have handed what they believe to be the final build before the release of the 737-800 over to their testing team and eagerly await their testing feedback. This is a promising sign for a release in the very near future. PMDG has also disclosed they are hoping to release it in a window between the 23rd of August and the 31st of August. The 737-800 package will contain 4 airframe types; the 737-800 passenger airliner, the BBJ2, the 737-800 BCF, and the 737-800 BDSF.  PMDG has also discussed that new sun visors will be added to their current line of 737 aircraft which will add to the immersion. On top of this, the developers added that the functionality for the cockpit map lights to move around, a feature common in most MSFS aircrafts that have left many disappointed up to now. To read the full changelog of updated features and improvements you can take a look at the PMDG forums.  Finally, the developers released a video showcasing the all-new light and sun visor features. Check it out here. Shoutout to RCFLYER86 from the official Threshold Discord server for bringing this news to our attention.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rjprfs</id>
    <title>RJ Professional by Just Flight Simulation for MSFS in development</title>
    <updated>2022-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rjprfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6303fcd2b01f2b88d62ede9b_Capture.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="273376"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After the great success of the B-146 Professional for x-plane 11, the developers of Just Flight have set themselves a new challenge: As in real life, they want to develop the 146 Professional into the RJ Professional, a new range that will be exclusively available for MSFS. Just Flight are excited to announce that they are working on the RJ professional range which will include 3 variants: The RJ70, the RJ85 and the RJ100. Variants exclusively available for MSFS. ‍ If we look at the historical context of aviation, the RJ range, derived from the 146 range from 1993 onwards (1988 for the RJ100). We can note improvements made from this date, such as the introduction of an EFIS cockpit with digital displays replacing the ADI, HSI and engine instrumentation present on the 146. ‍ This is exactly what Just Flight is putting forward in the development of the RJ Professional, the same changes are being implemented. There have been many other changes between the 146 and the RJ, both in real life and in the simulation world with Just Flight indicating these changes on the aircraft web page. ‍ ‍ ‍ On the 15th of August, Just Flight published development updates with images available of this future product, both cockpit and exterior model images are seen, without telling us much more. They simply inform us that work is still in progress, that pictures are available and that they will keep us informed of future updates. But for the moment, there is no official release date for this aircraft. ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thrstat</id>
    <title>Thranda reveals U206G Stationair in developement</title>
    <updated>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thrstat" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63051575033de8e1dbbd14ac_2116242128_Thranda_U206G-2022-08-1712_36_54PM.thumb.jpg.9e8cdc52d8aea1c08d1d99730144a82f.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="72365"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular aircraft developer Thranda, best known for their dynamic generation series of aircraft featuring the ever popular Pilatus PC6 and the DHC-2 to name but a few, have announced their next product for this line is the Cessna U206G stationair!  The aircraft will feature all the trimmings we have come to expect from Thranda’s dynamic generation series. It will incorporate the usual texture and paint editing tools along with cockpit panel customization and an array of extra options both inside and out providing you with everything you will need to fulfill your mission, whatever it may be. In a forum post online, Thranda have announced the project and provided a variety of screenshots from throughout the development process and some from what seems to be at a close to completed stage.  Although a release date is not provided by the developer, they have encouraged everyone to “stay tuned for release” hinting a release in the very near future is possible. Here at Threshold we will be sure to bring you any updates on release information.     ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pa24pi</id>
    <title>InDepthSimulations Piper Comanche 250 development update</title>
    <updated>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pa24pi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/630539197e66ee757d525825_pa24_-_2022-07-12_15.02.19.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="339180"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. InDepthSimulations have provided fans with an update in the development of their PA-24 Comanche 250 for X-plane 11. Exclusive news to threshold was provided by the lead developer from IDS around the future of the comanche project and whats to be expected!  The comanche 250 first flew in 1956 and production ceased in 1972 with just under 5,000 of the aircraft rolled off the production line. The comanche is still ever popular to this day and you can find them flying in many countries. Never before in X-plane 11 has the Comanche 250 been developed in such detail and its sure to be an impressive aircraft when it is finished.  Progress is going well on the Comanche with release planned for Q4 2022. We can see from previews supplied by InDepthSimulations that the modelling and texture work is progressing nicely.  ‍ The IDS comanche 250 will boast options for a modern avionics suite using the RSG G5 and G500, but if this isn't to your liking it will also have the option to use a standard 6 pack "steam gauge" setup.  ‍ Although still on target, development of the Comanche 250 has slowed slightly due to a small team, the developer has encouraged anyone who may be interested in joining up to assist in pushing this beautiful aircraft across the line to contact them through Discord ‍ Threshold will keep you updated on developments with the IDS comanche as it progresses closer to the finish line! </summary>
    <published>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/yaknor</id>
    <title>Northern Sky studio release Yakutat Airport</title>
    <updated>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/yaknor" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/630540e6eb659c78131a71c0_62fee0df7e2d2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1418657"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Northern Sky studio have released their all new Yakutat scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Yakutat airport is located in southern Alaska, It is an incredibly important airport for the area. Alaska airlines operate regular flights in and out of the field in both passenger and cargo Boeing 737-700 aircraft.  The location of the field is ideal for exploring Alaska or for short passenger flight operations to areas such as Juneau or Cordova. Yakutat also played a vital role in World War 2 as a landing field for aircraft between Washington State and Elmendorf Air Force Base according to ORBX.  ‍ ‍ A popular general aviation airport, the only airliner traffic seen regularly at Yakutat are Alaska Airlines 737-700's.  The scenery features:  This stunning scenery is available for only $11.98 from Orbx  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inibiz</id>
    <title>iniScene Release LEIB Ibiza Scenery for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inibiz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63065a9fc5d5e424ddd237c2_3.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2415001"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniScene has released their all new Ibiza scenery for Microsoft flight simulator. Once a military airport during the civil war, now a party haven that sees Europeans flock in their thousands for the time of their lives, Ibiza is one of the most incredible islands in the Beleric Sea. iniScene have released an outstanding version of LEIB for MSFS boasting some incredible features such as; This scenery is perfect for those who enjoy; Ryanair, Jet2 or Easyjet style operations, around europe in their flight sim. The scenery downloads at a reasonable 1.58GB and can be purchased from the iniBuilds website for £13.49 GBP. </summary>
    <published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg78</id>
    <title>PMDG Release 737-800NG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg78" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6306a7d02ca78ec9529b05bf_PMDG_NG38_screenshots4__18100.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="91333"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Popular aircraft developer PMDG have released their much anticipated Boeing 737-800NG for MSFS to complete their 737 collection which now features the -600, -700 and -800! The release of the 737-800 will no doubt be just as popular as the previous two models.  The 737-800 is one of the most successful aircraft to ever be built and is without a doubt the most successful aircraft ever produced by Boeing. The PMDG 737-800 features multiple variants on top of the standard passenger variant including freighter variants and the stunning BBJ2 variant.  ‍ The PMDG 737-800NG is available now from the PMDG website for a sale price of $69.99 and with a usual price of $74.00. Find out more and get a full feature list over at PMDG.COM ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
