<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-10-10T18:29:57.314569+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dqas24</id>
    <title>Microsoft September Dev Q&amp;A: The Threshold Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dqas24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f57bfb3572e461a8e6ef88_Fuji_MSFS_2024.jpg.avif"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following their recent preview event, Microsoft and Asobo have hosted another of their monthly developer live streams, this time focusing on the highly anticipated Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The lengthy hour and forty-eight-minute livestream covered various MSFS 2020 and FS24 topics and answered many of the community’s most burning questions about the upcoming sim, so we’ve compiled it all in one place! The live stream started with a section about Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Jorg Neumann, Head of Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressed criticisms of the newly released Boeing 707-320C by Aeroplane Heaven, stating: "The Aeroplane Heaven guys, they tried really hard," and acknowledging, "I know the INS is not what people want, but we will continue working on this and listen to the feedback." Additionally, Neumann announced the release date for AAU3 on October 1st and the release date of the highly-requested update for the ATR-42/72 series developed by Hans Hartmann, released on October 10th. We’ve divided this into sections, summarizing the answers for each question for ease of reading.  ‍ Q: Why is 64 GB the ‘ideal’ amount of RAM, and does more RAM help performance?‍ Sebastian Wloch, Asobo CEO and Co-Founder explains that 64 GB was chosen for users who want to “push every option to max detail” and do other things like recording or streaming, but the average user will only want 32 GB of RAM. He added later that FS24 will have an adaptive detail feature that automatically scales the sim's detail to hit a specific FPS target, but the user can disable it if they choose to.  ‍Q: On Xbox, can we expect the same performance and memory related stability issues in FS24 as in 2020? What optimizations have been made to make the new level of fidelity possible on Xbox consoles?‍ Wloch states that various improvements to the Xbox platform have allowed them to access 2.5 GB more RAM, which he says “really helps in terms of stability and performance”, in addition to the performance improvements baked into the new sim.  Executive Producer Martial Bossard adds that the new sim will no longer support DirectX 11 because FS24’s new rendering pipeline utilizes many of the new features of DirectX 12.  ‍Q: MSFS2024's reliance on online access for far more assets presumably means that a server outage is likely to affect far more users than the current server outages do. At present a lot of assets are stored on our systems whereas this will no longer be the case in MSFS2024, How feasible will it be to play offline in the future if at all?‍ Wloch starts by saying that most of the data was already being streamed in MSFS 2020, but they’ve added to that total, including Marketplace content. However, the user can decide if they want to stream or download content from the Marketplace. He continues to say that if the network is interrupted for up to a few minutes, users will not notice that much, but beyond that point, he states that “you need to be online at some point to fly”. Q: Will cloud and weather depiction be improved in MSFS 2024? Wloch mentioned many things in his answer, including the addition of cirrus clouds, redone lighting, weather systems like tornadoes, and translating the effects of the weather to the environment, such as trees, grass, and water. However, tornadoes will only be in missions because they do not have a reliable live data source for them. Q: Will there be a working weather radar? Bossard’s answer was very brief, saying that the feature is “still on the backlog”. Q: Will autogen buildings be getting a refresh in the new sim? Bossard says that work is still in progress on autogen buildings, but any change will come after the launch. Q: Will MSFS 2024 receive World Updates and City Updates? If so, will they also be released day-and-date for MSFS 2020?  Neumann gives a quick answer: “Check”. Wloch and Neumann mentioned a few other small features in this section, including adding a “historical world” for 24 hours, weather, and working windshield wipers. Q: Can I import all my settings/preferences/keybinds/etc. from Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 or will I need to set up all of that again? Bossard has some bad news: “Unfortunately, you would have to set [it] up again, because the way we are doing things is so different,...there is no way to translate one to the other”.  ‍Q: Will there be VR support in MSFS 2024? Will it be improved over the current implementation? Will it be available from Day 1?  Bossard confirms that VR will be supported from Day 1 and that they have made improvements to render thread performance. However, users can expect the same performance difference between 3D and VR as MSFS 2020. ‍Q: What you have made abundantly clear is that Al Aircraft traffic will be much better representing their real-life counterparts and that is really great. But I have questions to that point: Will we see an improved behavior from these Al vehicles (i.e. planes no longer driving through one another or ground vehicles not stopping when an airplane passes)?‍  Bossard says they “have tried to improve and to have better ground services”, but he acknowledges that “sometimes we have some weird things there”. He mentions the possibility of community improvement of ground services through the World Hub. Q: What improvements can we expect for the default ATC? Will you be utilizing Al similar to addons like SayIntentions and BeyondATC?  Neumann stated that “there are some” improvements to the default ATC system made by Asobo and WorkingTitle. He also mentions that the team looked at options like SayIntentions.ai but is not planning it for launch. Neumann does leave the door open for something akin to those products in the future, saying, “it’s good ideas that they [BeyondATC and SayIntentions] have”. Q: You said that if we crash our own plane in Career mode then it's lost. What happens if there's an internet outage or software crash in the middle of a mission? How does the sim handle such a situation? Will we lose a plane because of that?  Bossard clarified that the damage is “the result of the physic [sic]” and that they are “only handling that kind of situation when we are computing the forces and the effects of the crash”. Q: Do you have to go through all the trainings and check-rides to get to career missions or can you skip any part of it?‍ Bossard confirms that “you can skip it. Q: ﻿Can we use 3rd party planes / helicopters in career mode if the features they have are compatible with the mission tasks?  “Yes, but…under conditions”, says Bossard. He then explains that Marketplace aircraft have systems that check whether they have the right features to comply with specific missions. Q: Which items from the Feedback Snapshot and Development Roadmap will be implemented in MSFS 2020 and which items will be deferred to MSFS 2024  Neumann says that there is not a concrete list as of yet, but “there are goals to bring back certain features when possible to [MSFS] 2020”, but will separate the list “in the coming weeks”.  Q: Is it expected to let freeware developers join the Marketplace?  Neumann answered “probably, yes”, adding that “we just worked through some stuff with our…lawyers, so there will be some news here soon”. ‍Q: Will the SDK open up to allow more types of products to be developed i.e. Chaseplane for camera views, weather software like Active Sky, and tools such as AutoFPS?  Neumann explains that “this is not really an SDK question only”, and since they are 8 weeks out from releasing FS24, they would first have to make “everything tidy, and then we’ll talk about some of these things again”. Q: What about add-ons purchased from third-party stores (Orbx, simMarket, Aerosoft, PMDG, etc.)? Will they be transferable?  Neumann confirms that MSFS 2020 content can be copied “over to the community folder.” Notably, he did not provide a disclaimer about compatibility issues with some addons, but Microsoft and Asobo have repeatedly indicated this may be the case. Q: Can we buy Premium Deluxe planes separately in 2024? “Yes. I heard that loud and clear last time, and we did that,” Neumann says, acknowledging the community’s feedback.  ‍ Unlike in the past, where there was usually only one Q&amp;A session each month during the developer livestreams, Microsoft has announced that they will hold many more sessions covering specific topics during the ramp-up to the release. You can find the schedule below: This developer stream has revealed quite a lot about the upcoming simulator, but despite that, Microsoft and Asobo still have more to show. Throughout all these exciting new developments, Threshold will keep you up-to-date with the newest, so stay tuned for that and for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eje111</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family Update 1.1.0 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eje111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f68dba429996de1751e939_eje1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts recently updated their E-Jets Family lineup to version 1.1.0 for X-Plane 11 and 12, adding FMS speed mode, ILS autotune, steep approach capabilities (E170 &amp; 190 only), and over 160 new features, enhancements, and fixes. The update automates many things that were manual in the past, decreasing the required workload to operate the airplanes while also increasing the immersion factor. The speed management, for example, is now fully automatic, thanks to the new FMS Speed feature. The automation also extends to the ILS approach system, with an autotune feature that automatically tunes the correct frequency and handles the transition from LNAV&amp;VNAV to LOC&amp;GS, mimicking the expected real-life behavior. The E170 and 190 will also feature steep approach capability, making it possible to fly it into London City Airport realistically. It is famous for its 5,5-degree glide slope angle and the limited range of aircraft that can fly there. The E175 and E195 lack the certification in real life, therefore not sporting the feature. The displays can now be popped up, moved, and resized for a clearer, more accessible view. Positioning settings are persistent and will carry over on subsequent simulator loads. There are over 160 improvements in total, which follow below in the complete changelog: FMS SPEED ILS AUTOTUNE STEEP APPROACH (Available on the E170 &amp; E190) BRAND NEW POP-UP SCREENS OTHER NEW FEATURES FMS COCKPIT AUTOPILOT AUTOTHROTTLE (X-PLANE 12 ONLY) TAKEOFF AP MODES ENHANCED TO REFLECT REAL SYSTEMS PFD MFD EICAS EFB THRUST RATING SYSTEM ENGINE PERFORMANCE VNAV FLIGHT MODEL (X-Plane 12 only) SYSTEMS ANTI-ICE SYSTEM VR HARDWARE 3D MODEL SOUNDS ‍ Refer to their blog post for further information on the update and its features. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pngpk3</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack 3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pngpk3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f6958c7e1df501c5651ef9_pap1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx has recently released their third pack of Papua New Guinea Highland Bush Strips, featuring seven new airstrips (Nomane, Kora, Guwasa, Meninga, Herowenaq, Gimi, and Simogu) and 50 new models.  Bush airstrips in Papua New Guinea are generally the only gateway to certain remote villages, meaning it’s vital to their existence and the only way to bring supplies in. The weather is often harsh, the runways are often short and hand-carved, and the challenge is unparalleled. The new pack supplements Packs 1 and 2 with seven new destinations, 50 new models, custom runway elevation profiles, custom autogen, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $13.09, requiring at least 2.68 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/infaor</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Johannesburg O.R. Tambo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/infaor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f5620a8a54a6c83b90abdb_jobu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of O.R. Tambo International (FAOR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Johannesburg and Pretoria in South Africa, with a yearly average of 17.8 million passengers. The airport’s history begins in 1943, when the South African government planned to build three international airports, one on the Witwatersrand and two smaller ones in Cape Town and Durban. Four possible sites around Johannesburg were picked, and only two made it through the final scrutiny: Kempton Park and the existing airport at Palmietfontein, Johannesburg’s main airport at the time. They decided on Kempton Park, preceding the expropriation around the area within the same year and kick-starting the construction work, which took roughly eight years and cost the government 8 million pounds.  The advent of jet aircraft led to expansion work in the following decades, which included improved airside facilities, extra parking areas, hotels, and more. In the early 1990s, the terminal was expanded, receiving thirteen passenger bridges and modernizing the pre-existing infrastructure. By the mid-1990s, it had already overtaken Cairo as the busiest airport in Africa. It was within the top five in the Africa-Middle East Region, behind Dubai, Doha, and Abu Dhabi.  It’s a hub for AirLink, CemAir, FlySafair, LIFT, and South African Airways. Air China, Air France, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, KLM, LATAM Brasil, Lufthansa, Qantas, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Swiss, Turkish, United, and Virgin Airlines also serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside, custom night lighting, custom jetways, an up-to-date layout, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $20.05, requiring at least 7.44 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flwc24</id>
    <title>Flysimware Releases Sierra C24R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flwc24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f6f2ee85db9ae5dd3fec8f_sierra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Flysimware has recently released their rendition of the Beechcraft C24R Sierra for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engined low-wing aircraft first launched in 1977, based on the Beechcraft Musketeer. Developed as the retractable gear version of the Beechcraft Musketeer family (comprising the Model 23, Model 19 Sport, and Model 23-24 Super), keeping the engine choice of the Musketeer 23-24 Super, which couldn’t be fully unleashed due to the fixed-gear configuration. Thus, the Musketeer Super R was created in 1970, also known as the A24R, which competed directly with the Piper Arrow. Two years later, it was renamed “Sierra.” It sits right in the middle of their lineup between the cheaper, fixed-gear Musketeers and the fancier Bonanzas, selling for a standard price of $24,950. In 1974, the Sierra received an engine upgrade, sporting the Lycoming IO-360-A1B6 and a new propeller design. Three years later, the model represented by this add-on came, the C24R, which featured the same engine as the 1974 B24R, albeit with an even larger propeller and a slight aerodynamic cleanup, making it six knots faster. Production continued until 1983 when the lines were closed due to an aviation economic downturn. 744 Sierras were built during those thirteen years. The add-on claims to feature realistic flight dynamics, 4K PBR textures, interactive environment sounds, a Boris Audio Works Wwise sound set, custom-coded gauges, multiple choices of avionics (GTX 345, GMA 340, GNS 530, GTN 750, GTN750Xi), windshield rain effects, exterior icing effects, different cockpit variations (Garmin G5, Garmin G3X, and the choice between PMS/TDS GTN750/750xi or the built-in GTN 530), and ten liveries to choose from. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $35.14, requiring at least 4.39 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jff111</id>
    <title>Just Flight Provides F70/100 Progress Update</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jff111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f6fc56c996a71817dda672_3_9dCB7XLOuF.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight have released another development update on their upcoming Fokker 70/100 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator on their website. This time, the update covered the external textures.  The Fokker F70 and F100 are narrow-body regional airliners produced by the Dutch aircraft manufacturer, Fokker. Developed from the earlier F28, the F70 and F100 offered larger cabins, updated avionics, and higher MTOWs. Equipped with two Rolls-Royce Tay Mk 650-15 engines, the F100 could cruise at Mach 0.77 for a range of 1,700nm. According to JustFlight, the external textures have undergone a complete rework, and have been upscaled to 8K. This allows for many rivets and screws to be visible. Alongside the improved textures, the fuselage skin has also received a lot of attention from the developers, as ripples on the fuselage caused by many pressurization cycles can now be seen. The decals on doors, emergency exits, static ports, as well as the landing gear bay, were also redrawn and upgraded.  The developers have hinted that their next progress update might cover the aircraft’s systems. Unfortunately, as of the posting of this article, no information about the support for the upcoming FS24, pricing, or the release date has been announced. As always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and high-quality reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbgca</id>
    <title>Orbx Previews Landmarks Gold Coast for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbgca"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f9aa0bd8e37252ab50a2e6_11957-7ae170849d12b7159d37c7ee3cff89e3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx have announced another product from the ‘Landmark’ line - Landmarks Gold Coast. Joining the likes of Cape Town, Dubai, Singapore, London, Paris and such, the Gold Coast will be the 16th city to get its rendition developed for FS20 by Orbx. Gold Coast is Queensland’s second-largest city with a population of over 640,00 and is known as one of Australia’s best tourist destinations, the Gold Coast is famous for its long sandy beaches, surfing, and vibrant nightlife. Orbx’s rendition of ‘Goldy’ features over 40 custom buildings, animated boats along the coast, animated roller coasters, and the Gold Coast University Hospital with a helipad. The full feature list is as follows: No information about the pricing or the release date has been released. However, as always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo120</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Updates San Francisco International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo120"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66fc3f1c001ed29d56ddcabc_fran1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Flightbeam Studios recently issued a new update to their rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes performance enhancements, bug fixes, extra customizability, and more. Update 1.2—the second update since its release in mid-2024—brings new custom taxi lights, which do not rely on the SDK to create their glow and appearance. They are tailored to their preferences to match their real-world counterparts and meticulously hand-placed throughout the airport. It also introduces an accurate representation of the ILS antennas used at SFO.  The update also allows you to remove ground clutter partially or entirely (so you don’t get tangled with GSX stuff). The developers note that this will not improve performance much as it’s already extensively optimized as is (with the clutter enabled). Night lighting is said to have undergone improvements, with improved visibility and effects at close range. Geographic position markings were added to help with low visibility procedures, matching the real-life counterpart. The complete changelog for the update follows below: The scenery is available on Contrail for roughly $21, requiring at least 2.58 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42737</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases 737 Immersion Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66fc431a38d07bc6e9bb4a63_737im1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently released their 737 Immersion package for Microsoft Flight Simulator—part of their SimFX add-on—aiming to improve the overall realism of the effects for the PMDG 737 family with condensation, realistic chemtrails, brake smoke, and more. Built on the SimFx framework, it offers the best combination of effects and customizability via the SimFx interface. For the unaware, Parallel 42's SimFX is a visual effects utility covering a range of immersive scenarios. Environmental variables and formulas authentically govern every particle on the screen, and dynamic effects appear under the right conditions, creating unique moments in the virtual skies. The effects include contrails, heat blurs, wing wash, rotor wash, and more. Their immersion package for the 737 builds on SimFx's already extensive offerings, bringing nineteen custom effects for the 737 family (600,700,800 and 900), including swirling contrails, condensation effects, wastewater draining every hour, engine cold start effects, fuel jettison, cloud illumination, hot brake smoke, St. Elmo's fire, carbon brake dust, and water droplets.  It's available on Contrail and OrbxDirect for roughly $15.00. The add-on requires a SimFX copy to work. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777049</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777-300ER for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777049"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660b6a529653d007ea9eda3d_777new.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently issued a new update to their Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a series of visual and efficiency improvements to their latest airliner and a slight bit of information about their upcoming 777F. Update 2.00.0049 brings a substantial list of changes ranging from external model tweaks to sounds, EFB, and even LNAV tweaks. The complete changelog follows below: Randazzo has also taken a moment to explain why things have been so "slow" as of late with updates, with the culprit being a software reload on their deployment machine whose storage device had failed, taking the SDK to a slightly newer version that had a flaw with the memory allocation process, introducing memory corruption, and thus, instability. After weeks of research, tests, and failures, they managed to narrow down the issue, and the correction was as simple as rolling back to the previous version of the SDK, which fixed it. Narrowing down the problem, though, took them six weeks. They have also provided some information on the upcoming 777F, which entered beta last week. The plane's gameplay items are still not quite up to their standards, so they anticipate a few more beta builds before it's truly ready to leave the oven. The anticipated release date is around the end of October. PMDG has not said anything yet about the new simulator, but they plan to address the subject later today in a separate forum thread. The 777-300ER is available on their website and in the Marketplace for $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ran777</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS 2020 and Beyond</title>
    <updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ran777"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6700743a43d6279dcc6fba41_randy3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG has recently published a new development update delineating their plans for the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, pending updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, and their Boeing 777F, set to land before the new simulator releases. Robert Randazzo has divided the development update into two parts, concerning what is coming before MSFS 2024 releases and what is coming after it comes out in mid-November: ‍ The 737 Family is getting a significant update, which is supposed to get into testing soon. It brings many of the new features from the 777-300ER, like the new Navdata format. The process took longer than expected, but it's set to enter beta testing in the next few weeks. The update is scheduled to drop around the second half of October, bringing most of these planned changes for free. While it does diverge from their original plan of gradually rolling out the changes over September and October due to the memory corruption issue with the 777, the first update will bring a large chunk of the features, followed by smaller updates in the coming months to cover anything that might have been left unfinished. Updating the navdata via the tablet has been finally addressed, ultimately unlocking navdata updates for console users.  They will provide more information on the 737 update once it enters beta testing. ‍ The 777-300ER will get a new batch of liveries in the marketplace, mainly targeting console users, as the liveries can be obtained for free on PC. While they do not have a set timeline, they assume mid-October, like the 737 update. The 777F information is the exact same as yesterday's article, and the release is set for around the end of the month. ‍ Then, Randazzo hops right into the plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, regarding their current lineup being ported over to the new platform, new gameplay features from the new sim, new 777 expansions, 737 MAX, 747, and their "secret" project. ‍ Porting their product lineup to MSFS 2024 will begin as soon as they get their hands on the SDK. They are unsure whether changes will be required or not, nor do they know whether it's going to be straightforward, but they intend on bringing it over as quickly as possible within the limitations at hand. ‍ They have yet to have an answer on adding new MSFS 2024 features, such as walkaround and career mode compatibility, as they have yet to see the new platform. They will evaluate the features for their existing product lines and then determine the right course of action to make them compatible with the new stuff. Their primary focus will be on getting the products working fine first, and only then will they consider anything else.  ‍ The 777-200LR is projected to launch before the end of the year for both platforms, but PMDG makes sure to highlight that it's based upon publicly available marketing information from the new simulator. It does not take into account any possible challenges that might come with the advent of a new flight simulation platform and how that would impact higher priority items such as converting their pre-existing aircraft. The same applies to the 777-200ER. ‍ The 737 MAX project, on the other hand, has been deprioritized for the time being due to a higher-priority enterprise contract. That is because the developers working on the Max are also the same ones working on the high-priority enterprise project. They have been prioritizing the latter as it might play a factor in unlocking something for an upcoming post-747 project (hinted as a Big X Factor).  ‍ They also make sure to clarify they have nothing to do with the Asobo 737 Max, part of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024's default aircraft lineup. ‍ The PMDG 747 project has been underway since the beginning of the year. The developers are using all of the knowledge from their previous product lines to raise the detail bar a notch higher. They hint at a possible software build before the release of MSFS 2024 (for testing).  It's claimed to be their first product built with 3D scanning from inside and out, supported by high-detail images of the exterior surfaces using drone technology. That leads to "incredibly well-sculpted models that accurately capture even the really hard-to-model spots where compound curves can look different from all angles."  ‍ They do not have a projected release date for The Queen of the Skies, as the transition to MSFS 2024 will positively or negatively impact the overall process. PMDG will keep everyone updated with frequent development updates. ‍ Robert has also teased another – albeit so far "secret" – project, with an image of one of the steam gauges:  Their product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a330ms</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases A330 CEO Base Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a330ms"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6703f9e0da59a78affb1afc2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Aerosoft has recently launched the base pack for its long-awaited Airbus A330 expansion for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes the A330-300 PW variant. While some features are not included in the base pack, users can now fly this twin-engine wide-body aircraft. The first variant of the aircraft to fly the skies was the A330-300, which had its maiden flight in 1992. However, the plane did not enter service until 1994 with the airline Air Inter. After the A300, Airbus decided to design a new plane, the A330, as a descendant of the A300. Featuring fly-by-wire technology and a glass cockpit, the plane was very different from the original A300. In 2014, Airbus announced the new A330neo, making the A330 even more efficient. This variant entered service in 2018. As of the summer of 2024, a total of 1,610 A330 aircraft had been built. The plane is still being built and used to this day by airlines all over the world. The A330 CEO Base Pack includes the A330-300 with PW engines, with the RR and GE engine variants to be added later. The A330neo is also in development. The base pack offers various features such as a fully customized cockpit, custom fly-by-wire systems, custom autopilot systems, and more. It's important to note that there are some features not implemented in the base pack. Aerosoft has also confirmed that an update for MSFS 2024 will be provided free of charge. The newly released A330 CEO Base Pack requires 3 GB of storage space and is available at Aerosoft for $27.66. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx403</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Family for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx403"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/670599b4f21739aca4db9393_1250410_20240307064302_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations recently issued a new update to its A320 family lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes performance optimization improvements, new ATSU features, and more. Update 2.2.0.403 features a substantial amount of changes on the systems front, with a new source of GPS ephemeris data, ILS autotune improvements, multiple MCDU fixes and tweaks, the addition of AOC FREE TEXT and AOC ATIS request via VATSIM and IVAO, cargo distribution on loadsheet, along with weight and balance code changes to support sharklets and ACTs in the future. Furthermore, art fixes were rolled out to address a safety card mishap (the A319 and A321 safety cards showed up on the A320), flap rod fixes on the A319 and A320, overhead bin improvements, and more. The EFB has also seen minor improvements, such as better cargo distribution to target an optimal CG setting, better take-off performance figures based on airport elevation, and a bug fix that prevents the EFB from starting blank if it had been in sleep mode during the previous session. The Flight and engine Models had also undergone improvements, with a fully reworked FADEC providing accurate FLX data and wholly mitigating the discrepancy between its assigned trust rating and what was, in fact, displayed. The changes also make it so that the FADEC rating will subtly change during the take-off roll, as the system is continuously computing the appropriate thrust output, thus causing variation on the EPR/N1. IAEs are still going to see further tweaks. ‍ The official changelog for the update follows below: ‍ The A320 Family is available on their website for roughly $104.81. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tol339</id>
    <title>Toliss Simulations Shares New A330-900 Previews for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tol339"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6705a5043a20474ad655bd6c_tol10.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Toliss Simulations recently shared new screenshots of their upcoming Airbus A330-900 for X-Plane 11 and 12, which will be released in 11 days (19/10). The fresh batch of pictures showcases some of the features that will be present in the aircraft, such as the Interactive Simulation Control System directly in the tablet, a new HUD (X-Plane 12 only), the brand new DRAIMS (Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System), and the runway overrun protection system. A few external screenshots were also shared a day prior, wearing the Airbus house livery in its full glory during multiple stages of a flight.  They have also stated that the beta phase has been well underway and that there are no major roadblocks to report, with the release still scheduled for the original date (19/10).  There’s no information on pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kiwhok</id>
    <title>KiwiFlightSim Releases Hokitika Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kiwhok"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6705af75ad660cb092e7069b_hok1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. KiwiFlightSim Limited has recently released their rendition of Hokitika Airport (NZHK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This uncontrolled aerodrome serves the homonymous city in New Zealand and has a yearly average of 40,000 passengers. The airport’s history dates back to the early days of aviation, with records going as far back as 1923 when Captain Maurice Buckley landed his Avro 504 in Hokitika. This marked a significant milestone for aviation in the region and demonstrated air travel’s potential to connect isolated communities on the West Coast. Eleven years later, Captain Bert Mercer established New Zealand’s first commercial airline – Air Travel NZ Ltd –, operating flights between Hokitika and other settlements in South Westland. Air Travel NZ’s route coverage expanded greatly during World War 2, taking passengers to Greymouth, Westport, and Nelson. Its location, though, has changed over the years because of the previous area’s susceptibility to flooding, leading to the construction of an entirely new airport in 1951. The new aerodrome attracted new airlines, with its first indeed scheduled service starting in 1953 with NAC, flying their DC-3 from Paraparaumu, Nelson, and Westport. It’s currently served by Air New Zealand, with ATR flights to Christchurch. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom aerial imagery, custom 3D modeling, custom ground service equipment, hand-crafted apron markings, custom night lighting, custom windsocks, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.43, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pesbia</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Releases Biarritz Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pesbia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6705b526454d14b3cd29b730_bia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Pilot Experience Sim has recently released the second version of its Biarritz Pays Basque Airport (LFBZ) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the homonymous city on the Bay of Biscay and has a yearly average of 970,000 passengers. The airport’s history dates back to 1936 when it was established as an airfield for private aviation, growing along with the demand for air travel in the area, which became exponential after the end of World War 2, leading to significant expansion work. The airport has continued to evolve over the previous decades, with infrastructure improvements, renovation work (the most recent one dating back to a decade ago), and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, PBR texturing, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
