<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-01-01T18:38:56.451557+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asubbf</id>
    <title>Azrsim Releases Fuzuli International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asubbf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6949723e6063ffe8d96ff12d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Azrsim has recently released its rendition of Fuzuli International Airport (UBBF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. After previously launching Heydar Aliyev International Airport (UBBB), the main airport in Baku, earlier this year, the team has now turned its attention to another city in Azerbaijan. Fuzuli International Airport currently offers passenger flights solely to the capital, Baku. Fuzuli International Airport is a relatively new airport, having opened in 2021. It covers an area of just under 650,000 square feet and features a runway that is nearly 10,000 feet long. Currently, the airport is served exclusively by Azerbaijan Airlines, which offers flights to Baku; however, it also accommodates cargo flights. Azrsim’s airport rendition features an accurate airport layout, a fully custom-modelled terminal building, high-quality PBR materials, custom night lighting, and many additional features. The newly released Fuzuli International Airport by Azrsim is now available on SimMarket for approximately $17.64. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fslpwupdevu</id>
    <title>FSLabs Publishes Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fslpwupdevu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69499e89c9d1fe9be5f4f058_pw1.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently published a new development update regarding the long-awaited Pratt &amp; Whitney update for their A321neo, released earlier this year with LEAPs as the sole engine option initially. A combination of technical challenges and continued changes introduced through Sim Updates in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 has necessitated unexpected additional work and testing validation, which has pushed the update’s rollout date forward. Furthermore, they are actively supporting Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, while also laying the groundwork for a fully native 2024 product line, which adds further complexity to their development process. Rather than pushing a half-baked update, FSLabs chose to wait it out until it’s all deemed properly stable, avoiding a sequence of micro-updates.  They also do not expect the aforementioned update to be released before Christmas, as they don’t want to put unnecessary strain on their quality assurance and support teams, and they want to ensure full availability when the update is shipped. Development and testing will absolutely not stop during the holidays, though. They have also shared a few screenshots from their  current work-in-progress builds, and more details will be shared soon. ​ The add-on is available on their website for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkrov2</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Rovaniemi Airport V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkrov2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694b11664a22742aa86140e7_rova1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently released their updated rendition of Rovaniemi Airport (EFRO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the third-busiest airport in Finland, serving 500,000 passengers annually. It was built in 1940, originally featuring two grass runways. It was heavily utilized as a Luftwaffe Air base and supply center during the Second Soviet-Finnish War between 1941 and 1944. By the end of the conflict, the airport was heavily compromised. Rebuilding work was concluded in 1948, and regular traffic resumed in the second half of the same year. The current terminal building was completed in 1992 and expanded in 2000 with the addition of jetways. The runway underwent renovation work in 2016, with new pavement and LED lights, and 2019 marked the completion of the terminal’s third enlargement. It’s served all year long by Finnair, and a multitude of European carriers visit Rovaniemi during the winter season (Aer Lingus, Air France, easyJet, Eurowings, Ryanair, Transavia, Turkish Airlines, to name a few). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality 3D models, custom terminal interiors, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, precise runway elevation data, and more. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $19.42, requiring at least 3.04 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffu622</id>
    <title>Flight Factor Updates 757 V2 and 767 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffu622"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694b255103a678619d800e48_1791020844_757-300_xp12-2022-09-0814_00_23.jpg.64ae8513aa67809c30a0ab823f0bad9a.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Factor has recently released a minor update for the 757 V2 (v2.6.22) and 767 (v1.6.22) product lines, addressing several reported bugs. Featured is a possible fix for the spurious terrain look-ahead warning reported by many users. They also fixed the colour of the terrain look-ahead warning text to the highest level.  As for weather radar issues, Flight Factor has fixed bugs with the tilt control function, and a bug that caused the controls to malfunction if both weather radars were on.  To round out the update, Flight Factor fixed the issues with the EFB’s charts tab, that caused unpredictable behaviour if settings hadn’t been saved.  As always, the full changelog follows below: ‍ 757 v2.6.22 Updated implementations of TERR/WXR radars in all 757 models (including new WXR radar based on X-plane 12.3 capabilities) Updated Navigraph authentication method for Charts in tablet Added the ability to use shared Navigraph settings from other FF products Fixed possible crash related to TGDS plugin Fixed the necessity of often relogging in case of using Navigraph Charts in tablet Fixed the logic of the hydraulic system, PTU, yaw damper, and reserve brake Fixed EICAS message order ‍ 767 v1.6.22 Updated implementations of TERR/WXR radars in all 767 models (including new WXR radar based on X-plane 12.3 capabilities) Updated Navigraph authentication method for Charts in tablet Added the ability to use shared Navigraph settings from other FF products Fixed possible crash related to TGDS plugin Fixed the necessity of often relogging in case of using Navigraph Charts in tablet Fixed EICAS message order ‍ To get the update, simply run X-Updater located in your 757 or 767 directory.  New customers can purchase a copy of the Flight Factor 757 V2 or 767 from the Flight Factor website.  ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!     </summary>
    <published>2025-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1240</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.4.0 Beta</title>
    <updated>2025-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1240"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694b2a1a5c5001242ad2008a_CCheck_Update_Title_1-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In a surprise announcement, Laminar Research has released the beta version of their C-Check update, better known as X-Plane 12.4.0 Beta. The stated goal of the beta is to lay the groundwork for  X-Plane’s future.  Laminar Research has accomplished this by replacing core elements of the simulator and improving aircraft systems. The default A330 has been reworked to a "payware level", now, for example, allowing for realistic cold and dark starts. It also gives you the tools needed to conduct proper oceanic and long-haul flights. This includes a third MCDU for Airline Operational Communications.  The autopilot system has also been improved, making for smoother turns, better flight plan tracking, and more reliable coupled approaches. Finally, emergencies can now be simulated. On the general aviation side, X-Plane’s default X430 and X530 now have working terrain, traffic, and weather pages, while the X1000 now features a dedicated page showing ETE/ETA.  For lovers of custom scenery, the team has included a rendition of Bilbao Airport (LEBB) in Spain. Other improvements in the beta include native support for the Tobii Eye Tracker 5 on Windows, multi-threaded scenery processing, virtual reality improvements, ATC improvements, and more! You can find the full release notes here.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winctrl</id>
    <title>WINWING Confirms 2026 Rebrand to WINCTRL</title>
    <updated>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winctrl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694ec082209381a072c49f74_603811011_1551469795931056_8692167976900153039_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. WINWING has officially revealed a brand rework, confirming it will operate as “WINCTRL”, starting next year.  The change marks the retirement of the original WINWING name, as the company shifts towards a strategy of greater clarity, refinement, and long-term growth. In a message shared with the community, the team reflected on its six-year journey, from its first consumer flight control hardware, through countless iterations shaped by user feedback, detailed discussions, and a passionate core audience.  The new name, WINCTRL, is said to represent “precise control”, a theme the company says has always guided its design philosophy and its relationship with its customers. Under the WINCTRL banner, the company is promising smarter, more precisely tuned hardware, stronger customer support, expanded warranty coverage, and a closer community, including beta programmes and offline meetups for dedicated users. While no new hardware has been formally unveiled, the new “Cyber Taurus” is currently planned for a Q1 reveal. We'll keep you updated. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! </summary>
    <published>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmenevr</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Harstad/Narvik Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmenevr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694ecabfdb4991aa59525d82_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has just released its highly anticipated version of Harstad/Narvik Airport (ENEV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located in northern Norway, the airport serves the cities of Harstad and Narvik and handles over 800,000 passengers annually. The airport first opened its doors in 1973, following a two-year construction period that began in 1971. There was a lengthy debate and planning process before the construction of the airport commenced. When it first opened, the airport featured a runway that was 5,200 feet long, which has since been extended to its current length of 9,226 feet. Today, the airport serves as a joint public and military facility, with airlines such as Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe operating flights both domestically and internationally. The scenery package includes features like accurate runway, taxiway, and apron layouts, detailed interior and exterior modelling of terminals, custom local hangars and airport buildings, and realistic ground textures, markings, and signage, among others. Harstad/Narvik Airport by MM Simulations is now available on SimMarket for approximately $23.52. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inudec</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Posts December Development Update, Announces L-1011 TriStar for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inudec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694edc0c60a810b5593ae0df_AircraftDevBanner.png.cdea20ee03ce2df917a3e0cf9bf7fe24.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has published its final development update of 2025, opening with a recap of the past year before pivoting to the official announcement of the Lockheed L-1011 TriStar for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The update begins by looking back at a busy, at times challenging, year for the studio. iniBuilds highlights the releases of the A350 Airliner, A340 Airliner, F406 Caravan II, and Spartan 7W Executive, alongside an extended post-launch support cycle, particularly for the A350.  Much of the retrospective focuses on performance optimisation, WASM stability work, and long-term refinement across its MSFS 2024 fleet, rather than introducing significant new developments. One forward-looking note does emerge from the recap, however, with iniBuilds confirming that a free VIP variant of the A340 Airliner is scheduled to arrive in January. With housekeeping out of the way, IniBuilds moves to the main attraction. That is, the official confirmation of the iniBuilds Lockheed L-1011 TriStar for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024.  iniBuilds says the goal is to deliver the most authentic and immersive TriStar experience yet seen in home simulation, providing a ground-up recreation of the iconic widebody, and designed to take full advantage of MSFS 2024’s new features. The project will focus primarily on the L-1011-500 “Shortbody” variant, developed using extensive real-aircraft access, hands-on reference sessions, and detailed research.  Planned features include fully simulated electrical, hydraulic, pneumatic, and environmental systems, the Automatic Flight Control System, with CAT IIIB autoland, and multiple navigation configurations. These range from analogue radio navigation to the triple Litton INS setup, with optional modern navigation upgrades also available. A standout inclusion is the TriStar’s Performance Management System, integrated with the AFCS and INS. The system will compute optimal climb, cruise, and descent profiles, based on live aircraft data. Sound design is being handled by Echo19, who secured access to an operational TriStar at the TriStar Experience in Kansas City, Missouri.  iniBuilds continues by saying they have travelled internationally to gather extensive reference material, with the aircraft featuring high-fidelity exterior and interior modelling, evolving dynamic weathering, and an optional retrofit lower-deck lounge, a nod to one of the TriStar’s most distinctive design features. Further deep dives into the RB211 engines, Direct Lift Control, flight engineer systems, and additional features are planned for future development updates. Read the full update here. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaccu25024</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Releases Native Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaccu25024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694f09f57c89041e08b3844c_manche1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently released a native build of their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, including new 2024-only features such as the new EFB apps, dirt accumulation, and more. ​ The upgrade brings native 2024 gauges, a native 2024 EFB with charts and other apps, a full walkaround system using 2024’s standards, dirt accumulation on the exterior, dual PMS/TDS GTN 750/650 configuration, time compression support, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: It’s available in their store for $49.99, and owners of the MSFS 2020 version can upgrade for a discounted price ($14.99). The upgrade is not mandatory, and the previous version will continue to work in 2024, albeit without the new features. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/l73v2r</id>
    <title>LevelUp 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 Set for Dec. 30 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/l73v2r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695032e07ab2038b76a39d1a_Available-Now%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The LevelUp 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 appears set to release on Dec. 30, quietly revealed via its download page, with a short note simply stating, “See you on the 30th”. The update marks the long-awaited first stage of the V2 refresh for X-Plane 12, delivering a comprehensive visual and audio overhaul years in the making.  Stage 1 focuses on exterior and cabin upgrades, pairing a rejuvenated 3D model with brand-new 8K textures, optimised geometry, and a modular visual architecture, designed to keep file size small. The V2 package brings the complete five-member 737NG family, spanning the -600 through -900ER, all powered by Zibo systems, and all benefiting from a reworked cabin, improved exterior modelling, and a wide range of configuration options, from split scimitar winglets to eyebrow windows. Sound has also been a significant focus, with a revamped FMOD 2.0 soundset, professionally recorded material, improved performance, and far greater depth across both interior and exterior audio, including a more authentic CFM56 sound profile. Following the release of Stage 1, Stage 2 will introduce a fully reworked cockpit, flight model improvements and more.  We’ll keep you updated on any future developments, leading up to release day. For more information, you can check out the official LevelUp Discord server. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mgoatr</id>
    <title>Mango Studios Announces ATR 72-500 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mgoatr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69504c4feec84d0e916e5bcf_600347200_877109611962696_5780293440335014144_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In a surprise announcement, Mango Studios, perhaps a name more commonly associated with audio addons than aircraft, has revealed its first-ever aircraft project, the ATR 72-500 for X-Plane 12. The project is stated to have been in development for around nine months and is being created in partnership with Alsie Express, alongside volunteer contributors from across the flight simulation community.  According to Mango Studios, the goal is to deliver a highly authentic, deeply researched ATR simulation, built using real-world photographic references, pilot feedback, and extensive technical study. Planned features include a fully custom FMOD sound set, bespoke aircraft systems, a detailed 3D model with high-resolution textures, an integrated electronic flight bag, and custom animations throughout. While the aircraft remains firmly work-in-progress, early screenshots have already been shared, offering a first look at the external modelling and surface detail. You can read more about that here. No release window, pricing, or development roadmap has been announced at this stage, and Mango Studios has been clear that the project is still in its early phases, which the pictures so far also represent. You can read more about the project on the X-Plane.org forums. We will keep you updated as development continues. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mgmtdc</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Teases Major Hardware Refresh</title>
    <updated>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mgmtdc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69517398eec84d0e91a16508_602974703_122215487966063585_8627058572866468407_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Meridian GMT has recently teased that a major product update is just days away, with its official website set to receive a complete refresh on Dec. 30. This will include new product pages, several previously unseen features, and an expected launch window for its upcoming hardware lineup. The update was previewed in a short video teaser, where the team has promised a steady drip-feed of information.  Each day leading up to Dec. 30, Meridian GMT says it will highlight a new or updated feature on its Facebook page, with live answers to questions in the comments.  As part of the post, Meridian GMT confirmed a reset of its product naming, dropping the earlier phonetic system in favour of clearer, brand-led names.  Under the new structure, yokes will be grouped under the Horizon Series, while throttle quadrants will carry the Latitude branding, beginning with the Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant. Carrying on, as part of their daily feature highlights, Meridian GMT has also showed off two core pillars of the upcoming hardware refresh.  The first is "Quantum Leap", a new 16-bit TMR sensor system, borrowed from aerospace and industrial applications, designed to deliver higher resolution, lower noise, and more consistent, centre precision than traditional Hall-effect sensors. These are deployed selectively on axes where accuracy matters most, including roll, throttle, and trim.  Alongside this sits "ModulAIR", Meridian’s modular control architecture, built into both Horizon Plus and Latitude Plus, allowing pilots to expand and upgrade their setups over time, without replacing entire units. This is achieved while still maintaining mechanical and electrical compatibility across future generations, supporting a more flexible, long-term hardware ecosystem.  For more information and teasers, check out Meridian’s Facebook page.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/340dec</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Shares Full A340-600 Pro Test Flight</title>
    <updated>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/340dec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/695189c49517d8d65b230c98_69XntUbTIcU-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has delivered a pleasant surprise for fans of the A340, releasing a whole, uncut test flight video of the upcoming A340-600 Pro, showcasing the aircraft on a full Frankfurt–Boston sector. The footage, shared by the Aerosoft Flight team, offers an extended look at the aircraft’s current state, including system operation, flight dynamics, EFB interaction, sounds, and exterior visuals. The A340-600 Pro is being developed as a collaboration between Aerosoft and ToLiss, combining ToLiss’s systems and flight modelling expertise, with Aerosoft’s visual and artistic work.  The aircraft is planned for release on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, although it remains firmly in development for now.  As always, keep in mind that this is still a work-in-progress build, and does not necessarily represent the final product. As of the latest, you can expect release sometime in 2026. For more information and teasers, you can check out Aerosoft’s Discord server.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrfterjdec</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Posts Development Update for the ERJ Family 2.0</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrfterjdec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69525d539ee102ae2394925a_ERJ-FAMILY-2.0-FULL-SYSTEMS-SIMULATION-PREVIEW_12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts has provided an update on the upcoming ERJ Family 2.0 for X-Plane, confirming that the aircraft will not be released in 2025 as previously announced. The X-Crafts ERJ Family 2.0 will not be released in 2025, as the company has chosen to prioritise quality over meeting that deadline. They indicated that the main reason for the delay is that they have pushed their development efforts further than ever before. According to X-Crafts, their real ERJ pilot testers can fly the aircraft just like they would in real life, and 99 percent of all cockpit buttons are operational. The only exceptions are circuit breakers or buttons that cannot be realistically simulated in a flight simulator. Marko Mamula, founder of X-Crafts, states that all systems, including flight controls and an authentic FMS with holding patterns, have been implemented. A detailed systems showcase has also been posted. AirComms is a new on-screen interface designed to assist you in flying the aircraft. It will feature interactive tutorials, offer tips on when to perform specific actions, and provide warnings if certain tasks are overlooked. AirComms looks to be aimed at users who are less familiar with the ERJ Family, helping them to quickly get up to speed. X-Crafts has not provided an updated release date, but the aircraft is largely complete. They have mentioned that the main things still needed are documentation, website resources, screenshots, and other materials. ‍ For more on the ERJ Family 2.0, check out Marko Mamula’s blog post. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lvl737</id>
    <title>LevelUp Releases 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lvl737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6952fc3b056ada59f5b3f1b1_ForXP12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After the long wait, LevelUp has finally released the 737NG Series V2 Stage 1 update for X-Plane 12!  The new update brings new FMOD sounds, 8K exterior textures and new models, a remodelled cabin interior, as well as the newest ZiboMod systems update. Both the exterior and the interior have received big upgrades, with higher poly counts on the exterior - winglets, engine cowlings and gear tyres, which will make them look smoother compared to the older version. Along with the new 3D models, textures were also a part of the update, as all the above-mentioned items now have 8K textures. Meanwhile, the cabin has received a refresh, with the new models that are closer to the seats mostly used in today's aircraft. Another big part of the update are the new sounds. Using the 2.0 FMOD, it features an entirely new soundset, with plenty of new and improved sounds, such as stick shaker rattle, bleed air rush after shut-down, HUD handling sounds, improved environment sounds, cabin chatter, touchdown sounds, as well as improved touchdown sound logic. The LevelUp 737NG Series V2 update is available for download on the Threshold forums and the OrbxDirect for free, and requires just 0.94GB of free disk space. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/newgmt</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Website Relaunch Goes Live, Reveals Full Hardware Line-Up</title>
    <updated>2025-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/newgmt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69559d21c030d96f3ecf5e9c_latitude-product%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Meridian GMT has officially launched its redesigned website, marking a significant milestone for the studio and putting its long-teased hardware ecosystem in the spotlight. This follows the initial announcement made by Meridian on Christmas Day. The updated product pages are now available at MeridianGMT.com, showcasing various imagery, specifications, and feature breakdowns for the Horizon Plus Flight Controls, Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant, and the X-Ray Handheld FlightDeck. At the centre of the line-up is the Horizon Plus Flight Controls, Meridian’s flagship yoke system, designed around a modular architecture that allows pilots to tailor the setup for airliner or general aviation operations.  The system combines a full-range roll axis with a deliberately asymmetric pitch mechanism, providing precision during rotation, approach, and landing. At the same time, modular avionics bays on either side allow panels to be swapped, as flying styles change. Sitting alongside it is the Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant, a highly configurable throttle solution, with interchangeable lever sets and magnetic faceplates. This allows for quick transitions between various Boeing, Airbus, and GA configurations. Rounding out the ecosystem is the X-Ray Handheld FlightDeck, a compact controller designed for couch and casual flying, with magnetic faceplates, tactile controls, and a strong emphasis on accessibility.  Full information on X-Ray compatibility, particularly for console use, will follow once licensing processes are completed in January. ‍ The website relaunch also confirms Meridian’s move away from its earlier phonetic naming scheme, with product names now aligned directly to the brand’s identity, a change founder Nicki says represents a clean break from the company’s past, and a renewed focus on its own design language.  According to the published roadmap, a non-binding pre-order sign-up for the Horizon Plus Flight Controls is planned to open on Jan. 20, 2026, serving as a system and demand test, with full pre-orders expected from Feb. 1, 2026. The Latitude Plus Throttle Quadrant will follow shortly after. They also plan to showcase hands-on prototypes at FSWeekend in Lelystad and at FlightSimExpo 2026 in Saint Paul, Minnesota, ahead of beta units and wider pre-orders rolling out during the second quarter of 2026.  Pre-orders will, however, only open once production timelines are formally locked in with manufacturing partners. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
