<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-01-23T18:23:24.690483+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ontx12</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Ontario International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ontx12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659d9a888ab8e6c3467199ac_ont1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Ontario International Airport (KONT) for X-Plane 12, serving the cities of San Bernardino, Riverside, and Greater Los Angeles with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1941 as an Army Air Corps aircraft training and operation base. After the war, it became a large storage, sale, and scrapping center for Army Air Forces aircraft.   Shortly after, in 1946, the airport was renamed from “Ontario Municipal Airport” to “Ontario International Airport” because of outgoing trans-Pacific cargo flights. The first international passenger flight happened that same year, a Pacific Overseas Airlines flight from Shanghai to Ontario, inaugurating round-trip air passenger service between the United States and the Orient. Western Airlines began operating at the airport three years later, followed by Bonanza Air Lines in 1955.  A new terminal was opened in 1998, discontinuing the old terminals, which now function as the administration and the USO. There are 26 gates total, with 12 on T2 and 14 on T4. Terminal 2 hosts Alaska Airlines, Avianca El Salvador, China Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, United Airlines, and Volaris. Terminal 4 hosts American Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, and Southwest.  It’s a FedEx and UPS Airlines cargo hub, transporting cargo all over North America and Asia (UPS). Amazon Air, Ameriflight, Amerijet International, Asia Pacific Airlines, and Kalitta Air also serve it. Ontario International is the ninth-largest cargo airport in the United States.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with brand-new XP12 weather maps, accurate cargo ramps, an up-to-date ground layout, HDR lighting, PBR texturing, SAM jetways, LOD optimization, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.50, requiring at least 1.61 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/joemoe</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Development Progress on Oslo Gardermoen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/joemoe"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a1c4ff26983e141b4abff7_engm1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Jo Erlend has published a new batch of screenshots showcasing the development progress on his rendition of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM), to be distributed by Aerosoft. It’s the busiest airport in Norway, with a yearly average of 30 million passengers.  It is the main airport serving Oslo, located approximately 47 kilometers northeast of the city center. It opened in 1998 to replace the outdated Fornebu Airport, which had been operating since 1939. It was built to modernize and expand Norway’s airport infrastructure and improve accessibility to the capital city, quickly becoming the Main hub for domestic and international travel in the Country.   The new previews focus on ground service equipment, some of the detail work on the airside part of the terminal, and a short video demonstrating the night light effects.  There is no price or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you updated!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimjfk</id>
    <title>Nimbus Releases John F. Kennedy International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimjfk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a6f3d1727a992e0b11850b_nimbus1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has recently released their rendition of New York - John Fitzgerald Kennedy International (KJFK) for X-Plane 12, the busiest airport in New York City with a yearly average of 60 million passengers. ‍ Built on top of an old golf course 74 years ago, the then-called Idlewild Airport had a single 7,365 square meter terminal and six runways. The current name only came to be in late 1963, after John F. Kennedy’s assassination. It also marked the important leap to the busiest airport in the region, beating LaGuardia and reaching a respectable second place overall in the United States. ‍ The busiest international gateway to the United States is served and visited by over 90 airlines, covering all the inhabited continents around the globe. JetBlue tops the market share chart, with 28.8% or 15,624,961 passengers, followed by Delta Air Lines and American Airlines, with 28.4% (15,390,437) and 14.5% (7,870,971), respectively. From foreign operators, Air France leads the way with 1.9% of the total market share or 1,025,339 passengers. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR materials, custom night lighting, 3D native XP12 trees, populated parking lots, high-quality PBR vehicles, terminals with their respective interiors, native X-Plane ground traffic, native jetway system, water and snow effects, guidance lights for the Canarsie approach, and more.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $29.95, requiring at least 1.3 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbcoa</id>
    <title>Orbx’s Gold Coast Airport is Coming Soon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbcoa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a6f8a807177ff354b795a4_ybcg1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx's recently announced Gold Coast Airport (YBCG) is on "short final," according to a development update in their forum, bringing an up-to-date rendition of the seventh busiest airport in Australia to Microsoft Flight Simulator. It was built in 1936, consisting of three grass strips whose sole intent was to provide an emergency landing spot for aircraft flying between Brisbane and Sydney, with passenger service only beginning three years later. Regular service was only to begin after WW2, with Queensland Airlines and Butler Air Transport, followed by Ansett in 1950 and Trans Australia Airlines in 1954. Taxiways and runways were fully paved by 1958, allowing for the operation of larger, heavier aircraft such as the DC-9 and L-188 Electra. The current passenger terminal was opened in 1981 by Acting Prime Minister Douglas Anthony. The following year saw the main runway extended to 2,042 meters, allowing for the operation of wide-body jet aircraft. It was later extended to 2,500 meters sometime in 2007. The passenger terminal was upgraded in 2010, with an expansion that doubled its total size, accommodating a decade's worth of growth in passenger volume. It was then expanded again in 2016, 2019, and 2022, with a 30,000-square-meter expansion and overall infrastructure modernization. It's a hub for Bonza. AirAsia X, Air New Zealand, Eastern Air Services, Jetstar, Qantas, QantasLink, Rex Airlines, Seair Pacific, and Virgin Australia serve it regularly. Developed by Matteo Veneziani, the scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, 4K textures, an interior on the main terminal, unique GSE vehicles, dynamic airport lighting, custom ground textures, custom animated jetways, performance-friendly optimization, and more.  Pricing and release date are not available yet, but it's said to be coming soon.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbstn</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Gladstone Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbstn"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a6fd6070bb3fdfbfb673a6_glads1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of Gladstone Airport (YGLA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Gladstone in Queensland (Australia) with a yearly average of 240,000 passengers (as of 2011). It was built on a bulldozed airstrip in 1953, with work completed in 1956 and its official opening in 1957, although it had been frequently used a few months prior.  Nowadays, it’s owned and operated by the Gladstone Regional Council, which took the helm after the former owner (Gladstone-Calliope Aerodrome Board) was dissolved in 2007.   Bonza, QantasLink, and Virgin Australia currently serve it with flights to Brisbane, Gold Coast, and Melbourne.  ‍ The scenery will feature an up-to-date ground layout, custom runway and taxiway light models, and more. ‍ There’s still no information on pricing or a potential release date.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bladuk</id>
    <title>Black Square Publishes Development Update on the Dukes for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bladuk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a708129bb6cca94f6081e6_duke.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently published a new development update on their rendition of the Piston Duke and Turbine Duke for Microsoft Flight Simulator, modeled after the Beechcraft 60 Duke and BLR Performance Innovation's Grand Duke package, respectively.  The Beechcraft 60 Duke is a twin-engine fixed-wing aircraft first flown in 1966 and introduced in 1968, with 596 built during its fifteen years of production. Black Square's rendition uses the 1974 model as a reference (when the B60 variant was introduced with interior arrangement renovations and engine efficiency tweaks). It's powered by two Lycoming TIO541-E1C4 engines, developing 380 hp each, cruising at 330 km/h, with a service ceiling of 30,000ft and 1,227nm of range at 20,000ft with 45% power.  The Grand Duke package, on the other hand, adds 190 pounds of useful load, a 350 fpm increase in climb rate with winglets, and significantly lower approach speeds. The vortex generators are also said to make a dramatic difference in the aircraft's flight characteristics, considerably improving its safety may an emergency arise. Nick Cyganski, the developer, has spent months developing "countless new features" that were never seen before in Microsoft Flight Simulator, some of which shall make their way into older Black Square products in the near future. The first of these features is the new in-cockpit EFB tablet, claimed to be the most complete interface yet for monitoring systems in the simulator. It includes an option configuration, payload and fuel manager, live electrical schematic, and failure options.   Their goal was the creation of real-time graphical representations of some of the most complex systems in general aviation aircraft, allowing both experienced and novice pilots to understand an aircraft's intricacies. The Piston Duke (B60) will feature a reciprocating engine simulation, completely overhauling the engine start procedure and propeller feathering, along with the pre-existing fouling, vapor lock, flooding, backfire, and turbocharger simulations already present in their previous products. The crankshaft is driven by the physics of cylinder compression, fuel ignition, propeller drag, and friction throughout, and the engine oil pressure drives the propeller feathering, as in real life.  It will also feature instrument stiction and friction physics, with needles that can get temporarily stuck and unstuck with the engine vibration. Alternatively, one can tap on the gauges to get the needles to unstick.  The sounds were developed in partnership with Boris Audio Works, ensuring a high-quality sound floor on both variants.  Regarding navigation, it will feature the freeware KLN-90B GPS Navigator, along with support for the PMS GTN650 and TDS GTN650Xis, with 12 hot-swapping avionics combinations in total.   Beta testing has already started, and they plan to release the airplanes in March 2024. They will be available separately and in a discounted bundle, with a PDF user manual and a series of videos on Just Flights' YouTube channel.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbana</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Anacortes Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbana"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a70ba0814a009f818cceae_ana1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of Anacortes Airport (74S) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public-use airport serving Anacortes, Washington, with a yearly average of 9,000 aircraft operations. It was built in 1968 and inaugurated in 1969 on land purchased by the Port of Anacortes using FAA grant money. It’s included in FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems for 2017-2021 as a local general aviation facility, corresponding to 73% of its yearly traffic as of 2014. Air taxis make up the other 17%.  ‍ Developed by Andreas Hegi, the scenery was completely rebuilt for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with a 3D terminal interior, custom PBR textures, an accurate ground layout, custom airport signs and markings, and more.  There’s no information on the release date or pricing yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbluk</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Banja Luka International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbluk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a84636052597a2761c6cf8_banja.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of Banja Luka International Airport (LQBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Banja Luka in Bosnia and Herzegovina, with a yearly average of 460,719 passengers as of 2023. ‍ Construction started in 1976, and the airport was initially part of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, operating as a strictly domestic airport for many years. After the Bosnian War and the creation of Republika Srpska, Banja Luka was established as the capital, and the airport was granted international status and opened for civilian traffic in 1997.  ‍ The airport underwent heavy upgrade work between 2002 and 2003 for Pope John Paul II's visit in June 2003.  ‍ Aegean Airlines (seasonal), Air Cairo (seasonal), Air Serbia, Freebird Airlines (seasonal), Nouvelair (seasonal), Ryanair, Tailwind Airlines (seasonal), and WizzAir currently serve it. ‍ Developed by indie Radoslav Tucakov, the scenery features fully custom terminals and buildings, interior details, exquisite perimeter details, a custom village and air base near the airport, PBR texturing, and more. ‍ There's no information on the release date and pricing yet.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiman</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Manchester International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiman"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a859e05326a6f587cf3f15_manchester.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the third busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 23.3 million passengers.  Construction work began in 1935, and the airport was partially operating by 1937 (the official conclusion happened a year later). KLM was the first airline to launch scheduled commercial flights to the newly opened airport in 1938. ‍ It was converted into an RAF base during WW2 and played an essential role in military aircraft production and parachutist training. ‍ The post-war period saw its return as a commercial airport, with rapid growth during the 50s and 60s, where it eventually managed to be Britain's second busiest airport after London Heathrow. ‍ ‍ The airport was heavily expanded in the 80s and 90s to keep up with the exponential growth figures, eventually leading to the millionth passenger in a month mark in 1987. Plans for a new terminal were put in place, and it was opened by Princess Diana as Terminal A in 1989.  ‍ From 1997 to 2001, a second runway was built, leading to many protests from locals because natural habitats were disturbed and listed buildings had to be demolished, but they didn't have another option. ‍ New expansion work started in 2019 to keep up with the ever-growing passenger traffic figures. ‍ EasyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways have operating bases in Manchester. Many airlines from around the Globe serve it, including Air Canada, Air France, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad, Finnair, KLM, Kuwait Airways, Lufthansa, Qatar, Scandinavian Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish, Virgin Atlantic, and more. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models, SAM jetways, high-quality PBR textures, performance-friendly optimization, complete autogen around the airport, ground traffic plugins, and weather textures for X-Plane 12. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $26.11, requiring at least 3.78 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini103</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini103"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a9a2d24bcaac26dd4c31b3_a300mon.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued the third update for their recently released Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing many bug fixes, EFB improvements, and more. ‍  Update 1.0.3 brings animation and light position fixes, tweaks to the fuel system, and new EFB features for throttle calibration, draggable charts, and many system changes. The changelog follows below: ‍ ‍ Sounds Fixes/Changes  The update is available right now via iniManager for all owners.  The airplane can be purchased on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orygla</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Gladstone Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orygla"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aaee7deb1854891d1bf587_gladstone.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Gladstone Airport (YGLA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Gladstone in Queensland, Australia, with a yearly average of 240,000 passengers (as of 2011).  ‍ It was built on a bulldozed airstrip in 1953, with work completed in 1956 and its official opening in 1957, although it had been frequently used a few months prior. ‍ Nowadays, it’s owned and operated by the Gladstone Regional Council, which took the helm after the former owner (Gladstone-Calliope Aerodrome Board) was dissolved in 2007. ‍ Bonza, QantasLink, and Virgin Australia currently serve it with flights to Brisbane, Gold Coast, and Melbourne. ‍ ‍  The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, extensive terraforming, highly realistic aprons and taxiways, custom runway and taxiway light models, animated trains, realistic rail infrastructure, detailed terminal interiors, and crisp 15cm aerial imagery. ‍  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.26, requiring at least 1.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hlub</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Lubbock Preston Smith International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hlub"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aaf65a7fd8d4ba6f57327d_lubbock.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Lubbock Preston Smith International Airport (KLBB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Lubbock, Texas, with a yearly average of 520,000 passengers, making it the eighth busiest in the state. ‍ It opened in November 1937 as South Plains Airport. It was assigned to the World War 2 Army Air Forces Flying Training Command in 1942, then renamed South Plains Army Airfield and entirely converted to a military training airfield. ‍ The conversion process added three concrete runways, taxiways, a large apron, a control tower, and many large hangars made of semi-permanent materials, as they were intended for short-term usage. ‍  The base was activated that same year and remained in use by the military as a storage facility for two years after the war.  ‍ The end of 1947 marked its return to the government for civil use, and they built a passenger terminal around the southwest corner of the airfield that was actively used during the 50s and 60s. ‍ The passenger terminal was replaced by a bigger one in 1976, which is still in use today, albeit heavily upgraded over the years, with the latest one dating back to 2021. ‍ ‍ American Airlines, American Eagle, Southwest Airlines, and United Express currently serve it. Dallas Love Field is the busiest destination, with 168,000 passengers yearly, followed by Dallas-Fort Worth (147,000) and Denver (52,000). ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and high-detail models of the buildings, objects, and surroundings. ‍  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.24, requiring at least 3.84 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfl710</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker 70/100 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfl710"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aafd0d6258942e8a3fe157_fukker.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a new development update reporting their progress on the Fokker 70/100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, focusing on sound recordings. ‍ The developers claim that one of the most difficult aspects of aircraft development for a simulator is getting access to a real aircraft for sound recording. While it’s relatively easier to access older aircraft in museums for recording switches, knobs, doors, and so on, engine sounds can’t be recorded as they are generally no longer functional, making that part rather challenging. ‍ They managed to get access to three real Fokkers during a maintenance run-up in The Netherlands, recording high-quality audio from the turbine from RR Tay 620s and 650s (Fokker 70’s engines and 100, respectively), from low to full power band.  ‍ ‍ To read more about the recording session, click here for the full development update.  ‍ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgrio</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Releases Rio Branco International Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgrio"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ad9ad07954411000e5657e_riobranco.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently released an upgraded rendition of their Rio Branco International Airport (SBRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Rio Branco, Acre, Brazil, with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers. ‍ It was inaugurated 24 years ago, replacing Rio Branco’s previous main airport, whose area was not government-owned and judicially given back to its rightful owner, meaning they had to start from scratch on another piece of land.  ‍ It was expanded for the first time in 2014, bringing the passenger handling capabilities up to 2,4 million passengers yearly. ‍ Azul, GOL, and LATAM serve it regularly with flights to their hubs. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside, custom ground clutter, custom ground service equipment, and more. ‍ ‍ ‍ It’s available in their store for roughly $6. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbskan</id>
    <title>DarkBlueScenery Releases Kansai International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12 </title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbskan"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ada099d5b1da0944054bc6_kansai.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DarkBlueScenery has recently released their rendition of Kansai International Airport (RJBB) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Greater Osaka Area with a yearly average of 28 million passengers, making it the 3rd busiest in Japan. ‍ It opened in 1994 and was built to relieve overcrowding at Itami Airport, Osaka’s former main airport, with two large terminals designed by Renzo Piano. It’s the longest terminal in the world, with a length of 1.7km. ‍ Construction work started in 1987, and they had to build an artificial island with a sea wall, drainage system, and bridge to connect with the city. It eventually became the most expensive civil project in modern history, with a 15 billion dollar investment. The “growing pains” of creating an earthquake-proof artificial island paved the way for the New Kitakyushu Airport, Kobe Airport, Chubu Centrair International Airport, and even Hong Kong International Airport.  ‍ ‍ Its earthquake-proofness was tested just a year after its inauguration when Japan was struck by the Great Hanshin earthquake, whose epicenter was only 20 km from the airport. Yet, it didn’t sustain any damage at all. Four years later, its design was proven again when it survived a typhoon.  ‍ ‍ The fact it sits on an artificial piece of land has its downsides, though, with the total costs rising to 20 billion in the mid-2000s with all the maintenance work to stop it from sinking, which the engineers had predicted and expected. ‍ ‍ A new terminal building was inaugurated in 2012, further increasing its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ It’s a hub for All Nippon Airways, FedEx Express, Japan Airlines, Jetstar Japan, Nippon Cargo Airlines, and Peach Aviation. It’s served by many airlines from the neighboring countries and a few popular carriers from Europe, such as Air France, KLM, and Lufthansa. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K textures, custom ground markings, custom taxiway signs, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, accurate terraforming, and an accurately represented runway 06R/24L at its current status. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.41, requiring at least 808.75 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/330024</id>
    <title>Aerosoft’s Airbus A330 Shifted to MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/330024"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aee96a5efaf1c7b2c4c0de_aerosoftdelay.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has published their first A330 development update for 2024, stating their decision to shift the development effort to the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, allowing them to “greatly expand the focus of the project.” ‍ Announced three years ago, in January 2021, their A330 project won’t be coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, as they have decided to focus on the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 instead. Aerosoft will include multiple engine options, including a simultaneous release of the Neo and Ceo variants.  Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft’s former project manager, has made a statement in the Aerosoft forums, saying it’s a “puzzling statement” and a “surprising twist,” given they had recently tuned and tweaked the engine simulation and the new simulator might render all that work useless, leading to a full rework, and, potentially, further delays. “As there is no known release date of FS2024 and nobody knows how much adaptation will be needed, you end up with a project with no scheduled release date”, he completed.  ‍ Their decision to release for MSFS 2024 leads to many questions because little is known about the sim’s innards, how the backward compatibility will work, and how much it could further complicate the development process.  There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
