<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-17T18:20:45.387076+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inlppd</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Ponta Delgada - João Paulo II Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inlppd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d3963c85019f537ebbc02b_lppd1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="611286"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Ponta Delgada - João Paulo II Airport (LPPD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the municipality of Ponta Delgada in the Archipelago of the Azores with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport's construction started in 1963, with the official inauguration only happening six years later in 1969 by President Américo Tomás. Its primary purpose was serving inter-island connections and Europe, with regular flights to Lisbon beginning a year later.  A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1995 when the airport also got its current name after the Pope's visit to the Azores four years prior.  The following decade post-new terminal brought massive growth in passenger traffic, which has been steadily growing, connecting the Azores to the world.  Azores Airlines, Binter Canarias, British Airways, Edelweiss Air, Iberia, Lufthansa, Ryanair, SATA Air Açores, Smartwings, Swiss, TAP, Transavia, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Netherlands, and United Airlines all serve it, with most of them only offering their services during summer. It's also the most important cargo airport in the archipelago, handling over 10,000 tonnes yearly.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, hand-made textures, custom POIs, true-to-life landside recreation, a detailed terminal interior, an official GSX profile, and more.  It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.55, requiring at least 3.06 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winbsa</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Benito Salas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winbsa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d3a1aa257b3f6140bd6125_benito1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2764768"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Benito Salas Airport (SKNV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Neiva in Colombia with a yearly average of 270,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was built on land that once belonged to Bertha Borrero de Valenzuela (La Manguita Farm), Abacú Lozano, and Silvestre Falla Borrero, totaling up to 130 hectares. It was inaugurated under the government of President Misael Pastrana Borrero in 1974, with the terminal design signed by Antonio Uribe Martínez, a famous architect from Bogotá, making use of modern lines, large terraces, thick walls, and exposed brick facades. ‍ The airport is currently undergoing a renovation process that includes a new control tower and an improved parking garage. ‍ It’s served by Avianca, EasyFly, and LATAM Colombia, with daily flights to Bogotá and Cali (EasyFly only). ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom ground equipment, an up-to-date layout, a custom terminal interior, custom night lighting, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.84, requiring at least 995.73 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fv2bl1</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases A320 V2 Block 1 Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fv2bl1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d4fc1d20f1131e285fa6fb_v2-release.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="379095"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently released their biggest update so far for their A320 add-on, adding a new display rendering method, new pax layout, flight model improvements, and more.  According to the developers in a development update published earlier today, the update almost got delayed due to a game-breaking issue, which they managed to fix after three days of extensive testing.  Update v1.5.1.193 will bring substantial changes to the aircraft, easily noticeable through the hefty changelog with multiple fixes and additions. The highlights of V2 Block 1 are the new displays, performance improvements (which we have previously covered and shown some of their benchmarks), and a new flight model, with tweaks to the airplane’s behavior on multiple stages of the flight. The changelog follows down below: ‍ V2 Block 1 A320 CFM V1.5.1.193 [APP] [EFB] [DISPLAYS] [FM, FBW &amp; AUTOFLIGHT] [AVIONICS &amp; SYSTEMS] [VISUALS] [SOUND] [KNOWN ISSUES] ‍  The developers also warned about the fact that the aircraft is transitioning from a nine-month release to a completely different build tested by their internal circle of testers, reinstating that even though they have tested it a lot, oddities could happen on various hardware configurations.  The second part of the V2 update - Block 2 - is set to release next month, bringing an improved 3D model, a new engine option, and tweaks to some of the systems.  The add-on is available on the Fenix Simulations store for roughly $63.65.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flytee</id>
    <title>Fly X Simulations Releases Teesside International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flytee" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d51e374343d6f91839bd3f_tee1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="757840"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly X Simulations has recently released their rendition of Teesside International Airport (EGNV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving North East England with a yearly average of 200,000 passengers.  It started as an RAF airfield in 1941, housing the RAF and the Royal Canadian Air Force during WW2.   Twenty years later, the airfield was developed into a civil airport named Tees-Side Airport. Many airlines served it during its first decade, including British Midland, BKS Air Transport, Dan-Air, Autair, and Channel Airways.   The 1970s were particularly rough for Teesside regarding scheduled services, with holiday flights becoming its primary source of passenger traffic through the wings of Northeast Airlines, Britannia Airways, Aviaco, Spantax, and Aviogenex.   Privatization came in 1987, with local authorities retaining their shares and the airport getting its current name: Teesside International Airport.  The airport was heavily upgraded in 2017 after a troublesome decade post-2008 crisis leading to a massive drop in passenger traffic figures leading to many airlines abandoning it for other nearby airports.   The renewal and subsequent takeover in 2018 brought back a lot of traffic, and the figures have been rising ever since.  BH Air, Eastern Airways, KLM, Loganair, Ryanair, and TUI Airways currently serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR texturing, custom orthophoto for the airport and surroundings, custom terminal interior, custom ground textures, high-resolution textures, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.25, requiring at least 2.76 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthpva</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Puerto Vallarta Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthpva" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d5279471883bb3ca9c9dae_val1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1449461"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Licenciado Gustavo Díaz Ordaz International Airport (MMPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Puerto Vallarta in Mexico with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. ‍ The airport’s history dates back to the early 20th century when it started as a small airstrip serving the then small fishing village of Puerto Vallarta. In the 1960s, with Puerto Vallarta’s tourist boom, the government decided to invest in its potential and build a proper airport, which only started in the early 1970s, inaugurated in 1974. ‍ The airport has been upgraded and expanded multiple times ever since, with the most recent one starting in 2022, allowing for 65% more operations a year. ‍ It’s served by multiple airlines, including Aeroméxico, Aeroméxico Connect, Air Canada, Air Transat, Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Finnair, Flair Airlines, Frontier Airlines, Magnicharters, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, Sunwing Airlines, Swoop, TAR, TUI Airways, United Airlines, United Express, Viva Aerobus, Volaris, and WestJet. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail buildings, PBR texturing, custom animated jetways, custom ground poly, improved taxiway and runway lighting, hand-placed objects and clutter, and custom night lighting.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.73, requiring at least 339.26 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cssdvu</id>
    <title> Crosstail Studios' A-1H Skyraider Dev Update</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cssdvu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d650eb3a496e72855c8eb9_366375757_666912625484279_6941976853579164448_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="265516"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Crosstail Studios has made amazing progress in their A-1H Skyraider module for DCS World. They have all been working day and night in order to produce a realistic rendition of this magnificent aircraft. There are multiple areas which are touched on in this article ranging from Flight Model changes to their Future development plans. ‍ The journey has just begun! With plans to infuse life-like animations and intricate textures. Stay tuned, as they continue to develop this amazing aircraft and more updates come to light. In conclusion, Crosstail Studios continues to provide development updates to this module and although no pricing information or release date has been confirmed, Threshold will keep you informed as more news comes to light. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a120</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a120" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d65769ea6688dd6d79da83_comanche45.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="714985"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche to version 1.2.0, improving animations, ground physics tweaks, auto-rudder support, and more.  It’s the second update since its release in mid-July, bringing 40 changes. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ ‍ They finish the update announcement with a note saying they are still investigating an issue where the tablet is unclickable on SU13 Beta for VR users.  The add-on is available on their store for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfshou</id>
    <title>Windsock Simulations Bringing Houston Hobby to X-Plane 12!</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfshou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d67b17ef330ca4edb342d6_364801211_615774600538721_677912053120229073_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="230414"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Windsock Simulations has announced a partnership with FSim Studios which will bring their rendition of Houston's William P. Hobby airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12.  William P. Hobby Airport (KHOU) is located 7 miles from downtown Houston and is the oldest operating airport in the area. Houston Hobby as it's referred to features 4 runways and acts as a main operating base for Southwest Airlines. The airport sees over 13 million passengers each year and has flights operating to most parts of the United States as well as international service to many Central and South American destinations. Windsock stated in their announcement that the project is still in its early stages but is progressing quickly. They have not announced a release date, yet but have said "we don't expect it to be long…" Threshold is excited to bring you future updates on this and many other projects! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pu7071</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pu7071" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d6c38610115e25ed35735c_1250410_20230529191347_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2156550"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their 737 Lineup to version 3.00.0071, improving its stability, performance, and functionality on PC and Xbox. The new update focuses on performance improvements for lower-end machines and the Xbox Series S, improving memory usage. They have also fixed the engine spool behavior in low RPM ranges and made some AFDS roll control mode law adjustments, initialization sequence improvements, and back-end changes for future EFT compatibility. The complete changelog follows down below:   Robert Randazzo has also informed us about a delay on the 737-700 and -800's 3.00.0070 update on Marketplace (a version behind), which should match the other members of the lineup on 3.00.0071.   The EFB is still undergoing testing, with them recently pushing a build to their beta team with changes based on their feedback. They are already discussing a potential release date.  The 737 Lineup is available on PMDG's Store for $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800), $49.99 (737-900), and $34.99 (737-600). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teaneo</id>
    <title>Threshold Exclusive: Aerosoft Developing A321neo Alongside A330neo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teaneo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d6ec3b8a303ebccfee5d41_Airbus%20Neo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="514500"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. German flight sim developer Aerosoft is planning to develop an Airbus A321neo alongside the previously announced A330neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  ‍ According to a post on the website of the German Ministry of Economic Affairs and Climate Action, Aerosoft has received €459,000 from a grant to partially fund their development of the “AirbusNEO series”, which includes the A330neo and A321neo.  ‍ ‍ The grant was set up by the German government in 2019 to help boost the games sector within Germany, and to make Germany a hub for game development in Europe. The German government has provided up to €50 million each year in grants, and has funded over 400 different video game projects. ‍ Currently, Aerosoft has been hard at work on their highly anticipated A330ceo project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which has come under new management after their previous product manager of more than twenty years, Mathijs Kok, left Aerosoft for the PMDG team. As of the time of writing, Kok’s new position at PMDG has not been revealed to the public yet.As for the A321neo and A330neo, there are a lot of unknowns about their respective projects. The posting on the website says that, “Numerous functions, animations and sound effects are to be developed using state-of-the-art tools that have not yet been implemented in Microsoft Flight Simulator”, suggesting that the complexity of these two aircraft will be something unlike their previous work in MSFS. We do not know when an intended release date would be, which aircraft will be released first, or if Aerosoft plans on releasing them as a bundle, as suggested by the post.  ‍ At this point in time, much about both aircraft are up to speculation, but what we do know for certain is that they are planned, and they are coming in the near future.Threshold will keep you updated on all the developments regarding the upcoming Aerosoft airliners, so stay tuned! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mwitmg</id>
    <title>Matt Wagner Interviewed on 'The Mover and Gonky Show'</title>
    <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mwitmg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b327f6678e65e8f3e4d339_DCS_2.8_World_Combat_Flight_Simulator-04.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1140902"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Matt Wagner was recently Interviewed on 'The Mover and Gonky Show'. This was a two hour long video which included a DCS World Q&amp;A. There are some interesting points made in the video so I encourage you to watch the video aswell.  A Broader Scope:The grand vision is to have a battlefield where ground units can operate seamlessly alongside helicopters and jets. This would mean an immersive experience where users could transition between different theaters of war, each detailed and realistic. ‍ Ground Movement Animation:One of the focal areas for the Eagle Dynamics team currently is the ground movement for infantry. The older animations have stood the test of time but are now due for a refresh. An updated animation is in the works, promising more fluid and realistic movements, in sync with the advancements in game development technology. ‍ New Additions and Updates:While some might be disappointed about the absence of Ukraine and Taiwan maps due to their sensitive nature, the future holds promise: Media Influence:The recent release of Top Gun 2 has spurred an interest in DCS modules. The movie's success resulted in a surge of sales for DCS modules, prompting Eagle Dynamics to release the special 'Be a Maverick' pack, which bundled the F-14, F/A-18, and Supercarrier. ‍ Challenges and Solutions:It's not just about adding new content, but also about refining existing modules: ‍ Potential Future Additions:Questions have arisen regarding the addition of certain aircraft like the SAAB Gripen or the Rafael. The challenge in adding 4+ gen aircraft is the acquisition of necessary resources. However, with partnerships and introductions, nothing is off the table. There's even been talk about the Flanker being introduced as a full-fidelity DCS module, though data acquisition remains a significant hurdle. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kpvums</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Announces KPVU for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kpvums" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d965b9fb858e6b7c40cb29_Screenshot%202023-08-13%20at%207.19.22%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1467477"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has announced they are working on a version of Provo Municipal Airport (KPVU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The announcement comes just two days after a post the developer made on their social media accounts hinting that an announcement would be coming for somewhere "they love Beehives and Skiing".  ‍ Provo Municipal Airport is located 2 miles west of the city of Provo, Utah, and offers flights from both Allegiant Air and Breeze Airways. Provo Municipal features two runways with the larger of the two being 8600 feet long. The airport offers both terminal facilities as well as two FBOs (signature and Duncan Aviation). ‍ Verticalsim promises a list of features for the scenery that includes custom Ortho, high-resolution texturing, custom taxiway signage, and proper airport lighting. At this time the developer has not announced a release date or price point for the project. Threshold looks forward to bringing you updates on this and other flight sim projects, stay tuned for more! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiosl</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Oslo Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiosl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64db78f35b8f7a3fa27551ff_osl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3776960"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Oslo Airport (ENGM) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Greater Oslo Region with a yearly average of 30 million passengers.  It was opened 25 years ago, replacing Oslo's former main airport (Fornebu), deemed too small for the ever-growing demand for air travel in the region.  Sporting over 200 destinations (domestic and international), OSL is a hub for Norse Atlantic Airways, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe. The visitors' list includes most major european airlines, such as Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Swiss, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish, and WizzAir. Trondheim (2,092,000), Bergen (1,987,000), and Stavanger (1,603,000) are among the top three busiest destinations from Gardermoen, further reinforcing the strength of domestic operations in the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models, SAM animated jetways, PBR texturing on objects and ground, custom ground textures, ground traffic plugin, custom autogen around the airport, and performance-friendly optimization.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $24.04, requiring at least 2.72 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgbur</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Announces Uberaba Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgbur" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64db883044d339e25f2f93b4_sbur.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="498300"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently announced the development of Uberaba - Mário de Almeida Franco Airport (SBUR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Uberaba in Minas Gerais, Brazil, with a yearly average of 104,856 passengers. ‍ The airport was built in the 1930s, with its commercial debut in April 1934: a VASP flight on a Monospar ST4 from São Paulo, with a single stop in Ribeirão Preto. During its first decades of operation, it was only an airfield.  ‍ A passenger terminal was only built in 1950, and promotion to airport status only came in 1958 after it was donated from the city to the government (the now defunct Ministry of Aviation).  ‍ Infraero (a state-controlled airport administration company) took control in 1980, investing heavily in modernization and bringing it up to the expected standard of a commercial airport in Brazil: night lighting, a meteorological station, and an eventual terminal expansion many years later in 2008, doubling its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ It was recently purchased by Aena, granting them 30 years of administrative rights over the airport and the obligation of modernizing it within five years of taking control (by 2027, at the very least).  ‍ ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a detailed terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ There’s no release date or price information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgmaf</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Releases Uberaba Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgmaf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64dd0a1576ab009e67160439_1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="359609"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently released their rendition of Uberaba - Mário de Almeida Franco Airport (SBUR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Uberaba in Minas Gerais, Brazil, with a yearly average of 104,856 passengers.  Built in the early 1930s as an airfield, its commercial debut only happened in 1934 with a VASP flight on a Monospar ST4 from São Paulo with a single stop in Ribeirão Preto.  A passenger terminal was only built in 1950, and promotion to airport status only came in 1958 after it was donated from the city to the government (the now defunct Ministry of Aviation).  Infraero (a state-controlled airport administration company) took control in 1980, investing heavily in modernization and bringing it up to the expected standard of a commercial airport in Brazil: night lighting, a meteorological station, and an eventual terminal expansion many years later in 2008, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It was recently purchased by Aena, granting them 30 years of administrative rights over the airport and the obligation of modernizing it within five years of taking control (by 2027, at the very least).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a detailed terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  It’s available in their official shop for roughly $7.03. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflsof</id>
    <title>AflOSim Releases Sofia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflsof" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64dd11757ace5260f080195a_sof1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="984183"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AflOSim has recently released their rendition of Sofia Airport (LBSF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the capital city of Sofia in Bulgaria with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  The airport was built after a decree from Tsar Boris III in 1937 authorizing the construction on land within the village of Vrazhdebna. It was inaugurated two years later with its first passenger terminal.   After a brief period of military exclusivity during World War 2, it was returned to the city in 1947 with a new passenger terminal designed by Ivan Marangozov.   In the 1960s, said terminal was already at capacity, with extension work starting in 1968 to counter that issue. From a measly 600,000 passengers in the 60s, the airport was handling around 3 million passengers by the late 1970s.   With the numbers constantly growing, they started planning a new expansion in the 1990s, which comprehended the construction of Terminal 2. It was formally opened in 2006, after a 200 million euros investment from the European Investment Bank and the Kuwait Fund for Arab Economic Development.   Terminal 1 serves low-cost carriers such as WizzAir, easyJet, and European Air. Terminal 2 handles the “fancy” carriers with seven air bridges, 50,000 square meters of total area, 38 check-in desks, and a car park for 820 vehicles.  Aegean Airlines, Air Cairo, Air Serbia, Austrian Airlines, BH Air, British Airways, Bulgaria Air, Corendon Airlines, easyJet, EI AI, European Air Charter, flydubai, GullivAir, ITA Airways, Jet2.com, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Ryanair, Sky Express, SkyUp, Sun Express, Swiss International Air Lines, TAROM, TUI Airways, Turkish Airlines, Windrose Airlines, and WizzAir serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, moving jetways, animated people, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.27, requiring at least 621.71 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
