<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-11-12T18:34:26.112173+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pescdg</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Shares Charles de Gaulle Airport Previews for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pescdg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cc289c47b5cf47ce7cdd4_cdg1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pilot Experience Sim has shared previews of their upcoming Charles de Gaulle Airport (LFPG) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, Europe’s third-busiest airport, with a yearly average of 70.3 million passengers. The previews showcase their work on the ground textures near the runway, as well as a sneak peek of the control tower’s exterior and interior.  While there are no previews of the terminals yet, they ensure it’s being worked on, and images will be shared once it's deemed ready. ‍ There is no information regarding pricing or a potential release date, but Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdskrg</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases José María Córdova International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdskrg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cc41dc714587051b49d5c_skr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Colombian Virtual Design has recently released their rendition of José María Córdova International Airport (SKRG) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, located in Rionegro, 20 km away from Medellín, serving the entire Medellin Metropolitan Area with many destinations, both domestic and international. It is the second busiest airport in Colombia with 9 million passengers yearly.  It’s a hub for Avianca Colombia, Ultra Air, and Viva Air Colombia, with a destination list that encompasses Colombia, Mexico, the United States, and some of Europe. LATAM Colombia also features a list of domestic destinations from Rionegro. Among the international visitors, there’s Aeromexico with a hop to Mexico City, Air Europa with a long haul to Madrid, JetBlue to Fort Lauderdale, LATAM Perú to Lima, and Spirit Airlines with the Floridian trifecta (Fort Lauderdale, Miami, and Orlando). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal model, 4K textures, custom jetways, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, realistic ground markings, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.24, requiring at least 1.48 GB of free disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrxuxp12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases Weather Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrxuxp12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cdc7791c805834e8e819c_wea1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently released the long-awaited version 12.3.0 to the public, codenamed “Weather Update”. This significant update introduces a functional weather radar to the platform, A330 improvements, historical weather data, new camera controls, and more.  Featuring a brand-new, fully functioning weather radar, coupled with synthetic vision on their in-house Garmin G1000 simulation, virtually flying has reached never-before-seen levels of situational awareness.  The update also fully revamps the default Airbus A330-300, introducing refinements to most systems and resulting in a more accurate overall experience. It also includes exterior weathering, engine vibration animations, and interior changes (the cockpit lighting has been enhanced with backlit instruments, realistic spill lighting, and improved annunciator effects). Additionally, the flight management systems were tweaked to fully support a secondary flight plan, enhanced VNAV simulation, accurate roll rate and alpha protection under FBW, more precise climb, cruise, and descent predictions considering wind, constraints, and fuel use, and updated V-speed suggestions, fuel prediction logic, and ECAM messages. The Aircraft Operations Computer (AOC) and ATSU (Air Traffic Services Unit) on the A330 have been tweaked to realistically support ATIS, METAR, and PDC messages, with ACARS-style memo displays, and realistic data-link transmission delays. Furthermore, there were slight tweaks to the camera system, allowing users to adjust the intensity of the G-Loaded Camera, and the addition of a new hand-crafted airport (OMDB). ​ The aforementioned weather radar is now present in their A330, Boeing 738, on the X1000 (their Garmin G1000), and also on the “Benedix” RDR2000 WXR, their own interpretation of a Bendix-King weather radar, present on the Beechcraft Baron 58 and fully integratable with third-party aircraft (the source code is public on GitHub, and addon developers may modify it to suit their use-cases). In addition to the weather radar, 738 pilots may now enjoy the benefit of a terrain display, which seamlessly integrates with X-Plane’s global terrain database, thereby greatly enhancing situational awareness during mid-flight.  ​ They have also introduced an “engine health” system, where developers can enable engine “ages” at load, introducing natural variation in performance from the get-go, as in the real world. ​ The complete feature list and changelog are available on their blog. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/propklit</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Releases Little Rock Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/propklit"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690ce05098a91fa023973148_klit1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Propair Flight has recently released their rendition of Bill and Hillary Clinton National Airport (KLIT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Little Rock, Arkansas, with a yearly average of 2.3 million passengers, making it the second-largest commercial airport in the state. The airport opened in 1931 as Adams Field, after Captain George Geyer Adams, a city councilor for Little Rock and a strong advocate for the airport’s creation and opening.  With the advent of World War 2, the airport was utilized by the United States Army Air Forces Third Air Force for antisubmarine patrols and training.  The current passenger terminal was opened in 1972, with 12 gates. In early 2012, the airport’s name was changed from Adams Field to Bill and Hillary Clinton National Airport, after the Arkansas Native and former President Bill Clinton and his wife.  A year later, the airport featured as the worst among 67 domestic airports in a survey regarding passenger experience, with long lines and few food options among the main points of criticism. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, and United Express serve it. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a custom ground polygon, high-detail building models, custom animated jetways, realistic night lighting, animated people, an up-to-date taxiway network, and toggleable static aircraft. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.09, requiring at least 4.58 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msegpo</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Stornoway Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msegpo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690de8cdb7bd899f2b95cdc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDG has released its version of Stornoway Airport (EGPO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located on the Isle of Lewis in Scotland, just 2.3 miles from the town of Stornoway, the airport welcomes over 100,000 passengers yearly. Opened in 1937 for military purposes, the airfield served as a base for the Royal Air Force during the Second World War and later as a NATO forward operating base from 1972 to 1988. Today, the airfield is primarily used for passenger traffic but also accommodates helicopters, air ambulances, and more. Additionally, the airport has been utilised for cross-wind training for the Airbus A350. Currently, there are scheduled flights to Benbecula, Edinburgh, Glasgow, and Inverness, operated by Hebridean Air Services and Loganair, serving over 100,000 passengers annually. The newly released scenery features interior modelling, an up-to-date ground layout, a realistic lighting environment, detailed modelling, several landmarks, and more. Stornoway Airport by FSDG is now available for purchase at SimMarket for approximately $16.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sobrizzle</id>
    <title>SoFly Releases Bristol Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sobrizzle"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690df5795e941a7a7f9e14f5_sofly-bristol-airport-eggd-msfs2024-21.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly has recently released their rendition of Bristol Airport (EGGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the eight busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 10.5 million passengers. Built on top of a former RAF airfield, Bristol Airport was inaugurated in 1957, replacing Bristol’s former main municipal airport (Whitchurch).  In 1958, a 200,000-pound passenger terminal was built, part of the administration’s effort to make it the city’s de facto airport. Four years later, a new control tower was built. In 1969, the runway underwent its first expansion, and the terminal was extended to handle the predicted figures for the 1970s and beyond. In the early 1980s, despite being served by 17 charter airlines, the airport was operating at a loss until Les Wilson took over as managing director and completely turned the tide. He held this position until his tragic passing in a car accident in 1995.  The mid-1980s slight recovery from the crisis allowed the administration to expend an extra dime or two on the construction of a new international departure lounge. Four years later, a new concourse area was opened, and planning for a new terminal kicked into action, leading to its eventual approval in 1994. Work started in 1997, shortly after FirstBus Group bought a 51% stake in the airport, heavily investing in its new infrastructure. The terminal, which cost 27 million pounds, was ready by 2000.  Passenger numbers reached the two million mark for the first time that year. A year later, the airport was purchased by a joint venture for 198 million pounds, and 50% of it was sold again in 2006. In 2015, the terminal was expanded again with a larger departure lounge and an outdoor terrace, followed by a new terminal extension adding 9,000 square meters. The project reached completion in 2017. It’s a focus city for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Aer Lingus, Aurigny, Blue Islands, Edelweiss Air, KLM, Loganair, Pegasus Airlines, and Sun Express also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life elevation data, full GSX integration with animated doors, a dynamic airport environment, PBR texturing, dynamic seasons, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.25, requiring at least 3.11 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a32101</id>
    <title>Got Friends Updates Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen for MSFS to Version 1.0.1</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a32101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690e0a5c26f8e36cfb3dcd50_VIXXEN_1_1800x1800_eda1b648-26ff-400b-8c38-02d1624fe124_1600x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Got Friends has released version 1.0.1 of its Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, introducing several improvements. The update refines the aircraft’s flight model, featuring custom propeller and flap drag code. Instrumentation and cockpit visuals have also received attention,  including new EGT gauge interactions, more natural glass reflections, and improved lighting behaviour across both analogue and G3X-equipped cockpits. The EFB can now be used even with the battery and avionics switched off, the custom KAP-140 autopilot once again accepts hotkey inputs, and stall, oil temperature, and heading indicator behaviour have all been fine-tuned for better accuracy. Performance has also been improved through LOD optimisations, which should be most noticeable in multiplayer. Several other fixes have addressed smaller issues, including corrected gauge animations, a brighter heading bug, and restored exterior engine audio nodes. The update also adjusts weight station logic, allowing the user to load either a co-pilot or cargo, but not both, to maintain consistent visuals and flight behaviour. As usual, here's the full changelog: You can download the Got Friends Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen v1.0.1 update now through the Contrail app. TDS users must also update their TDS Expansion to version 1.0.1 for compatibility. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/56wv24</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Cheat River Island for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/56wv24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690e13e57ea98f4e6bb97129_2_5381e25d-234b-4965-8e16-0efa42545b07%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has released its first fully native Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 scenery, bringing 56WV, Cheat River Island, to the new sim. The backcountry strip in West Virginia is situated on a river island, in the Appalachian range, with approaches that wind through a narrow valley, changing weather conditions, and even the occasional turkey on the runway.  The MSFS 2024 version has been rebuilt to use the sim’s newer tech. That includes high-fidelity 3D models, enhanced textures, a custom asset library, TrailBlazer terrain shaping, dynamic fauna, and bespoke lighting and ambient sounds at the main building. The environment has also been tailored to match the region, featuring custom vegetation and autumn colours. The airfield features a 1,704 ft grass runway, with landings on Runway 30 and departures from Runway 12, a sloped terrain profile, and collision-aware objects surrounding the strip. On the ground, you can explore six miles of drivable roads, built for the //42 Juice Goose UTV, camp overnight with the //42 Campout Utility, or visit detailed micro-scenes, such as a lakeside campsite and a rustic bar, that come alive after dark. Wildlife encounters, ziplines, tractor rides, and even a hidden bear make are also included. The scenery is available now for $12.00 at the Parallel 42 store. Owners of the 2020 version can upgrade to the MSFS 2024 release for $2 by using the code 24CHEATS at checkout. Parallel 42 says the offer is valid for six months, through April 29, 2026. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phnl24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Daniel K. Inouye International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phnl24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690e4df0be048897dcce507d_FlightSimulator_2023-08-26_19-47-43.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released their rendition of Daniel K. Inouye International Airport (HNL/PHNL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located to the northwest of Honolulu, it serves the Hawaiian capital and the island of Oahu, with over 21 million passenger operations in 2024. Opened in 1941, it was originally named after a WWI naval officer, John Rodgers. It was the first “full” airport in Hawaii, as planes used to land on seaplane docks, small air strips and fields. After the Pearl Harbour attack, the Rodgers Field became the Naval Air Station for Honolulu, and the Navy built the control tower and the first terminal building, where passenger flights were allowed to operate during the daylight. After WWII ended, it was renamed to “Honolulu Airport” and received the “International” addition in 1951. Back then, it was one of the largest airports in the USA with four paved runways and three water runways, spanning across 4,019 acres (1,626 hectares). Due to its position, the Honolulu International Airport became a regular stop for all transpacific flights, and by 1950, it became the third busiest airport in the United States, and had the world’s longest runway (13,097ft/3,097m) in 1953.  During the Jet Age, the airport became a frequent stop for various carriers, such as Pan Am, United, Northwest Airlines, Air New Zealand, BOAC, Canadian Pacific Air Lines (later became CP Air), China Airlines, Garuda Indonesia, Japan Airlines, Korean Air, Qantas, Philippine Airlines, TWA, and many more. In 2006, the State of Hawaii unveiled a $2.3 billion plan for modernising Hawaiian airports, out of which $1.7 billion was designated for Honolulu Intl’ Airport. During the period of 15 years, the airport had received many upgrades, including a new concourse for wide-body aircraft, new parking garages, and renovated check-in lobbies and terminal interiors. During the process of airport modernisation, the airport also got renamed to “Daniel K. Inouye International Airport”, in honour of the late Medal of Honour recipient and U.S. senator, Daniel Inouye. The iniBuilds rendition of the largest airport in Hawaii features hand-made ground textures with crisp, true-to-life airport layout with custom ground decals, modelled terminal interior, signposts, vegetation, and parking barriers, dynamic airport lighting, custom static aircraft, LOD optimisation, and an official GSX profile. The scenery is available for purchase on the iniBuilds store for approximately $26.07, requiring at least 2.72GB of free disk space. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gksrb52</id>
    <title>Golden Key Studios Release B-52H Stratofortress for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gksrb52"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690f7417c681d576e7eb8af1_Ext_058_B2.PNG.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Golden Key Studios has recently released their rendition of the Boeing B-52H Stratofortress Bomber for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The famous eight-engined bomber has been a cornerstone of the US Air Force for many years. The B-52 series of aircraft have been in service with the US Air Force since 1955, marking its 70th anniversary this year. Over the years, the B-52 has undergone multiple upgrades since its introduction into service, with the B-52H variant being the most recent. The B-52H features newer JT3D-based engines, updated avionics, and various armament upgrades. Golden Key Studios’ rendition of the B-52H features a highly detailed 3D model, accurate systems, realistic sounds, and more. Features: ‍The Golden Key Studios B-52H Stratofortress is available for purchase on the MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024 Marketplaces. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksnov</id>
    <title>MK Studios Shares Major Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksnov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690f7d270123d4a2ef8be9dd_577404748_1257871459694472_2863767435695117347_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has broken a period of relative silence with a sizeable development update, outlining progress across several ongoing projects and updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Leading the update is Helsinki Airport (EFHK), which has officially entered beta testing. According to MK Studios, the release is expected within the next seven to ten days, with the NDA lifting early next week, indicating that new screenshots and streams are likely to follow soon. The Finnish theme continues, as the team also confirmed that Rovaniemi Airport (EFRO) is being reworked. The refreshed version is planned for December, just in time for winter operations, and for those planning a festive visit to Santa’s home turf. Beyond Finland, MK Studios shared progress on Rome Fiumicino (LIRF), noting that modelling exports have begun, and the project is expected to enter beta by the end of November.  Meanwhile, Vágar Airport (EKVG) in the Faroe Islands is undergoing a full rebuild, scheduled for January, featuring a new satellite image, improved terrain, updated buildings and POIs, and a refreshed apron layout, with an additional parking stand. Looking a bit further ahead, Porto (LPPR) and Fuerteventura (GCFV) are both scheduled for complete reworks sometime in Q1 or Q2 2026. The developer also mentioned that work is ongoing on professional training projects alongside these updates, explaining the recent hiatus. Finally, MK Studios issued a call for reference photos of the new Keflavik terminal, both inside and out, to support next year’s planned update to the Icelandic hub. If you have any, be sure to contact them! For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/changi26</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Releases Singapore Changi Airport 2026 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/changi26"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690f8226dd04e33f34ba0428_chan1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Imaginesim has recently released their updated rendition of Singapore Changi Airport (WSSS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, reflecting the latest changes to the airport. It was inaugurated 42 years ago when the Singaporean government was forced to build a new airport to cope with the region's ever-growing demand for air travel. Initially, their original plan was to expand Paya Lebar, the former main airport in Singapore; however, the 1973 Oil crisis changed everything. By 1975, they had already decided to build a brand new airport at the eastern tip of the main island of Changi, at the Changi Air Base. After its first year of operation, the airport had already handled an average of 12.1 million passengers, prompting the construction of a second passenger terminal in the 1990s. Terminal 3 soon followed in 2008, and then Terminal 4 in 2017. Terminal 5, which is planned to be larger than all four combined, is expected to open in 2030. It's a FedEx Express, Jetstar Asia, Scoot, and Singapore Airlines hub. AirAsia, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air India, Air New Zealand, All Nippon Airways, Cathay Pacific, China Southern Airlines, EVA Air, Garuda Indonesia, Hainan Airlines, IndiGo, KLM, Lufthansa, Qantas, Swiss, United Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines also serve it. The updated rendition features 13 km of new taxiways, a vast construction zone around Terminal 5, custom jetways, performance-friendly optimization, custom VDGS, high-definition textures, and more. It’s available on their website for roughly $26.30. Owners of the previous version are entitled to a 75% discount. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hcolum</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Columbia Metropolitan Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hcolum"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6912425c9e925befa7d115ba_colum1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Columbia Metropolitan Airport (KCAE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Columbia, in South Carolina (United States), with a yearly average of 1.2 million passengers. It was built in 1940 as Lexington County Airport and was rapidly acquired by the US Army Air Corps for World War II usage, hosting the 105th Observation Squadron and its fleet of Douglas O-38s and North American O-47s.  A year later, it was totally under military control, and a program was started to fully convert it into a military airport, becoming the Columbia Army Air Base. The Air Base was primarily used for training, and some of the combat crew members participated in the famous Doolittle Raid in Japan. Training was eventually phased down by the end of the war, and it was rapidly returned to civilian control, becoming Columbia Metropolitan Airport. For a brief period, a bombardment squadron was assigned to the airport, but it left in 1949. A passenger terminal was built in the 1950s and eventually burned down, only to be replaced by a new one, which opened in 1965. It was expanded in the late 1980s, with an expanded terminal, a runway extension, and the construction of a new parking garage (which only reached completion in 2003). Renovation work was carried out in 1997, essentially replacing the old structure. It’s a hub for UPS Airlines. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, and United Express serve it. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made surfaces, highly detailed terminals, a fully modeled landside area, custom dynamic lighting, over 150 handcrafted models, and custom animated jetways. ​ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.02, requiring at least 2.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simnaples</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Naples Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simnaples"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69148bc9792bec67bae9a6fb_naples1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimPixel has recently released their rendition of Naples International Airport (LIRN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Metropolitan City of Naples, Campania region, with a yearly average of 12.6 million passengers, making it the fourth busiest airport in Italy. The airport started its life in the early 1900s as “Campo di Marte”, a little airfield for general aviation, occasionally hosting flight exhibitions. World War 1 had the airport become a military airport to defend the town against the Austro-Hungarians and Germans. Then it saw heavy usage again during World War 2, this time by the United States Army Air Forces and the Royal Air Force, and later became a major transshipment hub for cargo. The commercial debut occurred in 1950, marking the official opening of “Naples Airport”. It serves as an operating base for easyJet, Ryanair, Volotea, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Arabia, Air Cairo, Air Canada, Air France, American Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Eurowings, Finnair, flydubai, FlyOne, Iberia Express, Israir Airlines, ITA Airways, Jet2, KLM, Lufthansa, Luxair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Smartwings, Swiss International Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, TUI, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution PBR textures, highly detailed terminals and hangars, dynamic night lighting, custom ground layout, static aircraft and ground equipment services, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $22.34, requiring at least 5.71 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dflrhode</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Studios Teases Rhode Island T. F. Green International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dflrhode"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69149283cd8f81afb4f9405d_rhode1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Dreamflight Studios has recently teased their rendition of Rhode Island T. F. Green International Airport (KPVD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Providence, Rhode Island, with a yearly average of 4 million passengers.​ It was dedicated in 1931 as Hillsgrove State Airport, and its first passenger terminal was built in 1933. Its original layout consisted of three 910-meter-long concrete runways. ‍ It was used for flight training by the United States Army Air Force during 1942 and 1945, hosting the 435th Army Air Force Base. ​ The World War II occupation period led to several upgrades, including runway extensions (300 meters each) and slightly improved infrastructure. In the 1960s, a new terminal was constructed, as the old one was insufficient to handle a metropolitan area with over a million people.  ​ It wasn’t until 1996 that it would see another upgrade, entirely replaced by a new passenger terminal with 18 gates. Four extra gates were added in 1997. ​ It’s a hub for Wiggins Airways and an operating base for Breeze Airways. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, BermudAir, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express serve it. ​ There’s no pricing information available yet, but it is expected to be released sometime this week. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/car390rel</id>
    <title>Carenado Releases B390 1A for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/car390rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6902655801dc90c1d37b973b_beec.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has recently released their rendition of the Beechcraft B-390 Premier 1A for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a light business jet first conceived in the mid-1990s.  The Beechcraft B-390 Premier 1A was an updated version of the Premier 1, which was designed in the mid-90s, first flown in 1998, and certified in 2001. The IA was almost like a real-life patch to fix some lingering issues with the project, such as the subpar brakes, the noisy cabin, and the cockpit, which was deemed below par by many. The aforementioned upgrade rolled out in 2006, and over 163 new Premiers were built in five years. The little jet is powered by two Williams FJ44-2A Turbofan engines. It cruises at 841 km/h, has a range of 950 miles, a service ceiling of 41,000 feet, and, depending on the configuration, can carry 6 to 7 passengers. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $24.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
