<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-12-19T18:38:38.889267+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atcvfr</id>
    <title>BeyondATC Announces VFR Support</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atcvfr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693b45fb1d4a36abbbf14bca_fgsgdg453.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. BeyondATC has released a YouTube video giving, the community insight into the program’s current status and future.  After the team spent 10 months stabilising the program's core features, they announced they are ready to move on to developing visual flight rules (VFR). The team plans to roll out VFR in phases, with coverage expanding over time.  In phase one, VFR coverage will be provided for the United States, the United Kingdom, and Australia, with a focus on circuit entry and exit. Phase two will introduce different types of airspace, while phase three will allow the completion of full VFR flights. The team notes that it will take time to roll out these features. However, if the developers’ plans go as expected, simmers will soon have new ways to integrate air traffic control into their flying experience.  To learn more about BeyondATC, you can check out their official website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fpifly</id>
    <title>Flight Panels Releases iFly 737 MAX8 Stream Deck Profile for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fpifly"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693b4c559033dabe4312487d_Store_-_iFly_Boeing_737_Max_8_-_Page_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flight Panels has released a new Stream Deck profile for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This time, the iFly Boeing 737 Max 8 is in focus. The package spans 34 pages and includes more than 1,200 images and over 830 custom-designed, pre-programmed buttons.  These mirror the layout and style of the iFly cockpit, allowing simmers to operate autopilot, radio, lighting, overhead systems, and other controls directly from their Stream Deck, rather than using a keyboard and mouse. The profile also exposes controls for ground services, aircraft performance information, ATIS, and various cockpit and cabin features.  It is designed to take advantage of newer MSFS 2024 features, including walkaround and external interaction points. Both 15 and 32 key layouts are included, with support for the Elgato Stream Deck XL, Stream Deck MK.2, Stream Deck Mobile on iOS and Android, and the Corsair Xeneon Edge.  The iFly 737 Max 8 Stream Deck profile is available now for $33 from the Flight Panels store and selected third-party marketplaces. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flight-sim-awards-2026---were-back</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Awards 2026  –  We’re Back</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flight-sim-awards-2026---were-back"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693ae05463e6d63e62e67e84_FLIGHTSIM_AWARDS_2026_at_FSWeekend__Celebrating_t_11-12-2025-15_14_45.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The Flight Sim Awards are coming back for 2026! The first award ceremony we held earlier this year was met with great enthusiasm from both developers and community members. All the feedback and lessons from last year have been taken into account, and efforts have been made to ensure that the Flight Sim Awards 2026 is bigger, better, and ready to celebrate in a meaningful way. The organizing committee, comprising FSElite, Cruiselevel, and Threshold, has been working diligently on the next ceremony, reviewing the structure to ensure a fair, transparent, and meaningful selection process. The awards continue to honour excellence and long-term contributions within the flight simulation community, recognizing achievements in development, creativity, and community engagement. In the updated structure, we aimed to create space for developers and creators who may not have fit naturally into previous categories. Each category has been reviewed to ensure relevance, clarity, and a balanced representation of the many areas that advance our hobby. We also added categories to highlight community contributions, which are often overlooked. All entries are evaluated according to shared principles: Each category represents a part of what makes flight simulation thrive: creativity, precision, and the human dedication behind the virtual skies. More information on the nomination process and jury panel will follow shortly. The next Flight Sim Awards ceremony will once again take place during the Captain’s Dinner at Flight Sim Weekend on Friday, March 20th, 2026. You can find more information on our website and tickets to FlightSimWeekend and the Captains Dinner here. Join the Flight Sim Awards Discord and be a part of the Awards community</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaerostaset</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaerostaset"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693c5fc6827fb40830e4fac5_aerostarup.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently issued a new update to their Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, adding visible passengers on all seats, multiple bug fixes, and more. ‍ This update focuses on refining systems, sounds, visuals, physics, and avionics, with some quality-of-life improvements sprinkled on top. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Changelog MSFS 2020 Specific ‍ The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42twxr</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Typical Weather for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42twxr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693c6410cece5aee88ec7d30_wx1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has recently released their first weather-related add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, named “Typical Weather,” due to the fact that it does not use live weather data but a historical compilation of weather figures from around the world, providing a typical METAR for that specific period of the year. Typical Weather is “an intelligent, location-aware weather engine that adapts to where and when you fly”, bringing a completely new approach to weather in simulators, delivering conditions that make sense for the place you are flying in without the unpredictability of live weather. Parallel 42 argues that live weather is “inconsistent”, allowing for clear sunny days in the middle of winter, contrary to the expectation of what you would expect from a determined location. Typical Weather prevents that from happening by using historical weather data from over 9,000 weather stations and nearly 20 million sample points, always providing what would be rather usual throughout the year. The plugin also allows the user to choose from atypical conditions if desired, with options ranging from fair to hazy, foggy, windy, precipitating, stormy, or IFR, all based on the region being flown in. Furthermore, the apps panel will also provide a detailed METAR, with wind and gust visualization, and the possibility to synchronize everything for multiplayer sessions, in addition to being either static or dynamic. ​ It’s available in their store for $20. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lr1233</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases 12.3.3 Hotfix for X-Plane 12‍</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lr1233"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693c99aacd333ac25b195e82_ReleaseNotes_XP12.3.3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently released a hotfix for X-Plane 12 to address a few minor issues found in their latest release.  The current iteration of X-Plane has been supported since December 2022. Since that time, many patches have been released, to fix bugs and expand on features.  According to this round of patch notes, X-Plane 12.3.3 addresses an issue with the latest version of Nvidia's Graphics Driver, as well as addressing an instancing objects issue within the software development kit.  Mac users are also told to check that they have the latest installer version, 5.2.1. Recent updates have focused on air traffic control, weather, cloud visuals, flight lessons, and general visual enhancements.  According to Laminar Research’s roadmap, version 12.4 will be a “C-Check”, focusing on systems and the user experience. You can get the update by simply running X-Plane 12 and following the update instructions. If you have yet to try X-Plane 12, you can try a free demo here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse26t</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2026 Tickets Now On Sale</title>
    <updated>2025-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse26t"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b7500fcdfc5dd98c62e07a_2025_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Tickets are now on sale for FlightSimExpo 2026, which will take place at Saint Paul RiverCentre in Minnesota, from Jun. 12-14, 2026.  Ticket sales opened today at 1800Z (1200 Central Time).  To attend, you can purchase the"Entire Event" ticket, which costs $75 for general attendees. It includes #FSExpoFriday product announcement seminars, the new Friday Exhibit Hall Preview, three days of exhibits, weekend seminars and workshops, plus access to post-event seminar recordings. FSA Captains receive additional discounts.  The first 200 Captains to register can secure an "Entire Event" ticket for $50, a discount of more than $30 compared to the standard rate, along with various other perks, such as a dedicated entrance line, priority add-on registration, and year-round discounts, through FSA. For those who prefer to attend on a specific day, single-day tickets are available for $40 on Friday, $50 on Saturday, and $30 on Sunday.  Each option includes exhibit hall access, that day’s seminars and workshops, and the usual badge, lanyard, and giveaways, with online viewing of seminars included for all ticket types. FSA highlights hotel rates starting at $149 per night, plus tax, at partner properties near the venue, which is about 25% cheaper than last year.  Discounted fares with Delta, United, Southwest, and selected codeshare partners are also available for flights into Minneapolis–Saint Paul International Airport. As in previous years, exhibitors, hardware manufacturers, communities, and training organisations are invited to participate as sponsors, exhibitors, and speakers, with booth packages including furnishings, internet, electricity, and event passes.  An initial list of partners for the 2026 show is expected in March 2026. More information on tickets, FSA Captain membership, exhibitor opportunities, and travel discounts is available via the official FlightSimExpo website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg73818</id>
    <title>PMDG’s 738NG for MSFS 2024 to Release on Thursday</title>
    <updated>2025-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg73818"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694055a2a2c7bdc35b2eb5de_maxi.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has published another development update regarding their upcoming 737-800 upgrade for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which will feature a comprehensive overhaul, including a new cabin, new cockpit textures, new sounds, and more. ​ The developers argue that their original 738 is a really old product in software terms (3.5 years old), and they had not yet fully understood the simulator’s potential at the time of release. 2024 has given them the opportunity to dive deeper into the potential offered by the new platform and bring it up to modern standards. ​ It’s said to be a significant overhaul of the 737 product line, wholly capitalizing on the sim’s capabilities: a new cockpit with new materials, lidar scanned models, new lighting, new surface textures; a new cabin, new interactable items around the airplane, customized door logic, operable cockpit windows, and a new 3D sound-set built by a professional sound engineering team whose lead sound engineer is also a type-rated 737 captain. ​ While there are still some cleanup details to finish around the external area, PMDG hopes to release it on Thursday (18/12), just before Christmas, so people can enjoy their Christmas break flying the brand-new product in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ​ They have also listed a few FAQ such as price (in line with previous products), discount for previous owners (previous owners will in fact get a discount, both on marketplace and pmdg.com), discount across purchase venues (if you bought it on marketplace, it will be only applicable to marketplace, and so on), and the potential release date for the other 737s (-600 and -900 in January, and -700 in February). ​If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfdufo</id>
    <title>Just Flight Shares Development Update for F70/100 Professional for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfdufo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6942a6ec48a8ef4b8c6123ce_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has released its latest development update for the upcoming F70/100 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The team reports significant progress since the last update and is nearing completion of the project. Along with the update, they have also shared a video trailer showcasing the new aircraft. Since the last development update, the team has refined, improved, and reworked various components of the AFCAS and FMS code. Additionally, the flight model has been enhanced further to better replicate the experience of flying the real aircraft, which real-world pilots have described as delightful to hand-fly. The sound developer has been diligently working on the aircraft, which will feature the highest number of individual sound samples he has ever included in a project. The team has stated that they will release a video providing a detailed overview of the sound features in due course. At the conclusion of the development update, the team mentioned that they are working hard to release the F70/100 Professional as soon as possible in 2026. ‍ You can read the full development update on Just Flight's website.  We will update you as soon as we have more information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hs7872</id>
    <title>Horizon Simulations Teases Boeing 787 Version Two, With A Look At New EFB</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hs7872"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6943d92f79c5eff17999cc7e_Image_6%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Horizon Simulations has teased a brand-new electronic flight bag as part of their upcoming 787 version 2 family.  The new EFB looks to include many of the features we have come to expect from a more complete aircraft model, including a working on-screen keyboard, pilot utilities, a landing performance calculator, and en route charts.  With no set release date, Horizon Simulations plans to continue issuing periodic developer updates on Discord. The next planned update will highlight 3D modelling work. Susequest updates will feature the PFD, MFD, CDU, and sound!  Horizon Simulations is inviting community members to provide feedback on the developer updates. So, if you have feedback, be sure to check out their Discord! For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ms4ps5</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 Releases on PlayStation 5</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ms4ps5"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6943e177006eb2c4ba2ada90_01_872423.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has ported its latest version of its landmark simulator, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, onto the PlayStation 5.  The full release of the sim for PS5 follows a phased rollout that included early access for those who pre-ordered the Deluxe, Premium Deluxe, or Aviator editions.  While the game experience remains the same for PS5 users, Microsoft has noted that access to the in-game marketplace will require a separate app.  As a consequence, purchases made in the in-sim marketplace won’t transfer over from other platforms. However, the port does offer more people the chance to take to the virtual skies.  Veterans of the PC launch will no doubt take note of Microsoft’s new phased release approach. This approach should hopefully negate the problems faced by simmers just over a year ago, when Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 launched on PC and Xbox, leading to vastly increased wait times.   Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 can be purchased from the PlayStation Store on your console. Where do you think the sim will be ported to next? Mac? The Nintendo Switch 2? Let us know!   For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vata16</id>
    <title>VATSIM Announces New Age Restrictions</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vata16"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6943e8633f6092fcf0bd6c05_vatsim_age.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a recent post, VATSIM confirmed that, starting January 1st, 2026, they will require all new users to be at least 16 years of age.  The online air traffic control network claims it is making this change as part of its ongoing work to ensure a safe and welcoming environment for all members. All current users aged 13 to 15 will be exempted from this policy.  While some see the recent changes as a necessary step to maintain the network's safety and security, many others feel that VATSIM’s policy shifts could deter membership growth.  How do you feel about the way VATSIM is being run? Does this make you more likely to sign up for VATSIM or maintain your current membership? Or is the organisation becoming a little too restrictive? ‍ Let us know! ‍ For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia350v120</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia350v120"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694458f037084547b380e37c_lufty.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, adding SEC flight plan fixes and wholly fixing a WASM-induced texture loading error introduced with Sim Update 4 (MSFS 2024). ​ Update v1.2.0 is a micro-update addressing issues with the secondary flight plan and a WASM texture loading bug introduced with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s latest major update. The complete changelog follows below: Fixed - Sec-fplan fixes for airway entry Fixed - SEC F-PLN - INSERT NEXT WPT adds waypoints to the top of F-PLN instead of after chosen waypoint Fixed - WASM next waypoint 'LNY vor' on SEC2, 3 F-PLN. Fixed - WASM texture loading bug introduced in SU4 on some machines Admin - Numerous file clean up and adhoc admin of project ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $80.49.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfla300b4dec</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes A300B4 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfla300b4dec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69445f74eb8e67ca0013a131_ext1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. As part of their End of Year Round Up, Just Flight has shared some of the progress on the A300B4 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024, with its exterior artwork nearing completion and ready for showcasing. They have meticulously hand-placed thousands of rivets on every inch of the aircraft’s surface, with the tail area being the most obvious due to its housing of so many critical structures. Special attention has been paid to weathering, resulting in a representation of an airframe that has been in service for many years, complete with streaks of dirt, detritus, traces of rainwater, run-down panels, and more. The flight deck is no different, as they have previously shared. Just Flight considers their A300B4 to be one of the most accurately represented wide-body airliners in any flight simulator. A bold claim, as they note, but they will let the people be the judges. As for the remaining work on the art department, their artist is currently finishing the textures of the landing gear, wheels, and landing gear bays, before eventually focusing on the cargo hold interiors. Once that is out of the way, the artwork will be complete for the A300B4-203 variant. But the -203 isn’t the only variant modeled, so there’s still a bit more work to do: the showcased plane is actually an A300B4-103, for example. A freighter variant will also be included. With that being said, they are not ready yet to show any of the other planned variants. ​ After the texturing work is complete, they will move on to livery creation for the variants at hand, and they promise to provide a large selection of top-quality work that will represent the A300B4’s diverse range of operators from every habitable continent.  ​ Furthermore, the developers have finally been able to share previews of the passenger cabin, modelled into a two-class layout from the 1980s, with the First Class cabin featuring 24 seats in a 2+2+2 configuration, and the economy cabin featuring 230 seats in a 2+4+2 configuration, narrowing at the rear to a 2+3+2 configuration. In line with their other products, the cabin will feature numerous simulated elements, offering “lots to play with” during the cruise phase. The cabin artwork is deemed ready, but there may be minor changes between what has been showcased and the final product at the time of release, most notably related to cabin lighting, as it has not yet been implemented. The flight model is progressing decently, and the extensive data they sourced from a variety of A300B4 variants has been proven rather useful, allowing it to perform as faithfully as possible to the numbers. The systems have now been fully coded, and the plane is getting ready to enter wider beta testing. Among the most recently completed systems, they highlight the Carousel IV-A Inertial Navigation System and the autopilot logic. ​ Since they have something nearing completion, they can finally begin proper testing with their beta team, allowing them to delve deeply into the system's intricacies to cross-check their functionalities against the aircraft’s FCOM and mitigate any issues that may arise. ​ Just Flight will be sharing more details earlier next year. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddepkt24out</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Katowice Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddepkt24out"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694464dfc3eed8da3962b8bf_epkt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Katowice Wojciech Korfanty Airport (EPKT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Katowice-Ostrava metropolitan area with a yearly average of 6.4 million passengers, making it the 4th busiest airport in Poland. It was originally built by the Luftwaffe in 1940, with three stone and concrete airstrips of varying lengths. It was used for handling military aircraft flying from Germany, carrying supplies to troops on the Eastern Front. It was also briefly used for aircraft testing in the final phase of World War 2. In 1945, the airfield was taken over by the Soviets, and it was subsequently handed over to Poland in the early 1950s, where it was used to house the Polish Air Force’s 39th Fighter Regiment. A new runway was built in the mid-1960s, and regular scheduled passenger traffic began in 1966. Poland’s entry into the European Union has substantially accelerated the airport’s growth, with Wizz Air choosing Katowice as its first base outside Hungary. Other low-cost carriers followed suit within the next couple of years. A second terminal was built in 2007 specifically for Schengen flights, and an arrivals-only terminal (Terminal C) followed in 2015. That year also marked the construction of Katowice’s new runway, which is 3200 meters in length (the second-longest runway in Poland). It’s a focus city for ASL Airlines Ireland, Buzz (Ryanair), Electra Airways, Enter Air, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa Cargo, Ryanair, Skyline Express, Smartwings Poland, and Wizz Air. Air Cairo, Air Dolomiti, Corendon Airlines, Freebird Airlines, Lufthansa, Nesma Airlines, Nouvelair, Pegasus Airlines, Plus Ultra, and Tailwind Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, a custom terminal interior, custom ground service equipment, an accurate runway profile, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $24.62, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/738202430</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737-800 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/738202430"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69449ad660638fea81aa0035_7321.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released the long-awaited Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version of their Boeing 737-800, their first product built natively for the new platform with a lidar-scanned flight deck, improved textures and lighting, new sounds, and much more. Their 738 leverages the capabilities of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 to lay the groundwork for a truly native product line that will follow from this (the next variants will gradually roll out over the next months).  ​ It’s said to be a significant overhaul of the 737 product line, wholly capitalizing on the sim’s capabilities: a new cockpit with new materials, lidar scanned models, new lighting, new surface textures; a new cabin, new interactable items around the airplane, customized door logic, operable cockpit windows, and a new 3D sound-set built by a professional sound engineering team whose lead sound engineer is also a type-rated 737 captain. The full changelog follows below: ​ It’s available on PMDG.com for $74.99, and owners of the MSFS 2020 version are entitled to a 60% discount ($30 total).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
