<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-12-17T18:20:47.359289+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flylas</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Harry Reid International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flylas" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6570ef72db08ffaa02700297_vegas.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1756401"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has recently issued an update to their rendition of Harry Reid International Airport (KLAS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Las Vegas Valley with a yearly average of 52.7 million passengers. Update 2.00 brings the airport up to date, improves jetway animations, enhances performance, improves the clutter on the apron, adds the new MGM Sphere with multiple animated projections, and more. The full changelog follows below: - KLAS airport updates- AI parking codes update- Performance enhancements- Improved Jetway animations- MGM Sphere (animated with multiple projections)- Harry Reid temporary signage updates- Improved apron clutter- Airport static jets update- Caesars Conference Center- Animated Las Vegas monorail- Las Vegas Convention Center- Circa Hotel (including wall animation and Stadium swim)- Improved Bellagio fountains animation- World Resorts wall animation- Mirage Volcano lava effects- Park MGM updated The update is available on their website and SimMarket, with Orbx and Marketplace coming soon.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/egnmv2</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Leeds Bradford V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/egnmv2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6569c87e4c9d45c83342ed63_leeds2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="221932"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their updated rendition of Leeds Bradford Airport (EGNM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving North and West Yorkshire with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers.  It was opened in 1931 as Leeds and Bradford Municipal Aerodrome (or Yeadon Aerodrome), mostly used for general aviation and training during its initial years, with scheduled flights starting in 1935.  Work on the main terminal started around the late 30s but only reached full completion after WW2.   Avro constructed a shadow factory during that WW2 period called the Leeds Bradford Airport Depot, with over 5,000 aircraft before its closure in December 1946.  In the early 1980s, the runway was extended, allowing it to be classified as a regional airport. After the extension, Wardair commenced international flights to Toronto in a 747 in 1984.  The airport underwent expansion work in the late 90s and early 2000s, allowing it to reach an 88% increase in passenger traffic by 2007 (2.9 million passengers visited the airport that year).  The highest airport in the United Kingdom (681ft!) is an operating base for Jet2.com and Ryanair and is served by Aer Lingus, Aurigny, easyJet, KLM, and WizzAir.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date 2023 airport layout, fully-reworked PBR ground poly, custom lighting, LOD optimization to ensure best performance, animated custom jetways, a high-detail ATC tower with animated air traffic controllers, detailed walkway interior, hand-placed animated horses, a detailed spotting area west of runway 14, updated signage, and more.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.85 (V1 owners are eligible for a discounted upgrade fee), requiring at least 6.01 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jester</id>
    <title>IndiaFoxtEcho and Heatblur releases the F-14 Tomcat for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jester" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65721d88680ba5516c1b8055_Screen_181005_062706_4c9a1cdd-c5a2-45ac-a9c2-eb40a0f86d08.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="189927"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IndiaFoxtEcho and Heatblur have released the highly anticipated F-14 Tomcat for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Tomcat, undergoing development for several months, has now reached its final stages after extensive testing by the duo. This marks Heat Blur's first release for Microsoft Flight Simulator, as the prominent Digital Combat Simulator developer collaborates with the established India Fox team. The Microsoft Flight Simulator version of the F-14 benefits from years of community feedback within the DCS community, resulting in the most accurate representation of the aircraft available for MSFS. The release introduces a host of new features, including comprehensive system modeling, fine-tuned flight models, and visually stunning enhancements spanning from 3D elements to textures. The development team has placed a particular emphasis on refining the core flying aspects of the aircraft, including avionics, navigation systems, and more. To enhance control and system management, the team has integrated JESTER, your AI RIO wingman. JESTER AI is designed to handle specific operations, allowing you to focus on flying the F-14 without distraction. Both models of the Tomcat are offered: the F14A and F14B, featuring the Pratt and Whitney TF-30 and General Electric F110 engines, respectively. The F-14 is now available on the Flight Simulator Marketplace (unarmed), the Heatblur store, SimMarket, and Orbx for $34.99. Discounts are available for previous DCS customers, with a recommendation to make the purchase through the HeatBlur online store. Existing owner? Check out this link here for a 30% off coupon! Release trailer here! Enjoy! As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniabs</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases A300 Liveries</title>
    <updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniabs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6573549fe18a6e9c6f544379_Discord_BjBPyRTVls.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="811863"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds, who are known for their work with Microsoft and Asobo in bringing the A310, and eventually, an improved A320neo to Microsoft Flight Simulator has teased some of the liveries that will be available with their upcoming A300. The liveries were teased in an announcement on their Discord stating that final feature implementation and testing are currently taking place.  iniBuilds first announced the project at FlightSimExpo earlier this year and has been slowly previewing the aircraft since. Currently, it's stated that the initial release is planned to be before the end of the year with the GE engine, both passenger and freighter layouts, and a planned hotfix if needed. In early 2024 users can expect to see the Pratt and Whitney engine variant with both a passenger and freighter option, a modern IDC radio panel will also be included in this update. Sometime in 2024, a paid update will be available, which will include the Primus Epic glass avionics package seen on many A300's today. With 2023 coming to a close there's a lot to look forward to in the realm of flight simulation, and we at Threshold look forward to bringing you all the breaking news! </summary>
    <published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsed17</id>
    <title>FSExpo 2024 Attendee Registration Opens on December 17</title>
    <updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsed17" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6573a3b5aeb8b173dd110340_2023_7.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="852813"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FSA has recently announced that attendee registrations for FSExpo 2024 will be opening on December 17, and the first 200 FSA members to register for the show can get a 3-day event access for only $50, saving more than $30.   The in-person registration includes:  Non-member pricing for Friday-Sunday begins at $80, with Weekend and online options also available.  The conference’s co-founder Evan Reiter urges FSA members to register ASAP, as they anticipate the $50 member registration will sell out within a day or two. “For those who can, we encourage you to plan travel now. Our discounted room rate at the Tropicana is more than 60% sold out, and prices may increase when the block fills”, he added.  Attendees can also book hotel rooms and access airfare and car deals now. To be notified when the registration opens, visit this page.   The pre-registration for sponsors and exhibitors is now open. If you are a prospective sponsor and exhibitor, refer to this page.   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uft777</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases New UFT Update and Previews Upcoming 777</title>
    <updated>2023-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uft777" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65655a83fd02b08016d36961_1250410_20231127095627_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2116268"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued a new update to their Universal Flight Tablet for Microsoft Flight Simulator, currently only equipping their 737 lineup but also planned to be on their upcoming 777 in the near future, which has also seen its first preview yesterday.  Update 3.00.0086 brings small fixes to the Universal Flight Tablet, part of their commitment to improve the product constantly. The complete changelog follows below:  Tablet Version 1.5.0 / PMDG 737 Build 3.00.0086 12634: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Map day/night mode and map type (Navigraph/PMDG) should be persistent (rmurdoch) 12740: [EFB - Performance and Computational] METARs with wind in MPS units handled improperly (rmurdoch) 12739: [EFB - General] 0-degree temperature breaks OPT, simple weather display (rmurdoch) 12772: [EFB - Performance and Computational] METAR with MPS wind unit converting incorrectly, breaking OPT (rmurdoch) 12815: [EFB - General] Remove dependancy on CDN for bootstrap css (rmurdoch)  The update has also been sent to the MSFS Marketplace and will probably be made available next Thursday.  They are still figuring out how to make the tablet work on the Xbox version, as there are slight differences between how the communications layer works.   When asked about more 777 information, Randazzo posted the first preview of their 777: a landing gear photo. No other information was shared about the matter besides that PMDG is working on new previews.    PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! </summary>
    <published>2023-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhsr71</id>
    <title>VSkylabs Releases the SR71 Blackbird</title>
    <updated>2023-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhsr71" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6577599d86a4da6df5512867_Homr.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1571334"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VSkylabs Aerospace Simulations has released their SR-71 Blackbird for X-Plane 12. VSkylabs began work on the Blackbird in January of this year(2023), aiming to deliver an accurate and more in-depth version of this iconic aircraft to X-Plane. VSkylabs, well-known for its focus on unique and iconic aircraft, recently released the Hungarocopter as well. VSkylabs is dedicated to numerous details and features specific to the SR-71, spanning systems, animations, and mission configurations. The flight model is currently at v1.0 (Early Access), with ongoing improvements planned for future releases. Notable flight model features include correct algorithms controlling Air Inlet spikes, ramjet characteristics, and propulsion simulation. Accurate throttle setting regimes enable conventional operations, where fully aft results in cutoff. The Chemical Ignition System is simulated, complete with visual startup effects. Furthermore, afterburner variable exhaust nozzles are simulated and animated. The Blackbird's unique air inlet system, including the inlet spike movements and settings, aft bypass doors, fuel systems,  electrical systems, and hydraulics, are also faithfully simulated. Flight control surfaces are animated to authentic real-life parameters. Air-to-air refueling sequences are simulated as well. The 3D model has been meticulously reconstructed from their older model to incorporate as many details into the sim as possible. The infamous A330 Start Cart is modeled and animated, featuring FMOD sounds of the Buick Wildcat V8 401 ci engines. Lockheed's D-21 reconnaissance drone is also modeled. The fully detailed VR-compatible cockpit replicates all the details of the actual aircraft.  See a complete and extensive list of features via the product page. Check out the free flight manual here. VSkylabs aims to build the most accurate SR-71 for any simulator, and so far, they have delivered. The SR-71 Blackbird is available for purchase via VSkylabs website or X-Plane.org for $37.00 ‍ As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates! </summary>
    <published>2023-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2sma</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Santa Maria Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2sma" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657769e723d826742443027c_sma.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="425526"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Santa Maria Airport (SBSM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Santa Maria in Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.  It was opened in 1945 on an urgent basis with the help of the United States Army, featuring a runway that was for many years the longest in the state, only behind Porto Alegre Airport after its expansion from 2280 meters to 3200, making it 500 meters longer than Santa Maria’s main runway.   An air base was inaugurated in 1971, sharing the facilities with the civil part. The agreement continued until 2015 when the full ownership was transferred to the Municipality of Santa Maria.  It’s currently served by Azul Linhas Aéreas, who has a daily flight to Porto Alegre and a single seasonal route to Florianópolis.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, PBR materials, custom vegetation, custom night lighting, and custom interiors for the tower and passenger terminal.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.92 and requires at least 22.43 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl131</id>
    <title>FSLTL updates Base Model to 1.3-1.3.1</title>
    <updated>2023-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl131" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65787bd3412c5b6d6047053d_FlightSimulator%202023-10-02%2016-38-48.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3193868"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSLTL, the developer behind the widely-used A.I. FSLTL Traffic for MSFS, has recently released an updated Base Model package featuring many enhancements. FSLTL seamlessly integrates aircraft into Microsoft Flight Simulator, providing users with a realistic, real-time experience of airline and general aviation traffic within the simulation environment. This software works seamlessly with MSFS default ATC and is VATSIM compatible through the provided VMR file. The latest update introduces an addition of 62 new liveries, comprising 38 for the 787-8, 16 for the ATR 42-500, and 8 for the ATR 42-600. This brings the total livery count to an extensive 1900! Additionally, the update addresses model issues, fixing broken animations like flaps and reversers. Other enhancements include the incorporation of "drooping elevator animations" for parked aircraft. An all-around overhaul of aircraft sounds has been implemented, ensuring a significant improvement across all models. Start-up and shutdown sounds have been completely revamped, with specific enhancements catering to V.R. and headphone users. In addition, the effects have been refined for optimal performance on all model LODs, featuring optimized heat blur effects contributing to an improvement in FPS performance. The lighting system has undergone a substantial rework, introducing new options that include faux flare and no flare lighting. The default is set to no flare, with adjusted flash rates on aircraft strobes, nav lights, and beacon lights to better align with real-world standards. Taxi and landing lights are now fixed to the front gear, extinguishing upon retraction. Some parked aircraft now feature logo lights, different colors for interior lighting, and smaller lights for aircraft positioned farther away from the user. Wingspan values have been adjusted to approximately 10 percent below real-life values to accommodate the additional 6m of space added to MSFS parking stands. The final version 1.3.1 includes minor fixes, with the VMR file receiving a complete update and the correction of the ICAO code for Porter Airlines DH8D to PTR. For users seeking to update or download FSLTL Traffic, the FlyByWire Installer provides a convenient installation process. Also check out the complete user guide with video tutorial here, FSLTL User Guide. ‍ As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aarc25</id>
    <title>Ant's Airplanes Releases CA-25 Winjeel for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aarc25" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6579115385f40d45baf51ed8_mediaslider01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="876549"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Developer Ant’s Airplanes has just released their latest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the CAC CA-25 Winjeel. This is Ant’s third aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, following the Tiger Moth, and the Ultralight Drifter. Ant’s also have a history of developing aircraft for FSX and P3D, and they also develop freeware for all three simulators. The CA-25 is a fixed wing, three seat, piston-driven taildragger and it was designed and built by the Commonwealth Aircraft Corporation in Australia. It was developed exclusively for the Royal Australian Air Force and it was used as their main training aircraft for four decades. The first CA-25 flew in 1955, and deliveries started later that same year. In total, 62 Winjeels were produced, and there are only 30 airworthy aircraft left today, with most being privately owned. The Ant’s Airplanes rendition of the CA-25 is based on a 1956 airframe, registered VH-OPJ, and has been modified to have an extra seat, bringing the total to 4 seats. Some of the features of the Ant’s CA-25 include: For more information and videos on the Ant’s Airplanes CA-25 Winjeel, you can head to their website. You can pick up the Winjeel at Simmarket, with availability on the Just Flight store coming soon as of the time of writing for $17.95 USD.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lgmvms</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Landmarks of Germany - Mecklenburg-Vorpommern for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lgmvms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657a65a8f4cd409103a0100d_84_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2217423"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. German developer FSDG have just released another product for their Landmarks of Germany series for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Their newest product covers the German Federal State of Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, in the northeast of the country, bordering Poland to the east, and the Baltic Sea to the north. In the pack, FSDG has included over 1,000 individual objects covering the whole state. Castles, famous buildings, bridges, television towers, radio towers, water towers, radar towers, chimneys, antennas, solar parks and lots of lighthouses can be found at their exact positions all across the state. This pack hopes to offer an enhanced VFR experience, and is part of a set that will eventually cover the entire country of Germany. You can get Landmarks of Germany - Mecklenburg-Vorpommern at the Aerosoft Store or FSDG's Website for €8.40, excluding VAT.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skytam</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Queen Tamar Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skytam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657b597975792750158eabab_tamar.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="972536"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyline Simulations has recently released their rendition of Queen Tamar Airport (UGSM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Mestia in Georgia, with a yearly average of 9,300 passengers as of 2022.  Mestia Airport was part of Georgia’s plan to increase regional tourist figures. It was built in 2010 with a GEL 8 million investment, with an architectural project that boasts a modern glassy style that contrasts with the natural surroundings and does not impact the environment. Designed and created by Jurgen Mayer-Hermann, the BBC considers the airport one of the world’s most beautiful.   With a 1,158-meter runway at 1,456 meters above sea level, the range of aircraft that can fly into this airport is limited. It’s currently only served by Vanilla Sky with their Let L-410 UVP-Es, taking passengers to Kutaisi, where passengers can connect with the rest of Europe.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, custom ground textures, custom 3D vegetation, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.68, requiring at least 644.37 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siachm</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Chiang Rai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siachm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657b6b31fd1f29d498da796e_chia.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="956365"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Chiang Rai International Airport (VTCT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the provinces of Chiang Rai and Phayao in Thailand with a yearly average of 1.6 million passengers.  It was opened in 1992, built to accommodate 3 million passengers per year and large widebody aircraft (747, 777, 787, A330, and A340).   There are plans to expand the airport, including an additional taxiway, more shops, and a runway extension. It’s expected to reach completion sometime in 2030.  While the airport had been operating at capacity for a while before the pandemic, the numbers have since plummeted and are still not showing signs of recovery.  Nok Air, Ruili Airlines, Thai AirAsia, Thai Airways International, Thai LionAir, and Thai VietjetAir currently serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom animated jetways, custom ground textures, hand-placed taxiway guidance signs, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.93, requiring at least 311.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs90ea</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Releases E190/195 for MSFS in Early Access</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs90ea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657b76260cb563a1c0f2ebb9_01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="934187"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio has recently released their rendition of the Embraer 190 and Embraer 195 for Microsoft Flight Simulator in an Early Access stage. This is the continuation of their well known E-Jets Series, which already includes their rendition of the Embraer 170 and 175. The Embraer 190 and 195 are stretched versions of the Embraer 170 series airframe. Built by Embraer in Brazil, the E190 and E195 differ from the shorter variants in the series with a more powerful engine, a larger wing, and larger horizontal stabilizer. The E190 entered into service in 2005 with JetBlue, and the E195 entered into service with FlyBe just a year later in 2006. The FlightSim Studio E190/195 is currently in an early access stage, with features such as a custom Autopilot system with LNAV and VNAV, and a custom FMS still being in development. As of the time of writing, the FSS E190/195 boasts features such as: For more information on the E-Jets Series by FlightSim Studio, you can head to their website. You can purchase the FlightSim Studio E190/195 at the Aerosoft Store for $39.99 USD.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxtpx</id>
    <title>FlightFX Teases New Cockpit Images of "Project ApX" for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxtpx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657bda5f25c7be3b68f1f797_Screenshot_2023-12-06_002847.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="2018984"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has recently released teaser photos of the cockpit of their next aircraft, which they dub “Project ApX” for Microsoft Flight Simulator. FlightFX, known for their general aviation aircraft, such as the highly popular Cirrus SF50 G2, and the Honda Jet, Project ApX is shaping up to be another exciting development in the MSFS General Aviation market. Project ApX was announced last month, and speculation has abounded around what FlightFX’s next project would be. Now that these teaser photos have been released, many flight simmers have predicted that Project ApX is the popular Cessna Citation X business jet. The photos also show a great amount of detail, with high quality textures and models, from the seats to the switches. All of this hints at a very promising aircraft for the sim. While FlightFX have not given any other details on Project ApX as of yet, or much on their next project, the Piaggio Avanti II, Threshold will keep you updated whenever they do, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a143</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a143" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657ccd9615031f61fa9848d9_a2a-comanche.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2289134"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently released a new update to their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, improving support for loading saved flights, fixing sound issues, and more.  Update 1.4.3, the fifth product update so far, brings versional parity with the newly released marketplace version of the Comanche, along with addressing a sound looping issue with the Wwise sound engine, and a couple of other changes that follow down below:   The aircraft is available on their website for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
