<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-04-26T18:29:58.309965+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdoc3</id>
    <title>PMDG Unveils Operations Center 3.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdoc3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently unveiled its new Operations Center 3.0, a complete overhaul of their product management application, which has been roughly the same since 2017. The new application features a fresh design, additional diagnostic tools, in-software add-on installation, streamlined livery handling, and much more. The rollout from OC2 to OC3 will be gradual, with the 777F being the first product to transition to the new suite. People who might be interested in checking the new Operations Center are instructed to uninstall their 777F, download OC3 from here, install it, enter their PMDG credentials, and then install the 777F from there. The 777-300ER will follow shortly (within the next few days), and once it is available, the procedure is expected to be the same as the one listed above. ‍ PMDG will also provide full documentation on operating the new Operations Center, which is said to be available “in time for the weekend.” ‍ As they move their entire product line to OC3, installers will no longer be available once the rollout is complete, as they want people managing their product line straight from OC3. ‍ They also hint at making a new 777 available soon, with “more news on that on the next update.” If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsesae</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2025 Schedule and Addon Experiences Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsesae"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67faceea35be38addd774d5d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The schedule for the upcoming FlightSimExpo 2025 has been announced, along with various addon experiences that will soon be available for booking. New information about the three-day event has just been revealed. A seminar schedule has been shared, outlining what to expect on each day of the event. On Friday, attendees can look forward to a range of product reveals, announcements, and updates covering various software and hardware developments. Saturday and Sunday will feature exhibits, seminars, and workshops. The schedule for the Community Stage is available now available online, while the schedules for the FSElite Stage and the SayIntensions.AI Stage will be announced closer to the event. In addition, several different addon experiences have been announced. These activities are available alongside the main event and include options such as tours at the local airport, workshops, and more. Registration for these experiences will open on April 19th at 12 PM ET. You can find more information about the various experiences here. As we look forward to all that the FlightSimExpo 2025 has to offer, more information about the event is available on the official website.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pd2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Shares Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pd2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fad7245aa3ed1bc5dbd717_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released another development update regarding nearly all of its products for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Key highlights from the update include the announcement of a release window for the upcoming PMDG 777-200ER for both MSFS 2020 and 2024, as well as a rollout sequence for the product line tailored for MSFS 2024. The development team has announced that the 777-200ER will be released simultaneously for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, with the launch expected between April 16th and April 29th. The add-on will feature different engine types, including the GE90-92 and the Rolls Royce Trent 892. Additionally, it will include a new generation of sound packages. There will be only one package available, which will include versions for both simulators. With the release of the first PMDG product for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 approaching, the team has announced a rollout schedule for their product lineup. The expected release dates are as follows:  ‍ - The 777-200ER is anticipated between April 16th and April 29th. - The DC-6 is scheduled for early May. - The 777F and 777-300ER are expected to be released between mid and late May. - The 777-200LR will be available from late May to early June. - The 737NGs do not yet have an estimated arrival time, as their conversion to 2024 has not yet begun. The team has announced that the 747 product lines will only be developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and not for 2020. Additionally, the PMDG Operations Center 3 has been expanded to include the 777F and 777-300ER. The DC-6 and all 737NG variants will be added very soon. Once these aircraft are added to OC3, they will be removed from OC2. We will inform you if we receive any further details about upcoming updates and releases. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/scpg36</id>
    <title>SimCoders and PAE Releases Beechcraft Bonanza G36 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/scpg36"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fc10d25955f6f85c05d172_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimCoders and PAE have recently collaborated to release the Beechcraft Bonanza G36 for X-Plane 12. This general aviation aircraft, renowned for its reliability and performance, has been meticulously recreated for the simulator with study-level detail. The Beechcraft Bonanza has a rich history. Manufactured by the US company Beechcraft, the first variant, the Model 35 Bonanza, was introduced in 1947 and produced until 1982. This model featured a distinctive v-tail design. In 1960, the Model 33 Debonair/Bonanza was introduced. It featured a conventional tail and remained in production until 1995. The latest variant is the Model 36 Bonanza, which was introduced in 1968 and is still in production today. The Model 36 is an extended version of the Model 33 Debonair/Bonanza. As of 2024, a total of 18,546 Beechcraft Bonanzas have been built. This general aviation aircraft is popular worldwide and can be found in many locations across the globe. The aircraft is equipped with a variety of features, including a fully simulated IO-550 engine, a custom fuel system, a custom G1000, realistic 3D modelling, REP features, and much more. The newly released aircraft is now available for purchase at the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $45.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftat17</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Athens International Airport to Version 1.7</title>
    <updated>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftat17"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fd40640c76383ff4a99a23_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyTampa has recently updated its Athens International Airport (LGAV) to version 1.7. This new version includes a range of fixes, improvements, and additional features. The most notable update is the compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, in addition to maintaining compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The scenery has undergone various enhancements as part of these updates. Some new features included in the update are improved terraforming, an extended solar farm, a newly added general aviation ramp, enhanced compatibility with MSFS 2024, and much more. See the full changelog below: ‍ Version 1.7: The updated version of Athens International Airport is now available, and can be purchased from FlyTampa for $17.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdd22</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Denver International Airport for X-Plane 12 to Version V2.2</title>
    <updated>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdd22"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fd635b4d099c2c8d076380_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Scenery Developer X-Codr Designs has recently updated its Denver International Airport (KDEN) scenery for X-Plane 12, bringing it to version V2.2. This update includes performance improvements that enhance efficiency by an average of 37%. Additionally, the update introduces various enhancements, new features, and fixes to improve the overall experience. Among the added features, we find higher resolution pavement, an updated gate layout, improvements to terminal exterior models, new details in terminal interiors, and much more. See the full changelog below: ‍ Version V2.2: The newly updated rendition of Denver International Airport is now available from the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $29.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lvabmt</id>
    <title>Lata Voadora Releases Campo de Marte Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lvabmt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fedd7dd8e78778841c5559_THRESHOLD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Lata Voadora has recently released their rendition of Campo de Marte Airport (SBMT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the first airport ever to open in Sao Paulo, Brazil.  It was founded in 1929 (95 years ago), and its first few years were far from glorious: it was bombarded during the Constitutionalist Revolution of 1932. That did not stop it from having its commercial debut a year later, with scheduled flights to Sao Carlos and Sao Jose do Rio Preto, Ribeirao Preto, and Uberaba. It was Sao Paulo's main airport until the opening of Congonhas Airport in 1936, which was bigger and less flood-prone (Campo de Marte had been flooded in 1929).  Nowadays, it mainly handles helicopters and general aviation and still hosts a nearly hundred-year-old flying club.  The traffic figures are around 60,000 aircraft operations per year, a massive drop from a decade ago when they reached almost twice that amount. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a high-detail model of the passenger terminal and its interior, custom landclass buildings, custom hangars, and much more. It's available on their website for roughly $7. Due to popular demand, an MSFS 2020-compatible version is in the works and set to be released by the end of the month. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fss72p</id>
    <title>Release Date Announced for FlightSim Studio Boeing 727 Passenger Version</title>
    <updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fss72p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ffc467cbce30a170ff83b6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightSim Studio recently made an announcement on its Discord channel, providing a quick update on the forthcoming passenger version of their Boeing 727 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The developer revealed details regarding the release date, pricing, and more. The highly anticipated passenger version of the 727 is set to be released on April 17th, between 10:00 and 14:00 UTC. The aircraft will first be available at Aerosoft, followed by Contrail shortly after. Other stores will have it available in the next 1 to 2 weeks, and the in-Sim Marketplace is planned to launch in about 2 to 3 months. The price for the passenger version will be the same as the freighter version, set at approximately $45.45. The passenger version will be offered as a standalone add-on and does not require the freighter version. Customers who own the freighter version will receive a 20% crossgrade discount. For those inquiring about compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the team is actively addressing an issue where the APU fails to start. Once this problem is resolved, a free update will be released to ensure compatibility with the latest simulator. With the official release set for tomorrow, various streamers have already gained access to the aircraft, showcasing it for those interested in a sneak peek. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hfat</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Fresno Yosemite International Airport V2 for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hfat"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6800e76fca1cd739ceafeb86_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly2High has recently released version V2 of Fresno Yosemite International Airport (KFAT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located in Fresno, California, this airport serves both military and civilian flights, accommodating nearly 2.7 million passengers each year. The airport originally opened as a military airfield in 1942, with construction of a passenger terminal beginning in 1946. Once the terminal was completed in 1948, both Trans World Airlines and United Airlines commenced operations at the airport. In 1959, work began on a new, larger passenger terminal, which was completed and opened for use in 1962. The current air traffic control (ATC) tower was finished in 1961. The terminal underwent an expansion in 1978. After renovations in 2006 made it capable of receiving international arrivals, international service began that same year. Today, the airport serves several airlines, including Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, and United Airlines, handling nearly 2.7 million passengers annually and just under 87,000 aircraft movements. The V2 version includes several features such as highly detailed models, high-resolution textures, and custom jetways. It also boasts a completely redesigned ground layout, new surrounding buildings, and enhancements to the main terminal when compared to the V1 version. The newly released version V2 is now available on SimMarket for approximately $18.18 and requires around 1.49 GB of disk space. For V1 owners, the V2 version is offered as a free upgrade. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b727pr</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Releases B727 Passenger for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b727pr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68010baadf6a12224d7d5fd6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightSim Studio has just released the much-anticipated passenger variant of the Boeing 727 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Following the release of the cargo variant last summer, users can now take to the skies with the passenger version of this three-engined aircraft. The first Boeing 727 entered service in 1964. Developed after the larger Boeing 707, this aircraft was designed to meet the demand for short-haul flights. There were two passenger variants: the Boeing 727-100 and the longer Boeing 727-200. Additionally, a cargo version of the aircraft was introduced. The Boeing 727 was in production from 1962 to 1984, with a total of 1,832 units built. It has been used by various airlines worldwide across commercial, government, military, and private sectors. The aircraft became an icon thanks to its distinctive three-engine design, making it recognizable around the globe. The FlightSim Studio B727 Passenger is packed with features that enhance the flying experience. The exterior boasts detailed PBR textures, custom animations, 3D lighting, and a variety of custom liveries. The interior includes a fully equipped cockpit designed for passenger operations, a custom cabin, tailored night lighting, and an extended EFB (Electronic Flight Bag). ‍ The flight dynamics have been developed by a real pilot, ensuring a high level of realism. System-wise, the aircraft is equipped with a comprehensive flight engineer panel, a custom SP-150 autopilot, and custom logic for the APU, GPU, generators, and more. For navigation, users can choose from five options: classic, retro, modern standard, modern realism, and futuristic. The sound package accurately replicates the JT8D-9 engine, contributing to the immersive experience.  ‍ The add-on aims to be a detailed and authentic recreation of the iconic airliner. The newly released Boeing 727 - Passenger Edition requires 5 GB of storage space and is now available at Aerosoft for approximately $45.45. Owners of the Boeing 727 - Freighter Edition qualify for a 20% upgrade discount. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350108</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350108"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68042929d55af3c27184af79_china1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued a new update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update introduces improvements to the step climb logic for better long-haul performance, overhauls the ECAM systems and logic, and fixes across art, sounds, and systems.  The step climb feature has been expanded, allowing pilots to manually enter an increased number of steps (or via SimBrief import). In combination with the auto step climb feature, fully optimum long-haul routes are now possible. The new ECAM additions include an ELEC and FCTL ECAM logic overhaul, built with the help of one of their qualified A350 engineers. The failure states have been thoroughly reviewed, and their associated system failures and redundancies have also been added (where possible). The complete changelog for the update follows below: v1.0.8Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️ Fixed: [FS24] APU door remained open after cycling APU master SW ON&lt;&gt;OFFFixed: [FS24] DOOR SD page OXY indication with CREW SUPPLY OFFFixed: [FS24] GLS: Arrival page not displaying LS and FREQ/CHANFixed: [FS24] FMS: Incorrect (FLAP 3) pseudo WPTFixed: [FS24] ND should show range distance while IR not lined upFixed: [FS20] Commbus Callback / Navigraph_Functionresult - Selecting SID from VHHXFixed: [FS24] OFFSET: End WPT drop-down menu not closing when WPT selectedFixed: [FS24] Incorrect WXR/PWS ON memo with engines OFFFixed: Negative course KDEN ILS 35RFixed: [FS24] MFD menu overlap issueFixed: [FS24] VD incorrect -ALT CSTR displayFixed: [FS24] MFD returning to FMS behaviour: should remember last accessed pageFixed: ATC COM - Hoppie CPDLC SPEED request limits Fixed: Route uplink on F-PLN page logic - discontinuitiesFixed: [FS24] VD not showing TO WPT in whiteFixed: [FS24] TO PERF page display after TO sequencedFixed: Insert history wind promptFixed: [FS20] PERF page - tab does not automatically change to correct segment of flightFixed: Flap pseudo formattingFixed: [FS24] FOR GA: SET TOGA MSG flashing after rotationFixed: [FS24] TLA-FLX mismatchFixed: [FS24] Sequenced ETP should disappear from NDFixed: [FS24] Early descent VDEV indicates higher than CRZ levelFixed: [FS24] DES: Preselected speed being followed but FMS shows original speedFixed: Missing "Minimums" and "100' Above" callouts when DH/DA is set in MDCUFixed: [FS24] GLS: Incorrect LAND 3 FMAFixed: [FS24] After landing, DOOR should only display after both engines are offFixed: [FS24] Thrust trend/command/transient missingFixed: [FS24] GA THR RED/ACCEL defaulting to AMSL instead of AGLFixed: APU switch button logic after shutdownFixed: [FS24] Modified SPD LIMIT not respectedFixed: [FS24] Incorrect ISA deviation in permanent dataFixed: [FS24] EFIS TRAF/ID turns ADS-B OFF&lt;&gt;ONFixed: Autosave/Resume not saving maintenanceFixed: Step ALTs logicFixed: FMS synced when both on active F-PLN pageFixed: C/L menu when closedFixed: Keyboard entry bugFixed: [FS24] MFD F-PLN: Clicking on blank area adjacent to F-PLN INFO opens menusFixed: [FS24] MFD notepad menu remains in view when notepad deselectedFixed: [FS20] Exception in Gauge MFD - CYYZ-VHHH F-PLNFixed: [FS20] Exception in Gauge MFD - LSZH to PHNL F-PLNFixed: [FS24] EDDF, DIXAT1C/1D blue diamond in F-PLN pageFixed: STEP DELETED message missingFixed: Unable to remove speed restrictions in certain casesFixed: [FS24] Double T/D shown during CLB phaseFixed: [FS24] Unable to change just the STAR, must reselect runway and approachFixed: MSG RECORD does not return to full message listFixed: [359][FS24] GA SOFT: SRS not maintaining correct speedFixed: [359][FS24] F/CTL ALTN LAW immediately after ADIRS OFFFixed:  Option to user-define default panel state (e.g., ON GPU or ON APU)Fixed: [FS20] After arrival, chocks, ASU, and ACU remain greyed outFixed: [FS24]  OIS Loadsheet renamingFixed: [FS20] OIS FLT OPS PLAN page bugs &amp; suggestionsFixed: [FS24]  OIS QoL double line textFixed: [FS24] OIS: CHOCKS greyed out on arrival but ops normalFixed: Aircraft options weathering sliderFixed: OIS Planner TAXI fuel defaulting to 20 KG instead of AUTO on spawnFixed: [35K][FS24] QoL OIS Maintenance/Chocks display for the 1000Fixed: [FS24] OIS TO PERF screen keyboard minus input not workingFixed: [FS24] OIS TO PERF incorrect SYNC during onwards flightFixed: GSX load can be triggered before data is loaded Fixed: Add warning or hide planner — OIS Planner requires Navigraph connectionFixed: Added Open in Browser button for NG linkingFixed: ETP next to runwayFixed: Cannot enter more than 4 Step ClimbsFixed: [FS24] S/C shown duplicated in F-PLNFixed: Timer inconsistenciesFixed: [FS24] F-PLN new destination shows original destination runways while on TPY planFixed: T.O/LDG memo active — WD line should draw for entire extension of memoFixed: [FS24] ECAM: ICE DETECTED logic incorrect when A-ICE already ONFixed: More button logic on ECAMFixed: Control surfaces move when Y HYD SYS is pressurised during ground cargo door opsFixed: Approach procedure not shown on ACTIVE/F-PLN/ARRIVAL page after selecting STAR/APPFixed: Position/NAVAIDs page shows DEST airport station data too early — should be &lt;300 NM from DEST and active PERF modeFixed: [FS24] FMS DEST button behaviour incorrectFixed: DEST EFOB shown when not calculatedFixed: AP off + DES mode — should revert to SPEED when slowing below VLSFixed: Chrono auto resets to 00:00 when stoppedFixed: Boxes around FMAFixed: A350 wheel page during go-around phaseFixed: FO KCCU DEST button causes CA-side MCDU to skip to destination pageFixed: Flap speeds on MDCU TO page flipping between valuesFixed: [FS24] SURV: ADS-B issueFixed: Incorrect VSD end bar position with DISCONsFixed: Engine pitch should be higher around 25% THRFixed: WASM crash — MFD exception on SEC to active swapFixed: [FS20] MFD exception — crash on clicking away from WPT drop-down in F-PLN pageFixed: [FS24] Freeze when entering approach dataFixed: Failed assertion !isnan entering FIX radiusFixed: [FS20] Gauge MFD exception — from PERF CLB to INIT then FUEL &amp; LOADFixed: [FS20] Gauge MFD exception — inserting HOLD at REQINFixed: [FS20] EFIS exception — switching to ANF in cruiseFixed: WASM error on load-in followed by WASM crashFixed: [FS24] OIS: MTOW PERF issueFixed: [FS24] Unable to get safe PERF when it should have workedFixed: OIS Planner — cannot generate plan when DEP/ARR airport is the sameFixed: Birdstrike logic request — raise availability ceiling to 37,000ftFixed: OIS boot time setting not respectedFixed: GSX refuel logic — ZFWCG calcFixed: DATALINK INIT wrong REGs (DRAIMS)Fixed: [FS24] SLS approach: Channel info missing in arrival pageFixed: VSD range indicator not aligned with pathFixed: Map auto-zooms on FINALFixed: Time counts backwards after 2400h in flightFixed: [359][FS24] Issue if TO WPT has AT ALT CSTRFixed: [CPDLC] Sound/light issue – Alert dismissal logicFixed: [359][FS24] Cruise managed target during SEL SPD incorrectFixed: Mailbox cursor unable to select "RECALL" buttonFixed: [FS24-SU2][A359] WASM MFD exceptionFixed: Pre-landing test missingFixed: [359][FS24] Go-around: Slats auto-retracted while on FLAP 3Fixed: [359][FS24] FCU ALT shows VS+0000 after pressing ALT — should remain dashedFixed: Barber pole behaviour after departureFixed: [PFD] Pitch bar should not display until airborneFixed: [PFD] THS visual indicator incorrect on takeoffFixed: [35K][FS24] FCU ALT 100/1000 knob plays double clickFixed: [FS20] Toggle SSA probes via OIS external optionsFixed: [359][FS24] FAP: Avionics and cargo bay lights not workingFixed: New OIS colors are not colorblind-friendlyFixed: [359][FS24] ALTN LAW incorrectly shown on groundFixed: [359][FS24] Flaps amber on ground with engines OFF — incorrectFixed: OIS weather conversion — MPS winds used as KTS without conversionFixed: [FS24] OIS TO PERF issue on turnaround — added user option to reset EFB PERF pagesFixed: Enroute Maps - only "standard" works after longer flights + fps loss when not loadingAdded: [FS24] OIS warning for pitot covers still on (same as ENG covers)Added: Route box to planning page as is required when using same DEP/ARR ICAOAdded: Refresh button for ZFWCG along with improved logicAdded: Auto remove covers option Added: CG values to AOC LoadsheetImproved OFP handling performanceImproved NG Token handling improvements for long idle times 3D Art 🎨🖌️Added: Engine coversFixed: -900 RAT animationFixed: Gap in engine and wing attachmentFixed: Visible gap between engine pylons and wing on -1000Fixed: [FS20] Rubber seals clippingFixed: [FS20] Drone camera collision not functioning properlyFixed: [FS20] Ice indicator object flippedFixed: [35K][FS24] Refuel belly panel errant model object when openingFixed: [FS20] Cabin windows tinted + reflectionsFixed: [359][FS24] Engine covers visible from insideFixed: [359][FS24] 359 engine cover says 350-1000Fixed: [FS20] Cockpit window shades disappear at LOD 1+Fixed: [FS20] Blending issue of glareshield between INT LOD 0/1+Fixed: [35K][FS24] Tail strobe has a detached elementFixed: [359][FS24] ENG covers clipping underside of engine Sounds 🔊Fixed: Retard callout repeating after landing and shutdownFixed: [FS24] TOO LOW GEAR played during go-around while climbing on edge caseFixed: Engine noise in flightFixed: [FS24] Rain sound effect too loudFixed: [FS24] CALLS: No sound when pressing PURSFixed: Work to equalise the ambience in flightFixed: Improved distancing of all walkaround interactives Fixed: Increase to engine pitch and vol at lower N1 - improved accuracy of spool pitch shiftFixed: Reduced wiper scratching effectFixed: pack and bleed buttons duplicate sound when switched offFixed: FCU knob sound doublingOverhaul of touchdown and rolling Optimisations to sound encoding (may help minimise cases of sounds not loading)Overhaul of engine sounds behind wing ‍ They also claim to be working very hard on an Xbox-compatible build, which is now undergoing testing to ensure proper stability and functionality. The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dfwimg</id>
    <title>imaginesim Updates Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dfwimg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68045f6a5af0ff18b1c77785_imaginesim_KDFW_MSFS2020_01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. imaginesim has recently issued an update to their newly released Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, addressing issues raised by customers such as ground blurring problems, a new jetway for stand A10, and more. The first update to be released for their DFW so far brings a host of improvements and refinements, mitigating the ground blur, adding additional taxiway guidance at RWY17C, extra center and edge lighting, refined service vehicle optimization, various model and texture improvements, more spills, grunge and smudges, terrain model refinements, a complete rebuild using the newest SDK, and more. The scenery is available on imaginesim’s website for roughly $33.15. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pesrij</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Releases Rijeka Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pesrij"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6804649b069e8c96e94bba7a_rijeka1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pilot Experience Sim has recently released their rendition of Rijeka Airport (LDRI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Rijeka, Croatia, with a yearly average of 164,000 passengers. The airport opened in May 1970 with a single terminal building, a single runway, and no taxiways.  Its layout remains largely the same, and the terminal building is still essentially the same as it was in the 1970s, albeit with minor modifications throughout the years to adapt the infrastructure to modern standards. Most of its traffic is strictly seasonal, and it is served by Air Dolomiti, Air Serbia, Croatia Airlines, Eurowings, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Trade Air, and Transavia. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, advanced LOD system, HD PBR texturing, advanced ambient occlusion, realistic runway profile, custom dynamic lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.62, requiring at least 1.16 GB of free hard disk space to install. Click here for the MSFS 2020 version. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slhgce</id>
    <title>SLH Sim Designs Releases Grand Case-Espérance Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slhgce"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68046b2c6eaabeb0fbcfcf9e_case1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SLH Sim Designs has recently released their rendition of Grand Case-Espérance Airport (TFFG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This airport serves the collectivity of Saint Martin in the Caribbean and has a yearly average of 192,000 passengers. The airport’s origins date back to the mid-20th century, when it started as a small airstrip catering to small private planes and the occasional charter aircraft. With the flourishing of tourism in the region in the following decades, expansion work was carried out to ensure it could accommodate larger propeller-driven aircraft, facilitating air travel to and from the island. In the 1980s, the island’s Dutch side handled most of the international traffic, while Grand Case was still a major player regionally, especially between French territories. Many upgrades occurred in the following years, including runway extensions, infrastructure modernization, and more. Eight years ago, it underwent major renovation work, including a modernized terminal building, a fire station upgrade, an extended parking apron, and a new control tower. Air Antilles, Air Caraïbes, St Barth Commuter, Trans Anguilla Airways, and West Indies Helicopters serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K texturing, animated ground equipment, custom dynamic lighting, a modeled tower interior, a custom GSX profile, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.34, requiring at least 767.78 MB of free hard disk space to install. Click here for the MSFS 2024 version. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42421</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases ChasePlane for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42421"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a03568493d826e0a991328_cp1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. After nearly a month of being a Club 42 exclusive for testing and refinement purposes, Parallel 42’s ChasePlane is now available to the public. This brings their advanced physics-based camera system to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. For the unfamiliar, ChasePlane was originally released in 2016 for Microsoft Flight Simulator X, later being made compatible with Prepar3d and rapidly becoming the de facto camera application for ESP-based simulators at the time. It would only be natural for them to develop it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 when that came about, but technical limitations have made that impossible until very recently, which is why it’s only a thing now, almost five years after the simulator’s release.  The add-on features highly realistic physics-based camera behavior based on extensive research and real-world pilot footage. This warrants realistic motion that dynamically responds to the environment, embracing the flight model rather than altering it. Pilots can feel the vibration during the take-off roll, the rush of turbulence, and the fluid shifts during maneuvers. ‍ As previously mentioned, a subscription system will no longer be required to store and share your settings in their cloud. Parallel 42 will now offer the service as a courtesy and take the costs upon themselves. ‍ Furthermore, ChasePlane 2020 owners will be entitled to a free upgrade once the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version is available.  ‍ The add-on is available in their store for $30.00. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdb772</id>
    <title>PMDG 777-200ER Release Window Updated</title>
    <updated>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdb772"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680a391a1d741e51793f3f54_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently updated the planned release window for the upcoming 777-200ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Additionally, the team has provided a more specific release window for the compatibility of the 777F and 777-300ER with MSFS 2024. A variety of other information has also been shared in the update. The release window for the PMDG 777-200ER has been updated. The original timeframe was between April 16th and April 29th, but it is now set for April 29th to May 1st, moving the release by just a few days. The team has confirmed that they will provide advance notice the day before the release.  ‍ This add-on will include various engine types, such as the GE90-92 and the Rolls Royce Trent 892, along with a new generation of sound packages. At launch, only one package will be available, which will include versions of the add-on for both simulators. Compatibility for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is scheduled for the second half of May for the 777F freighter variant, followed by the 777-300ER variant within 10-14 days after the freighter release. Finally, the team has shared updates on the 2024 compatibility for its DC-6. The overhaul for compatibility is nearing completion, and everything is coming together nicely. However, there are still some minor cosmetic improvements that need to be made. We will let you know if we receive any updates. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
