<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-05-02T18:21:47.750443+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teiipi</id>
    <title>Teikof Studio Releases San Luis Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teiipi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644afdce57febe5a7d24560c_ipi1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1657162"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Teikof Studio has recently released their rendition of San Luis Airport (SKIP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ipiales in Colombia.   The history of San Luis Airport dates back to the early 20th century when the first landing strip was built in the area. However, it was in the 1950s that the airport was officially inaugurated and began to operate commercial flights.  Throughout its history, San Luis Airport has played an essential role in the region's development, facilitating transportation and trade between the city of Ipiales and other cities in Colombia. In particular, the airport has been crucial for the tourism industry in the area, as it provides access to popular attractions such as the Santuario de las Lajas, a Gothic-style church built on a cliff overlooking the Guáitara River.  In recent years, San Luis Airport has undergone several renovations and upgrades to improve its infrastructure and capacity.   Despite its relatively small size, the airport plays a significant role in the economic and social development of the area. It is an important asset for the people of Ipiales and the surrounding communities.  Avianca and Satena serve it with flights to Bogotá and Cali.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal building and its interior, landmarks, custom ground markings, PBR textures, updated layout, and performance-oriented optimization.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.03, requiring at least 161.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfscha</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Brussels South Charleroi Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfscha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644b02c0815e532ccea279ef_bci1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3404817"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released the second version of their Brussels South Charleroi Airport (EBCI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Belgium with a yearly average of 8 million passengers.  Also known as Brussels-Charleroi Airport, it started as a training ground for pilots in 1919, keeping its training duties to this day with three flight schools.  ‍ Charleroi wasn’t a busy commercial airport until the late 1990s when Ryanair embraced it as one of their low-cost hubs. It’s now one of their continental bases, with many destinations. It wasn’t long until other LCCs wanted a piece of the cake, such as WizzAir, which forced them to build a new passenger terminal in 2008 and 2017, increasing the passenger handling capabilities from 5 to 10 million passengers, respectively.  It’s also home to Air Belgium, a scheduled and charter airline founded six years ago, offering many holiday destinations, including Guadeloupe, Martinique, Mauritius, and South Africa.  The V2 of Charleroi features custom airport buildings, custom vehicles, runway lengthening, improved runway lighting, and AFCAD changes. It’s a free upgrade for previous owners.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.87, requiring at least 473.08 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/penx12</id>
    <title>FS Designs Releases Pensacola International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/penx12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644b074def295c6a3d35e9fe_pensa1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1580647"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FS Designs has recently released their rendition of Pensacola International Airport (KPNS) for X-Plane 12, the second-busiest airport in North Florida with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers.  Pensacola got its first passenger terminal in 1935, with commercial service to begin two years later with Atlantic and Gulf Airlines, although very short-lived due to financial issues. National Airlines took over in 1938 with flights to Mobile and Jacksonville.  World War 2 saw the airport become a US Navy training facility, granting it a new control tower and runway.   The terminal was expanded 12 years ago at $35 million, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and modernizing the infrastructure. There are talks of a new concourse and parking expansion to come shortly.  American Airlines, American Express, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Silver Airways, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. Delta tops the market share chart with 26.04%, followed by Southwest and PSA Airlines with 21.63% and 10.87%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ortho imagery, high-quality 3D modeling, PBR texturing, custom 4K ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, up-to-date layout, and wear and tear effects using the latest technology.  It’s available on their store for $14.99, requiring at least 1.74 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksphl</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Philadelphia International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksphl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644bd6a6c68c7350c035891d_phl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3132915"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Philadelphia International Airport (KPHL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 21st busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 19.6 million passengers.  Philadelphia International started its life as a training airport back in 1925. For over 15 years, it didn’t even have a terminal building built in 1940, so airlines finally abandoned Camden Central Airport for it.   World War 2 converted the airport into a First Air Force training airfield, organizing and training various fighter and air bomber groups throughout the war. It was returned to civil control in September 1945.   It was granted international status that same year and got a new terminal in 1953, with further expansion in the late 1950s. By 1957, it was served by Eastern, TWA, United, American, National, Capital, Allegheny, and Delta.  The terminals were modernized for the first time in 1970, and new terminals followed in the same decade (D in 1973, E in 1977), costing around $300 million.  Nowadays, it’s a hub for American Airlines, with 63.75% of the market share, offering a huge list of destinations, domestic and international. Frontier takes second place with 11.02%, focusing on the domestic market and Central America. Spirit, Delta, and Southwest follow with 6.59%, 6.00%, and 4.51%.  The scenery features a high-fidelity rendition of the airport, with optimized texturing, main terminal interiors modeled, custom GSE vehicles, landside buildings, compatibility with most AI plugins, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.46, requiring at least 2.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrejt</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Previews E-Jets’  Authentic FMS </title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrejt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644d0149b7a25c1c07098cb3_xc1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1357105"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Marko Mamula, X-Crafts’ founder, has made an eight-minute video showcasing the progress on their FMS for the upcoming E-Jets Family release for X-Plane 11 and 12.   The video shows a step-by-step setup of two different routes, in America (Los Angeles to San Francisco) and Europe (Glasgow to London City), showing how the FMS handles altitude restrictions, etc.   The E-Jets Family by X-Crafts aims to bring highly detailed and accurate models of the interior and exterior of the entire lineup, with an authentic flight management system, autopilot modes, and realistic systems, helped by real E-Jet pilots and instructors.  The E-Jets are a series of regional jet airliners manufactured by Embraer, a Brazilian aerospace company. The E-Jets were introduced in 2004 with the E170 and E190 models and have since expanded to include the E175 and E195 models. They are designed for short- to medium-haul flights and can carry between 70 and 124 passengers, depending on the model. They are known for their efficiency, comfort, and versatility, making them a popular choice for regional airlines worldwide.  There’s still no information on a potential release date or pricing, but you can follow the development here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/apasfm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews A330 Sounds for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/apasfm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644d0c563d5903c067e309bb_kok1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1371680"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft’s Product Manager, has posted on their forum thread about the development progress on their upcoming Airbus A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator with two videos showcasing the work-in-progress sounds for the airplane. They mention having listened to it on a high-end audio system (Edifier R1700BT speakers driven by a Topping DX3 DAC), recommending everyone to play it as loud as possible to experience the quality of the sound set. The first video showcases the sounds as is, internally and externally. The second video has the headphone simulation activated, trying to mimic the behavior of a real-life Bose A20 Aviation Headset and its noise-canceling capabilities. They claim 99% of the customers have never been inside a real flight deck, therefore lacking a frame of reference, but also reinstating it’s as close as what a pilot hears as it gets.  P. Astarto, presumably one of their beta testers, shared two screenshots of a community-made AirAsia livery on taxi and take-off: There’s still no pricing and release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2lcy</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Announces London City Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2lcy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644dc77254ea1c0e15608174_lcy1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="555065"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently announced their rendition of London City Airport (EGLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in London with a yearly average of 5 million passengers. First proposed in 1981, the airport only came to be in 1987, after years of bureaucratic slowdowns. Work didn’t start until 1986 when they got the permission to begin constructing. For the first couple of years of operation, the airport only had a 1,080-meter-long runway with a 7.5-degree glide path slope, limiting it to a select range of aircraft like the Dash 7 and the Dornier 228. It wasn’t long until the airport submitted a request to extend the runway, making the glide path slightly less steep and thus allowing for an increased aircraft variety. Approval for the extension came in 1992, making the runway reach its current 1,508 meters of length, and the glide path was slightly reduced from 7.5 to 5.5, allowing even more aircraft to operate at the airport.  The airport is mainly served by British Airways, with many intra-European destinations such as Amsterdam, Barcelona, and Zürich. The visitors’ list includes ITA Airways, KLM, Loganair, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Luxair, and Swiss International Air Lines. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, a high-detail depiction of the airport terminal and its interior, landside details, custom ground clutter, and 3D people. It will be available on Tuesday (May 4th) for roughly $18.85 (14.99 pounds).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ec1352</id>
    <title>RotorSimXP EC135 for XP12 Coming May 1st </title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ec1352" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644e3eff81c827409f00e115_1974263960_ec135-2020-11-2017_09_34.png.dd1df78173f549e52b2925aa24f92722.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3803437"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. HSF Design and Rotorsim's popular EC135 Creation is confirmed as coming to XP12 on May 1st 2023. The Aircraft will see a host of new features and improvements over its XP11 predecessor. Developers took to Youtube to show some of the new and improved features of the rotorcraft which include new rain effects, sharper avionics displays and automatic weight/ Centre of Gravity changes.  The new and improved EC135 will be available on the Rotorsim.de website from May 1st. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swspc12</id>
    <title>SWS PC12 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swspc12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644e417c05664d672f9a68a2_343985416_3459106514366992_6171065092217622345_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="215830"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios have recently released a progress update on the development of their upcoming Pilatus PC12 for MSFS. The aircraft is expected to be a highly detailed recreation of the PC12 and from what we have seen so far, this looks to be holding true.  The progress report starts out with “The exterior model is now complete and we are finalizing the base materials and pumping out liveries. What is left to do on the exterior is finalise the flap animations, chocks &amp; reds. We are thinking also of animating the de-icing boots, but that will also require some effects work, so it is under consideration. The last thing will be the decals pass, where we will apply the rivets and stencils to the aircraft”  There has been some confusion among keen customers and members of the sim aviation community with the first part of the announcement, SimWorks studios from the beginning have pushed the upcoming pc12 as an in-depth aircraft, but in the latest post we see them debating as to whether the de-ice boots will be animated or not, many believe this is basic and should be without a doubt included for any in-depth recreation.  The details of the post go on to sadly explain why the project is behind schedule and that it will continue to fall behind schedule for the time being as developers need more hours in the project. We are informed that the initial release will be around the margin of $25-$35 but unfortunately will lack some features that will not be seen until subsequent updates, these features include A weather radar, 5 bladed propeller and the SWS tablet.  We will keep the community informed on this project as it goes through its development. </summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xprthp</id>
    <title>Better Rooftop Helipads for XP Released</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xprthp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644e485103893dea110c7c73_Pictures-17.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="488873"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Better Rooftop Helipads has been released for XP11 and XP12, this addon gives you enhanced buildings and rooftops for your helicopter operations around major cities.  The product features include:  Better Rooftop Helipads can be purchased from the Xplane.Org store for $19.95 ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/parvcp</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Releases Viracopos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/parvcp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644e6d81dab9f6b9078318b4_vcp1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3479893"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Paulo Ricardo has recently released his rendition of Viracopos International Airport (SBKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Campinas, Sao Paulo state, in Brazil. It's the fourth busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 11,845,500 passengers. The airport originated from a small airfield built in 1932 during the Constitutionalist Revolution in Sao Paulo. Then, in the 1950s, it started as a cargo airport, which is still one of its main roles today.   In the 1960s, it was Sao Paulo's international airport because Guarulhos did not exist yet, and Congonhas (SBSP) didn't have a long enough runway to accommodate international jet planes. The distance (100km) quickly became an issue, as people would fly to Rio de Janeiro - Galeão instead and then take a connecting flight to Congonhas. As a curiosity, it even showed up in the Guinness Book during that time as the furthest airport from the city it claimed to serve. It was Sao Paulo's international airport for nearly 25 years until Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) was constructed. Losing the "crown" didn't mean it would be forgotten and left to rot, with Infraero investing millions in improving the airport's infrastructure for passengers and cargo. It was divided into three steps, the first completed in 2004, with the construction of new passenger lounges and a new cargo terminal. The second step, in 2005, expanded the passenger terminal and built a control tower. The third phase, which consists of constructing a second runway, still has yet to happen. ‍ It's a popular alternate airport to Rio de Janeiro-Galeão and both Congonhas and Guarulhos in Sao Paulo because it hardly closes due to adverse weather conditions.  Viracopos is the second busiest cargo airport in the country, with 77,000 square meters of cargo terminals, 1,700 square meters for animal cargo, and 1,480 cubic meters of refrigerated space.  ‍ The airport is the hub for Azul Brazilian Airlines, covering a huge domestic network and a couple of international routes. GOL Transportes Aéreos, one of the biggest South American LCCs, offers five domestic routes from VCP. On the cargo side, it hosts Azul Cargo and LATAM Cargo.  The scenery features a highly accurate rendition of the airport and the surrounding city (Campinas), with a fully modeled passenger terminal and its interior, custom ground markings, landside buildings, custom ground clutter, custom night lighting, a realistic depiction of the internal layout with all of the shops as per real life, multiple POIs, and more. It's available on the MSFS Marketplace for roughly $15.99, requiring at least 4.70 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsscl650</id>
    <title>BSS Releases Soundpack for Hotstart Challenger 650</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsscl650" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644eb541ab76f87c4fb323fb_669001806_X-Plane2022-01-0900-15-55.jpg.49608ee2d0f29fb7bfba48f67f23d175.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="807434"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Blue Sky Star Simulations, better known as BSS, have released a sound pack for the popular Hotstart Challenger CL650. BSS is known for creating additional sound packs for many freeware and payware aircraft, these soundpacks revamp all sounds associated with the aircraft.   ‍ The Hotstart Challenger CL650 was released in early 2022 and has become a popular business jet addon. The Addon models the Bombardier Challenger CL650, a large cabin business jet based on the Canadair CRJ family aircraft. This jet can carry up to 19 passengers on trips up 4,000NM. The Hotstart CL650 was able to model this aircraft with “study-level” accuracy.  ‍ The BSS soundpack revamps many areas of the addon with new engine and wind sounds, a full feature list is as follows:  ‍ Existing Hotstart CL650 customers can purchase the sound pack from the X-Plane.org Store for $19.99. To purchase a copy of the Hotstart CL650, you can visit the X-Aviation.com store.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmddev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmddev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6306a7ff9e1844bf69c05102_PMDG_NG3_screenshots9__68685.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="173754"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo, PMDG’s founder, has recently published a development update on their forum regarding future updates for the 737 lineup and its potential Xbox release, the Universal Flight Tablet, the 777, and more.   Robert begins with information on an upcoming update for the 737 lineup. He claims they are refactoring some of the click-controls and animation logic to better conform with the new SDK standards, which differ from what it used to be back in 2020 when the aircraft was still under development. They managed to preserve all functionality on PC while also functioning identically on Xbox. They have also been refining AFDS roll control logic, improving magenta line computations, and continuing with the preparations to make the navdata system compatible with the new Navigraph database format.  With some of the aforementioned improvements, a new update is coming soon for the 737s. It will be available in the PMDG Operations Center for people who bought it directly via their website and a week later on the Marketplace (they state it’s hard to predict how long that will take, so it’s just an assumption).  PMDG claims to be “happy” with the 737 on Xbox, although holding off on releasing it just yet because they have not gained clarity on the timeline for the associated livery packages available in the Marketplace for use by Xbox customers. They are using the DC-6 as a gauge for how long it takes, and it appears to move through the process substantially slower than the aircraft itself. They intend to fully understand the timeline before releasing the aircraft. On that livery package note, they state that even though the original plan was to make it free of charge, the Marketplace has a minimum pricing of $4.99 per item, which will be the cost of each livery package, through no fault of their own.  The Universal Flight Tablet is said to be robust and ready for wide-scale testing after the developers had to fight an issue involving C++/WASM and their capabilities of sending/receiving data from the sim to the outside world. They don’t have a release timeline yet, but they say Navigraph/SimBrief users will be pleased with the UFT once it’s out.  The DC-6, on the other hand, also underwent heavy work to ensure proper compatibility with the Xbox, including changes to the shape/function of some clickable surfaces to facilitate their use on consoles. The changes are currently being tested; they claim it should be out late next week. PC users will also get the update, but it’s said to be “transparent,” given it targets Xbox folk.  They finish with information on the 777, saying “work is progressing nicely” and that the “pieces are coming together in a polished form.” Although they do not plan to show any in-development shots yet, they have claimed it’s “yielding some absolutely spectacular results” and that their development process has matured significantly since 2020. They promise that the wait and their silence will be paid off with great joy.  The 737 Lineup and the DC-6 are available on the PMDG Shop and in the MSFS Marketplace (partially).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carfle</id>
    <title>Carenado Updates Part of MSFS Fleet</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carfle" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644ecc7203a3d77f3160ae0b_carenado1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="348570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has recently updated some of their aircraft (PC12, C337 Skymaster, C170B, PA34 Seneca V, and PA28R Arrow III) to version 2.0 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing many improvements and bug fixes. The new update aims to bring the aircraft up to the latest standard with improved integration of the custom Garmins (WT, TDS, and PMS), engine sounds, overall flight dynamics, a redesign of the electrical system, VR compatibility improvements, improved engine startup and heat effects, and minor bug fixes. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ ‍ The update is now available on the MSFS Marketplace, free of charge. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orblc2</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases London City Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orblc2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6450f5bcb024aa0b4cfa0f8c_lon1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1542527"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently teased an upcoming update to their now nearly three-year-old rendition of London City Airport (EGLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in London with a yearly average of 5 million passengers. The original LCY came out back when the simulator was brand new, and developers were still getting acquainted with the SDK, making it quite outdated by contemporary standards, especially considering the real-life layout also saw changes in that meantime. Version two considers the airport expansion, with its parallel taxiway, new parking stands, and the remote digital control tower. ‍ They claim to have entirely rebuilt the airport, with an extensive rework of every detail, new textures, additional enhancements, and a custom ground poly.   ‍ The airport is said to integrate perfectly with their Landmarks London product, ensuring a highly immersive approach.  They claim it should be available soon on OrbxDirect, and previous owners will be able to get their hands on it for a small upgrade fee.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hbli</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Bellingham International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hbli" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6451290a2e7c1f23c6674ae2_bli1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1203983"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Bellingham International Airport (KBLI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third largest commercial airport in Washington with a yearly average of 316,693 passengers as of 2022.  The airport’s history dates back to October 1936, when the construction work began under the supervision of the WPA (Works Progress Administration), which had previously funded the purchase of the airport’s 200 acres of land from Charles F. Larrabee. Initially, there were plans for three runways, but only one was built, with 1,100 meters of length and 46 meters of width.   The US Army Corps of Engineers took over the entire project in 1940, expanding the airport to three full runways and building a basic infrastructure to operate as an airport. It was opened to the public a year later and then seized by the US Army not long after, following the Pearl Harbor attacks.   During World War 2, Bellingham International was utilized by the Fourth Air Force to provide an aerial defense to the Pacific Coast and later on for ferrying aircraft to Alaska for its subsequent transfer to the Soviet Union.  Post-war, the facility was closed and handed back to Whatcom County, slowly redeveloped as a civilian airport with a terminal designed by F. Stanley Piper. High costs led Whatcom County to sell it to the Port of Bellingham in 1957 for 1 dollar. The new owners were not fond of the high expenses either, only resurfacing one of the runways (16/34), which is still the sole runway in operation.  In 2010, the runway was resurfaced to accommodate Allegiant Air’s Boeing 757s on their nonstop service to Hawaii.   The terminal saw upgrades in 1980 with a two-phase project and a 38 million-dollar expansion in the early 2010s, increasing the number of gates and the general terminal area from 27,500 square feet to 104,000 square feet.   Bellingham is served by four airlines: Alaska Airlines (Seattle-Tacoma), Allegiant Air (Las Vegas, Los Angeles, Oakland, Palm Springs, Phoenix/Mesa, San Diego), San Juan Airlines (Eastsound, Friday Harbor, Lopez, Point Roberts), and Southwest Airlines (Las Vegas, Oakland).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of BLI, with an updated ground layout, custom ground markings, a terminal interior, and more.  It’s available on FlightSim.to for roughly $10.99, requiring at least 470.91 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
