<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-10-08T18:20:50.092663+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mawu15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Announces World Update XV: Northern Europe and Greenland</title>
    <updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mawu15" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6514df76ed08456e7a5e8230_capture_cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="836045"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In the Microsoft September development livestream hosted on Twitch, Microsoft and Asobo have announced World Update 15, which covers Northern Europe and Greenland, in partnership with Gaya Simulations. The update includes many improvements for the landscapes of Scandinavia, including, 5 bespoke airports, new cities with photogrammetry, 90 new Points of Interest, 3 bush trips, 3 discovery flights, 3 landing challenges, and brand new Digital Elevation Maps with a resolution of 40 centimeters.  Nine cities were announced to receive photogrammetry, including Oslo in Norway; Visby, Malmö, and Linköping in Sweden; and Aarhus, Copenhagen, Frederikssund, Roskilde, and Odense in Denmark. A tenth city, Gothenburg, was also teased, but it is still in development and going through further review by the Swedish Military, before being given the full green light.  The 5 hand-crafted airports are: Many of the bespoke airports, as well as the POIs have been created in collaboration with Gaya Simulations, known for their sceneries, and have worked with Microsoft before on World Update 14.  ‍ While an exact release date has not been set for World Update 15, Threshold will keep you updated when it does, so stay tuned for that, and even more high quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ib3an3</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases A300-600's 3D Model for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ib3an3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6515ba0313874d8b4a20b5c1_gabnriel.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1661196"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently published five new screenshots of their upcoming A300-600R(F) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing their work on the engine &amp; APU interior, and more. ‍ While the centerpiece of the teaser is the new images, they also mention that the detailed engine and APU interiors will be part of the maintenance system built into their Electronic Flight Bag. ‍ The Airbus A300-600 was the final variant of the A300 to be ever built (excluding the Beluga), featuring the modern avionics implemented with the A310, bringing a fully featured glass cockpit that removed the need for a flight engineer, an improved wing with a recambered trailing edge, single slotted fowler flaps, and the removal of slat fences. Three hundred thirteen units of the A300-600 were sold, and many are still flying today. ‍ There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msu13r</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 13</title>
    <updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msu13r" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651603c1597fbb56b23779c9_sc6vzv.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="219811"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has released Sim Update 13 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which includes many changes, bug fixes and improvements, and community requested fixes. The main focus for this Sim Update was many small fixes and changes to many facets of the simulator.  ‍ The main volume of changes came for the 747-8 and 787-10, which both have received fixes to their avionics by Working Title. Most notably, being the addition of SimBrief integration in both aircraft, as well as the addition of an EFB for the 787. The new EFB also allows for takeoff calculations, which you can send directly to the FMC. Another highly requested feature, step climbs, have also been implemented. ‍ The Garmin glass cockpits have also received improvements and changes courtesy of Working Title. Terrain and Weather Radar improvements have been of primary focus for this update, allowing users to control the gain of the weather radar through the settings pages.  ‍ On their September Development livestream, which happened just yesterday, they provided a list of some of the bigger community requests:  You can read the full list of the myriad of changes that Sim Update 13 brings on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Forums. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ineghi</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Southampton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ineghi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6516fed147230803ed1c7809_south.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="417634"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Southampton Airport (EGHI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Hampshire with a yearly average of 631,458 passengers.  The airport’s history dates back to 1910, when its meadows were used as a take-off and landing spot for monoplanes, then known as Eastleigh Airfield. It was then transformed into an aircraft acceptance base for the Royal Flying Corps during World War 1.  ‍ During the interwar period, the site served as a transit camp for refugees who wished to sail to America. Hangars were converted into dormitories for them.   Southampton Corporation purchased the site in 1932, naming it Southampton Municipal Airport, with part of it being utilized by the RAF after 1935.   Supermarine, a former British aircraft manufacturer, opened a test flight facility there and built a shed. Cunliffe-Owen Aircraft followed suit, later being bought out by Ford and utilized to manufacture Ford Transit vans until its closure in 2013.  During World War 2, the airport was transferred to naval command and renamed HMS Raven, spending most of it as a ground and air training facility. It was handed back to civilian ownership soon after, in 1946.  Thirteen years later, it was purchased by a racing pilot and began its transformation into a proper regional airport, with a concrete runway in 1963 and a railway station right beside it.   It’s served by Aer Lingus, Aurigny, Blue Islands, British Airways (seasonally), Eastern Airways, easyJet, KLM, and Loganair.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-crafted ground textures, a true-to-life landside recreation, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, an up-to-date layout, fully modeled local points of interest, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.85, requiring at least 2.47 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsschi</id>
    <title>FSSDesigner Releases La Chinita International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsschi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651706bd88d5780dcbdcd5cd_chi.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="276583"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSSDesigner has recently released their rendition of La Chinita International Airport (SVMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Venezuelan city of Maracaibo with a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers (as of 2008).  It opened in 1969, creating a gateway to western Venezuela and consequently alleviating the traffic on Simon Bolivar International Airport, serving the capital city of Caracas.  ‍ Nowadays, it’s the third busiest airport in the country, only behind Caracas and Porlamar. ‍ It’s served by Avior Airlines, Conviasa, Copa Airlines, LASER Airlines, RUTACA Airlines, Turpial Airlines, and Venezolana. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom taxiway signage, custom approach lighting systems, GSX compatibility, custom static objects, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.44, requiring at least 867.65 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfstaw</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Tawau Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfstaw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6518738547ce331c55baa8b2_taw1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="682575"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Tawau Airport (WBKW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Tawau Division in Malaysia with a yearly average of 572,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was opened in 2001, replacing the former Tawau Airport, whose runway was one of the shortest in the country, and the administration decided to build a new airport from scratch instead of dealing with extra expansion work (that they had previously conducted in the 60s and 80s).  ‍ ‍ With a 2,685-meter-long runway, a much bigger terminal building, an instrument landing system, and night certification, the new Tawau Airport became an essential asset to the region’s economy.  ‍ It is currently suffering from limited capacity issues, with expansion plans to increase the numbers to at least 2.5 million passengers annually.  AirAsia, Firefly, Malaysia Airlines, MASwings, and MYAirline serve it. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, custom groundpoly, custom jetways, and AI traffic compatibility.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.71, requiring at least 1.01 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgbsb</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Teases Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgbsb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65187ccd758cc3b372e8acd3_bsb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="691720"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently shared screenshots of their progress on Brasilia - President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR), the third busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. ‍ A proper terminal building was inaugurated in 1971, designed by Tércio Fontana Pacheco, a Brazilian Air Force architect. ‍ The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more, divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. ‍ New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. ‍ It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. ‍ The upcoming scenery is said to feature animated moving walkways, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, detailed landside, and more. There’s no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrs108</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Lays Plans for X-Plane 12.0.8 and Beyond</title>
    <updated>2023-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrs108" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651c786fa41cb40d1c0c88c1_a330.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="262358"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has made a blog post summarizing what is planned for X-Plane 12's recent future, including a new versioning scheme, engine model improvements, improved landing gear physics, and more. ‍ With the recently shipped 12.07, Laminar included three months' worth of rendering engine improvements, new cirrus clouds, lower VRAM footprint, improved cloud rendering, and OpenXR integration. For the next update, they have already laid out most of the futures that will ship with it.  ‍ The upcoming patch will bring a new naming scheme, giving Laminar "more numbers to play with," as the previous two digits could only go so far and, therefore, limit the number of patches they could potentially churn out.  ‍ They expect a beta build to be ready in a week or two, focusing on improving the flight model, networking/multi-monitor, and tools for using X-Plane with projectors: projector warping/blending will be available for X-Plane Professional license owners. ‍ With data from Pratt &amp; Whitney and Phillip Ringler, Austin Meyer has improved how the platform simulates engine performance, with jets, turboprops, and reciprocating engines following real-world figures more closely.  ‍ The landing gear physics was also improved, with better wheel inertia, weld modeling, and ABS revisions, making sure it stops the wheels from locking realistically. ‍ Last but not least, jet aircraft in X-Plane 12 will now accurately simulate how jets use their fuel to cool their oil, with the oil heating the fuel and its consequent dissipation through the wing's skin, operating as a radiator.  ‍ They have also laid out plans for 12.1.0, bringing real weather improvements, cloud shadows on the water, better bloom lighting effects, robust contrast adaptive sharpening, softer ground shadows, MSAA improvements, improved CPU performance, and better water opacity. ‍ They finish with a price hike announcement, from $59.99 to $79.99, allowing Laminar to expand its team and warrant its future development. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsipvu</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Provo Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsipvu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651dec48b559ecb068fde964_pvu.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="583290"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Provo Municipal Airport (KPVU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Provo in Utah with a yearly average of 145,000 passengers. ‍ Originally an uncontrolled airport, its control tower was built in 2005, followed by major improvements to the terminal in 2011, bringing it up to the required standard to receive airline service.  ‍ After three years of work, a brand new passenger terminal was completed in 2022 at a total cost of $40 million. It has four gates and can be expanded to ten in the future. Allegiant has announced plans to open a four-aircraft base at the airport, with Breeze following suit. Both are the only airlines operating in Provo. ‍ With two FBOs and a flight school, it’s also a significant regional general aviation airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a full 1:1 terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, high-definition PBR textures, custom orthophoto, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on Verticalsim’s Shop for $14.99, requiring at least 1.89 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsq850</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases TBM 850 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsq850" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651ec4e1b0116e311d9bc3d1_tbm.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="299595"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently released their rendition of the Daher TBM 850 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a high-performance single-engine turboprop plane introduced in 1990, with 1,000 built as of October 2020 across multiple variants. ‍ Its development dates back to the 1980s when Mooney and SOCATA (the original manufacturer of the TBM) started a joint venture to develop a new, enlarged turboprop design. It was marketed as the TBM 700 and became the world’s first high-performance single-engine passenger aircraft to enter production. ‍  The sales were booming, creating new variants and model improvements, which eventually resulted in the TBM 850’s release in 2008, offering 850 horsepower instead of 700, a modern avionics system, and a ceiling of 31,000ft.  ‍ ‍ Black Square’s TBM 850 brings nearly 100 possible failures, persistence, realistic 3D gauges, multiple navigation systems varying from the Bendix KNS-80 to a Garmin GTN 750, along with com radios, a transponder, and a weather radar. It also includes a 100-page manual with usage instructions. It was built from the ground up, meaning it’s not part of their Steam Gauge Overhaul series and is said to be their most advanced aircraft so far. ‍ The newly released TBM 850 is available for $41.99 on Just Flight, requiring at least 502 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samxia</id>
    <title>SamScene Releases Xiamen International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samxia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651f39976583cbd219eb4991_xia.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1445492"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SamScene has recently released their rendition of Xiamen Gaoqi International Airport (ZSAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Chinese city of Xiamen with a yearly average of 14.9 million passengers.  The airport was built in the 1980s on top of the former Xiamen Airport, abandoned for more than 30 years, with nothing left but a gravel runway. It opened in 1983, becoming China’s first “International” airport (naming-wise). That was not the single thing it pioneered: it was the first airport built with foreign capital in the country, the first to decentralize local government to implement localized management, and the first to rely on self-raised funds for large-scale expansion work.  ‍ If one thought that was pioneering enough, they were also the first airport to set up an air cargo terminal in cooperation with civil aviation circles on both sides of the Taiwan Strait and the first to introduce international low-cost airlines. ‍ ‍ Between 1984 and 2014, the airport went from 100,000 yearly passengers to 20.8 million, making it one of the busiest single-runway airports in China. ‍ It was expanded for the last time in 2014 with the opening of Terminal 4, and now it’s constrained by urban development around it, which made them kickstart the construction of a new airport on Dadeng Island, with two runways, a 550,000 square meter terminal, and the ability to handle up to 45 million passengers.  ‍ It’s a hub for XiamenAir and a focus city for Shandong Airlines, China Eastern, and Spring Airlines. The visitors’ list includes Air Macau, Cebu Pacific, Korean Air, Malaysia Airlines, and Philippine Airlines. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, custom jetways, realistic night lighting, basic interiors for performance (T4), and landside buildings. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.79, requiring at least 1.86 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bougpe</id>
    <title>Boundless Teases Free Inverness Update for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bougpe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6520717900dfb92f04bfd043_gpe2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437337"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released a short teaser video on their Facebook page showcasing the progress of its upcoming update for Inverness Airport (EGPE), bringing new ground textures, animated ground traffic, and more.  Inverness Airport is the main gateway to Northern Scotland, with a yearly average of 900,000 passengers as of 2019. It’s served by AlbaStar (seasonally), British Airways, easyJet, KLM, and Loganair.  The update will bring updated ground textures, animated ground traffic, upgraded lighting, upgraded lorry textures, upgraded terminal textures, a reduced file size, and an option to run without static aircraft.  ‍ While the update is not out yet, the previous version is available on their store for roughly $15.89, requiring at least 2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hspr</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Abraham Lincoln Capital Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hspr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65207d5d991a874fdbadf87f_spring1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="901806"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Abraham Lincoln Capital Airport (KSPI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Springfield, Illinois, with a yearly average of 145,000 passengers.  The airport opened in 1947, replacing Springfield’s former main airport, which was deemed inadequate for commercial operation due to terrible infrastructure. Initially, it sported three 5300 ft runways, a service apron, a temporary passenger terminal, and T-hangars for 38 airplanes.  ‍ The terminal was recently upgraded with funds from the Airport Improvement Program, a grant sponsored by the FAA. They have also improved the FBO, hangars, roadways, and parking lots.  It also houses the Capital Airport Air National Guard Station, making it a civil-military airport. It’s a 91-acre facility, hosting the 183d Fighter Wing, an Illinois Air National Guard Unit.   Traffic-wise, 64% of it is general aviation, 20% military, 15% air taxi, and only 2% corresponds to commercial. Allegiant Air, American Eagles, and Breeze Airways serve it with short regional ops.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and high-detailed models of all buildings.   It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $9.49, requiring at least 3.54 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwsan</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release San Diego International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwsan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6521bba174398f41fac4a04e_san1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="546503"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld &amp; AmSim have recently released their rendition of San Diego International Airport (KSAN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Californian city of San Diego with a yearly average of 22 million passengers, making it the third busiest in the state.  The airport was opened almost 100 years ago in 1928, the first federally certified airfield to serve all types of aircraft, playing an important role in testing sailplanes during the early 1930s.   It was taken over by the US Army Air Corps in 1942 to house the heavy bombers manufactured in the region. It led to an incredible expansion work that made the airport jet-ready even before the advent of commercial jet aircraft.   It was returned to the city right after the war, with Pacific Southwest Airlines starting service in 1949. By 1957, there were an average of 42 daily departures from American, United, Western, Bonanza, and PSA.  Paderewski Dean &amp; Associates built Terminal 1 and 2, which replaced the original terminal with a much larger area and modern infrastructure for the time (1967 for Terminal 1, and 1979 for Terminal 2).   A third terminal was built in 1996, along with a Terminal 2 expansion in 1998 that added 300,000 square feet to its total area.  It’s an operating base for Southwest Airlines and a focus city for Alaska Airlines. Air Canada, Air Canada Express, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, Japan Airlines, JetBlue, Lufthansa, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet also serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, a detailed terminal area, animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures, surrounding buildings, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.34, requiring at least 2.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ptable</id>
    <title>PMDG’s Universal Flight Tablet Set To Release Soon</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ptable" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6521dff7e1dde357d0673269_1250410_20230614041115_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2455681"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo from Precision Manuals Development Group has published a new development update, bringing exciting news about the Universal Flight Tablet, the 777, and pending updates for their existing lineup.  After nearly a month of complete silence, Randazzo says, “the fruit trees are now in bloom,” with their long-stuck projects and updates beginning to appear shortly, while also anticipating that the last quarter of this year and the next quarter will be “quite a bit of fun.”  They have decided on a release date for the Electronic Flight Tablet and have also started working on preview material, which should appear shortly. The release date will be shared along with the material, with PMDG warranting that users will know about the release date well in advance.  The UFT update will be a free micro-update for PMDG.com and Marketplace customers, but the latter will take longer to see the light of day because of Microsoft’s intake process. They estimate around 2-3 weeks from the release on their official website, and it’s just guesswork based on the average time it takes, according to their empirical data.  The 777 has not entered beta due to issues with the development team, but they are pleased with how it’s coming together, with handling characteristics and feel that are entirely unmatched, or so they claim. Previews will be held back for now as they want to show something remarkable.  Updates for the 737 were held back on PC because the new update will bring the EFB. Marketplace-wise, they are still dealing with the 3.00.0072 update that has been stuck for two months. They expect to get that sorted out soon.  PMDG has been working along with Working Title to find a fix to an issue with their DC-6’s gyropilot behavior, and they will roll out an update as soon as it’s ready.  The 737 lineup and the DFC-6 can be found on PMDG.com or via Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fleham</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fleham" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6522f1e541e2da0763da3258_schi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2880824"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has recently released their rendition of Amsterdam Airport Schiphol (EHAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the world's third busiest airport by international passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 72 million passengers. ‍ It opened 1916 as a military airbase, eventually converting into a civilian airport after WW1. It was captured during World War 2 by the Germans and destroyed. The rebuilding process started soon after, and it became the main airport of the Netherlands in 1949, undergoing an expansion project that sacrificed the town of Rijk to make room for their ambitious plans.  ‍ It was expanded again in 1967, with a new terminal area still partially used today (Departure Halls 1 and 2). Parts of the original piers (C, D, and E) are also from that period. A further modification was required in the 1970s to ensure Boeing 747 "compatibility," and a new pier was made for widebody aircraft in 1977. ‍ The 1990s brought further modifications, as the airport's new size meant the old control tower was not tall enough to oversee all of it, leading to the construction of a new one in 1991. Then, a new departure hall and a new pier (G) were added in 1993. ‍ With the construction of a sixth runway in 2003 came the need for another control tower to ensure they could oversee everything again. One was not enough. ‍ It's a hub for KLM, KLM Cargo, KLM CItyhopper, and Martinair, with the first being the Netherlands' national carrier. EasyJet, Transavia, and TUI fly Netherlands also have operating bases at the airport, flying people all over Europe. The visitors' list is quite substantial, as one would expect from the third busiest airport in the whole world, including the likes of Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air India, Air Malta, Air Transat, American Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Croatia Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Etihad Airways, JetBlue, Korean Air, Royal Jordanian, Ryanair, Turkish Airlines, and United Airlines. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, terminal interior models, PBR materials, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, custom terrain, and more. ‍ It's available on FlyTampa's website for $21.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
