<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-11-07T18:34:58.780638+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sofbrs</id>
    <title>SoFly’s Bristol Airport Releasing on Friday</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sofbrs"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690a1568a698ab902b58902d_sofly-bristol-airport-eggd-msfs2024-01.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly recently announced the development and imminent release of Bristol Airport (EGGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which will land on the virtual shelves on Friday (07/11).  Built on top of a former RAF airfield, Bristol Airport was inaugurated in 1957, replacing Bristol’s former main municipal airport (Whitchurch).  In 1958, a 200,000-pound passenger terminal was built, part of the administration’s effort to make it the city’s de facto airport. Four years later, a new control tower was built. In 1969, the runway underwent its first expansion, and the terminal was extended to handle the predicted figures for the 1970s and beyond. In the early 1980s, despite being served by 17 charter airlines, the airport was operating at a loss until Les Wilson took over as managing director and completely turned the tide. He held this position until his tragic passing in a car accident in 1995.  The mid-1980s slight recovery from the crisis allowed the administration to expend an extra dime or two on the construction of a new international departure lounge. Four years later, a new concourse area was opened, and planning for a new terminal kicked into action, leading to its eventual approval in 1994. Work started in 1997, shortly after FirstBus Group bought a 51% stake in the airport, heavily investing in its new infrastructure. The terminal, which cost 27 million pounds, was ready by 2000.  Passenger numbers reached the two million mark for the first time that year. A year later, the airport was purchased by a joint venture for 198 million pounds, and 50% of it was sold again in 2006. In 2015, the terminal was expanded again with a larger departure lounge and an outdoor terrace, followed by a new terminal extension adding 9,000 square meters. The project reached completion in 2017. It’s a focus city for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Aer Lingus, Aurigny, Blue Islands, Edelweiss Air, KLM, Loganair, Pegasus Airlines, and Sun Express also serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life elevation data, full GSX integration with animated doors, a dynamic airport environment, PBR texturing, dynamic seasons, and performance-friendly optimization. There’s no information on the pricing yet, but the scenery is set to release on Friday.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/twddoh</id>
    <title>Tuwaiq Designs Releases Hamad International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/twddoh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b49ce30d3407ce90fc65d_367846_Screenshot_2025-10-16_161906.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Tuwaiq Designs has released Doha Hamad International Airport (OTHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, marking the latest addition to the developer’s ongoing Qatar Project series. Opened in 2014, Hamad International replaced the old Doha International Airport and quickly became Qatar’s main aviation hub. It now serves as the home base of Qatar Airways, and is widely regarded as one of the most luxurious and architecturally impressive airports in the world.  In the years leading up to the FIFA World Cup 2022, the airport underwent a major expansion, adding new lounges, additional gates, and an enlarged terminal area, to accommodate growing passenger traffic. Tuwaiq Designs’ recreation of Hamad International aims to capture the airport’s scale and sophistication. The scenery includes accurate terminal models, with fully modelled interiors.  Furthermore, the scenery features PBR textures and custom ground surfaces, realistic lighting, reflections, and wear effects across runways and aprons.  Performance has also been carefully tuned with optimised LOD models, balancing frame rates and visual quality. Here’s the feature list: Tuwaiq Designs’ Hamad International Airport (OTHH) is now available on simMarket for $31.59, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsslhm</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Saint Lucia Hewanorra International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsslhm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b505a161b228f735b1bff_368086_Screenshot_2211%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TropicalSim has added another Caribbean destination to its Microsoft Flight Simulator lineup, releasing Saint Lucia Hewanorra International Airport (TLPL) for both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Hewanorra International Airport is the larger of Saint Lucia’s two airports, situated near Vieux Fort, on the southern end of the island, around 33 miles from the capital.  It is the main international gateway to the island, receiving traffic from airlines such as Air Canada Rouge, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, JetBlue, United Airlines, and WestJet, connecting the island to North America and Europe. TropicalSim’s scenery aims to closely mirror the real airport, featuring a newly modelled terminal, detailed interiors, and ultra-high-definition PBR texturing across the main structures and ground polygons.  The developer has also included native MSFS dynamic night lighting. The airport is designed to integrate seamlessly with the default simulator scenery. The scenery is available now on SimMarket for $20.96, including taxes. FEATURES For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cs76co</id>
    <title>CowanSim Updates S-76C++ for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cs76co"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b5d5eddab362deb9006c3_572814144_1421247343334345_8566726297088210018_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Cowan Simulations has released a significant update for its Sikorsky S-76C++ helicopter for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, now live on the Microsoft Marketplace. The update introduces enhancements to the helicopter’s autopilot, stability, and EFIS systems, with a focus on improved handling and more realistic system behaviour. SAS stabilisation has been refined, force trim and ATT modes are more accurate, and autopilot transitions should be smoother. Below 60 knots, ATT mode now holds bank for improved hover performance, while a cyclic trim failure will correctly revert to SAS mode as a failsafe. Furthermore, AFCS indicators now show actuator position, waypoint readouts are more accurate, and fail flags have been added across several displays. The engine governor has been retuned for better throttle stability, and OEI performance limits have been updated to reflect real-world behaviour. Additional tweaks include improved yaw control, better ILS tracking, enhanced VR eyepoint accuracy, and fixes to float physics and radar alt behaviour. For the full changelog, visit the CowanSim Discord. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tpmfox</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Aeronautical Releases Sierra TPM Module and Foxtrot Aviation Stick </title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tpmfox"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b89ee6d2057b38c4ce87d_last%20ned.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Honeycomb Aeronautical has just launched two new peripherals: the Sierra TPM Module and Foxtrot Aviation Stick.  Both products are now available worldwide, and slot into the brand’s existing Alpha, Bravo, and Charlie ecosystems. The Sierra TPM Module is designed for general aviation flying. It features three metal, vernier-style throttle, propeller, and mixture controls with fine adjustment, a low-profile trim wheel, a parking brake, a flap lever, and a landing gear lever, all accompanied by LED status indicators. The unit is designed to replicate real GA panels and integrates seamlessly with other Honeycomb hardware. The Foxtrot Aviation Stick is suitable for various types, including Airbus, aerobatic aircraft, and helicopters. It utilises an advanced gimbal mechanism, with 16-bit Hall Effect sensors for precise input, and offers adjustable linear resistance. without a centre detent, and includes a twist axis for rudder control. The grip is ambidextrous, featuring multiple programmable buttons, rocker switches, and a POV hat, along with an integrated switch panel, for starters, radios, and autopilot. Honeycomb says the new hardware is intended to give simmers more specialised controls, particularly for GA flying, while keeping the build quality consistent with its existing lineup. For more information, visit the respective Launch 2025 pages.  Both products are available worldwide, with the Foxtrot Aviation Stick priced at $149.99 and the Sierra TPM Module at $249.99, through Honeycomb’s official webshop. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbper</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Perth International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbper"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cb176e5167ea141d458f3_ypph1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of Perth International Airport (YPPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the 4th busiest airport in Australia, with a yearly average of 17 million passengers. The airport was built in the late 1930s to replace the city’s former main airport, Maylands Aerodrome. Maylands had become too small for the larger airplanes of that era and was impossible to expand. With the advent of World War 2, the Royal Australian Air Force redesigned the new facility for military purposes.  Civil operations started mid-war in 1944 with Qantas Empire Airways and Australian National Airways. This happened despite protests from military authorities, who were against it due to it “undermining” their defense and camouflage needs. The government ignored the protest and authorized the airlines to move from Maylands to the new airport. They wanted to operate larger aircraft, which were too large for the older airport. Perth was granted its International status in 1952, despite not yet having a proper passenger terminal. They were using an adapted hangar as the passenger terminal was still under construction. The jet age made Perth a strategic stopover for flights to Asia. This increased its passenger figures dramatically, forcing the administration to expand the infrastructure as demand grew.  A new terminal opened in the early 1960s to replace the adapted hangar terminals, finally bringing the airport into the modern era. In the 1980s, the project for a new international terminal was approved, featuring a modern design that would facilitate easy expansion whenever necessary. Construction work began in 1984, and the official opening took place in 1986. The international terminal was expanded from 2003 to 2004. The project added extra floor space, introduced new duty-free facilities, and modernized the infrastructure. In 2012, the airport was rated as the worst in Australia. This changed with the modernization and expansion that occurred in the years that followed. It eventually became the best airport in Australia six years later. As of 2025, they are expanding Terminal 2 again. The goal is to double its passenger handling capabilities by 2027. It’s a hub for Qantas, Virgin Australia, and Virgin Australia Regional, and an operating base for Alliance Airlines, Jetstar, National Jet Express, Network Aviation, and Skippers Aviation. AirAsia, Air New Zealand, All Nippon Airways, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Southern Airlines, Emirates, Singapore Airlines, Thai Airways International, and VietJet also serve it. ​ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout reflecting the latest changes, a highly detailed skybridge and T1 International Terminal, PBR materials, Dynamic Lighting, custom ground poly, custom jetways, high-resolution aerial imagery, and much more. ​ There’s no information on pricing or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddxp12ulli</id>
    <title>Digital Design Releases Saint Petersburg Pulkovo Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddxp12ulli"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cb9982c618ad4679d851e_ulli1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Digital Design has recently released their rendition of Saint Petersburg Pulkovo Airport (ULLI) for X-Plane 12, the second-busiest airport in Russia, with a yearly average of 18.1 million passengers. The airport’s construction started in 1931 near Leningrad (Saint Petersburg’s former name from the Soviet Union era), reaching completion a year later and already welcoming its first domestic flight from Moscow.  Four years later, they laid out the foundation for a new passenger terminal, and the construction started shortly after, only to suddenly stop in 1941 due to the German invasion of the Soviet Union. Between 1941 and 1944, there were no flights at all to the airport, as there was a hill nearby with German artillery that was bombarding Leningrad on a daily basis. It wasn’t until 1944 that the airport would be completely cleared of Germans, but there was a lot of maintenance to be done due to the substantial damage incurred to the infrastructure. Normal operations were only to resume in 1945, although only for cargo and mail. Scheduled passenger flights were resumed in 1948, following the completion of repair work on the terminal. A new terminal was inaugurated in 1951, followed by a new, extended runway in the mid-1950s, which allowed Pulkovo to handle larger aircraft and prepare preemptively for the advent of jet aircraft.  In May 1973, yet another passenger terminal was inaugurated, designed by Alexandr Zyk and regarded as a masterpiece of Soviet postmodernism. With the dissolution of the Soviet Union, passenger traffic figures declined substantially, dropping from 10 million per year in 1990 to roughly 5 million in 2006. The construction of a new terminal, Terminal 1, was approved in 2010, with a useful area of 150,000 square meters. It opened in 2013, featuring luxurious business lounges, restaurants, and pharmacies, and was able to withstand significant fluctuations in yearly passenger figures. It’s a hub for Aeroflot, Nordwind Airlines, Pobeda, Rossiya, Smartavia, and Ural Airlines. Air Cairo, Air Serbia, Azerbaijan Airlines, Belavia, Conviasa, China Eastern Airlines, Emirates, Mahan Air, NordStar, Nouvelair, Pegasus Airlines, S7 Airlines, SCAT Airlines, Turkish Airlines, Uzbekistan Airways, and Yamal Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR materials, custom jetways, custom aerial imagery, custom night lighting, city landmarks, and more. ​ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.69, requiring at least 2.26 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflf70nov</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes F70/F100 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflf70nov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cc01cbca31ca64f8d37dc_f701.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently published another development update on their upcoming Fokker 70 and 100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, explaining the reasons why they have been “silent” on the project for a while now. ​ The development team wanted to clarify that, although they have been silent on the development progress, this does not mean it has halted; rather, it has ramped up, and intensive work has been ongoing since they released the RJ Professional last year. ​ They also state the whole process has been a bit of a learning curve for the team, as they started with the relatively modest Piper PA-28, eventually moving on to military aircraft, and then airliners like the 146, F28, and the RJ, granting them a lot of mileage and experience, which is now being applied on the development of the F70 and F100, vastly more complex airliners with systems comparable to modern Airbus and Boeing aircraft. ​ As of October, both planes are fully functional in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, and beta testing has been underway for months. They have recently completed the integration of the new sound package, and the focus is now completely on finishing work on the automatic flight system and the FMS.  ​ The automatic flight system on the Fokker 70/100 is relatively complex, and they have spent months working on the lateral and vertical navigation profiles to ensure harmonious work with the autothrottle and FMS. Due to their extremely important nature to a realistic operation of the aircraft, they are working very efficiently on it.  ​ While they plan to long-term support the airplane, as they have with their previous releases, they want to ensure it’s a high-standard product upon release, even if it means delaying the release a bit. Each build is bringing them closer to the final product, but they are not ready to provide any time frame, although that time is inching closer and closer as they delve into the very intricate systems work.  ​ Furthermore, they have been working in parallel to bring their existing MSFS 2020 aircraft to 2024, while also taking the opportunity to further improve these products with new features. One of their year-long projects is soon to be unveiled: the 146 Professional 2.4, which includes free compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ​ Their upcoming A300B4 is also progressing very nicely, with the cockpit and cabin artwork now complete, and with the exterior artwork and systems now in later stages of development. News on that will be shared very soon. ​ They apologize for the long wait so far, but guarantee it will be well worth the wait: “We’ve got no doubt that these will be our best airliners yet, and we can’t wait to bring you the upcoming videos”. ​If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pescdg</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Shares Charles de Gaulle Airport Previews for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pescdg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cc289c47b5cf47ce7cdd4_cdg1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pilot Experience Sim has shared previews of their upcoming Charles de Gaulle Airport (LFPG) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, Europe’s third-busiest airport, with a yearly average of 70.3 million passengers. The previews showcase their work on the ground textures near the runway, as well as a sneak peek of the control tower’s exterior and interior.  While there are no previews of the terminals yet, they ensure it’s being worked on, and images will be shared once it's deemed ready. ‍ There is no information regarding pricing or a potential release date, but Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdskrg</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases José María Córdova International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdskrg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cc41dc714587051b49d5c_skr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Colombian Virtual Design has recently released their rendition of José María Córdova International Airport (SKRG) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, located in Rionegro, 20 km away from Medellín, serving the entire Medellin Metropolitan Area with many destinations, both domestic and international. It is the second busiest airport in Colombia with 9 million passengers yearly.  It’s a hub for Avianca Colombia, Ultra Air, and Viva Air Colombia, with a destination list that encompasses Colombia, Mexico, the United States, and some of Europe. LATAM Colombia also features a list of domestic destinations from Rionegro. Among the international visitors, there’s Aeromexico with a hop to Mexico City, Air Europa with a long haul to Madrid, JetBlue to Fort Lauderdale, LATAM Perú to Lima, and Spirit Airlines with the Floridian trifecta (Fort Lauderdale, Miami, and Orlando). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal model, 4K textures, custom jetways, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, realistic ground markings, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.24, requiring at least 1.48 GB of free disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrxuxp12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases Weather Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrxuxp12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690cdc7791c805834e8e819c_wea1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently released the long-awaited version 12.3.0 to the public, codenamed “Weather Update”. This significant update introduces a functional weather radar to the platform, A330 improvements, historical weather data, new camera controls, and more.  Featuring a brand-new, fully functioning weather radar, coupled with synthetic vision on their in-house Garmin G1000 simulation, virtually flying has reached never-before-seen levels of situational awareness.  The update also fully revamps the default Airbus A330-300, introducing refinements to most systems and resulting in a more accurate overall experience. It also includes exterior weathering, engine vibration animations, and interior changes (the cockpit lighting has been enhanced with backlit instruments, realistic spill lighting, and improved annunciator effects). Additionally, the flight management systems were tweaked to fully support a secondary flight plan, enhanced VNAV simulation, accurate roll rate and alpha protection under FBW, more precise climb, cruise, and descent predictions considering wind, constraints, and fuel use, and updated V-speed suggestions, fuel prediction logic, and ECAM messages. The Aircraft Operations Computer (AOC) and ATSU (Air Traffic Services Unit) on the A330 have been tweaked to realistically support ATIS, METAR, and PDC messages, with ACARS-style memo displays, and realistic data-link transmission delays. Furthermore, there were slight tweaks to the camera system, allowing users to adjust the intensity of the G-Loaded Camera, and the addition of a new hand-crafted airport (OMDB). ​ The aforementioned weather radar is now present in their A330, Boeing 738, on the X1000 (their Garmin G1000), and also on the “Benedix” RDR2000 WXR, their own interpretation of a Bendix-King weather radar, present on the Beechcraft Baron 58 and fully integratable with third-party aircraft (the source code is public on GitHub, and addon developers may modify it to suit their use-cases). In addition to the weather radar, 738 pilots may now enjoy the benefit of a terrain display, which seamlessly integrates with X-Plane’s global terrain database, thereby greatly enhancing situational awareness during mid-flight.  ​ They have also introduced an “engine health” system, where developers can enable engine “ages” at load, introducing natural variation in performance from the get-go, as in the real world. ​ The complete feature list and changelog are available on their blog. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/propklit</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Releases Little Rock Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/propklit"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690ce05098a91fa023973148_klit1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Propair Flight has recently released their rendition of Bill and Hillary Clinton National Airport (KLIT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Little Rock, Arkansas, with a yearly average of 2.3 million passengers, making it the second-largest commercial airport in the state. The airport opened in 1931 as Adams Field, after Captain George Geyer Adams, a city councilor for Little Rock and a strong advocate for the airport’s creation and opening.  With the advent of World War 2, the airport was utilized by the United States Army Air Forces Third Air Force for antisubmarine patrols and training.  The current passenger terminal was opened in 1972, with 12 gates. In early 2012, the airport’s name was changed from Adams Field to Bill and Hillary Clinton National Airport, after the Arkansas Native and former President Bill Clinton and his wife.  A year later, the airport featured as the worst among 67 domestic airports in a survey regarding passenger experience, with long lines and few food options among the main points of criticism. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, and United Express serve it. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a custom ground polygon, high-detail building models, custom animated jetways, realistic night lighting, animated people, an up-to-date taxiway network, and toggleable static aircraft. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.09, requiring at least 4.58 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msegpo</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Stornoway Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msegpo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690de8cdb7bd899f2b95cdc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDG has released its version of Stornoway Airport (EGPO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located on the Isle of Lewis in Scotland, just 2.3 miles from the town of Stornoway, the airport welcomes over 100,000 passengers yearly. Opened in 1937 for military purposes, the airfield served as a base for the Royal Air Force during the Second World War and later as a NATO forward operating base from 1972 to 1988. Today, the airfield is primarily used for passenger traffic but also accommodates helicopters, air ambulances, and more. Additionally, the airport has been utilised for cross-wind training for the Airbus A350. Currently, there are scheduled flights to Benbecula, Edinburgh, Glasgow, and Inverness, operated by Hebridean Air Services and Loganair, serving over 100,000 passengers annually. The newly released scenery features interior modelling, an up-to-date ground layout, a realistic lighting environment, detailed modelling, several landmarks, and more. Stornoway Airport by FSDG is now available for purchase at SimMarket for approximately $16.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sobrizzle</id>
    <title>SoFly Releases Bristol Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sobrizzle"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690df5795e941a7a7f9e14f5_sofly-bristol-airport-eggd-msfs2024-21.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly has recently released their rendition of Bristol Airport (EGGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the eight busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 10.5 million passengers. Built on top of a former RAF airfield, Bristol Airport was inaugurated in 1957, replacing Bristol’s former main municipal airport (Whitchurch).  In 1958, a 200,000-pound passenger terminal was built, part of the administration’s effort to make it the city’s de facto airport. Four years later, a new control tower was built. In 1969, the runway underwent its first expansion, and the terminal was extended to handle the predicted figures for the 1970s and beyond. In the early 1980s, despite being served by 17 charter airlines, the airport was operating at a loss until Les Wilson took over as managing director and completely turned the tide. He held this position until his tragic passing in a car accident in 1995.  The mid-1980s slight recovery from the crisis allowed the administration to expend an extra dime or two on the construction of a new international departure lounge. Four years later, a new concourse area was opened, and planning for a new terminal kicked into action, leading to its eventual approval in 1994. Work started in 1997, shortly after FirstBus Group bought a 51% stake in the airport, heavily investing in its new infrastructure. The terminal, which cost 27 million pounds, was ready by 2000.  Passenger numbers reached the two million mark for the first time that year. A year later, the airport was purchased by a joint venture for 198 million pounds, and 50% of it was sold again in 2006. In 2015, the terminal was expanded again with a larger departure lounge and an outdoor terrace, followed by a new terminal extension adding 9,000 square meters. The project reached completion in 2017. It’s a focus city for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Aer Lingus, Aurigny, Blue Islands, Edelweiss Air, KLM, Loganair, Pegasus Airlines, and Sun Express also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life elevation data, full GSX integration with animated doors, a dynamic airport environment, PBR texturing, dynamic seasons, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.25, requiring at least 3.11 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a32101</id>
    <title>Got Friends Updates Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen for MSFS to Version 1.0.1</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a32101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690e0a5c26f8e36cfb3dcd50_VIXXEN_1_1800x1800_eda1b648-26ff-400b-8c38-02d1624fe124_1600x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Got Friends has released version 1.0.1 of its Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, introducing several improvements. The update refines the aircraft’s flight model, featuring custom propeller and flap drag code. Instrumentation and cockpit visuals have also received attention,  including new EGT gauge interactions, more natural glass reflections, and improved lighting behaviour across both analogue and G3X-equipped cockpits. The EFB can now be used even with the battery and avionics switched off, the custom KAP-140 autopilot once again accepts hotkey inputs, and stall, oil temperature, and heading indicator behaviour have all been fine-tuned for better accuracy. Performance has also been improved through LOD optimisations, which should be most noticeable in multiplayer. Several other fixes have addressed smaller issues, including corrected gauge animations, a brighter heading bug, and restored exterior engine audio nodes. The update also adjusts weight station logic, allowing the user to load either a co-pilot or cargo, but not both, to maintain consistent visuals and flight behaviour. As usual, here's the full changelog: You can download the Got Friends Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen v1.0.1 update now through the Contrail app. TDS users must also update their TDS Expansion to version 1.0.1 for compatibility. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/56wv24</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Cheat River Island for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/56wv24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690e13e57ea98f4e6bb97129_2_5381e25d-234b-4965-8e16-0efa42545b07%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has released its first fully native Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 scenery, bringing 56WV, Cheat River Island, to the new sim. The backcountry strip in West Virginia is situated on a river island, in the Appalachian range, with approaches that wind through a narrow valley, changing weather conditions, and even the occasional turkey on the runway.  The MSFS 2024 version has been rebuilt to use the sim’s newer tech. That includes high-fidelity 3D models, enhanced textures, a custom asset library, TrailBlazer terrain shaping, dynamic fauna, and bespoke lighting and ambient sounds at the main building. The environment has also been tailored to match the region, featuring custom vegetation and autumn colours. The airfield features a 1,704 ft grass runway, with landings on Runway 30 and departures from Runway 12, a sloped terrain profile, and collision-aware objects surrounding the strip. On the ground, you can explore six miles of drivable roads, built for the //42 Juice Goose UTV, camp overnight with the //42 Campout Utility, or visit detailed micro-scenes, such as a lakeside campsite and a rustic bar, that come alive after dark. Wildlife encounters, ziplines, tractor rides, and even a hidden bear make are also included. The scenery is available now for $12.00 at the Parallel 42 store. Owners of the 2020 version can upgrade to the MSFS 2024 release for $2 by using the code 24CHEATS at checkout. Parallel 42 says the offer is valid for six months, through April 29, 2026. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
