<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-05-03T18:31:12.771143+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42421</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases ChasePlane for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42421"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a03568493d826e0a991328_cp1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. After nearly a month of being a Club 42 exclusive for testing and refinement purposes, Parallel 42’s ChasePlane is now available to the public. This brings their advanced physics-based camera system to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. For the unfamiliar, ChasePlane was originally released in 2016 for Microsoft Flight Simulator X, later being made compatible with Prepar3d and rapidly becoming the de facto camera application for ESP-based simulators at the time. It would only be natural for them to develop it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 when that came about, but technical limitations have made that impossible until very recently, which is why it’s only a thing now, almost five years after the simulator’s release.  The add-on features highly realistic physics-based camera behavior based on extensive research and real-world pilot footage. This warrants realistic motion that dynamically responds to the environment, embracing the flight model rather than altering it. Pilots can feel the vibration during the take-off roll, the rush of turbulence, and the fluid shifts during maneuvers. ‍ As previously mentioned, a subscription system will no longer be required to store and share your settings in their cloud. Parallel 42 will now offer the service as a courtesy and take the costs upon themselves. ‍ Furthermore, ChasePlane 2020 owners will be entitled to a free upgrade once the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version is available.  ‍ The add-on is available in their store for $30.00. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdb772</id>
    <title>PMDG 777-200ER Release Window Updated</title>
    <updated>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdb772"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680a391a1d741e51793f3f54_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently updated the planned release window for the upcoming 777-200ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Additionally, the team has provided a more specific release window for the compatibility of the 777F and 777-300ER with MSFS 2024. A variety of other information has also been shared in the update. The release window for the PMDG 777-200ER has been updated. The original timeframe was between April 16th and April 29th, but it is now set for April 29th to May 1st, moving the release by just a few days. The team has confirmed that they will provide advance notice the day before the release.  ‍ This add-on will include various engine types, such as the GE90-92 and the Rolls Royce Trent 892, along with a new generation of sound packages. At launch, only one package will be available, which will include versions of the add-on for both simulators. Compatibility for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is scheduled for the second half of May for the 777F freighter variant, followed by the 777-300ER variant within 10-14 days after the freighter release. Finally, the team has shared updates on the 2024 compatibility for its DC-6. The overhaul for compatibility is nearing completion, and everything is coming together nicely. However, there are still some minor cosmetic improvements that need to be made. We will let you know if we receive any updates. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/772428</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes 777-200ERs Preview Trailer for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/772428"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fc3c0c19e59717089bbb2_772-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a showcase trailer for their upcoming Boeing 777-200ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which is set to be released sometime this week. After a few months of SDK struggles with the new platform, PMDG is finally close to releasing their first fully compatible release while retaining compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020.  The add-on will include three engine models with their respective characteristics, sounds, and performance profiles, along with a number of new features for the product line (some of which are showcased in the trailer). It will also be available in the marketplace, albeit not within the same timeframe due to Microsoft’s verification process, which takes a few days/weeks.  Images are courtesy of SCOTSGOD. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2nor</id>
    <title>Uk2000 Scenery Releases Norwich Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2nor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fcd5910d6e1413e7c0614_norwich.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Uk2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Norwich Airport (EGSH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Norwich in the United Kingdom and has a yearly average of 319,040 passengers. It was first created as an RAF bomber station in 1939 and later made available to the United States Air Force, becoming Station 123. In 1967, the Royal Air Force left Norwich Airport, and some of the airfield and its buildings were sold to city and county councils, eventually developing it into Norwich International Airport. The main terminal opened in 1988, but it had been operating charter flights since 1971. 80% of the ownership rights were sold from the city and county councils to Omniport, which transformed Norwich into a hub for the now-bankrupt Flybe, consequently increasing its number of flights and destinations. It’s a focus city for TUI Airways and is served by Blue Islands, KLM, Loganair, and Ryanair. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, full-detail buildings, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR textures, custom vegetation, static GA aircraft, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.89, requiring at least 77.52 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfk024</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases John F. Kennedy International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfk024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fd1a760a2fe12ceb1ffa7_jfk24-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their revamped rendition of John F. Kennedy International Airport (KJFK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the busiest airport in New York City with a yearly average of 60 million passengers. Built on top of an old golf course 74 years ago, the then-called Idlewild Airport had a single 7,365 square meter terminal and six runways. The current name only came to be in late 1963, after John F. Kennedy’s assassination. It also marked the important leap to the busiest airport in the region, beating LaGuardia and reaching a respectable second place overall in the United States. The busiest international gateway to the United States is served and visited by over 90 airlines, covering all the inhabited continents around the globe. JetBlue tops the market share chart, with 28.8% or 15,624,961 passengers, followed by Delta Air Lines and American Airlines, with 28.4% (15,390,437) and 14.5% (7,870,971), respectively. From foreign operators, Air France leads the way with 1.9% of the total market share or 1,025,339 passengers. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an all-new high-quality set of ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout (as of March 2025), new custom jetway models, new LOD work for extra performance, a true-to-life landside recreation, and highly detailed airport buildings and surroundings. It’s available on their store for roughly $29.28, requiring at least 4.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Owners of the MSFS 2020 version can upgrade their licenses for only $6.70 by using the KJFK-UG coupon.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lgw428</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares Previews of Upcoming London Gatwick Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lgw428"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fd52e5c9765c26f5e5b37_gatters1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently previewed their upcoming London Gatwick Airport (EGKK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which is said to be reaching the final stages of its development cycle and nearing a potential release. ‍ iniBuilds has been working along with Gatwick staff team members to ensure the utmost accuracy on layout and details, showcased in the screenshots below: It's soon to enter beta testing, where their working group and internal staff "will ensure it's released in a good state." ‍ Content creators will be granted a copy when the release day draws near for showcasing purposes. ‍ The feature list will include an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, custom ground service equipment, custom jetways, an official GSX profile, and more. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniham</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Doha Hamad International for MSFS 24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniham"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fd99150e442b99b8da636_hamad1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently announced the development of Doha Hamad International Airport (OTHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the busiest airport in Qatar with a yearly average of 36 million passengers. Opened in 2014, it replaces Doha International Airport as Qatar's main airport. Built on 22 square kilometers of land, it can handle 320,000 aircraft movements and 2 million tonnes of cargo per year. DOH is the first Middle Eastern airport to get Skytrax's World Best Airport award (2021 and 2022), ending a nearly decade-long streak of Singapore's Changi. It's the hub for Qatar Airways, with a route network that covers most of the globe, from their next-door neighbors of Abu Dhabi to San Francisco. Such high coverage makes it so other carriers don't have much of a financially logical reason to fly to Doha, but there are still a couple of them, such as Air Canada, Air India, British Airways, Conviasa, Finnair, and Malaysia Airlines. Despite still being in very early development stages, iniBuilds has shared a few previews of the work they already got done while also justifying why they didn't go for it sooner. "We've been wanting to do this one for a while, however there's been lots of construction which has made it difficult to ensure we get it right. With this construction now getting to the point where we can accurately see what is being worked on, it has allowed us to get the references we need!". ‍ There is no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkssea</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Seattle-Tacoma Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkssea"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/681246267ca760575c1deb4e_seattle1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios recently released their rendition of Seattle-Tacoma Airport (KSEA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. It is the busiest airport in the Pacific Northwest, with a yearly average of 50 million passengers. It was created in the 1940s to replace Boeing Field – which was under military use in that period –with a site near Bow Lake being ultimately chosen to house the ambitious new project. However, it was not until 1947 that the first scheduled flight would take off from Seattle. A dedicated passenger terminal only came to fruition in 1949. Expansion work began in 1961 to accommodate airliner jets, and new concourses and satellite terminals were added within another decade, followed by an expansion of the main runway. The 2010s brought further expansion, following Delta Air Lines’ choice to make it their hub. A new international arrivals facility was launched three years ago, significantly increasing its passenger handling capabilities. It’s a hub for Alaska and Delta, with a huge domestic network covering both the west and east of the United States, along with several international routes with either Delta or the several other airlines that visit Seattle every day, such as Air Canada, American Airlines, British Airways, Japan Airlines, Turkish Airlines, and Virgin Atlantic. It totals up to 91 domestic and 28 international destinations! The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, terminal interiors, high-detail models, custom jetways, custom vehicle models, an up-to-date ground layout, true-to-life runway elevation data, and more. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $20.41, requiring at least 2.72 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hfli</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Bishop International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hfli"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68124f9ac9422e5cbfe12a94_flint1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Bishop International Airport (KFNT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Flint, Michigan, and has a yearly average of 396,000 passengers. Its history started in 1928 when the Arthur Giles Bishop family handed over 220 acres of land to Flint to construct an airport. The city diligently ran the airport until 1987, when it formed an administration authority with a neighboring county. It’s currently the third busiest airport in Michigan, only behind Detroit and Grand Rapids. It reached the million-passenger mark for the first time in the early 2000s. The current passenger terminal was built in 1993, finally allowing Flint to handle jetliners, which was not the case beforehand due to a lack of infrastructure (most of the traffic was propeller aircraft).  A renovation project started in 2007 and was completed in 2012. In the following years, further funds were granted to ensure further taxiway improvements. It’s an operating base for Allegiant Air and is served by American Eagle and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom terminal interiors, custom taxiway labels, true-to-life elevation data, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.59, requiring at least 1.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777501</id>
    <title>PMDG Confirms Release Date for Upcoming 777-200ER </title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777501"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fc3fa6ea0948a4723f968_772-2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently made an announcement in their forum confirming a release date for their long-awaited Boeing 777-200ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The release is set to happen between 1600Z and 2359Z on May 1st, creating a sizeable window that would allow PMDG to absorb any last-minute issues that may occur. ‍ Potential customers are instructed to pre-download Operations Center 3, which will handle PMDG’s product distributions from now on, replacing their old InstallShield method. Now, it will automatically show up for installation in the new operations center as soon as the transaction is confirmed, with the authentication stuff being automatically handled in the background. PMDG also mentions that the new product will feature new sound recordings for the 777, adding many new layers of quality and allegedly significantly increasing the immersion and overall experience. Engine sounds, on the other hand, are still being worked on, which means they will be released with the original sound set at first. ‍ Apart from the engines, all the other sounds are brand new and of much higher quality.  ‍ They have also improved the SimBrief integration, allowing users to import flight data, winds, forecasts, etc. Furthermore, they have built custom airframe profiles for inclusion on the platform, making the overall flight planning experience much smoother and more accurate. ‍ There is yet to be any information on the pricing, but we will keep you informed on the matter! Images are courtesy of SCOTSGOD. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/220430</id>
    <title>Synaptic Simulations Publishes A220 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/220430"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68128a7ea69cafeca9f40cdc_a2201.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Synaptic Simulations recently published a lengthy development update on their upcoming A220 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which is said to be an exceptionally accurate rendition of the popular narrow-body airplane. They have built it from the ground up by leveraging high-fidelity 3D scans, extensive reference data, and the latest development techniques, resulting in a true-to-life model of the airplane that “brings out every characteristic of the A220 while remaining performant”. They emphasize that while a great model goes a long way, exceptional texturing, and asset integration are just as critical. iniBuilds stepped in to help them with detailed texturing, flight modeling, sound design, and the creation of the electronic flight bag. Synaptic has dedicated significant development effort to capturing every detail, making sure everything is as close to the real thing as possible: rivets are marked with their correct part number and position, decals show appropriate wear across surfaces, wiring follows the real-world contours of the aircraft, and more. It also includes a detailed passenger cabin and a wide range of interactive components (like an openable engine cowling, APU maintenance doors, avionics bays, and maintenance panels throughout the airframe). On the systems aspect, they have managed to mimic the physical structure of the system in code with as much detail as is practical, modeling almost every computer, component, ARINC 429 bus, and any discrete or analog signal documented in operational and technical training manuals, allowing them to encapsulate the aircraft’s inherent complexities and nuances. The end result of this process is what they refer to as emergent behavior, which grants them the ability to realistically model many non-normal states without explicitly accounting for them. A total of 646 components have been modeled so far, covering everything from electrical and data buses to major systems like avionics computers, generators, and more. It has been carefully optimized, with each simulation tick currently processing in under 1 ms. To support development and future maintenance, they have developed custom in-sim instrumentation and visualization tools, which provide them with a debugging environment to quickly resolve any issues that might arise post-release. The electrical system simulated real-world voltage and current flow across every connection, with 368 components and 995 connections currently represented. It fully represents the aircraft’s primary and secondary power distribution architectures and their respective communication across the appropriate buses. Furthermore, every circuit breaker and solid-state power controller (SSPC) has been included, with 256 CBs and 636 SSPCs in total, with their respective custom logic applied where applicable. The developers have worked hard to faithfully yet performantly simulate the many data transfer protocols inside the aircraft.  Work has also extended to the aircraft’s fuel and hydraulic systems, which have been brought up to the same standard as everything else. The APU has also undergone reworking to feature a separate controller and a dedicated engine model designed to match real life, with failures included. ‍ They are in the process of implementing a custom flight control system from scratch, focusing on applying the principles of emergent behavior in addition to well-established control theory paradigms.  ‍ Thanks to its ease of use and incredible depth, they have been using Navigraph data for navigation data. This allows them to implement certain features without having to worry about having the data at hand.  Efforts have also been made to develop an interface that allows users to switch between Navigraph and the simulator’s default database on the ground as if they were airline technicians. ‍ The Multifunction Keyboard Panel (MKP) has also been recreated, with custom fonts, sizing, and placement matching the real-world counterpart as closely as possible. ‍ Their EICAS system processes messages by the aircraft’s data concentration system as per real life and triggers them by discrete or ARINC 429 buses routed from the relevant systems in accordance with their principles of emergent behavior. Their checklists can be easily modified if desired, and they hope this will stimulate the community to create and share their own airline-specific procedures. ‍ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but it is now known that it will be available on the iniBuilds Store and MSFS Marketplace from day one, with a two-phase launch: A220-300 base package first, followed by the A220-100 as a free update alongside additional quality-of-life improvements. ‍ More information will be shared in their next development stream in May, where they plan to unveil a deeper look across all aspects of their upcoming airplane. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mel024</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Melbourne International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mel024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6813d88f2c44ba334d4d232f_ymml1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their rendition of Melbourne International Airport (YMML) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves Melbourne, Australia, and has a yearly average of 35.1 million passengers. It was built in 1970 to replace Essendon Airport, Melbourne’s former main airport. Its lack of expandability and Melbourne’s ever-increasing demand for air travel created the necessity for a completely new airport elsewhere, and the search started more than a decade prior, in 1958. In that same year, the Commonwealth Government acquired 5,300 hectares of grassland in Tullamarine (which is still how some locals refer to the airport), and the construction effort was to start within a year. It was opened for international operations in mid-1970, relegating Essendon to domestic operations, albeit temporarily as that was also moved to Tullamarine in 1971. Its initial structure consisted of three connected terminals: International in the center, Ansett in the south, and Trans Australia Airlines in the north. It was designed to handle eight Boeing 707s per hour. Minor expansion works were done in 1973 to make the airport compatible with Boeing 747s.  ‍ The new airport had already experienced congestion within a decade, reaching a peak of 900 passengers per hour. ‍ In the late 1980s, the Government formed the Federal Airports Corporation (FAC), which took over Melbourne and 21 other airports in Australia.  The new administrators took the expansion work upon themselves, carrying out a domestic terminal upgrade, reaching completion within two years, and the creation of a second pier for smaller regional airlines. A year later, work started on expanding the international terminal. In 1995, a new three-level satellite concourse was opened, adding 10 jetways that doubled the airport’s passenger handling capabilities at the time. A year before that, the Federal Airports Corporation decided to privatize all of their airports in a multi-phase project. Melbourne was one of the first to be privatized, and Australia Pacific Airports Corporation acquired it for 49 million dollars on a 50-year long-term lease. ‍ They handled multiple car parking expansions in the late 90s and the expansion of Qantas’ domestic terminal with a second pier and 9 new jetways. ‍ A fourth passenger terminal was opened in 2000, the Domestic Express Terminal. ‍ Five years later, the airport was upgraded to become compatible with the Airbus A380. This included widening the main north runway, building dual jetways, extending the international building by 20 meters to include new penthouse airline lounges, and building an additional baggage carousel in the arrivals hall. In 2006, Terminal 2 was expanded with an additional 2,000 square meters and an additional level of airline lounges above the terminal. Two years later, a new Terminal 2 expansion commenced, adding another 25,000 square meters, five jetways on a new passenger concourse, and a new outbound passenger security and customs processing zone. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, PBR texturing, interior terminal modeling of the departure lounges, VDGS and custom traffic animations, meticulously hand-edited aerial imagery, custom taxiway signs, custom points of interest, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $22.28, requiring at least 6.57 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sog024</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Sogndal Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sog024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6813df8ff2bc1690d6c068b8_sogndal1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Sogndal Airport (ENSG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving the homonymous municipality with a yearly average of 70,000 passengers. The airport was opened in mid-1971, with a single, 800-meter-long runway and a small 70mx45m apron, which is only suitable for small regional airliners like the Twin Otter (one of the first to serve Sogndal with flights to Bergen and Alesund). In the early 1980s, the construction of a fire station allowed the airport to accommodate more types of regional airliners, and Wideroe introduced their Dash 7s on the route to Oslo Fornebu. Two years later, a significantly larger terminal was built, and the tower underwent renovation work. Ownership was transferred from the Municipality to Avinor on January 1st, 1997. Between 2004 and 2007, Sogndal underwent several upgrades to its infrastructure, with expanded safety areas, lights, parking, a new arrival terminal, a navigation system, and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, full PBR 4K texturing, custom orthoimagery, realistic representation of the PLASI (Pulse Light Approach System), and more.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.03, requiring at least 1.57 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777015</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 777-200ER for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777015"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/680fc3c0c19e59717089bbb2_772-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently released their long-awaited rendition of the Boeing 777-200ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, marking the start of a new era for their product line (the first to land in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024). After a few months of struggles with the SDK, PMDG has finally managed to get their new airplane in working order within the new simulator. The compatibility news went from sour at first to promising after SU 1’s first release earlier this year. The 777-200ER is an extended range – as per the nomenclature – variant of the 777-200, flying further and carrying more passengers than the original. It flew for the first time in October 1996, obtaining its certification only three months later and entering service in February of that same year with British Airways. It retains the same airframe as the original model, albeit with larger engines (three variants) and a higher maximum take-off weight (a direct consequence of the larger, more powerful engines). It has greatly helped to establish the 777 family as a leading wide-body airliner, which reached ultimate consolidation in 2004 with the advent of the 777-300ER, their most popular 777 variant to date. The add-on features an advanced simulation of all avionics and system management operations of the 777 flight deck, an accurately simulated display drawing process, a full electronic checklist, the PMDG Universal Flight Tablet, a full simulation of the 777’s autoflight director and autopilot systems, and more. The complete feature list follows below: PMDG 777-200ER features Avionics &amp; Flight Deck: Air Conditioning System: Auto-flight System: Brakes and Tires: Cabin: Datalink (Currently limited to Hopie Network for ATC services, but more coming!): Doors: Electrical System: Engines: Failures: Flight Controls and Flight Surfaces: Fly By Wire System: Fuel System: Ground Service Vehicles: Hydraulic System: Landing Gear: Lighting Systems: Navigation Data: Physics-based Flexing: Pneumatic System: Simulator Features:   Distribution: Users will receive a download link to the PMDG Operations Center software that is used to manage customer access to the software, along with access rights and installation.   Features and capabilities unique to the MSFS 2024 platform may not be available on the MSFS 2020 platform. ‍ It’s available on PMDG’s website for $77.72 Images are courtesy of SCOTSGOD. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dalxp1</id>
    <title>iBlueYonder Announces Dallas Love Field for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dalxp1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68150e3626daf7aa76c4b9e4_yonder1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iBlueYonder recently announced the development of a Dallas Love Field (KDAL) rendition for X-Plane 12 in partnership with StableSystem and joshomoore, which handled the porting process (the scenery was originally made for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020). Dallas Love Field is the 31st busiest airport in the United States, with a yearly average of 6 million passengers, opened 105 years ago as a training camp for WW1 pilots and then converted into a storage facility for surplus aircraft right after the war, where it barely saw any action for nearly ten years. It was then purchased by the city of Dallas in 1928 and opened for civilian use, with the first set of paved runways to come four years later.  The first proper terminal was built in 1940, serving 21 weekday airline departures from American, Braniff, and Delta.  World War 2 forced the airport to return to its training school roots, only ceasing after it was all over when it once again returned to being a civil airport.  With the increased passenger numbers during the late 1950s came the need for a new terminal (T3) designed by Donald S. Nelson. It would have three concourses, 26 gates, and the world’s first moving walkways.  Nowadays, the airport has a single terminal with 20 gates, with Alaska and Delta Air Lines having one each, and the remaining 18 are under Southwest’s helm. Not coincidentally, Southwest Airlines has 95.3% of the passenger market share, followed by Delta with 2.2% and Alaska with 1.7%. Houston (387,000), Denver (367,000), and Atlanta (358,000) compose the top list of busiest destinations from Love Field. While an official feature list hasn’t been revealed yet, its ported nature probably means it won’t differ much from the original, which features custom ground textures, a high-detail terminal model with its interior, hand-crafted and hand-placed signage, custom night lighting, and more. There’s yet to be any information on pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdblu</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Releases Blue Canyon Nyack and Scott Valley for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdblu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/681523df7ba5d6403cd5f684_codr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr Designs recently released their renditions of Blue Canyon Nyack (KBLU) and Scott Valley (A30) for X-Plane 12. Both are in California, 190 miles apart and have completely different infrastructures.  Scott Valley (A30) is located in northern California. It is covered in farmland, surrounded by mountains, and significantly elevated in some areas. In direct contrast with Blue Canyon, it features basic facilities like 100LL fuel, individual hangar units, etc. Blue Canyon (KBLU) is located 30 miles west of Lake Tahoe and 190 miles south of Scott Valley in the Sierra Nevada, with a thrilling approach on top of a canyon ridge over Interstate 80. Facility-wise, it’s as barebones as it gets, but hugely scenic to make up for that. Both sceneries feature accurate renditions with near-photoreal textures, ultra-detailed ground textures, immersive seasonal and weather effects, custom objects, pilot-controlled lighting, and more. It’s available on their website for $7.99 (KBLU) and $9.99 (A30). Buying both at once warrants a 25% discount on both, or 25% in one if you already bought the other. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
