<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-10-28T18:20:15.410636+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inkpsp</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Palm Springs International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inkpsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6532a5a832ff1653fb920ed6_inipsp1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="566644"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Palm Springs International Airport (KPSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Palm Springs area in California with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. Built by the US Army as an emergency landing field in 1939, it was later improved to serve as a staging field during World War 2. It was then sold to private buyers in 1946 and purchased by the City of Palm Springs in 1961 to become Palm Springs Municipal Airport. Airline service started with Western Airlines in the mid to late 40s, followed by Bonanza Air Lines a decade later. It was transformed into a dual runway airport in the 1990s and expanded with a new concourse in 1999, increasing its passenger handling capacity. The post-COVID period brought record growth, thanks to the arrival of Southwest Airlines with year-round flights to Oakland, Phoenix, Denver, and Vegas (the latter started a year later). Air Canada, Air Canada Rouge, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Flair Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet currently serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, highly detailed models, custom night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, LOD optimization, and more. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.19, requiring at least 3.57 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737uft</id>
    <title>PMDG Reveals Planned Release Date for Upcoming Universal Flight Tablet</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737uft" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65343e6b65baf3b73849208c_uft.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2640684"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo from PMDG has made a new announcement concerning their long-awaited Universal Flight Tablet for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with many preview images, features, and a release date.   ‍ They begin with an explanation of why it took relatively long to develop, with a bit of backstory on their pre-existing regulatory Electronic Flight Bag that was available for their P3D line of products between 2016 and 2022 and the decisions that led to developing a completely new tool from scratch, with a different approach and scope.  ‍ PMDG highlights that the Universal Flight Tablet is not an EFB, as EFBs are tightly tailored toward flight planning and management tasks with a fairly limited scope. They wanted to offer more than just that this time, which other developers have also been offering and has become the market standard as of late. Thus, the different naming.  ‍ Asobo’s SU13 removed one of their biggest limitations regarding communication with an external server, making it easier for PMDG to send data back and forth from the user’s aircraft to their server infrastructure and eliminating the need for the complex workaround method they had previously been utilizing.  ‍ One of the things that was not previously mentioned is that their tablet will be compatible with sim-enhancement tools from either themselves or partners, meaning it will provide an ecosystem for applications that will run inside that environment. They refer to it as the “garden.”   Upon release, which is scheduled for October 30, the application suite will be as follows:  Flight Plans/SimBrief Integration - Importing flight plans from SimBrief. - Download weather for the flight plan route. - Flight plan/weather sharing between tablet/aircraft. - Display of Operational Flight Plan. - Display of real time METAR information (native or simplified format)  Charting: - Navigraph Charts (Requires Navigraph Subscription) - Georeferenced aircraft on displayed charts where appropriate. - Flight centric chart selection/pinning of desired charts.  Performance Computation: - T/O, Diversion, Landing computations. - Data Import from flight plans or from the aircraft itself. - Reduced runway length computations. - Graphic display of displaced threshold data.  Plans for upcoming applications were already laid out, including ways to manage aircraft options, functions, and failures.   While more features are yet to be announced, they claim to have coordinated with other developers to include access to their applications from the tablet, bringing an entirely seamless integration.  The core functionality includes data entry via keyboard or on-screen, metric/imperial units, day/night setting, and independent tablets (pilot/co-pilot).   Their upcoming 777 will feature the tablet from the beginning, while the 737 Lineup will get the update on October 30, as previously mentioned.  The 737 lineup is available on PMDG.com or via Marketplace, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dddwro</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Copernicus Airport Wrocław for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dddwro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653447d22a5e93a42af6888e_wroclaw.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1604694"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Copernicus Airport Wrocław (EPWR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an international civil-military airport serving the city of Wrocław, in Poland, with a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers.  ‍ It was built by the Germans for military purposes in 1938 when the city was still part of Germany. It used to host a military aviation school, the Lufkstriegskule 5.   ‍ After a brief post-war Soviet occupation, it saw civil use as early as 1945, with four domestic service routes.  ‍ International service started in 1993 with a flight to Frankfurt, followed by many airport upgrades, including a new international departures terminal in 1997 and a domestic terminal in 1998. ‍ Further expansion happened in 2005, along with a name change: from Wrocław Airport to Copernicus Airport Wrocław, after the famous astronomer. The passenger terminal had been expanded to accommodate up to 750,000 passengers a year, and they soon had to increase the terminal’s size again because the airport’s yearly average had neared a million passengers by 2007.  ‍ In the mid-2000s, the administration contracted the architectural firm JSK to design a major expansion for the entire airport, including a larger terminal and apron, runway improvements, and more. The first stage opened six years later, bringing the passenger handling capabilities up to 3.5 million passengers a year. ‍ The airport is one of the Polish hubs for Ryanair (Buzz), flying passengers all over Europe. Enter Air, European Air Charter, Eurowings, Finnair, KLM, LOT, Lufthansa, Swiss, and WizzAir also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a performance-friendly design, custom-animated people and vehicles, modeled interiors, custom-animated jetways, high-quality static aircraft, city landmarks, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.89, requiring at least 1.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fleha2</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Amsterdam Airport Schiphol for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fleha2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65344c7d27c83b0010461bdf_update.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="270835"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has recently issued a new update to their rendition of Amsterdam Airport Schiphol (EHAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a list of new bug fixes and improvements.  ‍ Version 1.2, the second update so far, brings updated AI parking codes, taxiway layout updates, multiple fixes, lighting improvements, and more. The changelog follows below:  V1.2 (19 Oct 2023) -updated AI parking codes -taxiway layout update based on latest changes -fixed jagged shorelines -minor 3D and texture fixes -optmised taxiing over elevated taxiways -added more grasspads -added custom animated apron traffic -optimised highway lighting ‍  ‍ ‍ The scenery is available on their website for $21.99, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vuevia</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Velana International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vuevia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6536ed85c758d5b6c39bfc08_velana.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1277622"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Velana International Airport (VRMM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main international airport in the Maldives, serving its Capital city, Malé.  What once started as a small strip of land in the early 1960s became a proper airport only four years later, when the government and its people gathered together to build an asphalt runway: four city districts competed for who could be the fastest. Two years later, the runway was opened and ready for commercial action.  ‍ The upgrade to International status happened a decade after the initial tourism boom, with its official inauguration as Malé International Airport in 1981.   ‍ A few years ago, the administration expanded the airport with a new runway (that was serving as a taxiway until 2022 because there was an old seaplane terminal near it that was too close). They have also been building a new passenger terminal, a long-term project scheduled to reach completion by 2025. It features an area of around 78,000 square meters, serving up to 7.3 million passengers a year instead of its current capacity of only 1 million. ‍  It’s a hub for Maldivian and Trans Maldivian Airways. Aeroflot, AirAsia, Air France, Air India, Austrian Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, British Airways, China Eastern Airlines, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Gulf Air, ITA Airways, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Turkish Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and WizzAir visit it. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with its new passenger terminal (and interior), updated runway, custom taxiways, custom night lighting, LOD optimization, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.88, requiring at least 415.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdch7p</id>
    <title>PILOT'S GesmbH announces the upcoming release of the Dash 7</title>
    <updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdch7p" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6537def75eaeb757d29960be_NNOSE.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="374149"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Today PILOT'S GesmbH announced the imminent release of their long-awaited Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Known for their scenery and utility addons for FSX and P3D, they'll add the Dash 7 to their lineup soon. The Dash 7 is a rugged four-engine turboprop developed and manufactured by de Havilland Canada. It is known for its STOL performance, which gives it more destination options in rugged terrain and unpaved landing surfaces. Making its first flight in March of 1975, approximately 113 were built. The DHC-7 is powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney PT6A-50 engines producing around 1,100 shaft horsepower, allowing it to cruise upward to 230 knots. Its STOL capabilities allow it to operate out of runways as little as 2,000 feet long. This capacity makes it useful for passenger service and cargo. ‍ ‍ According to a recent Facebook post by PILOT'S GesmbH, you will soon be able to experience the STOL performance of the DHC-7 this weekend. The addon will include real-world liveries and equipment, such as the Working Title GNS 530 and a specific model supporting the GTNXi. Additionally, custom sounds are engineered for the Dash 7 with assistance and input from Air Tindi. There are many operational quirks modeled after the real Dash 7"One such unique feature is the nose wheel gear doors slowly opening after engines shut down with the subsequent hydraulic pressure drop". ‍ The Dash 7 will be available on their web store at www.pilots.shop this weekend. Make sure to create an account for purchase.   As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/8ak5es</id>
    <title>Emerald Scenery Design Releases, Fort Crosby </title>
    <updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/8ak5es" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6538103279bc2a87edba98db_9c38e6a5848b098fa0b42db4c410f85385de8fb1.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="178450"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Emerald Scenery Design, a developer creating sceneries for Prepar3D and Microsoft Flight Simulator, has recently released its newest addition - 8AK5 Fort Crosby. This latest release fits in well with their backcountry and tropical air strip themes. Located near Talkeetna, Alaska, this privately owned airstrip features a 1,500-foot gravel strip that turns into a dirt strip during summer; wintertime has snow berm build up alongside it. The development team has done an excellent job capturing the snow build-up, as shown in the screenshot below.  ‍ ‍ The scenery encompasses an area of 2.5 NM²/4.7 KM² and includes numerous hand-built home cabins and other lively objects that bring the scenery to life. The textures are high quality, featuring PBR and 4K resolution textures. Terraforming, dirt textures, ground coverage, and shrubbery are custom-made, and the 3D trees make the environment feel more vibrant. The development team paid close attention to environmental details to create an immersive Alaskan experience. ‍ ‍ The scenery has been improved with new features such as dynamic objects. These objects include automatic hangar doors, fauna, growing vegetation, and seasonal mushrooms. Butterflies can also be seen in the spring. Furthermore, there are weather effects such as rain puddles, roof snow, and icicles that appear at certain temperatures. With such a vast coverage area, you are bound to discover something new during each flight. ‍ ‍ ‍ Listed below is the full feature list from Emerald Scenery Design Features ‍ Dynamic Features ‍ ‍ Emerald Scenery Design’s Fort Crosby v1 can be purchased on their website and the (Marketplace coming soon) for only $9.99USD. File sizes are about 1.04GB unzipped on your machine. The release will also be available for Xbox users! Check out their official release trailer below! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more exciting releases and flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orvo17</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta 1.7</title>
    <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orvo17" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653987eaa6d74bf4afcc7e80_vol.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2107444"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated their flight tracking platform to version 1.7, adding a new user interface and many new features. Volanta’s new update brings  a new and improved navigation bar, a replay on altitude chart, new aircraft icons, flight and aircraft filtering, a dynamic airport display that will show airports based on their activity, an “Events” page with Volanta’s official events, and much more.  ‍  Many issues from the previous version were also addressed:  ‍  Volanta is available for free on their website.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pksgra</id>
    <title>PKSIM Releases Granada Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pksgra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6539a0ef89f80acd3bf67d6c_gra1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1685360"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PKSIM has recently released their rendition of Federico García Lorca Granada Airport (LEGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Granada in Spain with a yearly average of 1.1 million passengers. ‍ Construction work started in 1970, and the airport opened two years later as Aeropuerto de Granada. It replaced Armilla Airfield, which was Grenada's first airport.  ‍ The airport underwent multiple improvements in the 90s for the 1995 World Alpine Ski Championships, with an expansion of the apron, runway extension, and many improvements to the main terminal.  ‍ International service started in 2000, with a flight to Marrakech. Beforehand, the airport used to average 500,000 passengers a year, and with the advent of international operations, that rate was doubled within five years.  ‍  The promising growth was rapidly halted after the 2008 crisis, leading to a massive drop in passenger count and with the departure of Ryanair, one of their biggest carriers.  ‍  Numbers only were to recover in 2014, when British Airways embraced Granada on a seasonal basis, helping Granada to reach their highest average since 2008. Numbers kept steadily growing in the following years, despite nowhere close to the 2006 figures.  ‍ Things changed substantially with the arrival of Vueling in 2017, helping the airport return to its 1 million mark.  ‍ Air Europe, Binter Canarias, Iberia, Volotea, and Vueling currently serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, a new terminal interior, a GSX profile with walk-in gates, and landside buildings.  ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $19.67, requiring at least 218.19 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boudev</id>
    <title>Boundless Publishes Development Update </title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boudev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653a15204dab3b655828e252_vatry.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1091843"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently published a new development report on their progress on Paris Vatry and Inverness for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12. ‍ They begin with information on Paris Vatry (LFOK), which is claimed to be 95% finished, only depending on fixing a couple of issues that arose before release. While a time frame was not provided, it’s said that everything is in place to get them moving pretty quickly once the problem is solved.   ‍ New Inverness (EGPE) previews were also shown. It was announced recently, promising improved terminal textures, improved night lighting, new ground textures, improved FPS, new lorry and vehicle models, animated ground traffic, and optional static aircraft. ‍  They conclude by letting everyone know that their website has recently been updated with a new design (focusing on usability), and they have been working in the background on five unannounced projects, which should be revealed soon. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbpng</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbpng" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653a19978d68e76ff3fe4350_bush1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="553155"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released the PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a package with three challenging airstrips in Papua New Guinea, the toughest country in the world to be a bush pilot.  Bush airstrips in Papua New Guinea are generally the only gateway to certain remote villages, meaning it’s vital to their existence and the only way to bring supplies in. The weather is often harsh, the runways are often short and hand-carved, and the challenge is unparalleled.  Developed by Ken Hall, an independent developer, the scenery package brings three airstrips (AYYE, AYYW, and AYDN), featuring PBR texturing,  custom 3D vegetation (with modeled bananas), 100 custom-built and hand-placed models, handcrafted mesh for each airstrip, and custom hand-placed objects and people.     It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $11.94, requiring at least 2.40 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2gpk</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Glasgow Prestwick Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2gpk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653a1d651a1a861855e274fc_glashow.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1050676"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Glasgow Prestwick Airport (EGPK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Glasgow (Scotland) with a yearly average of 445,211 passengers.  It was officially opened in 1935, despite operating as an airfield for longer (since the early 1910s). Passenger facilities were added in 1938 and remained untouched until the government made them compatible with jet aircraft. ‍ The RAF used Prestwick to control trans-Atlantic flights during World War 2 as a gateway for US Army personnel and a training base for RAF pilots. ‍ Its commercial duties started right after the war, with a transatlantic flight between Prestwick and New York. ‍ The main runway was expanded in 1960 from the original 2,100 meters to 3,000 meters, which is still its current length.  ‍ During the early 1990s, Prestwick was in shambles, desperately needing “rescue,” which came in the form of a takeover from a Canadian entrepreneur (Matthew Hudson), who constructed a railway station beside it, making it the first Scottish airport with its own railway station. To this day, Matthew’s rescue effort is unanimously recognized as heroic. ‍ Ryanair embraced Prestwick in 1994, with a route from Dublin and a second route a year later to London Stansted. A third one followed suit in 1998, taking passengers to Paris-Beauvais. ‍ 1998 also marks the ownership transfer from Matthew Hudson to the Stagecoach Group, a transport group based in Perth, primarily focused on buses, trams, and train services. They sold it three years later for 33 million pounds. ‍ Infratil, a Kiwi company, was the new owner from 2001 onwards, responsible for revamping the main terminal in 2005 and redecorating most of it with very controversial touches. ‍ After over a decade of ownership, Infratil called it a day and passed it on to a new owner, which was no less than the Scottish government. They paid an incredible sum of 1 pound for it. ‍ It’s currently served by Ryanair, with flights to Alicante, Faro, Lanzarote, Málaga, and Tenerife-South. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR materials, optional static aircraft, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.85, requiring at least 60.82 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbmmsp</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Releases Minneapolis-Saint Paul International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbmmsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653aeb5a0623f1f8447b61e5_msp.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="212362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam has recently released their rendition of Minneapolis-Saint Paul International Airport (KMSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the metropolitan area of Minneapolis and Saint Paul with a yearly average of 31 million passengers.  It was built in 1919 on top of a former racetrack (Twin City Speedway), which also explains its first name: Speedway Field. It got its first hangar a year later, constructed for airmail services.  ‍ Terminal 1 was built in the late 50s, costing the administration around 8.5 million Dollars, with 56,000 square meters of total area, 24 gates, and two concourses designed by Lyle George Landstrom. It was concluded in 1962 and inaugurated a few days later. Further expansion happened a decade later with the construction of Pier D (now Concourse G). Existing concourses were rebuilt into bi-level structures with holding rooms and jet bridges. That same concourse was later improved in 1986. ‍ Terminal 2 was built in 1986 and rebuilt in 2001. It currently features 14 gates and serves Sun Country, Southwest, Condor, Icelandair, and JetBlue. ‍  It’s a hub for Delta Air Lines, Sun Country Airlines, and Bemidji Airlines. Aer Lingus, Air Canada Express, Air France, Alaska Air, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Condor, Denver Air Connection, Frontier Airlines, Icelandair, JetBlue, KLM, Lufthansa (mid-2024), Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-resolution textures, dynamic jetways with custom signage, custom ground textures, new flightbeam sound effects, key interior areas modeled in the terminal, dense amount of custom tarmac objects, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $20, requiring at least 407.1 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpg160</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Releases H160 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpg160" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653af541b8d120f680d27217_hyp.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="112782"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has recently released their rendition of the Airbus H160 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a medium utility helicopter formally launched in 2015 and introduced in 2021.  First revealed in 2011, the H160 was declared a “game changer” with advanced fly-by-wire controls, advanced pilot edge functionality, reduced vibration, Blue Edge active tracking rotor blades, and a “radically different cockpit.” With the development costs rapidly racking up, some of the promised features were either toned down or eliminated when the helicopter was formally introduced in 2015. The H160 features a light and efficient design, eliminating conventional hydraulic parts like the landing gear and brakes for electrical counterparts. It is one tonne lighter than its rival, burns less fuel, and is cheaper to operate in the long run.  It’s powered by two Safran Arrano 1A turboshaft engines, producing 1280 hp each, with a total range of 880 km, at 255 km/h, with a service ceiling of 20,000ft. HPG’s rendition features a high-detail 3D model, two variants (Civilian and Luxury), six liveries for each variant, PBR texturing, VR support, working doors, animated windshield wipers, animated flight controls, functional emergency floats, advanced avionics and systems, compatibility with either the PMS or the TDS Garmin GTN device, a functional weather radar, and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ Highly Detailed 3D Model, Textures and Animations Advanced Avionics &amp; Detailed Systems ‍ Powerful 4-axis Autopilot ‍ Helicopter Flight Model ‍ Immersive Sounds It’s available for $49.99 on HPG’s website.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsswin</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Winnipeg International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsswin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653c03082703ca4659ceeaae_win1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="228278"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has just released their rendition of Winnipeg International Airport (CYWG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 7th busiest airport in Canada with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. ‍ It opened in 1928 as Stevenson Aerodrome, over a local aviator. It was Canada’s first international airport, with Northwest Airways’ passenger and air mail service to Pembina, North Dakota, in 1931. Five years later, the City of Winnipeg and the Rural Municipality of Saint James agreed on developing the airfield as a modern municipal airport. ‍ The original main terminal was built in 1964 and expanded and renovated 20 years later by IKOY. It was closed in 2011 and demolished. A modern project from Cesar Pelli/Stantec replaced it, started in 2007 and finished in 2011. ‍ It’s a hub for Calm Air, Cargojet, Perimeter Aviation, and Bearskin Airlines. Air Canada, Air Canada Express, Delta Air Lines, Flair Airlines, Lynx Air, Porter Airlines, Sunwing Airlines, WestJet, and WestJet Encore also serve it. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality texturing, high-detail models, custom ground textures, a fully modeled terminal interior, custom jetways, and more. ‍ It’s available on their store for $18.99, requiring at least 2.93 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pildah</id>
    <title>PILOT’S Releases Dash 7 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pildah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653c0a80649d2fb01311f6fa_das1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2339944"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PILOT'S has recently released their rendition of the de Havilland Canada Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a turboprop-powered regional airliner with STOL Capabilities introduced in 1978.  ‍ First flown in 1975, the Dash 7 is a "Twin Otter but larger and with four engines," with oversized fan blades that would rotate at a slower speed to emit as little noise as possible, complying with the noise restrictions that were starting to creep in. It could carry up to 50 passengers, with a service ceiling of 21,000 feet and 690 nautical miles of range, all powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-50 turboprop engines, with 1,120 hp each.  ‍ As of July 2018, 17 Dash 7s were still flying worldwide with six different operators. However, the list of former operators is substantial: sixty civilian and three military operators. ‍ The add-on features 4K textures, authentic and realistic gauges, full TDS GTN750xi support (and default GNS 530), nine liveries, authentic color matching, and more. ‍ It's available on their website for roughly $21.13. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
