<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-07-31T18:21:43.872002+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrgne</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases East Midlands Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrgne" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bc65ad815d64a96071b3ae_ema1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="222970"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently released their rendition of East Midlands Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator (EGNX), serving the entire East Midlands region with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  The airport started as RAF Castle Donington in 1943, sporting three concrete runways and two hangars, and it hosted the 28 Operational Training Unit and the 108 Operational Training Unit during the short WW2 stint. It was closed and decommissioned three years later, in 1946.  Then, in 1964, a group of local government agencies bought the former airfield, investing heavily in transforming it into a commercial airport. It was then renamed East Midlands Airport and got ready for passenger traffic in early 1965.  The airport saw heavy upgrade work in the early 2000s when the traffic figures increased significantly. It included an extension of the passenger terminal, new car parks, and a new pier.  It’s an important cargo hub for DHL and UPS, which collaborate significantly to its second position in cargo traffic in the UK.  Airline-wise, it’s mostly an LCC airport, with the likes of Jet2.com (Alicante, Antalya, Faro, Fuerteventura, Funchal, Gran Canaria, Lanzarote, Málaga, Tenerife–South), TUI (Alicante, Hurghada, Lanzarote, Málaga, Sharm El Sheikh, Tenerife–South), and Ryanair (Alicante, Barcelona, Belfast–International, Bergamo, Berlin, Budapest, Cork, Dublin, Faro, Fuerteventura, Gran Canaria, Knock, Kraków, Lanzarote, Limoges, Málaga, Malta, Riga, Rome–Ciampino, Rzeszów, Tenerife–South, Wrocław).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with LiDAR elevation data, up-to-date satellite imagery, custom ground polygons with accurate weathering, an up-to-date airport layout, ATC/AI traffic integration, animated Skylink buses, dynamic gate doors (GSX is required), a custom GSX profile, a custom terminal interior, landside buildings, and more.  It’s available on Contrail for roughly $22, requiring at least 3.56 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samjej</id>
    <title>SamScene Releases Jeju International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samjej" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bda78afb12cff56096a3b8_jeju1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1423378"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SamScene has recently released their rendition of Jeju International Airport (RKPC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in South Korea with a yearly average of 31 million passengers.  The airport was built as a military airfield in 1946 and only converted to civilian use in 1963. The first international flight to Osaka, Japan, only happened a year later.  In the early 90s, due to the constantly rising passenger volume, the government decided to build a much larger terminal, reaching completion in 1997. It has been one of the busiest airports in the country ever since.  Jeju International Airport is a major hub for Korean Air and Asiana Airlines, and it also serves many other airlines, including Air China, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, EVA Air, Japan Airlines, Singapore Airlines, and Thai Airways.  The airport is currently operating at its capacity, so they are constructing a new one near the city of Seogwipo, expected to reach completion by 2025.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal interior, custom night lighting, a detailed city center, iconic points of interest, custom ground markings, custom jetways, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.45, requiring at least 1.33 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winyop</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases El Alcaraván Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winyop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bdabb6299243be7de1f2c8_yop1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1077617"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of El Alcaraván Airport (SKYP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Yopal, Colombia.  It was built in the 1960s to serve the oil industry in the state, with Aerotaxi Casanare S/A handling most of the passenger traffic.   In the late 90s, petrol companies worldwide gathered together to improve the airport’s conditions so it could accommodate larger aircraft. The president landed with a Boeing 707 to inaugurate the improvements in late 1996.  Ten years later, the Camera de Comercio de Casanare (their Chamber of Commerce) asked the Ministry of Transport to make it an international airport, which was only granted many years later. Despite being classified as an international airport and having an immigration facility, it has no international flights.  It’s currently served by Avianca, EasyFly, Latam Colombia, and Satena, with flights to Bogotá and Bucaramanga.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom night lighting, a terminal interior, hangars, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.35, requiring at least 2.59 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mskmum</id>
    <title>MSK Productions Releases Mumbai Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mskmum" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bdb07af02f056f360a427e_mumbai1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2248887"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSK Productions has recently released their rendition of Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport (VABB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Mumbai Metropolitan Region with a yearly average of 43 million passengers.  The airport started as a Royal Air Force airfield in the 1930s, housing multiple RAF squadrons during WW2, and was eventually handed over to the government to be converted into a civilian airport once the conflict had ceased.  The first expansion started in the 50s, with further work planned in the 60s but only executed in the late 70s, causing a lot of drama back then. Time magazine said the terminal was a “black hole” of sorts, and then a terminal building fire killed three passengers in 1979. It was overcrowded and unsafe.  The new terminal reached completion in 1980, costing 110 million rupees and temporarily solving the overcrowding. It was then modernized in the early 2000s, bringing it up to international standards.  It is currently the second busiest airport in India, after Indira Gandhi International Airport in New Delhi. Several airlines serve it, including Air India, IndiGo, Jet Airways, and SpiceJet.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom buildings, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, terminal 1 and 2 interiors, custom terraforming, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.23, requiring at least 380.25 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simda2</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Releases DA20-C1 Eclipse for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simda2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bdb3e173a9fad5ca6cb797_da1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="119963"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimSolutions has recently released their DA20-C1 Eclipse for X-Plane 12, a two-seat, single-engine airplane manufactured by Diamond.  The Eclipse is the “fancy” variant of the DA20 Katana, a light aircraft introduced by Diamond in 1993, ideal for flight schools and private pilots on a budget. On the other hand, the fancy Eclipse only came to be in 1999, featuring rear windows, better visibility, and a complete set of equipment.  It’s powered by a 125 hp Continental IO-240-B, cruising at up to 138 knots with a range of 629 nautical miles with a 30-minute reserve.  The add-on features an accurate rendition of the aircraft, with high-resolution textures, user-friendly systems, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:   Features Liveries  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $24.99, requiring at least 476 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lr1212</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Updates X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lr1212" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bfe8ede88eaaf5cf5ad8a4_Screenshot-2022-11-15-at-11.44.40.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2193773"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has released an early public beta for X-Plane 12.06. Users can expect a long list of bug fixes including fixes for users experiencing CTD crashes when landing at non towered airports and fixes to the Vulkan graphics API. The update also comes with a short list of known bugs including abnormal cloud shapes while using real world weather; Laminar has stated they aim to fix this in version 12.06b2.  Some of the more noticable bug fixes in the new beta include: The new beta comes just 12 weeks after the last update which focused mainly on fixes for the Laminar Research A330. </summary>
    <published>2023-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrwcee</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XIV: Central Eastern Europe</title>
    <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrwcee" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c024d24c470ee4cb573993_cee1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1065093"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released the fourteenth world update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, improving Czechia, Slovakia, Hungary, Slovenia, Croatia, and Bosnia-Herzegovina with fresh satellite imagery, better DEM data, and six hand-crafted airports developed in partnership with Gaya Simulations.  With 103 points of interest across the six countries (18 in Czechia, 15 in Slovakia, 19 in Hungary, 15 in Slovenia, 23 in Croatia, and 13 in Bosnia-Herzegovina), including castles, towers, churches, and other landmarks, it greatly improves the eastern european experience in the simulator.  They have also included six hand-crafted airports, one for each country:   Microsoft Maps &amp; Local, in collaboration with Vexcel, created ten cities throughout the region: Prague, Brno, and Plzeň in Czechia; Budapest in Hungary; Ljubljana and Maribor in Slovenia; Split and Dubrovnik in Croatia; and Sarajevo and Banja Luka in Bosnia-Herzegovina.   It also features three discovery flights, three landing challenges, and four bush trips.   The update is available right now in the MSFS Marketplace. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbhar</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces S43 Harvey Field &amp; W16 Monroe First Air Field for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbhar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c0b6d2fdb4085340f9ecea_harvey1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="662865"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of two general aviation airfields, minutes apart from each other: S43 Harvey Field &amp; W16 Monroe First Air Field, both in Washington, United States.  Harvey Airfield is a privately-owned public-use airport in Sonomish (WA), categorized on the FAA's National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems as a regional reliever facility. It was established in 1944 by the Harvey Family, getting a restaurant, an administration building, and a maintenance shop in 1947.   It is mainly used for flight training in general aviation airplanes and helicopters but also offers fuel and aircraft maintenance.  Monroe First Air Field is a public-use airport owned by the Washington State Department of Transportation. It opened in 1930 as a private airfield for Monroe Aircraft Corporation and was utilized in the following decade as a training base for the US Army.   The post-war saw the airfield become a general aviation facility, which continues to this day, even after its acquisition by the Washington State Department of Transportation in 1980.  Despite being small, it's considered a very important part of the state's history for its many purposes over its nearly 100 years of existence. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of both airfields, with custom dynamic lighting, full PBR 4K texturing, photo-realistic textures created with on-site photography, and more. ‍ There is no release date or pricing information. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyremm</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Updates East Midlands Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyremm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c1ab29dec58e0f24f6b460_mid1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="79127"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently released an update to their newly released rendition of East Midlands Airport (EGNX) with quality-of-life fixes and improvements.  The developer also claims it’s ready for submission to Microsoft for the marketplace intake on PC and Xbox. ‍  The list of changes includes the addition of Bus stops down the DHL road, reflection issues, snow coverage improvements, addressing of a terrain bump, and more. The complete changelog follows down below:  - Catering truck going through fence near baggage bay 1 - Taxiway M terrain bump - GT3 missing rear quarter window - Barrier reflections (Texaco Fuel Depot) - Bitumen Reflections (Old ATC Tower Wall) - Light Day/Night Cycles (PAX Terminal) - AI Not taking off Runway 09 - Skylink Bus does not have lights for LOD02 - Static 767 Nose Cone Shading issue - Snow Coverage issues - GSE Clutter at Stand 42 clipping through GSX stairs - Stand 12R spawn heading - Windsocks showing opposite wind - SEGRO Park Sign missing logos - Some PAX had snow on their heads Improvements: - Added missing Bus Stops down the DHL Road - Added parked vehicles to Diseworth Rd east of Aeropark - Terraforming improvements and adjustments   The product is available on Contrail for roughly $22, requiring at least 3.6 GB of free hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbswm</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases S43 Harvey Field and W16 Monroe Firstair for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbswm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c0b70082ebe960cd8307f1_harvey8.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="484819"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently launched their rendition of Harvey Field (S43) and Monroe Firstair (W16) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, both in Washington (United States) and only minutes apart from each other.   Harvey Airfield is a privately-owned public-use airport in Sonomish (WA), categorized on the FAA's National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems as a regional reliever facility. It was established in 1944 by the Harvey Family, getting a restaurant, an administration building, and a maintenance shop in 1947.   It is mainly used for flight training in general aviation airplanes and helicopters but also offers fuel and aircraft maintenance.  Monroe First Air Field is a public-use airport owned by the Washington State Department of Transportation. It opened in 1930 as a private airfield for Monroe Aircraft Corporation and was utilized in the following decade as a training base for the US Army.   The post-war saw the airfield become a general aviation facility, which continues to this day, even after its acquisition by the Washington State Department of Transportation in 1980.  Despite being small, it's considered a very important part of the state's history for its many purposes over its nearly 100 years of existence.  The scenery features a reedition of two classics for FSX and Prepar3d, with meticulously crafted buildings based on on-site photography, 4K PBR textures, custom dynamic lighting, and more.  It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.48, requiring at least 4.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2auco</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2auco" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c3fb66ce14663b7ea9d15b_a2a-5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="565164"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently released the first update for their newly released Accu-Sim Comanche, bringing a series of fixes and improvements. Update 1.1 restores missing engine cooldown sounds, fixes the issue with the B78XH add-on making the tablet not work correctly (unclickable), adds a series of flight model adjustments, and more. The complete changelog follows down below:  The official update announcement can be found here, along with the changelog.  It’s available for $49.99 on the A2A Simulations Store. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdpduf</id>
    <title>Grinelli Designs Publishes Development Update on F-100D Super Sabre Module for DCS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdpduf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c406be2159fa97ea3baa2c_sabre1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="177855"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Grinelli Designs has recently published a new development update on their upcoming F-100D Super Sabre Module for DCS concerning its current 3D modeling progress, sound design, and future development plans.   They have used advanced 3D scanning techniques and photogrammetry to obtain precise measurements, shapes, and textures of the exterior and cockpit, which were then sent to their modeling team to be used as a reference for their work.  Grinelli Designs has also recorded many cockpit sounds to enhance the product’s audio experience.  The current development progress is said to be steadily moving forward, with the airplane in a flyable state and with many advancements in the flight model, engine, fuel, and hydraulic systems, while also actively testing and refining the core systems of the aircraft.  Even though the addition of the 3D scans has improved the accuracy and fidelity of their upcoming product, they claim there’s more work to be done: continuous refinement of the exterior and interior, flight model tweaks, the implementation of a weapon system, and adding more liveries and customization options. They also claim they have been collaborating with real-world F-100D pilots and experts and actively listening to their insights and knowledge.  They finish the development update with a link to their progress tracker, where people can see how far they have come with the development so far. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swp12u</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Publishes Important Update on PC-12 Release</title>
    <updated>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swp12u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c6d169de96d1262081640c_364119781_750190990441917_15265037922812617_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="311836"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios has published a development update on their upcoming Pilatus PC-12 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  The update previews multiple features that will be included with the plane, as well as a tentative release window for the highly anticipated aircraft.  ‍ SWS reports that the executive cabin for the aircraft is now fully functional, with realistic cabin, flood, and reading lights being implemented. All the tray tables, seats, and armrests are also fully modeled and the drawers will close if the aircraft is banked too much. For the exterior, the update details that engine covers that are in addition to the Angle of Attack and pitot vane covers. Along with that, the "Remove Before Flight" tags on the covers will react to external forces such as aircraft slope, through a simulated gravity vector, and react to wind direction and speed.  ‍ The aircraft is around two weeks from completion, and if all goes well, SimWorks Studios plans to send it to Pilatus to verify that that the aircraft's systems and flight model act just like the real aircraft.  ‍ The team says that they are planning a mid-September release, as they are taking a two week break from August 14th through the 25th, and they want to give enough time to fix any bugs that their testing team, or Pilatus might find. As with many projects, this release window is subject to change. Whenever the release date is, Threshold will keep you updated, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs2afo</id>
    <title>FS2Crew Releases Animated First Officer - FBW A32NX Edition for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs2afo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c6dea0678309534b81c1b3_fs2c.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="91424"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  FS2Crew has recently released their first AI-powered animated first officer add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an expansion pack for their Flybywire A32NX FS2Crew.   ‍ The developers claim it has been something people wanted for a long time, but it was impossible in FSX and P3D because of technological limitations. MSFS, on the other hand, makes the “dream” come true with an AI co-pilot that can interact with the pilot and the aircraft.  The animated first officer will perform realistic cabin flows and checklists and physically interact with the environment, clicking on everything like you would expect a real first officer to.  They have included two videos from different content creators showcasing how the product works in practice:  It’s available on their official website for roughly $16.52 (on sale). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tpskv2</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Kansas City International Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tpskv2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c6e39a678309534b848d98_kansas1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="862503"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released an updated version of their Kansas City International Airport (KMCI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Missouri after St. Louis, with a yearly average of 9 million passengers.  The newly released version brings the airport layout up to current standards, with the new single terminal opened in 2023 that replaces Terminals B and C, with 40 gates in total.   Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express currently serve it. SWA has the majority of the market share with 45.43% of the traffic figures, followed by American and Delta with 14.27% and 14.08%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the new airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, PBR texturing, custom jetways, and a custom interior.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.37, requiring at least 435.56 MB of free hard disk space to install. Owners of the previous version are entitled to a $15.44 upgrade fee. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksyul</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Montréal-Trudeau International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksyul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c77424491eb63b3fd8f222_yul1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="528007"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Montréal-Trudeau International Airport (CYUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving greater Montreal and eastern Ontario with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.  It opened in 1941, replacing Saint-Hubert Airport - Montreal’s former airport - considered inadequate for the city’s needs into the 40s and beyond. It was constructed on land that once was a race track, chosen for its size and generally good weather conditions throughout the year. It also doubled as a military airport for almost twenty years.  In the 70s, the government planned on replacing it with a new, much larger airport - Montreal Mirabel -, then the largest in the world, repurposing YUL as a domestic airport. The whole project was centered around traffic growth that never happened for many reasons, which consequently caused the decline of both Montreal airports over the following decades.  The inconvenience of Mirabel grew larger and larger, to the point they decided to resume international operations in Montreal-Trudeau again in 1997 and charter flights in 2004 (and Mirabel ceased passenger operations entirely in 2004).   It’s a hub for Air Canada (Barcelona, Bogotá, Brussels, Calgary, Casablanca, Delhi, Denver, Edmonton, Fort-de-France, Frankfurt, Geneva, Halifax, Houston–Intercontinental, Lisbon, London–Heathrow, Los Angeles, Lyon, Mexico City, Miami, Milan–Malpensa, Paris–Charles de Gaulle, Pointe-à-Pitre, Providenciales, Rome–Fiumicino, San Francisco, San José de Costa Rica–Juan Santamaría, São Paulo–Guarulhos, Tampa, Tokyo–Narita, Toronto–Pearson, Toulouse, Vancouver, Winnipeg), Air Transat (Cancún, Cayo Coco, Fort Lauderdale, Holguín, Lisbon, London–Gatwick, Lyon, Málaga, Marseille, Miami, Montego Bay, Orlando, Paris–Charles de Gaulle, Port-au-Prince, Puerto Plata, Puerto Vallarta, Punta Cana, Samaná, Santa Clara, Toronto–Pearson, Varadero), and OWG (Cayo Coco, Holguín, Santa Clara, Varadero), flying passengers all over the globe.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with LiDAR airport elevation data, custom satellite imagery covering the airport and its surroundings, custom ground polygons, handcrafted 3D models of buildings, jetways, and facilities, realistic night lighting, and more.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.70, requiring at least 5.09 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
