<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-01-27T18:29:33.519734+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jlgrp4</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Rhodes International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jlgrp4"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67869650a2fb9d490056cc95_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. JustSim has released its first scenery fully adapted for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, revisiting a previous destination: Rhodes International Airport (LGRP). Rhodes is a popular summer destination in the Greek Islands, attracting over six million passengers annually. Civil aviation on the island began after World War II with the opening of Rhodes Maritsa Airport, which served as the main airport until Rhodes International Airport, also known as Diagoras International Airport, was inaugurated in 1977. Over the years, the airport has seen improvements, including expanded taxiways and a new passenger terminal that opened in 2005. In 2015, the airport was privatized and is now managed by Fraport AG/Copelouzos Group for a period of 40 years. Today, Rhodes International Airport hosts numerous airlines offering scheduled, seasonal, and charter flights to various destinations across Europe. According to JustFlight, the new scenery features high-resolution ground textures, high-resolution building textures, highly detailed 3D models, custom animated ground vehicles, and much more. The scenery requires 1.66 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $17.28. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ed2025</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Posts DCS 2025 and Beyond Video</title>
    <updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ed2025"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678a9159a7f32bf69bada631_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has unveiled its DCS 2025 and Beyond video, marking the start of the year for the team. This annual preview highlights new features and add-ons that will enhance the DCS experience. Viewers can expect an in-depth look at upcoming innovations for the flight simulation platform. The video begins by introducing Dynamic Campaigns, a feature that has been highly requested by the community for some time. For the first time since its announcement in last year's video, footage of the upcoming MiG-29A is shown in-game. Additionally, the Eurofighter Typhoon Tranche 1 and 2 are showcased after being absent for two years. Throughout the video, there are glimpses of Berlin, hinting at a potential new map, likely set in Germany. Other teasers include enhanced ground assets, a new variant of the Mirage F1M, the C-130 from Airplane Simulation Company, the Sparrowhawk HUD for both the F-14A and F-14B, and the F-100 Super Sabre. The video suggests that there is a wealth of exciting upcoming content to look forward to. At the video's conclusion, developers announced two exciting new aircraft for DCS. Development will begin in 2025 for a full-fidelity F-15C, an agile air superiority fighter, and an F-35A, a stealthy multirole fighter. Both are expected to be released in 2026. Once more information about any of the teasers is available, we will make sure to let you know. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl292</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates Airbus A321Ceo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl292"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de4adcd06a5053536bb2_labsup3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs has released another update to their newly released Airbus A321Ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. This update brings a realistic implementation of the Rockwell Collins WXR-2100 system (weather radar) and a series of fixes and improvements. Update v11.0.1.292—the fourth since its release—highlights the weather radar implementation. It seamlessly integrates the powerful Rockwell Collins suite, which has been meticulously designed to interact with the live weather environment in MSFS and produce accurate radar returns. They have also expanded their hardware integration, adding compatibility with WinWing, MiniCockpit, WingFlex, and more.  Besides the weather radar and new hardware integration, the update also brings numerous bug fixes, improvements based on user feedback, performance improvements, and an overall more stable system behavior. The highlights follow below: ‍ AOC ‍ Display and Cockpit Updates: ‍ Electrical and Power Systems: ‍ Flight Control Logic and Sensors: ‍ Flight Deck and Hardware Integration: ‍ ‍ FMGC: ‍ Flight Warning and Control: ‍ ‍ Navigation and Radios: ‍ ‍ Performance and Calculations: ‍ ‍ Sounds: ‍ Techlog: ‍ Weather Radar: ‍ The add-on is available on their website for $69.95. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simgmz</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Guardia Marina Zañartu Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simgmz"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678bc9aad9d514fbfc2b3dd7_zanartu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Simulación Extrema has recently released its rendition of Guardia Marina Zañartu Airport (SCGZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which serves Puerto Williams on Navarino Island, Chile. It was inaugurated in 1957 by President Carlos Ibáñez del Campo and named after a local naval aviation pilot, Guillermo Zañartu Irigoyen. It's the world's southernmost airport with scheduled flights, solidifying its history in aviation. ‍ It connects Navarino Island to Chile and the rest of the world, providing a vital link to an otherwise isolated region. Aerovías DAP serves it with scheduled flights to Punta Arenas and Santiago del Chile. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled passenger terminal, custom ground textures, custom ground clutter, and more.  It's available in the MSFS Marketplace for $11.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/psgmff</id>
    <title>PerfectSoft Studio Releases Fès-Saïss Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/psgmff"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678c2e986aa799876bcc8f50_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PerfectSoft Studio has released its rendition of Fès–Saïss Airport (GMFF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Located in Morocco, it serves the city of Fez and connects various destinations across Europe, welcoming approximately 1.4 million passengers annually. Fès–Saïss Airport is one of the busiest airports in Morocco. It aims to connect the region to Europe, a goal it has successfully achieved with a steady increase in flights. The airport reached the milestone of welcoming over one million passengers annually back in 2017. Operated by the Moroccan Airports Authority, it features a runway that is 10,500 feet long, capable of accommodating a variety of aircraft. The airport serves airlines such as Air Arabia and Ryanair, offering destinations like Amsterdam, Barcelona, Brussels, and many more. The newly released scenery features realistic modelling, PBR texturing, 4K textures, high-detail 3D models, and hand-placed vegetation, among other features. The scenery is available for around $15.41 on the SimMarket. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd118</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd118"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/678c68106aa799876b0f315e_1250410_20240201232908_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published their first development update of the year, which includes further information on the progress of porting their current product line over to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, their upcoming 777-200ER, and more. They are still waiting for Asobo to address specific issues with MSFS 2024 that seem to be blocking the conversion for the time being (memory allocation issues, instability, etc). They have forwarded their findings to the development team and hope these fixes will be made available by SU1.  While they hope that SU1 will allow them to work with MSFS 2024, they are not entirely optimistic yet: “In our experience, there is still downside risk that getting these two fixes rolled into the platform might simply move us forward a few spots, so that we can crack our shins on the next obstacle,” explained Randazzo. The plans for product line compatibility remain similar, with the DC-6 being made compatible yet not bringing any new features per se, the triple sevens eventually making their way into the new platform, and the 737 is undergoing a major overhaul with new sim features such as walkaround, career mode features, upgraded textures, new models, a brand new cabin with a working cockpit door, enhanced gameplay features and interactivity within the cabin environment, and new sounds.  The 737 will also receive an update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which aims to fix the spinning logo bug on the Universal Flight Tablet. Their upcoming 777-200ER is entering beta testing, and PMDG plans to release it for MSFS 2020 and 2024 (like the 777F). Due to the existing workload, no new features are planned for the product. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kiad20</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Washington Dulles International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kiad20"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6792c47e55378a8b549eb1bb_354130_24.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FeelThere has just released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020: Washington Dulles International Airport (KIAD). Located in Dulles, Virginia, Washington Dulles International Airport is situated 26 miles west of downtown Washington, D.C., the primary city it serves. The airport is the 10th busiest in the United States for international passenger traffic, handling over 20 million passengers annually. It opened on the 17th of November 1962 and is named after John Foster Dulles, a former U.S. Secretary of State. Today, Dulles serves as a hub for United Airlines and is frequently utilised by codeshare partners. According to FeelThere, the airport scenery features highly detailed buildings with PBR texturing, fully modelled terminal interiors, and a realistic ground polygon with authentic decals, dirt, and taxi lines. Additional enhancements include custom animated jetways, an updated AFCAD with accurate parking and signage, and improved lighting for taxiways, runways, and aprons. ‍ The full feature list follows: – Highly detailed buildings with PBR texturing. – Terminal interiors modelled. – Complete modelled ground polygon including realistic decals, dirt, taxi lines and surfaces. – Custom animated jetways. – Airline parking codes and modified airport services. – Updated AFCAD, parking spots, taxiway names and taxi signs. – Improved taxiway and runway lighting. – Custom modelled clutter and unique objects placed throughout the airport. – Improved night lighting and apron lamps. The scenery requires 1.2 GB of storage space and is available for $10.79, which is a 10% discount off the regular price of $11.99, through the FeelThere website. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Also, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samkun</id>
    <title>SamScene Releases Kunming Changshui International Airport for MSFS20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samkun"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6792ffaae00d09465038149c_kun1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SamScene recently released their rendition of Kunming Changshui International Airport (ZPPP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Kunming, China, with a yearly average of 42 million passengers. Built in 2009 as a replacement for Kunming Wujiaba International Airport, it quickly became one of the busiest airports in the world.  Its construction time was marked by tragedy, with seven construction workers dying in 2010 after an incomplete overpass collapsed, and eleven workers were injured a year later when a tunnel under construction also collapsed. Such was the cost of finishing such a large project within two years. Its main terminal is China's second-largest terminal building, with 548,300 square meters and 66 gates with jet bridges, 88 in total.  It's a hub for China Eastern Airlines, Hongtu Airlines, Kunming Airlines, Lucky Air, Ruili Airlines, and Sichuan Airlines. AirAsia, Air China, Batik Air Malaysia, Beijing Capital Airlines, Chengdu Airlines, China Express Airlines, China United Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Hebei Airlines, Juneyao Air, Korean Air, Scoot, Spring Airlines, Thai AirAsia, Tibet Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed terminal buildings, custom ground markings, custom jetways, 50 iconic buildings, detailed surroundings, and performance-friendly optimization. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $17.16, requiring at least 3.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfssub</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Subang Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfssub"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679304607662732e128c5caf_subang1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MFSG recently released their rendition of Sultan Abdul Aziz Shah Airport (WMSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Greater Kuala Lumpur and has a yearly average of 949,934 passengers. Inaugurated as Subang International Airport in 1965, it was Kuala Lumpur’s main gateway until Kuala Lumpur International Airport was constructed in Sepang (1998).  It was designed by architects Kington Loo and C.H.R. Bailey, featuring an innovative design for the time, with an iconic floating concrete shell roof supported by mushroom-shaped columns.  By the late 1990s, its growth became an issue and a potential hazard, as two major fires - with casualties - had already occurred in the early 1990s. With its capacity stretched to the maximum, the government decided to build an entirely new airport elsewhere. Nowadays, the airport serves mainly as a central hub for regional and charter carriers, attracting many domestic travelers due to its proximity to the city center and overall convenient location. It’s a hub for Firefly, and AirAsia, Batik Air Malaysia, Berjaya Air, Scoot, and TransNusa also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.57, requiring at least 102.21 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsw25t</id>
    <title>FlightSimWeekend 2025 Tickets Now Available</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsw25t"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679386cbf9de5d70d60d9a34_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Tickets for the upcoming FlightSimWeekend 2025 are now on sale! This annual event will take place at the Aviodrome Aviation Museum in Lelystad, the Netherlands, on March 15th and 16th. Each year, it brings together flight simulation enthusiasts to explore the latest innovations in flight simulation software and hardware. There are a total of two ticket types available. They are as follows: ‍ ‍ If you plan to attend both days, purchasing the two-day ticket will save you 25% compared to buying two separate one-day tickets. For more information about the event, including travel, logistics, and other details, please visit the FlightSimWeekend website.  FlightSimWeekend 2025 will be held at the Aviodrome Aviation Museum on March 15th and 16th. Tickets are available for purchase online. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inipvd</id>
    <title>IniBuilds Teases Rhode Island T.F Green International Airport</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inipvd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6793c42dddab1ca4d22dabc3_Rhode_Island_T._F._Green_International_Airport_sign.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Renowned developer IniBuilds has recently teased its next project: Rhode Island T.F. Green Airport (KPVD), through a story on its Instagram and Facebook pages  T.F. Green Airport is located 10 miles south of Providence, Rhode Island, the primary city it serves. The airport features two runways and accommodates approximately 3.5 million passengers annually. ‍ The airport, named after former Rhode Island governor Theodore Francis Green, opened in 1931 and was rebuilt in 1966. It now primarily serves the East Coast. ‍ IniBuilds is one of the leading developers in flight simulation. They have created the A330-300 and Airbus Beluga for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Additionally, they have developed several classic Airbus aircraft for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and X-Plane 11. ‍ Details regarding features, compatibility, and other specifics remain unknown.  ‍ For further updates on T.F. Green Airport, iniBuilds, and more, stay tuned to Threshold! ‍ Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x-plane-12-1-4-released-in-public-beta</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12.1.4 Released in Public Beta</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x-plane-12-1-4-released-in-public-beta"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6793da062f37a769aea67c68_Flightlessons_Title_6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The latest version of Laminar Research’s X-Plane, 12.1.4, is now available in public beta. This update, known as the flight lessons update, introduces numerous quality-of-life improvements, along with new flight lessons. ‍ Flight lessons Version 12.1.4 introduces new flight lessons for beginners. Users will be guided through four introductory lessons in the Cirrus SR-22 before moving on to the Lancair Evolution. All of this is led by Austin Meyer, the creator of X-Plane. ‍Camera updates The new build introduces a new physics-based camera option. According to Laminar Research it will simulate the forces experienced while flying a real aircraft. The new camera system is primarily focused on enhancing the interior view, however a new hand-held camera mode has also been added for external views. Scenery Salzburg Airport (LOWS) has undergone significant improvements, particularly in its local autogen, which has been enhanced considerably. Additionally, the Red Bull hangars and Salzburg Castle are now featured.  ‍ Parts of southern Germany, northern Italy, and Austria are now the demo area, with Salzburg being the location for the new flight lessons. ‍ In addition Barra Airport (EGPL) has also been updated. The Scottish airport is known for its unique runway—or lack thereof. Safe Mode Laminar Research is introducing a "safe mode" feature. This allows plugins to be isolated without needing to delete them manually one at a time when searching for the source of a crash. Additional improvements were made, including new library objects and enhancements to the G1000 with the introduction of the SAR function, along with other general updates. ‍ Refer to the X-Plane blog post for further details on the update. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw737</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases PMDG 737NG Sound Set for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67943969ef071b7748080568_boris5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Boris Audio Works has recently released their long-awaited sound set for the PMDG 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The set brings meticulously engineered sound captures from the cabin, engines, environment, and more. Recorded with state-of-the-art audio equipment from a real 737NG airplane, Boris Audio Works’ latest product promises a comprehensive audio package with a clear engine, cabin, fans, pack, ground roll, buttons, hydraulic pump sounds, and cabin chatter for extra immersion. Furthermore, the package also features a headphone simulation with noise canceling for those who aim to get a more realistic audio experience during their virtual journeys. The complete feature list follows below: The product is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.47, requiring at least 391.17 MB of free hard disk to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737112</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup &amp; Shares 747 Previews </title>
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737112"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679444116a9bb190466e481a_randy.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a new development update for their current and future products, including a new 737 lineup update, a 777 product line (new and upcoming variants), and a 747 Classic project. The 737NG lineup has been updated to v3.00.0112. This update primarily focuses on fixing the ongoing issues with the Universal Flight Tablet, trying to reduce or wholly eliminate the eternally spinning PMDG logo bug. Minor fixes on other fronts also further refine the product’s stability. ‍ Their main plan for the 737NG lineup was to stabilize it further, and their focus has now shifted back to their upcoming products. Extra effort will eventually be put into the revamped version for MSFS 2024, with new model upgrades, sounds, and an entirely new sound engine. ‍ The 777-200ER is still being readied for beta testing. Its release is planned to be MSFS 2020 only at first and then a free upgrade to MSFS 2024 later. The 200LR, which is set to come right after, will follow the same order. ‍ Regarding the upcoming 747 project, PMDG is still unsure whether the first to be released will be the -100 or the -400, as both are advancing as core development projects. Work has sped up quite significantly since they moved part of the 777 development team to the project. ‍ They have also previewed part of the modeling work on the 747-100s cockpit, reinforcing that wear, tear, and proper labeling have not yet been added.  Given the 747-100s manual nature of systems management, they will implement a virtual copilot and virtual flight engineer to help manage their systems efficiently and realistically, albeit with an option to disable them if desired. PMDG claims it’s still “too soon” for 747-400 cockpit previews, but the systems simulation work is well advanced. ‍ The 747-100 previews are the first to deviate from PMDG’s usual modus operandi: instead of sharing images only when the product is nearly finished / ready for testing, they show it early in its development stage. ‍ Their product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdsu1</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Optimistic Statement on MSFS 2024 SU1 Public Beta Compatibility </title>
    <updated>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdsu1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6700743a43d6279dcc6fba41_randy3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Robert Randazzo, PMDG's CEO, recently made an announcement post in their forum with further information on how their product line is faring with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024's latest public beta update and where they now stand regarding the eventual compatibility upgrade. They built the triple 777 in MSFS 2024 using the latest SDK, and it ran in a "mostly stable fashion" with debuggers attached. The airplane operated through an entire flight, and the many issues that showed up in the process were cataloged. They will be addressed starting next week to warrant the best experience possible. That means they have removed the "blockers" that were preventing them from starting work on the compatibility upgrade, and now they can finally begin the process. ‍ While it does run in MSFS 2024 already, it's not truly usable yet as many things don't work properly and require further adjustment. ‍ In Randazzo's words, their optimism needle for MSFS 2024 has "moved to the mid position," and PMDG looks forward to bringing its simulation value to the new platform.  ‍ PMDG's product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/grutbf</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Grumman TBF Avenger for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/grutbf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6795c3d361a267f1da7cc5f4_avenger5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of the Grumman TBF Avenger for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This WW2-era airplane was developed for the United States Navy and Marine Corps and eventually adopted by many air and naval aviation services worldwide. It was designed in 1940 to replace the Douglas TBD Devastator, offering an airplane that was very much in line with the technology adopted by the Axis forces at the time, in complete contrast to the Devastator, which was considered obsolete by 1939. The Avenger was designed to easily fit in aircraft carriers, with easily stowable wings that allowed way more airplanes to fit in the same carrier.  With a maximum speed of 447 km/h, 1456km of total range, and a service ceiling of 22,600 feet, the mighty Avenger was one of the most iconic World War 2 bombers, permanently changing naval warfare.  Crafted with Paul Bennet’s expertise (an aerobatic pilot who happens to own one of the last airworthy Avengers), the add-on features realistic aerodynamics, high-quality sounds, high-quality 3D modeling and texturing, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.68, requiring at least 2.23 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
