<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-04-16T18:33:53.608969+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol111</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta Tracking Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ede84006d2282d11f6d3c5_social.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx recently updated Volanta with a real-time tracking feature for premium members, polling the aircraft’s position locally every second. The new update also brings several bug fixes and new enhancements. Update 1.11 is one of Volanta’s most significant updates yet, featuring real-time tracking for premium members, improved map performance, ultra-low hardware usage when minimized, 3D mode tweaks, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Volanta can be downloaded for free on their website. Certain features require a premium membership.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1222</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.2.0 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1222"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ef0ee9572b607093dd0c18_lgt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research recently released a major update to X-Plane 12, which brings massive improvements to cloud rendering, lighting, environmental effects, and graphics performance. Their graphics team has been working to mitigate the famed dark cockpit issue, bringing significantly improved interior rendering quality. The light coming into the cockpit correctly follows the aircraft's contours and structural details. Furthermore, the graphics engine's exposure handling has also been improved, bringing exposure fusion—a familiar feature on most modern smartphones—to the virtual realm of X-Plane 12. It consists of taking multiple photos at various levels of exposure and then automatically stitching them together, yielding a potentially impressive-looking result.  The sky brightness has also been tweaked to ensure it's more natural and doesn't burn people's retinas. Ground object brightness values have also been tweaked to ensure they are not overly bright. Their graphics engine as a whole has also undergone changes, with an upgrade to their shader compiler, which manages resources more efficiently and thus brings smoother performance figures. Texture handling has also been tweaked to ensure faster loading times and more efficient rendering. Their VRAM management method has also been tweaked, ensuring it prioritizes smaller memory requests before large ones, aiding total memory allocation. Additionally, it makes multiple attempts to allocate memory before giving up, allowing the system to free up space when needed and ultimately reduce the chances of blurry textures or slow performance overall. The cloud rendering system has also been changed, with a small radius surrounding the camera's viewport sporting high-quality clouds, nearly eliminating cloud pixelation effects around the airplane. They hint at it being a stepping stone to other cool rendering effects in the future. Last but not least, they have also changed how their light rendering system works by breaking them into tiles, yielding better performance in demanding environments such as large airports and cities. In addition, they have also made minor changes to colors, bringing more realistic color accuracy, improved sky rendering, better cloud shadows, cloud shadows on clouds, cloud-aware ambient light, and more realistic shadows overall. Detail has also been enhanced on surface textures around airports, and weather effects now also show outside of the airport's area, accumulating on main roads, as suggested by the community. ‍ The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Known Issues ‍ Fixes and Enhancements General ‍ Graphics ‍ ‍ Scenery ‍ The update is currently available on the public_beta branch on Steam. Laminar customers can get the update by toggling “Check for new betas as well as updates”. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350107</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350107"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f3036d228ee951d79aa105_stairs1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued a new update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is their last weekly build for the foreseeable future as they work on a longer-term—and more substantial—patch. Update v1.0.7 brings enhanced SimBrief integration (you can now plan your flight directly from the EFB), integrated air stairs for people without GSX (only available with GSX disabled for the same reason), and reintroduced engine and pitot cover logic using MSFS 2024’s SDK. The airplane’s FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator) bug was wholly mitigated, with no issues on the flare, land, and rollout modes.  The complete changelog follows below: v1.0.7 Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️ Fixed – FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator) bug: We’ve fully resolved issues related to the Flare, Land, and Rollout modes. A logic bug previously caused the Flare mode to not display correctly on the FMA, even though it was functioning in the background. This is now fixed and displayed correctly in all landing scenarios.  ‍ Fixed – Flex Temp  Output: We’ve corrected an issue where incorrect Flex Temperature values were affecting the engine power rating. The system now provides accurate thrust settings based on the entered Flex Temp.Fixed - No confirmation box when deleting pilot stored elementsFixed - SEC/Wind data bug fixedFixed - CRZ temp range on INIT page bug ranges fixed Fixed - Add door variables to autosaves Fixed - ETA box overlapping on oceanic requestFixed - Route uplink FMS message missing bug fixed Fixed - Up and down double chevrons on sec f-plan aren't working correctly fixed Fixed - PFD ALT flashing box feedbackFixed - Step alt revision menu bug Fixed - Selecting TERR off in SURV still have terrain visible on NDFixed - Manual time selection memo missing on WDFixed - SD Position/Time date format Fixed - D-ATIS unread message behaviour Fixed - Callsign not imported properlyFixed - Glideslope aural alert being triggered prematurelyFixed - D-ATIS envelope behaviour when message is readFixed - FMA logic with FD from cold and dark stateAdded - GRID heading display on ND for polar flightsFixed - CRZ TEMP format issue at INIT pageFixed - Direct to a waypoint with approach armed logic wrongFixed -  Strobe light/beacon sync timing not using correct logicAdded – FMS Store route ability added Fixed – GA soft mode bugs Fixed - ENG fire test feedback implemented Fixed - Heatblur excessive in some cases Fixed - Check "toggle autopilot" logicFixed - OIS cursor behind keyboardFixed -  Parking brake ECAM bug Fixed – TORA value changing bug fixed for TO PERF (previously not working)Fixed - Chocks not always visible when selectedFixed - Fuel panel does not open during GSX refuellingFixed - GSX Loadsheet page integration updated and improveFixed - Added new ECAMs and CategorisationFixed - Removed some excessive debugging to improve perfPartial Fix - Introducing some key adjustments for early rotation in some cases. (WIP and will be refined further).Added - GROUND page submenu will flash yellow when GSX requires user input 3D Art 🎨🖌️Added -  Engine coversFixed -  Collision mesh in FS2024 not workingFixed -  Add 3D models of pilots in cockpit from outside viewFixed - Pilot model in Drone/Showcase camera - sunk in cockpit Sounds 🔊Fixed - Hydraulic sound to sys slider / volume/positioning adjustFixed - Fixed cockpit rain event cue not workingFixed - Rain base level adjustImprovement - Improved sys and engine faders on shutdownFixed - Fixed glareshield knob rotary soundsFixed - Fire test sound adjustmentsFixed - Fixed ECP ALL pb making a double click soundFixed - Fixed engine light off sound timing when coolingAdded - Fixed MX call tone missingFixed - Fixed call button interaction too quietImprovement - Edits to cabin announcement clipsFixed - FS24 A359 Cabin announcement distancing tweak in business classFixed - Reduced audio ducking of cabin and packs ambience at higher N1Fixed - Fixed wiper sound inconsistency at fast settingFixed - Fixed wiper sound positioningFixed - Fixed wiper sound doubling on fast modeFixed  - Fixed oxy test sound would play from interacting with oxy percentage buttonFixed - Excessive wait for AP disconnect CRC and warning Improvement – Overhauled engine start soundsFixed - ENG Fire test sound feedbackFixed - Flap sounds overpower interior engine soundsFixed – Ground roll (taxi) sample repetitiveness. The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbgpl</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Global Power Lines for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbgpl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f30b0e7e45b39b5eaa9034_power1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released a realistic pack of Power Lines for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The pack replaces the generic power tower models in the simulator with highly detailed, handcrafted 3D models, aiding VFR navigation and low-level flying. The package features 19 unique tower types for realistic regional variation, with an extended draw distance for improved visibility, performance-friendly optimization (no performance impact), and the promise of ongoing updates with additional towers and refinements. Furthermore, it comes with a management tool for adjusting specific settings, such as wire omission in certain cases.  Microsoft Flight Simulator’s data set still controls their placement and orientation, as placing them manually would require over 100 GB of additional data and significantly impact the overall performance.  The add-on is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $8.38, requiring at least 103.38 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeedlw</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Dortmund Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeedlw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f4e4183593a99a5d0b7617_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has recently released its rendition of Dortmund Airport (EDLW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located only 6.2 miles east of Dortmund, this international airport serves over 3 million passengers each year. The airport began its first commercial flights in 1925, and service continued to expand until the Second World War, during which it served as a German airbase. After the war, commercial service to the airport was not reinstated until 1979. Construction of a new terminal started in 1998 and was completed in 2000. Since then, the airport has experienced rapid growth in traffic. Today, airlines such as Condor, Eurowings, Wizz Air, and many others provide a variety of year-round and seasonal destinations, resulting in over 3 million passengers traveling through the airport each year. The scenery includes various features such as terminal interiors, animated passengers, custom jetways, functional VDGS, a custom GSX profile, and much more. The newly released rendition of Dortmund Airport is now available from Aerosoft for approximately $13.75. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeeddl</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Düsseldorf Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeeddl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f79a478fc41918dd7ee9bc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has just released its latest scenery: Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. As the fourth busiest airport in Germany, it welcomes over 19 million passengers each year, thanks to more than 150,000 annual aircraft movements. The airport opened in 1927 and welcomed its first international flights two years later, in 1929. As World War II approached, the airport ceased operations for civil aviation in 1939. However, it reopened for civilian use in 1948. From 1969 to 1986, the airport underwent significant developments, including a runway extension and the addition of three new terminals, reflecting the rapid increase in air traffic. In subsequent years, the airport has continued to expand and improve, with the construction of a new parking garage, railway station, and more. Today, it serves as a base for airlines such as Condor, Corendon Airlines, Eurowings, SunExpress, and TUI fly Deutschland, among others, offering numerous destinations around the globe. The scenery features a detailed recreation of Düsseldorf Airport, including accurate airport buildings and facilities, an updated airport layout, custom terrain elevation mesh, custom aerial imagery, custom jetway models, and more. The newly released version of Düsseldorf Airport is now available from Aerosoft for approximately $18.53. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pfs600</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Releases Shark 600 for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pfs600"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f7a44f8ae921fb2be68cb1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Propair Flight has released its Shark 600 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The ultralight aircraft, produced by Shark.Aero, is now available for flight simulation enthusiasts in the virtual sky. The Shark 600 is a two-seat aircraft manufactured by Shark.Aero. As a lightweight aircraft, it is designed for efficiency, high speed, and comfort. The Shark 600 also incorporates modern technology, ensuring it meets the latest standards in aviation. The add-on includes a 3D model based on the real aircraft, detailed textures, animations, a custom Dynon SkyView HDX avionics suite, a custom flap system, and more. The new Shark 600 from Propair Flight is now available on the Propair Flight website for $5.53. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/imkdfw</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Releases Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/imkdfw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f9662923c500293d805c4a_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Imaginesim has just released its version of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. It is the third busiest airport in the world in terms of passenger traffic and aircraft movements. Last year, nearly 88 million passengers travelled through the airport. Planning for the airport began in 1927, but the plans underwent numerous revisions over the years, delaying construction until 1969. After several years of discussions, planning, and construction, the airport finally opened in 1974. At the time of its opening, it was the largest airport in the world by land area. Since then, the airport has experienced significant growth in traffic, and various expansion projects are currently underway or planned for the future. Today, the airport serves a variety of airlines, accommodating nearly 88 million passengers annually through just over 743,000 aircraft movements. The scenery package includes a variety of features, such as highly detailed terminals, high-definition texturing, custom SafeGate™ Visual Docking Guidance, and custom jetways, among many others. A version for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is also in development, and it will be available as a free upgrade for current owners. Additionally, animations for the Skylink train are in progress. The newly released Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 is now available from Imaginesim for approximately $32.64. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdoc3</id>
    <title>PMDG Unveils Operations Center 3.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdoc3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently unveiled its new Operations Center 3.0, a complete overhaul of their product management application, which has been roughly the same since 2017. The new application features a fresh design, additional diagnostic tools, in-software add-on installation, streamlined livery handling, and much more. The rollout from OC2 to OC3 will be gradual, with the 777F being the first product to transition to the new suite. People who might be interested in checking the new Operations Center are instructed to uninstall their 777F, download OC3 from here, install it, enter their PMDG credentials, and then install the 777F from there. The 777-300ER will follow shortly (within the next few days), and once it is available, the procedure is expected to be the same as the one listed above. ‍ PMDG will also provide full documentation on operating the new Operations Center, which is said to be available “in time for the weekend.” ‍ As they move their entire product line to OC3, installers will no longer be available once the rollout is complete, as they want people managing their product line straight from OC3. ‍ They also hint at making a new 777 available soon, with “more news on that on the next update.” If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsesae</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2025 Schedule and Addon Experiences Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsesae"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67faceea35be38addd774d5d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The schedule for the upcoming FlightSimExpo 2025 has been announced, along with various addon experiences that will soon be available for booking. New information about the three-day event has just been revealed. A seminar schedule has been shared, outlining what to expect on each day of the event. On Friday, attendees can look forward to a range of product reveals, announcements, and updates covering various software and hardware developments. Saturday and Sunday will feature exhibits, seminars, and workshops. The schedule for the Community Stage is available now available online, while the schedules for the FSElite Stage and the SayIntensions.AI Stage will be announced closer to the event. In addition, several different addon experiences have been announced. These activities are available alongside the main event and include options such as tours at the local airport, workshops, and more. Registration for these experiences will open on April 19th at 12 PM ET. You can find more information about the various experiences here. As we look forward to all that the FlightSimExpo 2025 has to offer, more information about the event is available on the official website.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pd2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Shares Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pd2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fad7245aa3ed1bc5dbd717_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released another development update regarding nearly all of its products for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Key highlights from the update include the announcement of a release window for the upcoming PMDG 777-200ER for both MSFS 2020 and 2024, as well as a rollout sequence for the product line tailored for MSFS 2024. The development team has announced that the 777-200ER will be released simultaneously for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, with the launch expected between April 16th and April 29th. The add-on will feature different engine types, including the GE90-92 and the Rolls Royce Trent 892. Additionally, it will include a new generation of sound packages. There will be only one package available, which will include versions for both simulators. With the release of the first PMDG product for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 approaching, the team has announced a rollout schedule for their product lineup. The expected release dates are as follows:  ‍ - The 777-200ER is anticipated between April 16th and April 29th. - The DC-6 is scheduled for early May. - The 777F and 777-300ER are expected to be released between mid and late May. - The 777-200LR will be available from late May to early June. - The 737NGs do not yet have an estimated arrival time, as their conversion to 2024 has not yet begun. The team has announced that the 747 product lines will only be developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and not for 2020. Additionally, the PMDG Operations Center 3 has been expanded to include the 777F and 777-300ER. The DC-6 and all 737NG variants will be added very soon. Once these aircraft are added to OC3, they will be removed from OC2. We will inform you if we receive any further details about upcoming updates and releases. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/scpg36</id>
    <title>SimCoders and PAE Releases Beechcraft Bonanza G36 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/scpg36"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fc10d25955f6f85c05d172_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimCoders and PAE have recently collaborated to release the Beechcraft Bonanza G36 for X-Plane 12. This general aviation aircraft, renowned for its reliability and performance, has been meticulously recreated for the simulator with study-level detail. The Beechcraft Bonanza has a rich history. Manufactured by the US company Beechcraft, the first variant, the Model 35 Bonanza, was introduced in 1947 and produced until 1982. This model featured a distinctive v-tail design. In 1960, the Model 33 Debonair/Bonanza was introduced. It featured a conventional tail and remained in production until 1995. The latest variant is the Model 36 Bonanza, which was introduced in 1968 and is still in production today. The Model 36 is an extended version of the Model 33 Debonair/Bonanza. As of 2024, a total of 18,546 Beechcraft Bonanzas have been built. This general aviation aircraft is popular worldwide and can be found in many locations across the globe. The aircraft is equipped with a variety of features, including a fully simulated IO-550 engine, a custom fuel system, a custom G1000, realistic 3D modelling, REP features, and much more. The newly released aircraft is now available for purchase at the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $45.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftat17</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Athens International Airport to Version 1.7</title>
    <updated>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftat17"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fd40640c76383ff4a99a23_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyTampa has recently updated its Athens International Airport (LGAV) to version 1.7. This new version includes a range of fixes, improvements, and additional features. The most notable update is the compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, in addition to maintaining compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The scenery has undergone various enhancements as part of these updates. Some new features included in the update are improved terraforming, an extended solar farm, a newly added general aviation ramp, enhanced compatibility with MSFS 2024, and much more. See the full changelog below: ‍ Version 1.7: The updated version of Athens International Airport is now available, and can be purchased from FlyTampa for $17.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdd22</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Denver International Airport for X-Plane 12 to Version V2.2</title>
    <updated>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdd22"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fd635b4d099c2c8d076380_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Scenery Developer X-Codr Designs has recently updated its Denver International Airport (KDEN) scenery for X-Plane 12, bringing it to version V2.2. This update includes performance improvements that enhance efficiency by an average of 37%. Additionally, the update introduces various enhancements, new features, and fixes to improve the overall experience. Among the added features, we find higher resolution pavement, an updated gate layout, improvements to terminal exterior models, new details in terminal interiors, and much more. See the full changelog below: ‍ Version V2.2: The newly updated rendition of Denver International Airport is now available from the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $29.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lvabmt</id>
    <title>Lata Voadora Releases Campo de Marte Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lvabmt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fedd7dd8e78778841c5559_THRESHOLD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Lata Voadora has recently released their rendition of Campo de Marte Airport (SBMT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the first airport ever to open in Sao Paulo, Brazil.  It was founded in 1929 (95 years ago), and its first few years were far from glorious: it was bombarded during the Constitutionalist Revolution of 1932. That did not stop it from having its commercial debut a year later, with scheduled flights to Sao Carlos and Sao Jose do Rio Preto, Ribeirao Preto, and Uberaba. It was Sao Paulo's main airport until the opening of Congonhas Airport in 1936, which was bigger and less flood-prone (Campo de Marte had been flooded in 1929).  Nowadays, it mainly handles helicopters and general aviation and still hosts a nearly hundred-year-old flying club.  The traffic figures are around 60,000 aircraft operations per year, a massive drop from a decade ago when they reached almost twice that amount. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a high-detail model of the passenger terminal and its interior, custom landclass buildings, custom hangars, and much more. It's available on their website for roughly $7. Due to popular demand, an MSFS 2020-compatible version is in the works and set to be released by the end of the month. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fss72p</id>
    <title>Release Date Announced for FlightSim Studio Boeing 727 Passenger Version</title>
    <updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fss72p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ffc467cbce30a170ff83b6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightSim Studio recently made an announcement on its Discord channel, providing a quick update on the forthcoming passenger version of their Boeing 727 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The developer revealed details regarding the release date, pricing, and more. The highly anticipated passenger version of the 727 is set to be released on April 17th, between 10:00 and 14:00 UTC. The aircraft will first be available at Aerosoft, followed by Contrail shortly after. Other stores will have it available in the next 1 to 2 weeks, and the in-Sim Marketplace is planned to launch in about 2 to 3 months. The price for the passenger version will be the same as the freighter version, set at approximately $45.45. The passenger version will be offered as a standalone add-on and does not require the freighter version. Customers who own the freighter version will receive a 20% crossgrade discount. For those inquiring about compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the team is actively addressing an issue where the APU fails to start. Once this problem is resolved, a free update will be released to ensure compatibility with the latest simulator. With the official release set for tomorrow, various streamers have already gained access to the aircraft, showcasing it for those interested in a sneak peek. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
