<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-15T18:22:10.031608+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kausmfs</id>
    <title>Dominic DesignTeam Releases Austin–Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kausmfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638ef23655f464fbf8202b53_Screenshot%202022-12-06%20at%201.41.38%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4150568"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Dominic DesignTeam released their rendition of Austin–Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The product will bring the Texas airport to life with high quality models, customized objects such as signs and passengers, and detailed textures. 	According to the developers, the scenery will feature PBR textures, dynamic lighting, and custom jetways. Additionally, for added realism, all pavements have been “painstakingly hand-crafted” and ground markings have been modeled based on the real life airport. 	Austin–Bergstrom International Airport, located 5 miles from Austin downtown, is one of the main international airports serving the city. It provides flights to some 75 destinations around the world. Top operators at the airport include Southwest, Delta, and American Airlines. Currently, Dominic DesignTeam’s Austin Airport can be purchased on simMarket for $18.99 USD or EUR 20.10, excluding any sales taxes that may incur. The developers recommend at least 870M of free space in order to successfully install the product.</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksrvn</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Rovaniemi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksrvn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638f7b34fdc31d1a20d021ba_efro1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1117127"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released an update to their rendition of Rovaniemi Airport (EFRO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Finland with 500,000 passengers per year. It’s visited by many airlines during the winter season, which includes Aer Lingus, Air France, easyJet, Eurowings, Ryanair, Transavia, and Turkish Airlines.   Built in 1940, featuring two grass runways, and used as a Luftwaffe air base and supply center during the Second Soviet-Finnish War between 1941 and 1944. Rebuilding work started in 1948, with regular traffic returning in the beginning of the second half of that year.   The current terminal building finished in 1992, with its first expansion happening in 2000 (and the inclusion of jetways). The runway underwent renovation work in 2016, with new pavement and LED lights, and 2019 marked the completion of the terminal’s third enlargement.  The scenery update added conditional visibility to the winter objects, smoke effects for cold weather, glass improvements, and general fixes. The complete feature list for the scenery follows down below: It’s available on Orbx Direct for $6.69 (on sale, 50% off), requiring at least 1.23 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbmyl</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces McCall Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbmyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638fa581410b823612bbcd65_call1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="455971"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator by an independent developer (Mark Taylor). It’s a city-owned public-use airport in McCall, Idaho, categorized in the FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems as a general aviation facility.   With 80 hectares of total area and a 1,862m long runway, McCall averages around 119 flights per day, and over 43,000 a year, with 84% of them being General Aviation flights, 16% air taxi and the remainder comprehending military traffic.   The scenery features realistic ground and apron texturing (including the recent apron resurfacing), true-to-life night lighting, PBR textures, extensive LOD work focusing on optimal performance, custom static aircraft, airport specific windsocks, 160+ custom objects, many custom animations, and hand placed vegetation.  Orbx plans to ensure that owners of the first version, previously released by Mark Taylor on another reseller, will be redeemable on Orbx Direct via license key.   The scenery landing page is available here, although it’s not available for purchase yet.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbosl</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Oslo Gardermoen for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbosl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638fc11ecaf33e597c68abe5_osl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1758242"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Norway, nearing 30 million passengers per year with almost 200 destinations. It’s home to Flyr, Norse Atlantic Airways, and Wideroe.   The airport’s history dates back to 1740 when the Norwegian army used Gardermoen (then Fredericksfeldt) as a camp. It remained as such until 1860, when barracks and stalls were constructed to house more people and protect against the harsh weather. Insulated buildings were the next logical upgrade, in the early 1900s. It became an airport in 1912 when the first of many flights took off.   Gardermoen was taken over by the nazis during the German occupation in 1940, building the first aircraft facilities and two runways with 2,000 meters each. The Norwegian Air Force took it back as soon as WW2 ended, housing three fighter squadrons. In 1946, Braathens SAFE used the facilities as their technical base, which only lasted for two years. It was also during that period when Oslo Gardermoen became the reserve airport for Fornebu, which used to be the main airport. All the intercontinental flights were redirected to OSL because Fornebu was undergoing runway extension work. It wasn’t until 1998 that Gardermoen became the main airport in Oslo.  The scenery will feature custom orthoimagery, PBR textures in 4K, interior modeling, 3 different types of animated jetways to match the real world, fully functioning VDGS on all appropriate gates, custom ground service equipment, and optimization work to warrant good performance.  It is allegedly coming in January 2023, priced at roughly $21.00. There’s no information on the install size yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mexfaa</id>
    <title>Mex High Flight Releases Tahiti International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mexfaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63913bc4204b611dbe188f28_tahiti1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2324223"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mex High Flight has recently released their rendition of Faa’a International Airport (NTAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, connecting Tahiti to the World. Also known as Tahiti International Airport, it’s home to Air Tahiti and Air Tahiti Nui, with domestic flights to other islands in French Polynesia and intercontinental legs to Canada, Chile, France, Japan, New Zealand, and the United States.  Aside from the local airlines,  it’s also visited by Air France (Los Angeles and Paris), Air New Zealand (Auckland), Delta Air Lines (beginning in late December 2022, from Los Angeles), French Bee (Paris Orly and San Francisco), Hawaiian Airlines (Honolulu), and United Airlines (San Francisco). The yearly figures sit around 1.6 million passengers total. With a single, 3,420 meters long runway, Tahiti International can accommodate large aircraft such as the Boeing 747 and the Airbus A380.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR texturing, realistic night lighting, hand-placed objects, realistic AFCAD, friendly framerate, and GSX compatibility.  It’s available on SimMarket for $18.40, requiring at least 513MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ecugal</id>
    <title>Ecuavirtual3d Releases San Cristóbal City &amp; Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ecugal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6392389be3fb77845d05b634_galap2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2256824"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Ecuavirtual3d has just released their rendition of San Cristóbal de Galápagos and its airport, San Cristóbal Airport (SEST), for Microsoft Flight Simulator, both in the archipelago of the Galápagos Islands in Ecuador. The airport is served by Avianca Ecuador, Equair, and LATAM Ecuador, with flights to Guayaquil and Quito. The yearly figures sit at around 200,000 passengers.   With a single 1,900m long runway, the approach to both ends happens to be over the ocean, sitting just at the coast of San Cristóbal.   The scenery features a faithful replica of the airport, with accurate modeling based on original references, fully customized ground textures, custom taxiway signs, custom traffic on the avenues, a control tower with an interior, taxi routes for airplanes, and static objects, vehicles, and aircraft.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.90, requiring at least 93 MB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsgemb</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Uploads New Embraer 175 Teaser Video for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsgemb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63938aabe43a3a0bf9a3da58_1756.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1126836"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG, in partnership with AviationLads, has teased their Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator again, focusing on the interior. In 44 seconds, there’s a glimpse of the cockpit (including a cold &amp; dark power up) and the passenger cabin, with attention to interior lighting.   It is the second teaser so far, with the first one airing last friday and showcasing the external modeling, engine sounds, and different liveries from some of the 12 real-world operators.   According to a Facebook post by AviationLads, the next teaser will be “more technical” with a systems showcase, due next week.  The E175 is part of the Embraer E-Jets family, seating 78 to 88 passengers in different cabin configurations, with a range of 1800 nautical miles on the standard variant. There are 12 operators around the World, with SkyWest being the largest (193 aircraft).   There’s no information regarding pricing or release date yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpnbr</id>
    <title>RDPresets Announces Bergen Flesland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpnbr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/639390e458c4aa2d4c611a84_bergen1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="743439"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced their rendition of Bergen Flesland Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6.5 million passengers. It’s owned and operated by Avinor (state owned company).   It’s a focus city for Bergen Air Transport, Bristow Norway, CHC Helikopter Service, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe, making for a huge domestic and international network. CHC and Bristow feature an unusual type of passenger traffic, transporting people to offshore oil platforms in the North Sea. It’s visited by many other airlines such as Air France, airBaltic, Finnair, Flyr, Icelandair, KLM, Lufthansa, and WizzAir, along with seasonal carriers.  The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with a modeled interior, custom ground textures, and detailed landside buildings.   It should be available tomorrow on the RDPresets Store. There’s no information on requirements yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxmyl</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases McCall Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxmyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6393997608813abdd302ff66_kmyl1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2065484"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, by their newest independent developer Mark “Milo” Taylor, which already made a rendition of MYL under MSX Creations. This new rendition is an overhaul of the previous work, with custom library objects, scenery placement and re-texturing.   It is a city-owned public-use airport in McCall (Idaho), categorized by the FAA as a general aviation facility. It had 43,600 aircraft operations between August 2009 and August 2010, averaging 119 flights per day, 84% of which comprehended general aviation traffic, and 16% were air taxi, with the remaining 1% being military traffic.    With a 1862m long runway, McCall Mun. Airport can accommodate most private jets and medium-range airliners.   The scenery features true-to-life ground and apron texturing (including the recent apron resurfacing), realistic night lighting, PBR texturing, level of detail work to warrant good performance, multiple custom static aircraft, airport specific windsocks, over 160 custom objects, multiple custom animations, and hand-placed vegetation.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $19.06, requiring at least 3.64 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdscae</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Teases São Paulo Catarina Executive for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdscae" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394c9ab55496a9252a993a0_catarinacover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1999138"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently teased their rendition of São Paulo Catarina Executive International (SBJH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the Metropolitan Area of São Paulo, Brazil. It’s the first private executive airport with International status in the country, built on 5.2 million square meters of land and situated near the main business centers of the state.  The airport development project aims to bring together characteristics from the best general aviation airports in the World, such as Teterboro and Paris Le Bourget, with help from companies such as Airport Consulting Vienna (ACV) and Ramboll, a Danish consulting engineering group. Built to accommodate up to 200,000 take-offs and landings per year, including long range jets, thanks to its 2500 meter long runway. It's the only executive airport in Brazil with authorization to operate flights to New York, London, and Paris. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR models, a "98% accurate" terrain mesh, fully updated satellite imagery, custom objects, and models built based on projects sent by the airport administrator. There’s no information on install size or release date yet, but said to be coming soon (awaiting Marketplace approval).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfluns</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases UNS-1 Custom FMS for the 146 Professional</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfluns" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394db9693646f7f44a95546_ansett%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1453796"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a developer update covering their progress on the UNS-1 Custom FMS for their 146 Professional, an old style FMS released in 1982 and widely used until the early 2000s, providing GPS navigation with LNAV output to the autopilot and horizontal situation indicator. Users can toggle between the modern FMS, the UNS-1, or no FMS in the Electronic Flight Bag Configuration Menu, without reloading the aircraft.   The new UNS-1 will be capable of loading and saving MSFS flight plans, along with full SID/STAR support with transitions and approaches. It also includes advanced features such as real-time fuel monitoring, as long as the user inputs the necessary information (passenger count, cargo, fuel quantity, etc.).   Like the real unit, it features VNAV, but it doesn’t communicate with the autopilot, making it the user has to manually manage the climbs and descents with IAS and VS, although the built-in VNAV will be able to calculate the top of descent and target vertical speed.  The developer claims it is still under extensive testing, with guidance videos to come once it’s closer to release. Cover picture is courtesy of DragonRuins. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpbea</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Bergen Flesland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpbea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6394e7f5f994d3f539c94e08_enbr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2371006"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has just released their rendition of Bergen Flesland Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. It is an important Scandinavian destination, served by many airlines such as Scandinavian Airlines, Norwegian Air Shuttle, and Widerøe, with a significant intra-european route network.   The origin of the airport dates back to the early 1950s, when a national military communications project secured the construction of a 1460 meter long runway, and 4 million norwegian krone were provided by the municipalities of Bergen and Fana to build a terminal and a road. Additional NATO grants in 1953 warranted a longer runway (2440 meters) and better infrastructure. A DHC-3 Otter was the first aircraft to land on Bergen Flesland, on 18 June 1954, when only 800 meters of the runway were complete. The first revenue chartered flight was a leg to Oslo, transporting SK Brann to play a football match.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models, PBR texturing, 3D interior, more than a thousand clutter objects on the apron, realistic and functioning VDGS, custom ground textures, performance optimization, accurate night lighting, custom taxi signage, and ground traffic.  It’s available on the RDPresets Store for roughly $21.07 or on SimMarket for $19.00, requiring at least 1 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dwdewr</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Teases Newark Liberty International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dwdewr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63963e2f2c7c446aca562cac_kewr6.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3572706"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently made an Instagram post showcasing the development progress on their rendition of Newark Liberty International Airport (KEWR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in the New York airport system, only behind JFK, with an average of 33 million passengers a year as of 2021.  It’s a United Airlines hub, with 66.5% of the yearly figures. JetBlue (7.6%), Spirit Airlines (5.5%), American Airlines (5.5%), and Delta Airlines (3.8%) take the rest of the share. It’s also a cargo hub for FedEx Express.   The developer claims it’s already on Beta 5 and potentially becoming the first release candidate, allowing them to prepare the installer, make promotional media, and get the marketplace stuff ready. It’s claimed to be “incomparably more detailed” than the previous KEWR for P3D.  There is no information regarding features, installation size, pricing, or release date. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/snocph</id>
    <title>SimNord Previews Copenhagen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/snocph" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6397ebd629334ae31cc57c3e_ekch1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1624727"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimNord has recently previewed their progress on Copenhagen Airport (EKCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second largest airport in the Nordic countries, serving Denmark and Southern Sweden with over 30 million passengers yearly. It’s the main hub for Scandinavian Airlines, and an operating base for Sunclass Airlines and Norwegian Air Shuttle.   Aside from the local airlines, it’s visited by over 50 airlines from around the World such as Aegean, Air Canada, Air China, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, Finnair, Qatar Airways, Turkish Airlines, etc. Oslo, Amsterdam, and Stockholm are the busiest European routes as of 2021, with roughly 400,000 passengers each. Dubai (105,000), Doha (104,794), and Newark (66,034) top the charts of busiest intercontinental routes.  There is no information regarding features, pricing, or release date. Threshold will keep you updated on the matter once there’s new information. Shout out to PopFizzels for the news scoop. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrgla</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Updates Glasgow Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrgla" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6397fb1b4add32cae71a9eb2_egpf1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="193892"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently updated their rendition of Glasgow International Airport (EGPF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the ninth-busiest airport in the United Kingdom with nearly 10 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic). It is owned and operated by AGS Airports, which also own Aberdeen and Southampton.   It’s a hub for EasyJet, Loganair, Jet2.com, and TUI Airways, with many domestic and intra-European routes. British Airways features three domestic routes to London City, London Heathrow, and London Gatwick. As far as transcontinental flights go, it’s visited by Air Transat with a leg to Toronto, and Emirates to Dubai. The busiest routes as of 2019 are London Heathrow (865,008), London Gatwick (641,566), and Dublin (500,441), operated by British Airways and Aer Lingus.  The scenery update features a new terminal glass, minor fixes to terminal geometry, static aircraft v2, major taxiway lighting improvements, minor changes to ATC Tower interior, GSX integration (with dynamic doors), added vehicle paths for ground service equipment, ground polygon adjustments, airline specific parking codes, static people replaced with animated ones, trees on the approach to runway 23 were removed, and other minor fixes and improvements.  Update 1.1.7 is now available on Orbx Direct, for roughly $20.26 (update is free for current owners). Other storefronts will follow shortly, according to the developer. At least 2.65 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. The new GSX Profile is available on FlightSim.to, free of charge. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflfst</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews FS Traffic for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflfst" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63992d42091a99ed93aa6418_fstraffic1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1981461"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently uploaded a video previewing the Regional AI Aircraft for their upcoming FS Traffic add-on. The regional set includes 12 different airplanes (A220-100, A220-200, ATR-42, ATR-72, CRJ-700, CRJ-900, CRJ-1000, Dash 8-Q400, ERJ-145, E-170, E-190, and E-195) with multiple livery combinations from around the World. The video showcases some of the new planes, the AI traffic interaction with ground service equipment, and the newly added animations and effects.  ‍  FS Traffic promises to add tens of thousands of real-life commercial flights from different periods, with worldwide coverage from a popular data source. The data covers the summer of 2022, with 2021 and 2019 to come later through a free update. The traffic will be controlled by the date and time of the day, with different densities. It also offers model-matching compatibility with platforms such as VATSIM.  On the latest developer update, they claim all the core features are fully functional, with all the liveries, including additional paint jobs based on feedback from the public. Their testing team is undergoing expansion to maximize efficiency and ensure compatibility with other products.   There is no information on pricing and release date yet, but they claim to be aiming for an early 2023 release. Shout out to genista for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
