<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-05-14T18:19:55.339748+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnancy</id>
    <title>France VFR Releases Metz-Nancy-Lorraine Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnancy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6456b0500ecf7b713408630a_nan1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="264175"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. France VFR has recently released their rendition of Metz-Nancy-Lorraine (LFJL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Lorraine region of France with a yearly average of 250,000 passengers. The airport opened in October 1991, replacing Nancy-Essey and Metz-Frescaty, sporting modern infrastructure and supporting the region’s economic growth and development. In 2006, the airport underwent upgrades, with the runway being lengthened to 3,050 meters, along with refurbishing work on the terminal, built in the 90s. It’s 7500 square meters large, with 14 check-in desks, two gates, and two luggage claim belts.  It’s served by Air Algerie (Algiers, Constantine, Oran), TUI fly Belgium (seasonally), and Twin Jet (Marseille, Toulouse).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, photo-realistic 3D buildings, realistic night lighting, multiple charts provided, and custom vegetation. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.09, requiring at least 280.75 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mx6bos</id>
    <title>MisterX6 Updates Boston Logan International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mx6bos" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6459ce0b4e1a000ede9da7b1_bosx1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1376413"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. MisterX6 has recently updated their rendition of General Edward Lawrence Logan International Airport (KBOS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the busiest airport in the Northeastern United States outside the New York Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 42 million passengers as of 2019.  Opened almost a hundred years ago in September 1923, it was mainly used by the Air National Guard of Massachusetts and the United States Army Air Corps. Scheduled passenger service started in 1927 with Colonial Air Transport, flying people between Boston and New York City.  The airport had its first expansion during the 1940s and 1950s when the rise in demand for air travel forced the operator to increase its area size through landfills in Boston Harbor. In that same decade, the terminals were expanded, with Terminals B and C being constructed in 1949, still in use in 2023.   Shortly after WW2, Boston became a transatlantic gateway. American Overseas Airlines offered a weekly Boston-Shannon-London service in the late 40s, Pan Am’s direct flight to Shannon and Santa Maria Island in the Azores, then to London and Lisbon. In the early 50s, BOAC started nonstop operations from Glasgow, and Air France made a multi-stop link from Paris-Orly to Boston. By 1957, there were 49 weekday departures on average.  In the 70s, with the advent of jet aircraft, the routes multiplied: Pan Am started a daily service to London Heathrow with the legendary 747-400, and the daily traffic average skyrocketed. Such a boom forced the airport to grow even further, with the newly built Terminal E (1974) becoming the second-largest international arrivals facility in the United States.   Nowadays, Boston Logan International Airport has four terminals with 102 gate positions in total and six runways.   It’s a hub for Cape Air and Delta Air Lines, the latter holding 19% of the market share, with JetBlue taking the lead at 30.08%, and American Airlines is third with 18.54%, followed by United (10.42%) and Southwest (4.65%). Washington, DC, is the busiest national destination with 769,000 passengers, followed by Chicago-O’Hare (717,000) and Orlando (678,000). The international top three comprises London Heathrow (664,886), Dublin (346,232), and Paris Charles de Gaulle (326,184).   The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with animated airport vehicles and ship traffic, animated marshallers and jetways, custom ground textures for taxiways and runways, photoscenery for the airport and surrounding area, lots of Boston landmarks, and now compatible with X-Plane 12.  It’s free on X-Plane.org, requiring at least 495 MB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to agonyair for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jarcop</id>
    <title>JarDesign Teases CoPilot Addon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jarcop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a8e87642f0702c8abdedc_linda1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2315905"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. J. A. Romanov, JARDesign's owner/developer, has recently published a short video on his YouTube channel teasing his upcoming CoPilot Addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which aims to add a realistic First Officer model in the cabin that can execute multiple tasks. According to the developer, it consists of an animated copilot object and a WASM module, combining speech simulation, speech recognition, a systems engine based on visual avionics, and more.  The video demonstrates the copilot's behavior on multiple aircraft, executing different cabin flows, chatting with the developer, and following checklists. Due to its config file dependent nature, it should theoretically work with any aircraft as long as someone sets it up properly. They claim to be still working on it, with no information regarding pricing or availability yet.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lamx12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Publishes Short Term Roadmap for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lamx12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a93759cd41b66f42251dd_xp1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="1906242"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently published a new short-term roadmap for X-Plane 12, delineating the next steps for versions 12.05 and 12.06.   With every 12.0X release, they aim to stabilize the product, complete or tune planned features, and improve performance. Since the early access release in late 2022, they have been working on maximizing X-Plane 12’s potential and overall experience with many bug fixes, improved AMD card performance, NOAA weather processing, and more.  For version 12.05, which is currently in Release Candidate, they plan to improve the A330 flight experience with a fully custom MCDU, autopilot, and flight systems. Based on real pilot feedback, the simulator’s flight model was also improved, better matching the real world.   In the near future, 12.06 will deliver the result of three months worth of rendering engine improvements, according to their claim, with new cirrus clouds, lower VRAM use, improved cloud rendering in general, and OpenXR integration for VR folks.  It will also bring several ATC/AI improvements, with AI aircraft behaving more realistically, better conveying the experience of flying close to other aircraft.   Even further ahead, they have already made plans for 12.07, which should focus on improving lighting, water mixed render targets, networking fixes, atmospheric scattering, turbine engine improvements, and more.  There’s no release date for the updates yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbw380</id>
    <title>FlyByWire Simulations Teases A380X’s Wing Flex </title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbw380" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a9a77a5d90f86407e360f_wing1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1193830"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyByWire Simulations recently published a YouTube video showcasing the wing flex physics of their upcoming Airbus A380 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With each wing weighing around 50 tons and up to 150 tons when loaded with fuel, it’s far from the average wing out there, meaning the developers had to develop an entirely new wing flex system from scratch, correctly simulating the bending of the wing along its entire length, with varying resonance. They also state how each fuel tank has its mass and position in the wing, affecting the physics and increasing the complexity of such simulation. The work is still in progress, and the developers aim to bring a result as close to the real thing as possible. The A380 is a double-deck, widebody commercial airliner produced by Airbus. It’s the largest passenger airliner in the world, with a seating capacity of up to 853 passengers in a single-class configuration or 544 passengers with a typical three-class layout. It was designed to address the increasing demand for air travel while providing a fuel-efficient and eco-friendly option for long-haul journeys powered by four engines (either a Rolls-Royce Trent 900 or the General Electric GP7200), with a range of up to 8000 nm. Despite its impressive features, the A380 faced several challenges in the commercial market. Its high price tag, maintenance costs, and the increasing popularity of smaller, more fuel-efficient aircraft led to lower demand for the A380. In February 2019, Airbus announced that it would stop producing the A380 after delivering its final orders in 2021. There’s no information regarding a potential release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asoat4</id>
    <title>Asobo Studio Updates ATR 42-600/72-600 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asoat4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645aa804ff8b15fa42c6acc2_genista1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3363772"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo Studio has recently released an update to their Expert Series I: ATR 42-600/72-600 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing multiple fixes and improvements. Update 1.0.8 is the first update for the ATR lineup, smoothing VNAV flight path calculation, fixing multiple CTDs, EWD Alerts Overflow behavior improvements, slight flight model tweaks, and much more. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ The ATR 42-600 is a twin-engine, high-wing turboprop seating up to fifty passengers, introduced in late 2012. It’s an updated ATR 42, the initial combined effort between Airbus and Leonardo in the 1980s. The “42” came from the original seat count.  The ATR 72-600 is a relatively stretched version of the ATR 42-600 with a seating configuration ranging from 70 to 78 seats, with a range of 850 miles, and cruising at 320 miles per hour. The ATR Bundle is available on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $19.99, with a 30% discount for deluxe/premium deluxe owners. Images are courtesy of adam and genista. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbsth</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases St Helens Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbsth" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645aad6209fbf947772f465a_sth1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3233889"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of St Helens Airport (YSTH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a small regional airport serving the town of St Helens on the northeast coast of Tasmania, Australia.   In 1933, a local pilot named Bill Knight began using a small airstrip in St Helens for his flying activities. This airstrip was located on private land and was only suitable for small aircraft. However, it became popular with local pilots, who began using it for recreational flying.  Nowadays, it’s primarily used for transporting fresh seafood - one of St Helens’ economic fortes - to the Australian mainland. Scenic flights also take place in St Helens occasionally, showcasing the wonders of the Tasmanian east coast to everyone interested.  The scenery is developed by Ken Hall, featuring photorealistic textures, custom vegetation, and custom edge lights.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $5.41, requiring at least 744.70 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrejet</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrejet" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645c091641f287c65c43e439_E-JETS_FAMILY_BY_X-CRAFTS_E175_006.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="128662"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts have released their updated E-Jets Family for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. This release follows their older E-Jets and ERJ products. This new version of the E-Jets family covers the E170, E175, E190, and E195 models. The aircraft is a complete rebuild of its original E-Jets family featuring a new authentic FMS and all-new systems.  The E-Jets family is a collection of regional jets from the Brazilian aircraft manufacturer Embraer. The E170/175 has become wildly popular on short routes in the 70-seat American regional market. The E170/175 Features a range of around 2100 NM while the larger E190/195 jet features a range of 2300 NM. The larger E190/195 has become popular with many larger airlines to serve routes with medium demand.  The X-Crafts E-Jets family has a large feature list including an authentic FMS, systems that closely simulate the real aircraft, a custom EFB, and custom FMOD sounds. The aircraft comes compatible with both X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12 and utilizes SkunkCrafts Auto Updater. Other features include: Systems &amp; Autopilot Avionics Flight Model FMS Electronic Flight Bag ‍ The aircraft is available from the X-Plane Store with many options to choose from, users can purchase each model individually or as a complete package with all four models. Customers of the X-Crafts E-Jets 2.5 are eligible for a 15% discount on the full family package only. As always stay tuned to Threshold for more news. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/100btu</id>
    <title>OneHundred Simulations Releases Tucuruí Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/100btu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645d4c0da28b72251e7164bf_sbtu1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="883648"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. OneHundred Simulations has recently released their rendition of Tucuruí Regional Airport (SBTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Tucuruí in Pará, Brazil.  Recently renovated, the airport got the green light to operate commercial flights in 2021 after a decade of inactivity. It was closed in 2015 because its infrastructure was deemed improper for any commercial operations, creating a significant hassle for the locals who depended heavily on the airport.   A hydroelectric plant nearby (Usina Hidroelétrica de Tucuruí) also weighed a lot on the decision to reactivate the airport, given they would have no way to get aerial rescue without an operating landing strip. On top of that, when the city’s hospital had to transfer patients to a bigger city, they had to drive for over 8 hours. It was judicially reopened in November 2021.  The airport is relatively modest, with a 2,000-meter runway and a single passenger terminal, albeit with all the required bits for commercial operation.  It’s served by Azul Conecta, with daily C208 flights to Val de Cans International Airport (SBBE).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Tucuruí Regional, with custom 3D objects, high-detailed textures, realistic ground layout, PBR texturing, and custom ground textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.75, requiring at least 45.79 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spcapa</id>
    <title>SDProjectsCO Releases Apartadó Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spcapa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645d538e87d941955234366e_apa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="757137"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SDProjectsCO has recently released their rendition of Antonio Roldán Betancur Airport (SKLC), serving the town of Apartadó in Antioquia, Colombia, with a yearly average of 210,000 passengers.  The airport was named after Antonio Roldán Betancur, a Colombian politician who served as Governor of Antioquia in the late 1980s. The airport was built in the late 1960s to early 1970s, primarily to serve the needs of the local population and to facilitate the transportation of goods and people in and out of the region.  The airport had a single dirt runway and elementary facilities in the early years. Over time, the runway was paved, and a small terminal building was constructed. However, the airport remained relatively small and basic, serving mainly as a regional airport with limited flights to other cities in Colombia.  In recent years, the airport has seen some improvements and expansions. In 2014, the runway was extended to accommodate larger aircraft and the terminal building was renovated and expanded to improve passenger comfort and service. The airport now has a modern terminal building with check-in counters, waiting areas, and other amenities.  EasyFly serves it with a route to Medellín - Olaya Herrera, and SATENA with two routes: Bogotá and Medellín - Olaya Herrera.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail 3D model of the main terminal, PBR texturing, custom night lighting, custom ground textures, a true-to-life airport layout, and custom ground clutter.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.95, requiring at least 123.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aau2be</id>
    <title>Working Title Releases Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 2 Beta for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aau2be" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645de8a72d16b421bb8457b4_scot1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3587664"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Working Title has recently released the first beta patch of the Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing issues with the Garmins (G3000, G5000, GNS430W, and GNS530W), bringing a complete overhaul of the avionics on the Boeing 787-10 and 747-8i, and more.   The highlight of the update is the overhaul on the default Boeings, bringing accurate fonts, look, functionality, and feel, with advanced flight plan support, integrated checklists on the MFD, performance-based VNAV with idle descent capabilities, RNP/ANP indications, functional GPS and IRS navigation systems, fully featured autopilot with autoland, flare, and rollout modes, a fully featured autothrottle system with correct AT modes, and much more.  The 787-10 also gets a revised soundscape, a HUD overhaul with nearly all real-world symbology, and a brand new fly-by-wire system accurately replicating the real-life counterpart.   They have also made sure to list some limitations, including the lack of an EFB on the 787 for performance calculations, the pedestal CDU on the 747 mirrors the left CDU for performance reasons, and issues with the electrical and fuel system on the 747. The complete list of known issues accompanies the changelog below:  Garmin G3000 / G5000 Garmin GNS430W / GNS530W ‍ WT21 ‍ ‍ Boeing 787-10 / Boeing 747-8i ‍ Cessna Citation Longitude ‍ Daher TBM 930 ‍ If you want to learn how to install the beta branch, please refer to the official guide here. Images are courtesy of SCOTSGOD. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vustuc</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Tucumán International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vustuc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645e8c6a055cc2edf6551b15_tucu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1691680"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Teniente General Benjamín Matienzo International Airport (SANT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of San Miguel de Tucumán in Argentina, with a yearly average of 500,000 passengers.  Built in the early 1980s and inaugurated in 1986, replacing the older Tucumán airport, which sat right in the center of the city, with no room to expand in length (and it only had a 1,600-meter runway), and with noise abatement restrictions creeping in, they had no choice but to close it.  The new airport features four departure gates, two arrival gates, immigration services, and the second-largest cargo terminal in Argentina.   It’s named after General Benjamín Matienzo, who died trying to fly over the Andes to Chile.  In September 2017, the single runway was extended from 2,900 meters to 3,500 meters, making it the second-longest runway in the country.   It’s served by Aerolineas Argentinas (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Córdoba (AR), Puerto Iguazú, Salta, San Carlos de Bariloche, São Paulo–Guarulhos), Andes Líneas Aéreas (Cayo Largo del Sur), FlyBondi (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque), and JetSmart Argentina (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Buenos Aires–Ezeiza).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality model of the main terminal and its interior, a fully modeled control tower, custom ground textures, a true-to-life ground layout, and correct parking positions in the commercial apron.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.92, requiring at least 194.35 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siachi</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Chiang Mai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siachi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645ea14a96754f91728d2e64_vtcc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="612925"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Chiang Mai International Airport (VTCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Thailand with a yearly average of 11 million passengers.  In the early days, the airport was a small airfield used primarily by the Royal Thai Air Force. In the 1950s, the Thai government recognized the need for a larger airport to serve the growing city of Chiang Mai and decided to expand the airfield. In 1954, the airport officially opened to commercial traffic, with Thai Airways operating the first scheduled flight to Bangkok.  Over the next few decades, Chiang Mai International Airport underwent several expansions and renovations to accommodate the increasing number of passengers and airlines. In 1995, a new international terminal was built, which increased the airport's capacity to handle more international flights.  The most recent expansion dates back to 2014, when Airports of Thailand (the operator) expanded the apron for larger aircraft, enlarged the terminal (international arrival hall and domestic departure hall) and made it a 24/7 airport.  It's a focus city for Bangkok Airways (Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Koh Samui, Krabi, Phuket), Nok Air (Bangkok–Don Mueang, Ubon Ratchathani, Udon Thani), Thai AirAsia (Bangkok–Don Mueang, Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Beijing–Daxing, Changsha, Da Nang, Hangzhou, Hanoi, Hat Yai, Hua Hin, Hong Kong, Khon Kaen, Krabi, Macau (resumes 1 July 2023), Phuket, Singapore, Surat Thani, Taipei–Taoyuan), and Thai Smile (Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi). The visitors' list includes Air China, China Airlines, EVA Air, Jeju Air, Korean Air, Spring Airlines, and VietJet Air.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3d models for the terminal, control tower, tango squadron museum, cargo terminal, new parking building, and more. The jetways are customized, with normal and glass variants, and it sports custom ground markings, VDGS, custom night lighting, and hand-placed ground objects. The developers also listed some upcoming features that will come free of charge with an update:   It's available on SimMarket for roughly $15.29, requiring at least 173.15 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsshou</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Houston Hobby International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsshou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645ea7e826186b7c73c64eaa_hou1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="193984"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently released their rendition of William P. Hobby Airport (KHOU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Greater Houston with a yearly average of 13 million passengers.  Opened in 1927 as a private landing field in a pasture, it quickly became a full-blown airport. It got its first bits of commercial traffic in the early 30s by the wings of Braniff International Airways and Eastern Air Lines. Seven years later, it was purchased by the city of Houston and named Houston Municipal Airport (it was initially called W. T. Carter Field). A year later, in 1938, it was renamed Howard R. Hughes, responsible for several airport improvements. The name was quickly changed because the regulations didn’t allow federal improvement funds for an airport named after a living person.   With the advent of Houston Intercontinental Airport in 1969, most airlines went to the new airport, leaving HOU with no scheduled traffic. It wasn’t until the 70s, with Houston Metro Airlines, a small commuter airline, that the airport saw the resumption of passenger services. It was a cross-town service from the airport to IAH.   Southwest embraced HOU in 1971, flying nonstop to Dallas Love Field and San Antonio, followed by Braniff and Texas International shortly after to offer some competition.  Currently, Southwest holds most of the market share, flying to over 50 destinations all over North and Central America. It’s also served by Allegiant Air, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, and Frontier Airlines, albeit with a substantially smaller participation in raw passenger volume.  The busiest destinations from Houston Hobby are Dallas Love Field, Denver, and Atlanta, with 380,000, 327,000, and 325,000 passengers each, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality 3D model of the passenger terminal and its interior, custom ground textures, improved high-resolution orthographic imagery, an up-to-date AFCAD (as of 2023), custom taxiway signs, handmade PBR textured buildings, and the Hobby Airport DoubleTree Hilton.  It’s available on Contrail for roughly $18.98, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Tang0 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pilda7</id>
    <title>PILOT'S Showcases Upcoming Dash 7 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pilda7" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645ff7accbd9ed6df12967bf_dash1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="351879"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PILOT'S GesmbH has recently published a couple of work-in-progress screenshots of their upcoming de Havilland Canada Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This classic turboprop regional airliner preceded the popular Dash 8. First flown in 1975, the Dash 7 is a "Twin Otter but larger and with four engines," with oversized fan blades that would rotate at a slower speed to emit as little noise as possible, complying with the noise restrictions that were starting to creep in. It could carry up to 50 passengers, with a service ceiling of 21,000 feet, and 690 nautical miles of range, all powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-50 turboprop engines, with 1,120 hp each. As of July 2018, 17 Dash 7s were still flying around the world with six different operators. However, the list of former operators is substantial: sixty civilian operators and three military operators. PILOT'S rendition is "nearing release," according to the developers, followed by a collection of screenshots showcasing the interior and exterior of their upcoming product. They claim to be continuously fixing bugs and tweaking the aircraft's behavior to match reality, with one more beta cycle to go until it's ready to release (according to their prediction).  Some screenshots also show the recently implemented TDS GTN integration, which adds modern navigational features to this almost 50-year-old regional airliner. There's no release date and pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed!Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pxbdev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pxbdev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64602cb6154231df36c97570_ran1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1908166"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo, PMDG’s Founder, has published another development update for Microsoft Flight Simulator regarding an upcoming patch for the 737 lineup and its eventual release on Xbox, more info on the EFB, and more.  The forum post begins with Randazzo explaining an issue with his internet connection, which has delayed both the update on PC and the 737’s arrival on Xbox, which are set to release soon. They plan to release a complete set of micro-updates for the 737 next week, including the aforementioned AFDS improvements, a few more fixes and tweaks, and the mitigation of a long existing bug with the V-speed computations misapplying corrections for head/tail wind components.  Randazzo also reminds everyone that the marketplace update will take longer due to Asobo’s approval process. His estimation for the rollout is either May 18 (the most favorable outcome) or May 25. The same applies to the Xbox version, which was pushed simultaneously.  Still on that Xbox note, Robert says that the 737 for Xbox won’t have any extra liveries to begin with, as their original plan was to wait for the liveries to be approved first, but they saw lots of feedback on their forum from the console simmers that would not mind an early release without any livery packs for the time being. Liveries of which, to no fault of their own, will cost $4.99 per pack (the in-game marketplace does not allow for free content, and that price tag is the minimum value).   The Universal Flight Tablet is still being worked on, with work going on refining the PERF process and refinement on native mapping features for non-Navigraph subscribers while also working hard on the Navigraph integration for Navigraph customers. They also made sure to explain once again why it has been taking so long to come out, bringing up how it’s a sandboxed environment and the communication between that environment and the “external world” is a little bit complicated.   They finish the UFT news bit with the information that an external-to-PMDG developer is working on adding extra functionalities, “showing what the tablet is truly capable of.”  Its initial release is said to bring a “number of features,” with more to come. “Navigraph and Simbrief users will be pleased by the care that has gone into ensuring a nice, tight weave between our technology and theirs,” said Randazzo.  ‍ The DC-6 update has been pushed to the marketplace, and the expected date is the same as the 737’s update. Either May 18 or May 25. Non-marketplace owners will get a micro-update this week incorporating these changes, which, according to Randazzo, should be transparent.  The development update ends with more information on the 777, which is progressing nicely, and they claim to be very happy with how things are going.  The 737 Lineup and the DC-6 are available on the PMDG Shop and in the MSFS Marketplace (partially).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
