<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-06-19T18:22:05.615624+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssda20</id>
    <title>SimSolutions' DA20 nearing completion</title>
    <updated>2023-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssda20" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64837745e1be006af07b40de_banner.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="538225"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimSolutions' latest creation, A Diamond DA20 for MSFS 2020 is now nearing its final stages of development. The developers behind the project have disclosed to Threshold that there are only a number of small functions remaining to be added, along with the finalisation of the sound profile for the aircraft.  The aircraft is based on a popular training aircraft and as such will contain a true to life avionics package, one would come to expect from a training aircraft. It will boast a GNS430 Navigation unit along with a standard transponder, the cockpit and exterior have been recreated in excruciating detail. Particular attention has also been paid to lighting both inside and outside the aircraft. Instrument panels will be accurately illuminated along with accurate flood lighting.  A release date and price is still yet to be confirmed by SimSolutions, but once it is we will be sure to keep you updated!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shdsen</id>
    <title>SHADESCENE Releases Senai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shdsen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6484faaed1c92f93178d10cd_senai1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1093606"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SHADESCENE has recently released their rendition of Senai International Airport (WMKJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the town of Senai in Malaysia with a yearly average of 4 million passengers.  Opened in 1974 and taken over by a private company (Senai Airport Terminal Services Sdn Bhd) in 2003, it’s the only privately managed public airport in Malaysia.   Its infrastructure can handle up to 4.5 million passengers and 80,000 tonnes of cargo per year, serving as a gateway for Iskandar Malaysia and its surroundings. With a 3,800-meter-long runway, it can handle small, medium, and large aircraft.  It’s served by AirAsia (Alor Setar, Guangzhou, Ho Chi Minh City, Ipoh, Kota Bharu, Kota Kinabalu, Kuala Lumpur–International, Kuching, Langkawi, Miri, Penang, Sibu, Tawau), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur–International, Kuala Lumpur–Subang), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Penang), Indonesia AirAsia (Jakarta–Soekarno-Hatta, Surabaya), Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur–International), and Thai AirAsia (Bangkok–Don Mueang).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terraforming, custom jetways, hand-placed taxiways, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, an animated radar tower, and a moderately detailed terminal interior with performance in mind.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.69, requiring at least 692.20 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asfs24</id>
    <title>Asobo Studio Announces Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</title>
    <updated>2023-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asfs24" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/648636c7e9a39e4a1a63dca0_fs20241-min.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2205105"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo Studio has made a surprise announcement on the Xbox Game Showcase: Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, soon to be available on Xbox, PC, and xCloud, bringing a plethora of new missions, content, and more. Aside from the two-minute trailer, Asobo has yet to reveal much information other than that it will be a standalone title and not an update to MSFS 2020.  The trailer shows many new features, including aerial construction, aerial firefighting, agricultural aviation, air ambulance missions, air racing, executive transport, gliders, helicopter cargo transport, rescue missions, skydiving, scientific research, and more. Lizard Doggo, from our Discord, has compiled a list with everything shown in the trailer:  ‍ There’s no information regarding backward compatibility with MSFS 2020 or the lack thereof.  It will be available on day one on Xbox Game Pass, PC Game Pass, Xbox Cloud Gaming, Windows 10/11, and Steam. The release date is yet to be defined (coming in 2024). Shout out to Lizard Doggo for the list! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsmar</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Marche Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsmar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64864ad3f2a68e210b0024b8_marche1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2833851"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Marche Airport (LIPY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Ancona and its surroundings with a yearly average of 489,000 passengers.  The airport started as a military airfield in the early 20th century, initially belonging to the Italian Air Force and taken over by the USAF for a few months in 1945 before being turned over to the local authorities.  It was opened for commercial operations in 1961, becoming the gateway to the Marche region in Italy. With a single terminal building and a short runway, it was only a short time until it underwent expansion work.   In recent years, the airport has continued to evolve and adapt to the changing aviation landscape. Various airlines, including low-cost and full-service carriers, have established routes to and from Ancona Falconara Airport, connecting the region with major cities across Europe.  It’s served by Albawings (Tirana), easyJet (Gatwick), Lufthansa (Munich), Ryanair (Catania, Charleroi, London–Stansted), Volotea (Cagliari, Catania, Palermo, Paris–Orly), and WizzAir (Tirana).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D buildings, custom ground textures, custom GSE, realistic glass windows, and an up-to-date layout.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.17, requiring at least 526.04 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swpc12</id>
    <title>SimWorks Releases PC-12 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swpc12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6486a9d21e72027a7d1959e9_352579726_717504257043924_5929771581922209650_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="427931"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer SimWorks has published a Facebook post detailing the group’s progress on their much anticipated PC-12 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, providing updates on the aircraft’s avionics, interior modeling, and lighting. According to SimWorks, the team has completed the PC-12’s electrical systems, a major milestone in the plane development. They are currently working on integrating the system with the various cockpit instruments. In addition, progress is being made on the plane’s avionics where the EADI has been finished while the finishing touches are being put on the EHSI.  As for the modeling and lighting, the developer claims that the interior design of the plane is 90%, with night lighting being gradually implemented into the cabin and cockpit. Finally, the exterior lighting of the PC-12 is now fully functional, though “a couple of quirks” still needs to be fixed, Currently, the developers have not provided a firm release date for the airplane, nor have they disclosed the PC-12’s expected price. Threshold will keep you updated on this front ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxideu</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Deauville-Normandie Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxideu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6487a95f669cba770b9e4a79_nor1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="865099"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has recently released their rendition of Deauville-Normandie Airport (LFRG)  for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the commune of Deauville in France with a yearly average of 160,000 passengers.  Inaugurated in 1931 by the initiative of Eugène Collas (the mayor of Deauville back then), it initially served as a business airport, eventually opening up for tourist charter flights as time went by.  For a short while, it used to be considered a third airport for Paris, but the distance (two-hour drive) and the lack of transportation options made it unfeasible, and they quickly ruled it out.  In 1952, they built a cement runway, allowing it to handle more aircraft types. Seven years later, a control tower was built, along with a runway extension to 1,600 meters in 1961.  In 1971, a passenger terminal was inaugurated, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and making it more suitable for commercial flights.   Recently, the operator has decided to build a new terminal, scheduled to reach completion in late 2023, expanding its area from 1,750 to 3,800 square meters. The state will cover 95% of the total cost; the remainder will come from Deauville. They also intend to add a photovoltaic park nearby to reach completion between 2024-2027. ‍ It's served on a seasonal basis by Aegean Airlines and Volotea. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detailed PBR models of the terminals and their respective interiors (built with performance in mind), custom taxiway signs, 3D passengers, custom ground textures, and custom night lighting.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.77, requiring at least 543.61 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwdab</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Daytona Beach International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwdab" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6488fc627380a3a08f0f2408_dab1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4041400"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the World and AmSim teamed up again to build a rendition of Daytona Beach International Airport (KDAB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, known for headquartering the Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University.  Daytona Beach was built in the 1930s on a 299-ha piece of land featuring two grass runways. Passenger service started in the same decade with Eastern Air Lines, followed by National Airlines a year later.   A little before World War 2, the airport got four paved runways, allowing for the operation of DC-2s and DC-3s. WW2 had the airport taken over by the US Navy, becoming the Naval Air Station Daytona Beach, followed by an extensive military construction effort. Many of the buildings were utilized by Embry-Riddle University after their move from Miami two decades later.  In 1992, a large terminal was built, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and transforming the old terminal into an international passenger terminal, followed by a final runway extension that sticks to this day.   As of mid-late 2021, the airport had 364,071 aircraft operations, with 62% corresponding to general aviation. The passenger figures sit at an average of 800,000 per year.   It’s served by American Airlines (Charlotte), American Eagle (Charlotte), Avelo Airlines (to begin in June 2023), and Delta Air Lines (Atlanta).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, high-resolution ground textures, landside buildings, a detailed terminal interior, and compatibility with FSLTL traffic.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.26, requiring at least 2.75 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to mtn_dude_ for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbhot</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Mount Hotham Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbhot" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6489012ebe60b888ff0f62f3_hot1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2328170"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Mount Hotham Airport (YHOT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving a ski resort on Mount Hotham in southeastern Australia. It’s the country’s highest airport.  Privately owned, the airport was opened in 2000 after a $17 million investment and four years of extensive planning.   It’s served by a single charter airline, Airly, flying from Bankstown and Essendon.   Orbx’s rendition portrays the airport as it were during its “golden age” when domestic and regional services still served it (QantasLink canceled their service in 2011 because it was losing them a lot of money). It features custom ground textures, a high-detail terminal interior, custom vegetation, custom animation, airport-specific static aircraft, over a hundred custom assets, and full PBR texturing.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.88, requiring at least 1.94 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbschu</id>
    <title>DarkBlueScenery Releases Chubu Centrair International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbschu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/648ae91302a85e6316d7c3f6_chubu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="276459"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DarkBlueScenery has recently released their rendition of Chubu Centrair International Airport (RJGG) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the city of Nagoya with a yearly average of 12 million passengers.  Serving the third largest metropolitan area in the country, Centrair was built to alleviate traffic into the former Nagoya Airport (now Nagoya Airfield) and redirect some of the cargo shipments that were initially directed to Tokyo or Kansai.   Construction work started in late 2000, reaching completion five years later at 668 billion yen. With a single runway and 42 gates, it is divided between two terminals, one for the major carriers and the second one for budget airlines. There are plans to add two new runways: a parallel runway by 2027 and a runway on the airport's west side that would replace the current runway.  It's a hub for All Nippon Airways and Jetstar Japan and features a strong presence of Japan Airlines and Polar Air Cargo. The visitors' list includes Air Busan, Air China, Asiana Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, Cebu Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Etihad Airways, Jeju Air, Korean Air, Singapore Airlines, Thai Airways, and United Airlines.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a realistic 3D model of the passenger terminals, custom ground service equipment, performance-friendly optimization, and more. The developer recommends using X-Plane 12 to have the best experience possible.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $17.28, requiring at least 492.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boufar</id>
    <title>Boundless Announces Faro Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boufar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/648af08ab0876993343dde1b_faro1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="174573"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently announced their next project for X-Plane 11 and 12: a rendition of Faro International Airport (LPFR), serving the city of Faro in Algarve, Portugal, with a yearly average of 8 million passengers. It was inaugurated in 1965 by then president Américo Tomás, with a government-owned DC-3 being the first airplane ever to touch its runway, followed by TAP Air Portugal’s Lockheed Super Constellation, transporting government officials and important guests. Scheduled passenger service started two days after, connecting Faro to Lisbon. In that same year, the airport recorded 58,000 passengers. Faro has only seen two significant developments in its first 40 years: a new passenger terminal building in 1989, and its eventual enlargement in 2001, to cope with the increased demands for air travel. The 2010s brought even more pressure for expansion, which reached completion in 2013 after a two-phase work, increasing its passenger handling capacity from six million to eight million passengers. Minor expansion work went on over the remainder of the decade, with the airport now able to handle up to 9 million passengers a year, with 22 stands and 36 boarding gates.  It’s a base for EasyJet and Ryanair, flying to many European destinations. The visitors’ list includes many traditional European airlines such as Aer Lingus, British Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian, and TAP Air Portugal and popular low-cost carriers such as Condor, Eurowings, Jet2, Smartwings, and Wizz Air. There’s no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpfar</id>
    <title>RDPresets Announces Faro International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpfar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/648cf31e5d63e7b9918d8d5f_far1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2005014"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently teased their upcoming rendition of Faro International Airport (LPFR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Faro in Algarve, Portugal, with a yearly average of 8 million passengers. In 1965, Faro Airport was officially inaugurated by then-president Américo Tomás. The historic moment was marked by the landing of a government-owned DC-3 aircraft, followed by TAP Air Portugal's Lockheed Super Constellation, which transported government officials and esteemed guests. Two days later, scheduled passenger service commenced, connecting Faro to Lisbon, and the airport welcomed approximately 58,000 passengers in its first year. During its initial four decades of operation, Faro Airport experienced two notable developments: a new passenger terminal in 1989 and its first expansion in 2001. However, it was during the 2010s that the pressure for growth became even more significant, leading to a comprehensive expansion project that reached completion in 2013 through a two-phase approach. The project increased the airport's passenger capacity from six million to eight million. Additional minor expansion work took place throughout the decade, resulting in the current capability of handling up to 9 million passengers annually. The airport boasts 22 stands and 36 boarding gates. Faro Airport is a base for popular airlines such as EasyJet and Ryanair, offering flights to numerous European destinations. The airport's list of visitors includes traditional European carriers such as Aer Lingus, British Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, and TAP Air Portugal. It also caters to well-known low-cost carriers like Condor, Eurowings, Jet2, Smartwings, and Wizz Air. The scenery is set to release tomorrow, and the pricing has yet to be discovered. Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbssa</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Stockholm Arlanda Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbssa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/648d444013b0e4ccdff0ce9c_arlanda1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2349763"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Stockholm Arlanda Airport (ESSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the province of Uppland in Sweden with a yearly average of 26 million passengers. It’s the busiest airport in the country and the third busiest in Scandinavia.  Opened in 1962, it quickly replaced Stockholm Bromma as the country’s main international airport due to its longer runway, allowing SAS to utilize the DC-8 for flights to North America. It was mainly an international airport during its first decades, with most domestic flights operating out of Bromma.   In 1983, Linjeflyg, a former domestic airline, moved from Bromma to Arlanda, operating their domestic routes on Terminal 4. A few years later, the airport got two new terminals exclusively for domestic use.   The airport currently features four terminals, three in use as of 2022, with no separation between domestic and international flights.   It’s a hub for Scandinavian Airlines and Eurowings Europe and a focus city for Finnair, Novair, and Ryanair. London is the most popular European destination, with nearly 2 million passengers shared between Heathrow and Gatwick, followed by Copenhagen with 1,394,000.   The scenery, developed by one of their independent developers, Marcus Nyberg, features animated jetways, functional and correct VDGS, enhanced interiors for all terminals, high-quality custom GSE, animated vehicles, weather-influenced snowbanks, a high-resolution mesh, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $24.01, requiring at least 6.35 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpfia</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Faro International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpfia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/648dbef181b3a3da9d25339a_fa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2273961"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently released their rendition of Faro International Airport (LPFR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Faro in Algarve, Portugal, with a yearly average of 8 million passengers.  In 1965, Faro Airport was officially inaugurated by then-president Américo Tomás. The historic moment was marked by the landing of a government-owned DC-3 aircraft, followed by TAP Air Portugal's Lockheed Super Constellation, which transported government officials and esteemed guests. Two days later, scheduled passenger service commenced, connecting Faro to Lisbon, and the airport welcomed approximately 58,000 passengers in its first year.  During its initial four decades of operation, Faro Airport experienced two notable developments: a new passenger terminal in 1989 and its first expansion in 2001. However, it was during the 2010s that the pressure for growth became even more significant, leading to a comprehensive expansion project that reached completion in 2013 through a two-phase approach. The project increased the airport's passenger capacity from six million to eight million. Additional minor expansion work took place throughout the decade, resulting in the current capability of handling up to 9 million passengers annually. The airport boasts 22 stands and 36 boarding gates.  Faro Airport is a base for popular airlines such as EasyJet and Ryanair, offering flights to numerous European destinations. The airport's list of visitors includes traditional European carriers such as Aer Lingus, British Airways, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, and TAP Air Portugal. It also caters to well-known low-cost carriers like Condor, Eurowings, Jet2, Smartwings, and Wizz Air.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models and textures, custom clutter, realistic and functioning VDGS, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, a fully modeled interior with 3D passengers, and performance-friendly optimization.  It's available on the RDPresets Store for roughly $19.99, requiring at least 1.26 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbmel</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Melbourne Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbmel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649056e45095ca885fb0ea99_melb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="719386"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Melbourne Airport (YMML) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Melbourne in Australia with a yearly average of 25 million passengers. It is the second busiest airport in the country!  Built in the 60s and opened in 1970, it replaces Essendon Airport (Orbx’s home) as the city’s main airport due to its relatively short runways, small terminals, and its expansion limitations that were a consequence of the urban development around the area.   During its first year of operations, Melbourne only handled international traffic, handling 155,275 international passengers that year and six airlines.   It originally featured three connected terminals, an international at the center, a terminal for Ansett to the south, and one for Trans Australia Airlines to the north. It could withstand 8 Boeing 707s and a rate of 500 passengers per hour, with expansion work three years later to comport the Boeing 747.  It wasn’t long until the passenger figures increased drastically, forcing further expansion: the Ansett terminal, domestic, got bigger, followed by an upgrade to the international terminal in 1993 and the opening of a new three-level concourse in 1995, with ten additional jetways.  In 1997, Melbourne was privatized, on a 50-year long-term lease, followed by a series of upgrades and improvements, including the construction of a multi-story carpark with 3,100 parking spaces, a 276-room hotel, and the expansion of the Qantas domestic terminal with a second pier and nine additional stands.  In 2005, the airport underwent more construction work to become A380-ready, with a runway widening, the addition of dual jetbridges, a terminal extension, and a subsequent expansion of terminal 2 in 2006 and 2008, massively increasing its passenger handling capabilities.  The airport has 68 gates, 53 used for domestic operations and 15 for international.   The airport is a hub for Jetstar (Adelaide, Auckland, Ayers Rock, Ballina, Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Brisbane, Busselton, Cairns, Canberra, Christchurch, Darwin, Denpasar, Gold Coast, Hamilton Island, Hobart, Ho Chi Minh City, Honolulu, Launceston, Newcastle, Perth, Phuket, Proserpine, Queenstown, Singapore, Sunshine Coast, Sydney, Townsville), Qantas (Adelaide, Alice Springs, Auckland, Ballina, Brisbane, Broome, Cairns, Canberra, Christchurch, Dallas/Fort Worth, Darwin, Delhi, Denpasar, Gold Coast,  Hamilton Island, Hobart, Hong Kong, Jakarta–Soekarno-Hatta, London–Heathrow, Los Angeles, Perth, Queenstown, Singapore, Sunshine Coast, Sydney, Wellington), Rex Airlines (Adelaide, Brisbane, Burnie, Canberra, Devonport, Gold Coast, King Island, Merimbula, Mildura, Mount Gambier, Sydney, Wagga Wagga), and Virgin Australia (Adelaide, Ballina, Brisbane, Cairns, Canberra, Darwin, Denpasar, Gold Coast, Hamilton Island, Hobart, Launceston, Nadi, Newcastle, Perth, Queenstown, Sunshine Coast, Sydney). The visitor list includes Air China, Air India, Air New Zealand, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, LATAM Chile, Singapore Airlines, United Airlines, and more.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR texturing, interior terminal modeling of departure lounges, VDGS, custom traffic animations, crisp satellite imagery, custom ground clutter, custom POIs, LOD optimization, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $23.92, requiring at least 6.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navwxr</id>
    <title>Navigraph Implements Weather Layer Feature in Charts 8</title>
    <updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navwxr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649065f47d1d65462b3f7a13_wxr1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="161058"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Navigraph has recently added Weather Layers to their Charts 8 application, allowing users to fetch real-time weather information, including precipitation, winds, turbulence, METARs, cloud coverage, and more.  With an array of dynamic weather layers, pilots will have a comprehensive meteorological insight, with a set of different layers that will help with flight planning and decision-making for VFR and IFR simmers. The complete feature list follows below:  Radar – Monitor real-time precipitation and storm activity. The weather radar also supports a 2 hour playback to facilitate the anticipation of weather conditions for your flight. ‍ AIRSIGMET / CWA (AIRman’s METeorological Information / SIGnificant METeorological Information / Center Weather Advisory)  – Stay informed about significant weather hazards and hazardous flying conditions such as thunderstorms, turbulence and icing across your route. ‍ METAR (METeorological Aerodrome Report)  – Display real-time meteorological aerodrome report information such as temperature, dewpoint, wind and ceiling to gauge current weather conditions at airports around the world. ‍ Turbulence – Identify regions of potential turbulence along your flight path to ensure a smoother journey.  ‍ Icing (Severity) – Understand the severity of icing conditions in different regions and adjust your flight plan accordingly. ‍ Reflectivity – Gain insights into precipitation by visualizing areas of precipitation and their severity. ‍ Cloud Cover – Evaluate cloud coverage and make informed decisions based on ceiling conditions displayable from FL20 up to FL500. ‍ ISA (International Standard Atmosphere) Temperature – Gain a better general understanding of the regional temperatures and plan your flights more accurately by incorporating International Standard Atmosphere temperature variations. ‍ Tropopause – Identify the upper limit of the troposphere to gain a better understanding of weather at high altitudes. ‍ Convective Cloud Top Level – Visualize the top levels of convective clouds to assess the potential for severe weather. ‍ High Cloud Top Level – Identify the altitude of high-level clouds, allowing for a better understanding of high altitude weather. ‍ Visibility – Display regions with low visibility to ensure safe and efficient navigation. ‍ MSL (Mean Sea Level) Pressure – View mean sea level pressure to understand the regional atmospheric conditions. ‍ Jet Streams – Discover the location of jet streams at different altitudes and plan your flights accordingly. ‍ Wind Barbs – Observe wind directions and strength with wind barbs at different altitudes for increased situational awareness and accurate flight planning.  Navigraph also adds that a 24-hour forecast is available for all layers except AIRMETs/SIGMETs, METAR, and radar; A 6-hour playback is available for all layers but AIRMETs/SIGMETs and METAR, while the radar offers a 2-hour playback.  They have attached a video showcasing some of the weather layers in action:  The new feature is available right now for Navigraph Ultimate subscribers. Click here to subscribe! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrcfrc</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update II France &amp; Local Legend 09 Latécoère 631</title>
    <updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrcfrc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64906cd180725061b6e7ca32_fr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="878399"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Microsoft Flight Simulator team has unveiled an exciting new update through a video on their youtube channel. City Update II: France is here, and it brings with it the breathtaking beauty of five iconic French cities: Amiens, Angers, Nantes, Nîmes, and Reims. To add to the excitement, this update coincides with the prestigious Paris Air Show and includes the highly renowned Paris–Le Bourget Airport (LFPB) in both standard and festival configurations. Each city featured in this update has its own unique charm and historical significance. Let's take a closer look at what makes them so special. To further celebrate French aviation heritage, the Microsoft Flight Simulator team is launching the Local Legend 09: Latécoère Model 631 aircraft. This impressive flying boat, designed and manufactured by France's Latécoère Corporation, represents a source of great national pride. The Model 631, an all-metal, high-wing, six-engine aircraft, took its maiden flight on November 4, 1942, and held the distinction of being the largest flying boat in the world for several years. Its elegant design and significant role in trans-oceanic travel make it a must-have addition for aviation enthusiasts. ‍ The Latécoère Model 631 comes with 16 liveries and will be available for purchase at $14.99. With its unique blend of beauty and historical significance, this aircraft perfectly complements the City Update II: France. ‍ To embark on this virtual journey through France and experience the wonders of City Update II, ensure that your Microsoft Flight Simulator is updated to version 1.32.7.0. Once updated, download the City Update II for free and prepare to be amazed by the stunning sights that France has to offer. ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
