<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-12-22T18:39:24.297267+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfdufo</id>
    <title>Just Flight Shares Development Update for F70/100 Professional for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfdufo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6942a6ec48a8ef4b8c6123ce_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has released its latest development update for the upcoming F70/100 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The team reports significant progress since the last update and is nearing completion of the project. Along with the update, they have also shared a video trailer showcasing the new aircraft. Since the last development update, the team has refined, improved, and reworked various components of the AFCAS and FMS code. Additionally, the flight model has been enhanced further to better replicate the experience of flying the real aircraft, which real-world pilots have described as delightful to hand-fly. The sound developer has been diligently working on the aircraft, which will feature the highest number of individual sound samples he has ever included in a project. The team has stated that they will release a video providing a detailed overview of the sound features in due course. At the conclusion of the development update, the team mentioned that they are working hard to release the F70/100 Professional as soon as possible in 2026. ‍ You can read the full development update on Just Flight's website.  We will update you as soon as we have more information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hs7872</id>
    <title>Horizon Simulations Teases Boeing 787 Version Two, With A Look At New EFB</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hs7872"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6943d92f79c5eff17999cc7e_Image_6%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Horizon Simulations has teased a brand-new electronic flight bag as part of their upcoming 787 version 2 family.  The new EFB looks to include many of the features we have come to expect from a more complete aircraft model, including a working on-screen keyboard, pilot utilities, a landing performance calculator, and en route charts.  With no set release date, Horizon Simulations plans to continue issuing periodic developer updates on Discord. The next planned update will highlight 3D modelling work. Susequest updates will feature the PFD, MFD, CDU, and sound!  Horizon Simulations is inviting community members to provide feedback on the developer updates. So, if you have feedback, be sure to check out their Discord! For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ms4ps5</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 Releases on PlayStation 5</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ms4ps5"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6943e177006eb2c4ba2ada90_01_872423.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has ported its latest version of its landmark simulator, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, onto the PlayStation 5.  The full release of the sim for PS5 follows a phased rollout that included early access for those who pre-ordered the Deluxe, Premium Deluxe, or Aviator editions.  While the game experience remains the same for PS5 users, Microsoft has noted that access to the in-game marketplace will require a separate app.  As a consequence, purchases made in the in-sim marketplace won’t transfer over from other platforms. However, the port does offer more people the chance to take to the virtual skies.  Veterans of the PC launch will no doubt take note of Microsoft’s new phased release approach. This approach should hopefully negate the problems faced by simmers just over a year ago, when Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 launched on PC and Xbox, leading to vastly increased wait times.   Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 can be purchased from the PlayStation Store on your console. Where do you think the sim will be ported to next? Mac? The Nintendo Switch 2? Let us know!   For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vata16</id>
    <title>VATSIM Announces New Age Restrictions</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vata16"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6943e8633f6092fcf0bd6c05_vatsim_age.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a recent post, VATSIM confirmed that, starting January 1st, 2026, they will require all new users to be at least 16 years of age.  The online air traffic control network claims it is making this change as part of its ongoing work to ensure a safe and welcoming environment for all members. All current users aged 13 to 15 will be exempted from this policy.  While some see the recent changes as a necessary step to maintain the network's safety and security, many others feel that VATSIM’s policy shifts could deter membership growth.  How do you feel about the way VATSIM is being run? Does this make you more likely to sign up for VATSIM or maintain your current membership? Or is the organisation becoming a little too restrictive? ‍ Let us know! ‍ For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia350v120</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia350v120"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694458f037084547b380e37c_lufty.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, adding SEC flight plan fixes and wholly fixing a WASM-induced texture loading error introduced with Sim Update 4 (MSFS 2024). ​ Update v1.2.0 is a micro-update addressing issues with the secondary flight plan and a WASM texture loading bug introduced with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s latest major update. The complete changelog follows below: Fixed - Sec-fplan fixes for airway entry Fixed - SEC F-PLN - INSERT NEXT WPT adds waypoints to the top of F-PLN instead of after chosen waypoint Fixed - WASM next waypoint 'LNY vor' on SEC2, 3 F-PLN. Fixed - WASM texture loading bug introduced in SU4 on some machines Admin - Numerous file clean up and adhoc admin of project ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $80.49.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfla300b4dec</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes A300B4 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfla300b4dec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69445f74eb8e67ca0013a131_ext1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. As part of their End of Year Round Up, Just Flight has shared some of the progress on the A300B4 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024, with its exterior artwork nearing completion and ready for showcasing. They have meticulously hand-placed thousands of rivets on every inch of the aircraft’s surface, with the tail area being the most obvious due to its housing of so many critical structures. Special attention has been paid to weathering, resulting in a representation of an airframe that has been in service for many years, complete with streaks of dirt, detritus, traces of rainwater, run-down panels, and more. The flight deck is no different, as they have previously shared. Just Flight considers their A300B4 to be one of the most accurately represented wide-body airliners in any flight simulator. A bold claim, as they note, but they will let the people be the judges. As for the remaining work on the art department, their artist is currently finishing the textures of the landing gear, wheels, and landing gear bays, before eventually focusing on the cargo hold interiors. Once that is out of the way, the artwork will be complete for the A300B4-203 variant. But the -203 isn’t the only variant modeled, so there’s still a bit more work to do: the showcased plane is actually an A300B4-103, for example. A freighter variant will also be included. With that being said, they are not ready yet to show any of the other planned variants. ​ After the texturing work is complete, they will move on to livery creation for the variants at hand, and they promise to provide a large selection of top-quality work that will represent the A300B4’s diverse range of operators from every habitable continent.  ​ Furthermore, the developers have finally been able to share previews of the passenger cabin, modelled into a two-class layout from the 1980s, with the First Class cabin featuring 24 seats in a 2+2+2 configuration, and the economy cabin featuring 230 seats in a 2+4+2 configuration, narrowing at the rear to a 2+3+2 configuration. In line with their other products, the cabin will feature numerous simulated elements, offering “lots to play with” during the cruise phase. The cabin artwork is deemed ready, but there may be minor changes between what has been showcased and the final product at the time of release, most notably related to cabin lighting, as it has not yet been implemented. The flight model is progressing decently, and the extensive data they sourced from a variety of A300B4 variants has been proven rather useful, allowing it to perform as faithfully as possible to the numbers. The systems have now been fully coded, and the plane is getting ready to enter wider beta testing. Among the most recently completed systems, they highlight the Carousel IV-A Inertial Navigation System and the autopilot logic. ​ Since they have something nearing completion, they can finally begin proper testing with their beta team, allowing them to delve deeply into the system's intricacies to cross-check their functionalities against the aircraft’s FCOM and mitigate any issues that may arise. ​ Just Flight will be sharing more details earlier next year. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddepkt24out</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Katowice Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddepkt24out"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694464dfc3eed8da3962b8bf_epkt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Katowice Wojciech Korfanty Airport (EPKT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Katowice-Ostrava metropolitan area with a yearly average of 6.4 million passengers, making it the 4th busiest airport in Poland. It was originally built by the Luftwaffe in 1940, with three stone and concrete airstrips of varying lengths. It was used for handling military aircraft flying from Germany, carrying supplies to troops on the Eastern Front. It was also briefly used for aircraft testing in the final phase of World War 2. In 1945, the airfield was taken over by the Soviets, and it was subsequently handed over to Poland in the early 1950s, where it was used to house the Polish Air Force’s 39th Fighter Regiment. A new runway was built in the mid-1960s, and regular scheduled passenger traffic began in 1966. Poland’s entry into the European Union has substantially accelerated the airport’s growth, with Wizz Air choosing Katowice as its first base outside Hungary. Other low-cost carriers followed suit within the next couple of years. A second terminal was built in 2007 specifically for Schengen flights, and an arrivals-only terminal (Terminal C) followed in 2015. That year also marked the construction of Katowice’s new runway, which is 3200 meters in length (the second-longest runway in Poland). It’s a focus city for ASL Airlines Ireland, Buzz (Ryanair), Electra Airways, Enter Air, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa Cargo, Ryanair, Skyline Express, Smartwings Poland, and Wizz Air. Air Cairo, Air Dolomiti, Corendon Airlines, Freebird Airlines, Lufthansa, Nesma Airlines, Nouvelair, Pegasus Airlines, Plus Ultra, and Tailwind Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, a custom terminal interior, custom ground service equipment, an accurate runway profile, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $24.62, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/738202430</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737-800 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/738202430"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69449ad660638fea81aa0035_7321.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released the long-awaited Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version of their Boeing 737-800, their first product built natively for the new platform with a lidar-scanned flight deck, improved textures and lighting, new sounds, and much more. Their 738 leverages the capabilities of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 to lay the groundwork for a truly native product line that will follow from this (the next variants will gradually roll out over the next months).  ​ It’s said to be a significant overhaul of the 737 product line, wholly capitalizing on the sim’s capabilities: a new cockpit with new materials, lidar scanned models, new lighting, new surface textures; a new cabin, new interactable items around the airplane, customized door logic, operable cockpit windows, and a new 3D sound-set built by a professional sound engineering team whose lead sound engineer is also a type-rated 737 captain. The full changelog follows below: ​ It’s available on PMDG.com for $74.99, and owners of the MSFS 2020 version are entitled to a 60% discount ($30 total).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42cpl2024</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases ChasePlane for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42cpl2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6945c8beb19429369755b7ea_cpl1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has recently released their long-awaited physics-based camera system for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, providing realistic motion that dynamically responds to the environment, creating unparalleled immersion. For the unfamiliar, ChasePlane was originally released in 2016 for Microsoft Flight Simulator X, and later became compatible with Prepar3D, rapidly becoming the de facto camera application for ESP-based simulators at the time. After many years of waiting, Parallel 42 finally managed to break Asobo’s absurdly locked camera system, bringing ChasePlane to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 in early 2025, with the promise of eventually making it 2024 compatible, which has now been fulfilled. ​ The add-on features highly realistic physics-based camera behavior based on extensive research and real-world pilot footage. This warrants realistic motion that dynamically responds to the environment, embracing the flight model rather than altering it. Pilots can feel the vibration during the take-off roll, the rush of turbulence, and the fluid shifts during maneuvers. ​ ChasePlane 2020 owners can upgrade to 2024 for free by using the code “CPWEN” at the checkout page. ​ It’s available in their store for $30.00. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia340106</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia340106"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6945cc52f4876d97e2db3310_tor1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their newly released A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing a “substantial round of refinements” that focus on systems, visuals, and more. ​ Update v1.0.6 enhances navigation and FMGS behavior, resolves certain edge-case system issues, and introduces fully simulated offset functionality, alongside an expanded flight attendant panel experience. There are also numerous visual enhancements, including gear, camera views, and cabin details.  ​ Furthermore, the Electronic Flight Bag has been updated to enhance unit handling, improve performance calculations, and facilitate its integration with FSDT’s Ground Services X. ​ The complete changelog follows below: V1.0.6 SYSTEMS :gear: FIXED ENG sd on ND not simulated FIXED GSX refuel still not opening the refuel access panel under the wing FIXED ETP floating in a random location of the ND FIXED PFD/ND HDG value should show when off screen with FD off FIXED Mismatch between inbound course and track diamond in PFD and ND ILS ROSE mode FIXED GPS page coordinates fluctuating during jamming FIXED ACCU PRESS + BRAKES TEST refined FIXED After go-around A/THR not working at level-off and LVL MCT not showing FIXED Manual Min EFOB resets and stays in large text FIXED Changing runways/resetting MCDU does not erase previously entered TO SHIFT FIXED Altitude constraints still show as FLs when below TRL with low transition altitude FIXED Changed unit options reset when returning to TO PERF FIXED CPDLC identifier field remains populated after logon request sent FIXED AIRPORT key on right MCDU not sequencing properly FIXED OPT ALT appearing higher than REC MAX FIXED A350/A340 always ADS-C connected when logged on FIXED MORA linked incorrectly to CSTR FIXED Editing an active offset not possible FIXED Offset unusable due to LSK reselection behavior FIXED TO PERF SYNC FMGS auto-filling WEIGHT without unit conversion ‍ ART :art: FIXED Center gear left wheel tread rotation inverted FIXED Wipers reset when changing from fast to slow and then continue incorrectly FIXED Nose gear strut not compressing FIXED Saved camera feedback FIXED Left wing texturing artifact under aileron when snow is on FIXED Cabin collision hitbox refinement on left side FIXED Contrail display issues ‍ EFB:computer: FIXED EFB NG navdata download issue FIXED EFB payload page summary: TOW displays T despite KG unit FIXED EFB landing performance add Vapp FIXED Reverse on axis loading incorrectly FIXED Align planner setting size with A350 FIXED Wipe TO/LDG PERF pages when changing aircraft weight units FIXED TO PERF option to switch units on QNH/m/ft/lbs/kg ADDED GSX Loading Suggestion ADDED Switchable units on takeoff calculator ‍ SOUNDS:loud_sound: FIXED Reworked 3D spatialization for flaps and slats FIXED Slat sounds near wing root FIXED PRED W/S OFF memo triggers a click sound FIXED APU sounds not changing with position relative to aircraft when APU BLEED = ON FIXED Increased low pass on APU cone FIXED Intermediate callouts missing FIXED Gear down needs more aerodynamic rumble FIXED Gear drag position not audible in cockpit FIXED Improved triple click sound FIXED Modified master warn sound sample FIXED ISIS missing interaction sounds FIXED Deprecated sound events causing doubling on ACP FIXED Improved samples and variety of larger dial interactions FIXED Ambient mixing adjustments in flight FIXED Improvements to wiper mix FIXED Reduced low pass on turbulence bumping FIXED Tweaks to payload sounds in cargo hold FIXED Oxygen test mixing FIXED Toilet door timing synced with animation FIXED Missing cabin ambient sounds FIXED Fuel pumps audible unrealistically outside FIXED Wind ambience in flight ADDED More audio detail to pedestal rotary knobs ADDED Improved WXR tilt and gain interaction sounds ‍ The add-on is available in the MSFS Marketplace for roughly $59.99 If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/smrsin</id>
    <title>SIMMARKET Resumes Sales in Norway</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/smrsin"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6945d12d35a6525aa640f0f3_SimMarketNorway.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. SimMarket has confirmed that they have resumed sales in Norway. ‍ Sales to customers with a registered address in Norway were temporarily halted due to the site’s months-long struggle with external tax regulations.  ‍ While SimMarket staff were actively working to find the proper solution, Norwegian customers remained patient and persistent. In a statement released on Instagram, SimMarket thanked its Norwegian customers for their passion and continued support during the sales hiatus ‍ SimMarket is one of the leading retail outlets for flight simulation. It offers customers unlimited downloads and permanent on-demand access to their order history. ‍ You can check out their offerings at https://secure.simmarket.com/ ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nimbusordout</id>
    <title>Nimbus Simulation Studios Releases Chicago O’Hare Intl for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nimbusordout"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6945d5f3761a23e13a3a2c29_cha1.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has recently released their rendition of Chicago O’Hare International Airport (KORD) for X-Plane 12, the world’s fourth busiest airport, with a yearly average of 80 million passengers. Their X-Plane 12 version of O’Hare takes full advantage of the simulator’s new technologies, bringing realistic wetness, season support, detailed terminal interiors, and more. The full feature list includes new 4K orthophotos, performance-friendly optimization, VRAM-friendly optimization, full 3D interiors, 3D people, custom ground markings, custom ground textures, and much more. It’s available on X-Plane.Org for $29.95, requiring at least 1.1 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iadfwl</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Liverpool John Lennon and Dallas Fort Worth Airports for MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2025-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iadfwl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6945ee14a7000f4791f1cb63_DFW8.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In their most recent scenery development recap on their forums, iniBuilds has confirmed that they are working on renditions of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) and Liverpool John Lennon Airport (EGGP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ‍ Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (DFW) is one of the world’s busiest airports by aircraft movement, and recreating the complexity and scale of the airport has been quite the task for the iniBuilds team. Development work has been underway for months, ranging from detailed ground poly work to getting the unique architecture of the terminals correct. Greg Jones, iniBuilds’ Head of Scenery and Geospatial Development, says that DFW’s size has been a challenge for the team to adapt their work flow integrating new features.  “Adopting MSFS2024 as our core development platform gave us new opportunities to introduce levels of detail and quality previously not possible. … Early in 2025, we had a commercial opportunity to work on Dallas Fort Worth. We jumped at the chance to produce what will be, by far, the largest project we’ve ever done”, Jones explains. He expands on their goals for DFW, stating that they are putting “performance at the core of everything” and “[The] testing team is hard at work ironing out any kinks, and so far the results have been stellar”. As of writing, iniBuilds has not confirmed a release date for their rendition of DFW, but they say that users “shouldn’t have to wait many more months” for a release. ‍ Following in the footsteps of their recent release of Manchester and Leeds Bradford v2, iniBuilds’ newest UK airport will be Liverpool John Lennon, an airport with a rich history and scenic approach over the river Mersey. In their announcement iniBuilds asks for help from anyone who works at Liverpool John Lennon Airport or has airside access and can provide high-quality reference photography or technical data. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsuaaa</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Almaty International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsuaaa"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6946a048f893547ba96e4000_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. VueloSimple has just released its version of Almaty International Airport (UAAA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located in the largest city of Kazakhstan, Almaty, the airport serves almost 11.5 million passengers annually. The airport first opened its doors in 1935, initially serving smaller civil and military aircraft. The main terminal was built in 1973. In 1998, the runway was reconstructed and achieved CAT II certification, which elevated the airport's status to that of an international airport. A new terminal was completed in 2004, and a second runway opened in 2008, receiving CAT III certification. Most recently, Terminal 2 was inaugurated in 2024. Today, the airport serves a variety of airlines, including Air Astana, Pegasus Airlines, and SCAT Airlines, accommodating nearly 11.5 million passengers annually. The newly released scenery comes packed with features such as detailed 3D models, up-to-date airport layout, accurate night illumination, and much more. The newly released Almaty International Airport by VueloSimple is now available on Contrail for approximately $15.21. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmkbzn</id>
    <title>TaiModels Releases Bozeman Yellowstone International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmkbzn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6947ed1dbb743c3e82bd0ea6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TaiModels has released its latest scenery add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, featuring Bozeman Yellowstone International Airport (KBZN). Located in Montana, this airport serves the city of Bozeman and annually welcomes over 2.6 million passengers. The airport opened in 1941 under the name Gallatin Field, although the first passengers did not arrive until 1942. By the end of the 1960s, the airport underwent several improvements, including a runway extension. It was not until 2011 that the airport was renamed to its current designation. That same year, the terminal was expanded. In 2012, the airport began allowing international flights. Recently, in 2024, a new expansion of the airport's infrastructure was announced. Today, the airport serves a variety of airlines, including American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, and United Airlines, providing a wide range of destinations. TaiModels’ rendition of Bozeman Yellowstone International Airport comes with features such as PBR ground markings and textures, detailed terminal interiors, accurate airport lighting, taxiways, and aprons, and much more. Bozeman Yellowstone International Airport, by TaiModels, is now available from iniBuilds for $18.61. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asubbf</id>
    <title>Azrsim Releases Fuzuli International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asubbf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6949723e6063ffe8d96ff12d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Azrsim has recently released its rendition of Fuzuli International Airport (UBBF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. After previously launching Heydar Aliyev International Airport (UBBB), the main airport in Baku, earlier this year, the team has now turned its attention to another city in Azerbaijan. Fuzuli International Airport currently offers passenger flights solely to the capital, Baku. Fuzuli International Airport is a relatively new airport, having opened in 2021. It covers an area of just under 650,000 square feet and features a runway that is nearly 10,000 feet long. Currently, the airport is served exclusively by Azerbaijan Airlines, which offers flights to Baku; however, it also accommodates cargo flights. Azrsim’s airport rendition features an accurate airport layout, a fully custom-modelled terminal building, high-quality PBR materials, custom night lighting, and many additional features. The newly released Fuzuli International Airport by Azrsim is now available on SimMarket for approximately $17.64. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
