<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-12-12T18:39:51.744325+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse26d</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2026 Tickets Go on Sale This Week</title>
    <updated>2025-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse26d"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693608ac172c409c55fcb9a9_og.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Flight Simulation Association has confirmed that tickets for FlightSimExpo 2026 will go on sale at 1200 CT on Sunday, 14 December. The show returns on 12-14 June 2026, at the Saint Paul RiverCentre in Minnesota, a short drive from Minneapolis–Saint Paul International Airport and the Mall of America. An “Entire Event” ticket covers all seminars and workshops, “#FSExpoFriday” product announcements, three days of exhibits, the new Friday Exhibit Hall Preview, and access to post-event seminar recordings.  Pricing starts at $50 for the first 200 FSA Captains, while the standard “Entire Event” ticket for non-Captains is set at $75, with new single-day options available.  Co-founder Phil Coyle notes that last year the same ticket was $84, and that attendees this time “get 20% more time in the exhibit hall”. Alongside the lower ticket prices, FlightSimExpo highlights hotel rates that are about 25% cheaper than at the 2025 event, with rooms starting from 149 dollars per night, plus tax.  Discounted fares with Delta, United, Southwest, and codeshare partners are already live, together with car-rental offers.  You can also purchase a membership for FSA Captain and online event access from the website. As usual, developers, hardware manufacturers, communities, and other organisations are invited to participate as sponsors, exhibitors, and speakers, with booth packages, including furnishings, internet, electricity, and event passes.  The team promises everything from product reveals and hands-on exhibits to virtual reality and training demonstrations, and a full seminar programme, with an initial list of sponsors and exhibitors to be published in March 2026. More information on registration, partner opportunities, and travel offers can be found on the FlightSimExpo website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse2d2</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2026 Announces Friday Exhibit Hall Preview And Single-Day Tickets</title>
    <updated>2025-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse2d2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693610f7ff71790a2327f760_Friday%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Flight Simulation Association has announced several changes for FlightSimExpo 2026, including Friday exhibit hall access for the first time, and new single-day ticket options for attendees who cannot commit to the full three-day show. New for 2026, the exhibit hall at the Saint Paul RiverCentre will open on Friday, 12 June, from 2130Z to 0000Z, directly after #FSExpoFriday’s product reveals and developer updates, which now begin at 1700Z.  FSA Co-Founder Evan Reiter said the change is a direct response to attendee feedback, noting that “this change allows us to offer attendees 20% more time in the exhibit hall without changing the overall travel footprint for our partners”. The rest of the weekend schedule remains familiar, with announcements, hands-on exhibits and demonstrations, product updates, developer Q&amp;As, workshops, and more on Saturday and Sunday.  Co-Founder Phil Coyle added that the team is planning additional off-site activities, such as tower and airport tours and museum visits, with details to follow in early 2026. Alongside the expanded Friday programme, FlightSimExpo 2026 will introduce new single-day ticket options.  In addition to a full “Entire Event” ticket, attendees will be able to purchase Friday-only, Saturday-only, or Sunday-only access, aimed particularly at simmers who cannot attend all three days, especially those local to the Minneapolis–Saint Paul area. Sponsor, exhibitor, and speaker registration is open now. Software developers, hardware vendors, non-profits, and other flight simulation organisations can book all-inclusive booth packages, that include furnishings, internet, electricity, and event passes, with educational speaking slots available at no charge. Attendees who cannot travel to Minnesota will again be able to follow #FSExpoFriday and the weekend seminars online, via the FSA Captain subscription, or a one-time online-only ticket. FlightSimExpo 2026 takes place on 12-14 June 2026 at the Saint Paul RiverCentre, approximately eight miles from Minneapolis–Saint Paul International Airport. Tickets go on sale on 14. December, and you can read more here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sasdec</id>
    <title>SimAtlas Launches Subscription Library for MSFS Payware Add-ons</title>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sasdec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6936f69bf0f73f73487e54a1_SimAtlas%20Logo.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. SimAtlas has officially launched as a subscription service for Microsoft Flight Simulator, offering PC users a new way to access payware add-ons.  For a promotional rate of $12 per month initially, and $16 per month thereafter, subscribers gain access to a library of more than 100 payware products, representing over $1,400 in combined retail value. Content is licensed directly from developers and delivered through a dedicated desktop client, which handles installation, updates, and Community folder management automatically.  The software is designed to work alongside AI traffic packages and GSX, and needs to remain open while MSFS is running.  The team says its goal is to make high-quality content easier to discover, and significantly more affordable to enjoy, while still supporting creators financially, and stresses that SimAtlas does not remove or restrict existing one-time purchase options.  A free demo tier with select freeware content is also available, allowing users to test the platform before committing to a paid plan. For developers, SimAtlas offers a recurring revenue model on top of existing sales channels. Content is wrapped in the client’s DRM system and remains accessible only to active subscribers, with the company stating that a significant majority of subscription income is returned to participating developers as royalties.  Studios may choose to license a single product or an entire catalogue, and the platform supports all add-on types that live in the Community folder. Freeware authors can also distribute their work through the free tier for additional visibility, albeit without monetisation. Further information, including the current content line-up and developer onboarding details, is available on the official website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfssu4rel</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 4 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfssu4rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693717494decabc2eb142f58_SU4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has recently released the long-awaited Sim Update 4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, introducing substantial performance improvements, numerous bug fixes, and additional enhancements. ​ With a kilometer-long checklist, Sim Update 4 might just be the most important Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 patch yet, bringing huge improvements to the table, especially on the performance front, where it had been previously lacking, being borderline unplayable on systems with not enough VRAM due to how DirectX 12 handles that by nature, tanking performance and causing stutters. SU4 attempts to lower that footprint slightly, allowing breathing room for it to work without major hiccups here and there. ​ Furthermore, the update also adds the Boom XB-1 and launches the Red Bull Air Races mode. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ The update is now available on all compatible platforms. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2amanche24</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Announces Native Accu-Sim Comanche 250 Update for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2amanche24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69371a4dfe1ab8acb2e4ad84_manche1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently announced the development of a native build of their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, including new 2024-only features such as the new EFB apps, dirt accumulation, and more. The upgrade - which will be paid for - will bring native 2024 gauges, a native 2024 EFB with charts and other apps, a full walkaround system using 2024’s standards, dirt accumulation on the exterior, dual PMS/TDS GTN 750/650 configuration, time compression support, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ - Native 2024 gauges and model with optimized LODs - Native 2024 EFB, allowing the tablet to show charts and other EFB apps - Full walkaround using 2024 system - Dirt accumulation on the exterior, persistent between flights - Dual PMS 750/650 and TDS GTNxi 750/650 GPS configurations for those who want more GPS in the cockpit - Narco NS-800 RNAV configuration for those who want less GPS in the cockpit - STEC ST-901 GPSS module for those who want to follow magenta line on autopilot - Optional Asobo G5 electronic instrument retrofit - Other improvements like time compression support ‍ It will be a $14.99 upgrade for MSFS 2020 owners. ​ They followed up with a brief Q&amp;A regarding specific aspects of the product, such as livery compatibility and persistence files: Persistence (.dat files): You’ll be able to manually copy your 2020 files into the 2024 version to continue your aircraft history. Instructions will be provided at release; feel free to post on the A2A Forums if you need help. ‍ MSFS2020 liveries: They won’t work as-is, but can be updated to 2024 format (similar to the Aerostar transition). ‍ Aircraft replacement: The Native 2024 Comanche replaces the 2020 version for MSFS2024 users. Your MSFS2020 Comanche will continue working for those who want to keep it. ‍ Performance: Accu-Sim prioritises simulation over visuals. There’s only so much detail we can add before impacting performance and we tend to push as much as we can to the core simulation elements over the eye candy. The MSFS2024 Native Comanche uses optimized LODs and as a native model, keeping performance at least on par and often slightly improved over the 2020 version. ‍ Marketplace: Paid optional upgrade. We’ll coordinate with store partners so existing customers receive a discount. Marketplace releases usually take longer; the A2A Store and other vendors go live first. ‍ There’s still no information on the release date, but more details will be shared in the coming weeks. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flysbje24</id>
    <title>flyt Simulations Updates Jericoacoara Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flysbje24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69385b51e43554672176f031_je1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt Simulations has recently released a Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024-native version of Comandante Ariston Pessoa Regional Airport (SBJE), offering full compatibility, reduced VRAM usage, and additional features. Funded by a government plan to develop regional aviation in Brazil, construction work began in 2011 and concluded three years later. The inauguration, however, only took place in 2017 after a series of organizational mishaps. The passenger terminal, designed by Francisco Antonio Laprovitera Teixeira, consists of a single block with departure and arrival areas, food kiosks, bathrooms at each extremity, and—unfortunately—few check-in desks. Its 2200m runway is long enough to accommodate an Airbus A320 and its Boeing counterpart, the 737-800. ​ It’s served by Azul (Belo Horizonte), Azul Conecta (Fortaleza, Parnaíba), Gol Transportes Aéreos (São Paulo - Guarulhos), and LATAM Brasil (São Paulo - Guarulhos). The update introduces native MSFS 2024 compatibility, reduced VRAM usage, enhanced LOD optimization, new vegetation models, and terrain CGL changes.  ​ It’s available in the Marketplace for $9.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msstex</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Stranger Things Expansion for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msstex"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6939fa912fde9293d7bf5633_MSFS24_Spotlight_Keyart_V5.1_16x9_WithLogos-scaled.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a move that might turn a few heads, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 has received a free Stranger Things expansion, created in partnership with Netflix. The package drops the Simmer in Hawkins, Indiana, and asks them to support the town, as it faces lockdowns, patrols, and threats from the Upside Down. At the centre of the expansion is a Bell UH-1H Huey, in Hawkins Heli-Tours colours, flown under the watch of Murray Bauman. Players can complete five story-driven missions that include everything from rescue work to supply runs and chase sequences, before unlocking a tour mode that allows free exploration.  The release also adds a detailed recreation of Hawkins, with more than 40 recognisable locations from the series, along with themed avatar outfits and "supernatural encounters. The helicopter itself has been developed by Taog’s Hangar, which is now confirmed as a first-party partner on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024.   The Stranger Things Expansion is available now, through the in-sim Marketplace on PC, Xbox, and PlayStation. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rsfdec</id>
    <title>Rowsfire Opens Pre-orders for New 1:1 Panels</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rsfdec"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6939fe993d278c0f42dae6d9_rowsfire_a9cb7fa2-7310-4faf-8509-58c9f42fb826%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Rowsfire has opened pre-orders for a new range of 1:1-scale Airbus-style panels for home cockpit builders.  The line-up includes the A111 RMP-ACP Radio and Audio Panel, the A112 Cockpit Lighting and Weather Radar Integrated Panel, the A113 Cockpit Lighting, DFOR, and ATC Integrated Panel, and the A109 ATT, ADIRS, and EIS Integrated Panel.  ‍ According to the company, the first early-bird batch of A111, A112, and A113 units sold out within 2 days, and further production slots are now available. Each module is built with full-scale dimensions, dedicated hardware controls, and support for Microsoft Flight Simulator, via Rowsfire’s own interface layer.  The panels are intended to drop into existing desktop or shell cockpits, offering a more realistic alternative to mouse-driven virtual controls while keeping wiring and setup accessible to enthusiasts. Further details on pricing, availability, and the new panels can be found on the official website of Rowsfire. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sflyat</id>
    <title>SoFly Confirms December Release For AeroTone Audio Enhancer</title>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sflyat"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693a07a04524e948041eb647_aerotone.co_-_Google_Chrome_19-11-2025-22_15_30_b05508c2-0898-49fc-b64a-375a621c6fc5.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly has confirmed that AeroTone, its new audio enhancement add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, will release on Dec. 17, 2025.  The product was previously announced under the working title Aircraft Sound Enhancer, and has since been renamed and expanded. AeroTone is built around a custom in-sim panel that runs entirely inside the simulator, with no need for external tools. From this panel, users can adjust individual sound layers, fine-tune levels, and save profiles per aircraft.  Settings are stored and recalled from within the cockpit, so you can switch between aircraft and keep separate sound setups without additional configuration. On the audio side, SoFly has partnered with Echo19 to create a high-quality soundscape that reacts to the aircraft and environment. Ground roll, vibration, airframe stress, turbulence, touchdown effects, and avionics noise are all driven by in-sim conditions, with separate treatments for cockpit and cabin views.  AeroTone is compatible with every aircraft and vehicle by default, while more than 120 official profiles will ship at launch for popular types. Simmers can also create their own profiles, reset back to an official or community preset if needed, and import community-created configurations.  The intention, according to SoFly, is to make AeroTone easy to use for beginners, while still offering enough depth for those who wish to customise every detail. AeroTone also includes regionalised ATC ambience, with many hours of prerecorded chatter, that adapts to your current location and flight phase.  Different accent sets cover regions such as the United Kingdom, the United States, Europe, Australia, Africa, Asia, and Oceania, with distinct sets for ground operations and en-route traffic. AeroTone will be available for PC at launch, supporting both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, with game controller support included. SoFly plans to bring the add-on to Xbox and PlayStation 5 via the in-sim Marketplace after the initial release. Pricing has not yet been announced. Learn more here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ss680u</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Previews Citation C680 Sovereign+ For MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ss680u"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693afd810b86ca891f2ec171_Screenshot_2025-11-23_232724.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a recent Discord post, Skyward Simulations has shared some screenshots and a feature list for their upcoming Citation C680 Sovereign+ for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This will be the team's second project and represents a huge leap for the team. Their first project was the relatively simple Diamond DA-50RG. A far cry from a Citation in both speed and complexity. The team notes how much progress has been made on the new project and promises that a release date announcement is coming soon. So far, the new plane has been confirmed to feature a fully simulated electrical system, anti-ice system, SimBrief integration, checklists, FADEC, autothrottle, EFB, fully modeled interior, G5000 avionics, and much more.   With their ambitions set so high, hopefully, Skyward Simulations can deliver this beautiful bird to a virtual hangar near you soon. You can check out the full feature list and more on their Discord.  Their DA-50RG can be found on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace and Orbx. It was originally released for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, so it lacks some fidelity on the walkaround, but it still represents an enjoyable experience that will help set your expectations for what is to come. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrmotorworks</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases Motorworks: Traffic &amp; Transport (Europe) for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrmotorworks"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693b16518c519c243e3f1644_motor1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently released a comprehensive pack of European vehicles for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, replacing generic traffic, parking lot, and special scenery vehicles with over 40 unique and high-quality models. While the cars are European, they replace vehicles globally (sim limitation), spanning different regions, as listed on this map. All vehicles feature 4K textures (with a lower texture option for performance-constrained rigs), accurately scaled, properly LOD'd (allowing for a significant performance boost), and region-accurate license plates for Europe. Additionally, over 40 highly optimized parking lot vehicles are included. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $10, requiring at least 1.48 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inimanup</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Manchester Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inimanup"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693b182ae7e9c11fca03b879_inimanup.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their newly released Manchester Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing taxiway realignments, updated ground markings, and more.  ‍ Update v1.0.2 addresses visual bugs, misalignments, and adds missing airline parking codes, as well as taxi light adjustments, among other improvements. The complete changelog follows below: ​ v1.0.2 - Taxiways E &amp; D shifted as appropriate to allow additional parallel spacing - All markings, connections and lighting adjusted to suit - Changed layout of D/E connection at NC - Some taxi sign adjustments - Moved blast wall to correct diagonal position. - Moved GSE per above - Added missing airline parking codes - Fixed z-fighting T1/3 - Fixed floating approach light 23R - Fixed mast light colouring - Fixed bugged exclusion on default street lights ​ The scenery is available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $23.92, requiring at least 4.76 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atcvfr</id>
    <title>BeyondATC Announces VFR Support</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atcvfr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693b45fb1d4a36abbbf14bca_fgsgdg453.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. BeyondATC has released a YouTube video giving, the community insight into the program’s current status and future.  After the team spent 10 months stabilising the program's core features, they announced they are ready to move on to developing visual flight rules (VFR). The team plans to roll out VFR in phases, with coverage expanding over time.  In phase one, VFR coverage will be provided for the United States, the United Kingdom, and Australia, with a focus on circuit entry and exit. Phase two will introduce different types of airspace, while phase three will allow the completion of full VFR flights. The team notes that it will take time to roll out these features. However, if the developers’ plans go as expected, simmers will soon have new ways to integrate air traffic control into their flying experience.  To learn more about BeyondATC, you can check out their official website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fpifly</id>
    <title>Flight Panels Releases iFly 737 MAX8 Stream Deck Profile for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fpifly"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693b4c559033dabe4312487d_Store_-_iFly_Boeing_737_Max_8_-_Page_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flight Panels has released a new Stream Deck profile for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This time, the iFly Boeing 737 Max 8 is in focus. The package spans 34 pages and includes more than 1,200 images and over 830 custom-designed, pre-programmed buttons.  These mirror the layout and style of the iFly cockpit, allowing simmers to operate autopilot, radio, lighting, overhead systems, and other controls directly from their Stream Deck, rather than using a keyboard and mouse. The profile also exposes controls for ground services, aircraft performance information, ATIS, and various cockpit and cabin features.  It is designed to take advantage of newer MSFS 2024 features, including walkaround and external interaction points. Both 15 and 32 key layouts are included, with support for the Elgato Stream Deck XL, Stream Deck MK.2, Stream Deck Mobile on iOS and Android, and the Corsair Xeneon Edge.  The iFly 737 Max 8 Stream Deck profile is available now for $33 from the Flight Panels store and selected third-party marketplaces. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flight-sim-awards-2026---were-back</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Awards 2026  –  We’re Back</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flight-sim-awards-2026---were-back"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693ae05463e6d63e62e67e84_FLIGHTSIM_AWARDS_2026_at_FSWeekend__Celebrating_t_11-12-2025-15_14_45.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The Flight Sim Awards are coming back for 2026! The first award ceremony we held earlier this year was met with great enthusiasm from both developers and community members. All the feedback and lessons from last year have been taken into account, and efforts have been made to ensure that the Flight Sim Awards 2026 is bigger, better, and ready to celebrate in a meaningful way. The organizing committee, comprising FSElite, Cruiselevel, and Threshold, has been working diligently on the next ceremony, reviewing the structure to ensure a fair, transparent, and meaningful selection process. The awards continue to honour excellence and long-term contributions within the flight simulation community, recognizing achievements in development, creativity, and community engagement. In the updated structure, we aimed to create space for developers and creators who may not have fit naturally into previous categories. Each category has been reviewed to ensure relevance, clarity, and a balanced representation of the many areas that advance our hobby. We also added categories to highlight community contributions, which are often overlooked. All entries are evaluated according to shared principles: Each category represents a part of what makes flight simulation thrive: creativity, precision, and the human dedication behind the virtual skies. More information on the nomination process and jury panel will follow shortly. The next Flight Sim Awards ceremony will once again take place during the Captain’s Dinner at Flight Sim Weekend on Friday, March 20th, 2026. You can find more information on our website and tickets to FlightSimWeekend and the Captains Dinner here. Join the Flight Sim Awards Discord and be a part of the Awards community</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaerostaset</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaerostaset"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/693c5fc6827fb40830e4fac5_aerostarup.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently issued a new update to their Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, adding visible passengers on all seats, multiple bug fixes, and more. ‍ This update focuses on refining systems, sounds, visuals, physics, and avionics, with some quality-of-life improvements sprinkled on top. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Changelog MSFS 2020 Specific ‍ The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
