<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-01-03T18:22:01.708302+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gf2112</id>
    <title>Global Forests Updated to Version 2.1 for XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gf2112" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a9b5b0d00104be72bc3eb0_FQlvahYU.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="269798"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The well-known package for X-plane that enhances forestry and tree sceneries that are automatically generated has recently received a new update which promises to provide users with an entirely new and improved experience.  In their latest 2.1 version update, all regions have been re-compiled to bring the latest and most accurate version possible. Along with this, the team behind Global Forests have added coverage for South American rejoins, Which were previously not included.  Along with the news of their latest update, the team behind Global Forests have revealed it will now be available exclusively through Orbx.  To read more about the announcement you can follow this link!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hche</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Cheongju International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hche" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63aba1b4aaed7110b371340f_cheo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="370215"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Cheongju International Airport (RKTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Cheongwon-Ku, Daejeon, and Sejong with an yearly average of 2 million passengers. It was built as a military airbase in 1978, with the international airport plan to begin construction in 1984 and its eventual conclusion in December 1996, opening in April 1997.  Back in the 80s, Cheongju was selected as a potential construction site for Korea’s main international airport, but Incheon ended up being the chosen one.  The airport was built to handle the current yearly traffic (2 million people) and 196 thousand airplane operations, along with a parking lot big enough for 770 cars. It also happens to house a fighter wing of the Korean Air Force, which means taking photographs of the apron, runways, and the military facilities is strictly prohibited. It’s served by nine airlines, with a selection of domestic routes and international legs to China, Japan, Taiwan, and Thailand. Aero K and Asiana fly from Cheongju to Jeju, Bamboo Airways operates a seasonal leg to Quy Nhon, Jeju Air flies to Guam, Jeju, Osaka-Kansai, and Taipei-Taoyuan, Jin Air and Korean Air fly to Jeju, Sky Angkor Airlines operates a seasonal hop to Siem Reap, T’way Air flies to Da Nang, and Yakutia Airlines operates two seasonal journeys to Khabarovsk and Vladivostok. The scenery features an accurate rendition of RKTU, with custom jetways, dynamic lighting, PBR materials, animated humans, and performance friendly optimization. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.75, requiring at least 2 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pkskrg</id>
    <title>PKSIM Releases José María Córdova International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pkskrg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63acefed3e3fcfaa593ad1c0_skrg1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2976933"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PKSIM has recently released their rendition of José María Córdova International Airport (SKRG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, located in Rionegro, 20 km away from Medellín, serving the entire Medellin Metropolitan Area with many destinations, both domestic and international. It is the second busiest airport in Colombia with 9 million passengers yearly.   It’s a hub for Avianca Colombia, Ultra Air, and Viva Air Colombia, with a destination list that encompasses Colombia, Mexico, the United States, and some of Europe. LATAM Colombia also features a list of domestic destinations from Rionegro. Among the international visitors, there’s Aeromexico with a hop to Mexico City, Air Europa with a long haul to Madrid, JetBlue to Fort Lauderdale, LATAM Perú to Lima, and Spirit Airlines with the Floridian trifecta (Fort Lauderdale, Miami, and Orlando).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of SKRG, with a detailed terminal model, custom jetways, custom ground textures, the Avianca maintenance facility, custom night lighting, realistic ground markings, and a detailed control tower interior.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.12, requiring at least 1.48 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simrep</id>
    <title>SimCoders Releases Reality Expansion Pack SR22 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simrep" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ad0c13a1f81e76eda2c07f_rep1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1009292"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimCoders has recently released an expansion pack for the default Cirrus SR22 included in X-Plane 12, improving the flight dynamics, adding an interactive walkaround system, a mass and balance tool, a custom piston engine simulation, and more.   The Cirrus SR22 is a single-engine aircraft launched in 2001, manufactured in Duluth, Minnesota. It’s an “upgraded” SR20 with a more powerful engine, larger wings, and improved fuel capacity. It’s one of the most successful general aviation airplanes of the past twenty years, topping the sale charts since 2003 with over 6149 units built in total (as of 2019). It’s also the most produced GA aircraft of the 21st century.  The Reality Expansion Pack SR22 improves the default SR22 with a substantial list of new features, including a custom flight model with realism in mind, an advanced walkaround system with the possibility to check lights, cockpit, control surfaces, engine cowls, pitot tubes, etc., a mass and balance tool with a variable center of gravity depending on the load, a complex damage system triggered by pilot actions and based on real world data, a simulation state saving so that every switch and lever stays where it was when you closed the simulator, an economy system fully compatible with FSEconomy, a custom piston engine simulation with many realistic features, a custom electrical and avionics system with realistic battery behavior, custom simulation of hypoxia with its common symptoms such as tunnel vision and hard breathing, and native VR support. The complete feature list follows down below:  ‍  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $19.99.  Shout out to Luke on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xprimu</id>
    <title>X-Rotors Seeks Developer for AW139 Primus Flight System</title>
    <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xprimu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ade715274c6fcf8909a727_X-Plane_Screenshot_2022.12.14_-_21.55.38.15.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1716467"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Rotors, a leading developer of Helicopters in X-Plane, is seeking a talented developer to join their team in creating a hi-res OpenGL-designed Primus flight system for the AW139 helicopter. The AW139 is a famous aircraft for various applications, including offshore oil and gas transportation, emergency medical services, and VIP/corporate transportation. The Primus flight system is a state-of-the-art avionics suite that provides pilots with a wide range of information and capabilities, including navigation, communication, and flight management. ‍ The successful candidate will have experience in developing flight simulation systems using OpenGL, as well as a strong understanding of avionics and aircraft systems. They will work closely with the X-Rotors team to design and implement the Primus flight system, ensuring that it meets the high standards of realism and functionality expected in a professional flight simulator. If you are a developer with the skills and experience needed to contribute to this exciting project, we encourage you to apply. This is a unique opportunity to be a part of a cutting-edge development team and make a real impact on the future of flight simulation. To apply, please contact X-Rotor on their website. ‍ We have previously reviewed the AW109 from X-Rotors on our YouTube channel. You can see the video here. ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pr7lup</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737 Lineup Update</title>
    <updated>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pr7lup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63af73d41471189c580845c3_737-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="913368"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their 737 Lineup to version 3.00.0056, reducing code execution latency, virtual cockpit model improvements to improve rendering efficiency, fixing the parking brake lever lock switch keybind, and improved data display on the in-game HUD.  Regarding the 737-900, they have pushed a new beta build to the testers for data collection. It’s still being “tidied up” with an eventual release getting closer, although they reinforced it won’t be before 2023, as work continues on a broad array of features.  The PMDG Universal Flight Tablet will be added to the -900 testing program by next week, putting them in a good position to begin rolling out the first functions for the EFB. They plan to release one function at a time to not overload the beta testing team, aiming for an eventual continual update process that should cover the entire fleet of existing and upcoming aircraft. They also stated the tablet will be updated separately from the aircraft update channel, meaning it might evolve independently and faster than the airplane updates.  The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Images are courtesy of Genista. Shout out to Geeky on the Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsmvir</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Viru Viru International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsmvir" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63af79106cce8065cb874015_viru1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="951180"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released their rendition of Viru Viru International (SLVR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Santa Cruz de la Sierra in Bolivia. It’s the largest airport in the country in terms of passenger density, handling traffic from the Americas and Europe.   It’s the hub for Boliviana de Aviacíon, founded in 2007 and currently the biggest airline in the country, offering flights to Buenos Aires, Cochabamba, La Paz, Lima, Madrid, Miami, Oruro, São Paulo, Sucre, Tarija, and Trinidad. The regional EcoJet, from Cochabamba, also offers a wide variety of domestic legs to Cobija, Guayaramerín, Riberalta, Sucre, Tarija, and Trinidad. As far as international visitors go, there’s Aerolíneas Argentinas with a sole leg to Buenos Aires, Avianca with a leg to Bogota, Copa (Panama City), Gol (São Paulo), Latam Chile (Santiago), and Latam Perú (Lima). Miami is the busiest international destination as of 2016 with 386,496 passengers, followed by São Paulo (372,773), and Buenos Aires (358,943).  The scenery features a detailed rendition of SLVR, with custom night lighting, native MSFS dynamic lighting, seamless integration with default MSFS scenery, PBR materials, and native gITF models.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.57, requiring at least 1.7 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/upship</id>
    <title>Major Update To Global AI Ship Traffic For MSFS Released</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/upship" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b031be180a5604b1d7d189_ai-boats-ships-ai-msfszip-70-screen-71.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1384359"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Henrik Nielsen, the creator of a popular freeware utility add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, has released a major update for the product. The update, which brings the add-on to version 3.0, significantly improves the realism of the virtual world in the flight simulator by adding a wide variety of ships, boats, and ferries with realistic 3D models and authentic routes. One of the key features of the update is the addition of more than 400 new ship models from around the globe, including cruise ships, fishing boats, container ships, oil and gas tankers, and ferries. This brings the total number of unique ship models to almost 900, with a total of over 1,800 ships including repaints. The update also expands the coverage of ship routes, increasing traffic density in different regions. In addition to the new ship models, the update includes more than 100 new ferry routes and the ability to witness real-world naval exercises featuring ships from various countries. These exercises, which include full-scale NATO landing exercises on the West Coast of the Jutland Peninsula in Denmark and similar exercises by the Brazilian and Chinese navies in their respective areas, add a level of realism and immersion to the virtual world. Other features and improvements in the update include light, smoke, and wake effects on all ship models, as well as dynamic sounds for each type of ship model. The update is compatible with the latest sim update and has a minimal impact on performance, depending on the density of ship models in a given region. The download size is approximately 2.2 GB, with an installation size of 5.6 GB. To learn more about the update and how to download and install it, visit the Global AI Ship Traffic MSFS GAIST Ultra V3 page at flightsim.to. </summary>
    <published>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simsol</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Announce Diamond DA20 For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simsol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b03bc7699a14463bc31c35_DA27.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4183387"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimSolutions, a leading aircraft design and development brand in the flight sim community, has announced its “return to Diamond” with the Diamond DA20-C1 Eclipse for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This marks the company's first foray into the new simulator and represents a significant milestone in its efforts to provide users with the most accurate and detailed aircraft models possible. According to the developer, the decision to create the DA20-C1 for MSFS was inspired by a personal passion for flying the aircraft. "Being the aircraft that I currently fly, I thought it was only fitting to remodel it with as much detail as I can to give an accurate model and operation of the DA20-C1”. "I am thrilled to have made the decision to create this aircraft for MSFS, but it will take some time." While the development of the DA20-C1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator is currently the group's top priority, it has not ruled out the possibility of releasing a version for X-Plane in the future. "An X-Plane version will likely come later," the development team said. SimSolutions expressed its gratitude to its supporters and wished them a Happy New Year. "We thank you so much for the support this year and are wishing you a very Happy New Year," To find out more, visit their Discord </summary>
    <published>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbr757</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Announce New Project and Progress Update on 757</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbr757" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b0b52ec67b7de6cfd68cdc_sneak_peek4.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="171873"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Bluebird Simulations has recently announced that it has a new project in the works. While details about the project are currently scarce, the company has stated that it will provide updates on the progress of the project in the coming months. Although details are being kept quiet, they have provided this teaser:  In the meantime, Bluebird Simulations is continuing to focus on its core project, the 757 addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Fans of the project can expect to see lots of updates on development progress and new features for the 757 in the coming weeks. This news is sure to be exciting for flight simulator pilots, who have come to rely on Bluebird Simulations teaser photos and development updates for their MSFS 757 fix!  Stay tuned for further updates from Bluebird Simulations as the team continues to work on its new project and further the 757 toward release.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jstgir</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Girona-Costa Brava Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jstgir" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b105fde039e62ff6bf08bf_girona1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="513764"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. JustSim has recently released their rendition of Girona-Costa Brava Airport (LEGE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Girona in north-eastern Catalonia. It averages around 2 million passengers per year, peaking during the summer when nine european airlines (Brussels Airlines, Enter Air, Jet2.com, LOT Polish Airlines, Ryanair, Smartwings, Transavia, TUI Airways, and TUI Fly Belgium) add the city to their destination list. The Irish low-cost carrier is the only one to maintain a fixed schedule throughout the year, although fairly limited (Kraków, London Stansted, Nuremberg, and Pisa).  Built in 1965, Girona had modest traffic figures up until the early 2000s, when Ryanair chose it as their “Barcelona” due to its proximity with the Catalan Capital, and cheaper landing fees and operating costs. The airport saw an increase from mere 275,000 passengers in 1993 to over 5 million during the “Ryanair era” which ended in 2012 when they decided to move the operations to El Prat. Traffic figures got halved a year after, and it has been consistently around that ballpark ever since. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport and its facilities, with custom ground textures, landside buildings, custom clutter, and updated taxiways. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.06 (with a discount for owners of the P3D/XP11 version), requiring at least 1.67 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/essvsl</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Freeware Visby Airport (ESSV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/essvsl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b124d9a9c234497d169cd7_essv9-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="373711"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Skyline Simulations released its rendition of	 Visby Airport (ESSV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. A freeware, the scenery brings the users into the kingdom of Sweden with its high quality textures and objects. 	Visby Airport, located in Gotland, Sweden, is the region's only commercial airport. It is served by airlines such as SAS, Finnair, Ryanair, and Norwegian Air Shuttle. In 2016, the airport saw some 460,000 passengers, mainly in the summer months. 	According to Skyline Simulations, the scenery is built using the latest layout of Visby Airport using UHD and PBR textures for the ground, decal, buildings. In addition, there is 3D vegetation and ground traffic all around the airport. Finally, custom night textures are also included to add to the immersion. Currently, Visby Airport is a freeware available to download from Skyline Simulation’s webstore. The developer recommends users to have 1.22 GB of free hard drive space to successfully install the product.</summary>
    <published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taismf</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Sacramento International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12 </title>
    <updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taismf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b2f3829c897f5ecafea5f1_smf1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4061105"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Sacramento International Airport (KSMF) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the gateway to the California State Capitol. It’s the sixth busiest airport in California, averaging 11 million passengers yearly as of November 2022.   Boasting 50% of the traffic market share, Southwest Airlines is the largest airline in Sacramento as of 2021, followed by American Airlines (677,052) and Delta (665,468), with 11.83% and 11.63%, respectively. The busiest domestic destination is San Diego, with 540,000 passengers per year, transported by either Southwest or Alaska Airlines. Las Vegas takes second place with 529,000 (Frontier, Southwest, and Spirit), and Denver (Frontier, Southwest, and United) is third with 458,000. The international destination list includes Vancouver (Air Canada Express), Guadalajara (Aeroméxico and Volaris), León, and Mexico City (Volaris).   It is also the gateway to famous attractions in Northern and Central California like Lake Tahoe, Yosemite National Park, Old Sacramento State Historic Park, Yolo Bypass Wildlife Area, Cosumnes River Preserve, Hawver Cave, and Marshall Gold Discovery State Historic Park.   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of KSMF, with SAM jetways, high-quality PBR textures on objects and ground, performance-oriented optimization, autogen around the airport, ground traffic plugin with cars and trucks, and weather textures for X-Plane 12.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket and X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $20.50, requiring at least 765 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksdub</id>
    <title>MK Studios Previews Dublin Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksdub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b2fd0d83feb76a29cbd780_dub1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="516993"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently uploaded three preview pics of their upcoming Dublin Airport v2 (EIDW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, announced in  August 2022. It’s said to be a complete rework with new ground textures,  models, and layout.   DUB is the busiest airport on the island of Ireland, with a yearly average of 32 million passengers. The second place, Belfast International Airport, sits at just a fraction of that amount with 6 million passengers. It is the hub for Aer Lingus, Ireland’s national carrier, with an extensive route network encompassing North America and Europe. It also hosts Ryanair, one of the largest low-cost carriers in the world, featuring a significant domestic and intra-European network.  MK Studios’ first iteration of Dublin Airport came out in November 2020, one of the first payware airports for the then brand new simulator, featuring a fully detailed rendition of the airport, with updated ground layout and stands (not anymore), a terminal interior model, AI compatibility, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s still available on SimMarket and Orbx Direct for roughly $10. Owners will be eligible for a discounted price once V2 is available.   There is no information on the release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/coconc</id>
    <title>Colimata Releases Concorde FXP v3 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/coconc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b3f0b0e4af5c5099c128e4_conc1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1280024"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Colimata has recently released the third version of their Concorde add-on, especially for X-Plane 12 (not compatible with X-Plane 11). It’s said to bring their product to a new level in terms of visuals, flight model, and functionality.   The Concorde was a supersonic passenger airplane operated by British Airways and Air France between 1976 and 2003. It was developed in the 1960s as a joint venture between the British and French governments, making its first flight in 1969. It was known for its sleek, delta-wing design and the ability to fly at speeds of up to Mach 2, or twice the speed of sound (it was the first commercial airplane to break the sound barrier and could fly from London to New York in just over three hours). Despite its short service life, the Concorde remains an iconic and influential aircraft in aviation history.  The Colimata Concorde is a highly detailed and realistic aircraft simulation for X-Plane 12, featuring a 3D cockpit with front, center, roof, side and engineering panels. The cockpit features 4K texturing and over 1000 click regions, as well as 700+ custom lights for warning lamps, night lighting, and exterior lights. The aircraft also includes a PRO or STANDARD complexity setting. The external model is equally detailed, with accurate 3D modeling, moving engine parts, and opening doors and service panels. The flight model offers realistic takeoff and landing behavior, and refined subsonic and supersonic flight. The sound design is immersive, with 3D audio and a wide variety of sound effects. It’s fully VR-compatible and includes an autopilot with 16+ functions. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ 3D COCKPIT EXTERNAL MODEL   FLIGHTMODEL   SOUND   VR   IN ADDITION     MANUALS ‍  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $54.95 (on sale), requiring at least 600 MB of free disk space. Owners of the previous version are eligible for an upgrade discount. Shout out to PrivatePilot on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrgnx</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Previews East Midlands Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrgnx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b3fa3c5b09f42118975625_gnx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2867697"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue has recently published a roadmap for 2023 with their many plans for the new year, including a couple of preview images of his upcoming East Midlands Airport (EGNX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, developed with ‘incredible attention to detail’ and featuring ‘numerous exciting features.’ He’s also announced an eventual update to his Edinburgh Airport (EGPH) with ‘new models, textures, mesh, custom satellite imagery, and more.’ The preview images show the control tower and the Rolls Royce Hangar, built by RPS Group and designed to accommodate separate heritage and corporate hangars.  ‍ The hangars are connected by a central spine and feature a dedicated maintenance and workshop space for each one. Additionally, there is a shared area for conferences, offices, a seminar space, a library, crew and locker rooms, and restrooms. The design even had children and students in mind with a STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) facility where they could attend training events and seminars. The project (the real-life counterpart) was developed in close contact with Rolls Royce, with all their requirements in mind, from the concept to the space planning and detail design. ‍  East Midlands Airport is located in Leicestershire, England, and serves the East Midlands region of the country, including the cities of Derby, Leicester, and Nottingham. It is the largest cargo airport in the UK and the seventh busiest airport in terms of passenger numbers. In 2020, the airport handled around 5 million passengers and over 200,000 tonnes of cargo.   It has a single terminal and serves a variety of airlines, including budget carriers such as Ryanair and easyJet, as well as traditional carriers like British Airways and KLM. The airport has a diverse route network, with direct flights to destinations across Europe and some long-haul destinations in the Middle East and the Caribbean. Domestically, the airport has good connectivity to major cities in the UK, including London, Manchester, and Glasgow.  ‍ Facility-wise, it has a range of amenities for passengers, including a range of shops and restaurants, as well as lounges and a business center. The airport also has good transport links, with a railway station located within the terminal building and regular bus and coach services to nearby cities and towns. In recent years, the airport has undergone several expansion projects to improve its capacity and facilities, and it is well-regarded as a modern and efficient airport.  There’s no information regarding the release date or pricing yet, but we’ll keep you informed once there’s new intel. Shout out to Luke on our Discord for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
