<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-02-21T18:25:17.682710+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vertpa</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Tampa International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vertpa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ec06a25f90b7e2d650c2e2_tampa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1075288"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Tampa International Airport (KTPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Tampa Bay Area in Florida with more than 93 non-stop destinations throughout the globe.  Tampa is known as the birthplace of commercial airline service, when a Benoist Flying Boat took off from St. Petersburg (Florida) to Tampa Airboat Line in early 1914, consecrating itself as the first scheduled commercial flight in the world. It was a 23-mile-long flight, and the service ran for about five months. The airport itself dates back to 1928, then called Drew Field. It was heavily used during WW2 for training, where it underwent modernization and expansion.   Post-war, it went back to its original role of being just an airport, with its first international flights to begin a couple of years later, in 1950. A new terminal reached completion not long after, in 1952. A decade later, with the popularity of jet aircraft and many new airlines flying to Tampa, expansion became a priority, with the authorities planning a replacement terminal in an undeveloped site at the airport, whose production kicked off in 1968 and completion came three years later, increasing the capacity and consolidating Tampa as an important domestic and international destination.   The airport collects several quality awards, including Best Overall U.S. Airport in 2007 and 2008 by Zagat Survey, Second Best Airport in the World by Condé Nas in 2008, and 6th place on CNN’s Ten of the World’s Most Loved Airports, and it’s considered by Airports Council International as the best airport in America for its size (2020).  With an average of 20 million passengers yearly, Tampa is served by most major domestic airlines, including Southwest (27.81% of the market share), Delta Air Lines (17.52% of the market share), American Airlines (16.89% of the market share), United Airlines (10.69% of the market share), and Spirit Airlines (10.03% of the market share). The top domestic destinations list includes Atlanta (925,000 passengers), Chicago-O’Hare (463,000), and Charlotte (450,000).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with an updated taxiway layout, animated passengers with “half-interior” airside and terminals, proper AI routing and vehicle pathing, realistic airline codes, custom taxi signs, custom airport lighting, a blend of custom and photorealistic imagery, animated HVAC fans, flags, and trams, handcrafted mesh with taxiway bridges, high-resolution color-graded imagery, surrounding area landmarks (Raymond James, International Plaza, Grand Hyatt, etc.).  It’s available on Verticalsim’s Shop for $21.99, requiring at least 4.12 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navios</id>
    <title>Navigraph Charts Beta Release for IOS and Android </title>
    <updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navios" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ecf9699462032e52b73501_navigraph.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="274608"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight sim navigation services provider Navigraph has just announced an open BETA for their charts application on mobile devices that operate using either IOS or Android. This is welcome news to many in the flight sim community who have been waiting eagerly for the announcement.  Instructions to sign up on IOS are as follows: press the link to Join the TestFlight beta program below. The Charts app will be installed via the TestFlight app. Links for the Android-based APK and other information surrounding the beta can be found on the Navigraph website.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniokc</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Oklahoma City Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniokc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ed4e066624e16f8534be7d_okc1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1480883"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of Oklahoma City Airport (KOKC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest commercial airport in Oklahoma with a yearly average of 4 million passengers.  Oklahoma City Airport, or Will Rogers World Airport, first opened in 1911 as Oklahoma City Municipal Airfield renamed 30 years later after Will Rogers. It served as a major training facility during WW2, with over fifteen air force groups stationed there over the course of the war. Post-war saw commercial activity in the late fifties, with over 48 daily commercial flights from different airlines.  ‍ In the late 90s, expansion talks ensued from the old age of the original terminal, dating back to 1967. Plans launched not much later, in 2001, with the demolition of the twin concourses to make room for the new project: a larger terminal with high ceilings and modern facilities. One hundred and ten million dollars, and five years later, the project finally reached completion, with the third phase still pending.  The aforementioned third phase only happened in March 2019, finishing roughly two years later, substantially increasing the passenger handling capacity and the overall quality of the facilities.  iniBuilds’ rendition will feature an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with a fully modeled interior, up-to-date airport and terminal layout, HD textures, 3D people, detailed jetways, correct airline parking allocations, fully modeled landside, and custom taxi signs.   There’s no information regarding pricing or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shaazi</id>
    <title>Shadescene Releases Sultan Abdul Aziz Shah Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shaazi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ed59d949b58bbd48b7bfca_subcover-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1394293"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Shadescene has recently released their rendition of Sultan Abdul Aziz Shah Airport (WMSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the township of Subang, in Petaling District (Selangor, Malaysia), with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  It used to be Kuala Lumpur’s main airport from 1965 to 1998, before the opening of Kuala Lumpur International Airport in Sepang. Original plans suggested a conversion to a low-cost carrier base, but the residents voted against it. It was repurposed to serve general aviation and turboprop domestic and international flights.  It’s the base for SKS Airways, Firefly, Batik Air Malaysia, and Raya Airways.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with a replica of the famous old terminal 1, custom terraforming, custom scenery objects for the terminal, high-resolution textures, hand-placed taxiways, and runway light system, full day and night lighting, and hand-crafted ground markings and textures. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.90 (currently on sale for 10.71), requiring at least 140 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boulin</id>
    <title>Boundless Publishes Further Information on Dublin Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boulin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ed89e34f9bfc9fb4a53a04_boundless1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="358209"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently posted on their Facebook page with new information on the upcoming update for Dublin Airport (EIDW), including pricing, upgrade fees, and more.   Dublin Airport is the 12th busiest airport in Europe, with a yearly average of 30 million passengers. It hosts their flag carrier Aer Lingus, the low-cost carrier beast Ryanair, and TUI Airways, with a significant route network that encompasses most of Europe and some key cities in North America.   As previously mentioned, the new update will include full X-Plane 12 compatibility, overhauled lighting, the integration of the new runway, Terminal 1 lighting improvements, airside traffic (X-Plane 12), new fence models, new ground textures, partially photorealistic textures based on 2023 imagery, performance improvements, general bug fixes, new ground service equipment vehicles with updated liveries, road network improvements, and more. They have now mentioned the addition of optional animated ground traffic using the Living Scenery Technology plugin, with instructions to be included with the download.   The base price of the Dublin package will be increased from roughly $24 to $26.47, reflecting the additional work and expenses. It will be a free upgrade for existing users. Threshold will let you know once the scenery is out! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fre767</id>
    <title>Project76 B767 Updated to Version 0.6.7</title>
    <updated>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fre767" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ee1d509d44a3a863bdbf40_144913730_B767-2023-02-1516_48_23.png.1aa56b46b2d0b983e3a255306014269c.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1381835"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Freeware Boeing 767 project “project76” has just been updated to version 0.6.7. This is a project I personally have been following for some time and it continues to impress update after update. The latest update for the aircraft brings a host of improvements, additional new features and fixes!  ‍ The full changelog for version 0.6.7 (alpha) features the following:  - Cockpit lighting   - added lighting for panel instruments, backlit marks, floodlights, and dome lights   - added dimmers for cockpit lighting   - added dimmers for FMS CDU panels   - added dimmers for ADI, HSI, and EICAS CRT displays ‍ - Winglets   - added type-accurate winglets, including lights   - added menu option to toggle winglets on and off   - includes default winglet textures plus separate textures for several bundled liveries ‍ - Panel instrument graphics   - updated to 4K higher resolution graphics   - fully custom ADI with FMA, dual cue FD, speed trend arrow, and other indications   - improved accuracy of EICAS graphics   - added screen glow to all CRT displays   - altered registration placard to white letters on black ‍ - Exterior graphics   - added metal windshield frames to the base livery and several bundled liveries   - updated tail surfaces to include metal leading edges ‍ - Cockpit windows   - enabled animation for opening/closing Pilot and Copilot windows, including hand cranks   - added menu options for opening/closing cockpit windows ‍ - Engine Start   - improved accuracy of the engine start sequence   - corrected engine fuel cut-off switch operation ‍ - Flight Model   -various tweaks to plane maker settings to improve overall drag, performance, and handling ‍ - Autopilot   - enabled LNAV functionality   - used XP11 default airliner autopilot modes to create semi-realistic Boeing 767 Autopilot and Autothrottle You can pick up the latest version of the Aircraft here!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simupd</id>
    <title>Simbrief Receives Massive Update and Overhaul </title>
    <updated>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simupd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ee3e38bcfb61e9a3cf71b9_Logo_SimBrief_Navigraph.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="53395"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simbrief is the most popular and widely used flight sim dispatch system which is offered for free by parent company Navigraph. It’s been a considerable amount of time since anything major has changed with SimBrief after the acquisition by Navigraph… Until now that is! Simbrief has received a complete re-design and new look which streamlines the entire service and gives it a fresh, new, easy-to-use look.  The new SimBrief look has certainly gone down well with the flight sim community so far since its release a short time ago, many think it is a fantastic new design which not only makes it easier to use but adds more neat features such as personal flying statistics.  ‍ Other new features in this update include:  You can check this latest version of simbrief out for yourself over at www.simbrief.com ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsbru</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Brussels South Charleroi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsbru" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ee9457b3a8f928620b0319_bru1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3260154"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Brussels South Charleroi Airport (EBCI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, also referred to as Brussels-Charleroi Airport. It is the second busiest airport in Belgium, with a yearly average of 8 million passengers (pre-pandemic).  Charleroi is a popular low-cost alternative to Brussels Airport (EBBR), being an important hub for Ryanair, WizzAir, and TUI fly Belgium, both offering an extensive intra-European network. It’s also home to Air Belgium, a scheduled and charter airline founded six years ago offering many holiday destinations, including Guadeloupe, Martinique, Mauritius, and South Africa. The history of Brussels-Charleroi dates back to 1919 when it used to be a flying school, with maintenance activities to start a year later. To this day, it’s still a busy general aviation airfield with three flying schools.  The airport’s traffic grew in the late 1990s when Ryanair embraced Charleroi for the first time (it went on to become one of their continental bases). Other low-cost carriers like WizzAir soon joined the trend, increasing the traffic figures and justifying the construction of a new terminal, which opened in early 2008 with a capacity for up to 5 million passengers a year. It wasn’t long until it reached that limit, which led to the creation of a second terminal in 2017, accommodating up to 10 million passengers a year.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with custom buildings around the area, custom vehicles, custom objects and clutter, navigation infrastructure, and custom lighting. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.26, requiring at least 680 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/evex12</id>
    <title>Everest UHD Scenery For XP12 </title>
    <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/evex12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63ef825ab5f56962971c7e17_A11F.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="226719"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Talented scenery developers, Frank Dainese and Fabio Bellini have teased the latest project of their mountain scenery masterpieces, Everest UHD for XP12. This brings the Nepal mountain range and an area of around 7000 square Kilometers of stunning scenery to Xplane 12. The other detailed mountains included are Lhotse, Makalu, Cho Oyu, Nuptse, Pumori, Ama Dablam, Taboche and Baruntse. All were reconstructed in 3D with models derived from further modified DEM data. The scenery also includes in-depth recreations of 7 airports including the infamous Lukla and 8 heliports.  It is currently unclear as to when exactly this scenery will become available but we expect it won't be very long!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbmoe</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Oslo Gardermoen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbmoe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63efeded4697640e5616d345_garden.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2060806"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Norway with 30 million passengers per year. Opened 25 years ago, Gardermoen replaces the outdated Fornebu Airport, which used to be the main airport in Oslo from its inception in 1939 to 1998. Bigger, substantially more modern, and with better accessibility, the new airport went on to become the busiest airport in Scandinavia.  Sporting over 200 destinations (domestic and international), OSL is a hub for Norse Atlantic Airways, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Wideroe. The visitors' list includes most major european airlines, such as Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Swiss, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish, and WizzAir. Trondheim (2,092,000), Bergen (1,987,000), and Stavanger (1,603,000) are among the top three busiest destinations from Gardermoen, further reinforcing the strength of domestic operations in the airport.  The scenery features detailed modeling and texturing of the terminal and surrounding buildings and hangars, with PBR texturing in 4K, interior modeling, three different types of animated jetways to match the real world, fully functioning VDGS for all appropriate gates, animated traffic, custom ground service equipment, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.62, requiring at least 6.34 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hlog</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Lognes Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hlog" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63eff582374b9224a3b7831e_lognes1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2427388"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Lognes-Émerainville aerodrome (LFPL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the community of Lognes in the suburbs of Paris (roughly 28 km east of it).  Opened to public air traffic in 1947, it’s the biggest private light aircraft aerodrome in the country, with the unusuality of being open to international traffic, unlike many other french airfields. The fact it sits close to five other aerodromes makes it extremely handy for flight schools, increasing its traffic figures. Lognes is open to light aviation under VFR, handling up to 80,568 aircraft movements back in 2014, ranking it within the top 10 in France (movement-wise).  With a 700-meter-long paved runway and a 1,100-meter-long grass runway, the airfield is ideal for small general aviation aircraft, especially trainers such as the 152, 172, etc. As a curiosity, Lognes hosts AGILE, an association created in 1983 whose focus is the management of the 25 to 30 aircraft that belong to the club’s members.The scenery features an accurate rendition of the aerodrome, with PBR texturing based on on-site photography, detailed modeling including the tower interior, animated humans, and custom lighting.  It’s available for free on SimMarket, requiring at least 275 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthnas</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Nashville International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthnas" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f006fabb25c11a994ce745_nash1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1222254"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Nashville International Airport (KBNA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Nashville Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 18 million passengers.  Opened in June 1937, passenger service started a month later with American Airlines and Eastern Air Lines. It originally featured three runways, a three-story passenger terminal, a control tower, two hangars, and a beacon. The yearly figures hit nearly 190,000 passengers.  It was used as the headquarters for the 4th Ferrying Command during World War 2, ferrying aircraft to Europe at the height of the war. The ferrying operations demanded a lot of space, which implied an expansion to 1,500 acres of total area.   Nearly a decade later, the City Aviation Department made plans to modernize and expand the airport, with a new terminal, runway expansion, and a new crosswind runway to come in 1961.  As a curiosity, Nashville Intl. was the first municipal airport in the United States with a public reading room.   It has seen a lot of expansion work over the following years, with its peak in the late 1980s, when American Airlines made a hub in Nashville and attracted many companies to the city, such as Nissan and Saturn Corporation. The hub eventually closed in 1995, when American couldn’t afford to lose any more money (it wasn’t profitable even during its heyday).   The airport has been recently modernized, with operations starting in 2006 and reaching its conclusion five years later, expanding the ticketing and check-in areas, renovating and constructing new bathrooms, and bringing the total size of the terminal to 1 million square feet. In 2021, the operator made a plan called “New Horizon” to further improve the airport, at the cost of 1.5 billion USD. Construction is set to begin in 2023 and reach completion in late 2028.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with over a hundred custom-modeled buildings, taxi bridges, custom night lighting, custom jetways, and custom ground polygon.   It’s available on SimMarket and on FeelThere’s Shop for $21.39/$19.99 (respectively), requiring at least 609 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bb7572</id>
    <title>BlueBird Sim 757, One-Year Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bb7572" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f2505d1ab2a2cf1b8707b4_fuse.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="931493"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BlueBird Simulations have released a youtube video in which they celebrate the one-year anniversary of the development of their upcoming Boeing 757 aircraft for MSFS. In the update, the team thanked those who have contributed to the project, answered various questions the community has had and displayed some of the aircraft's features in flight.  BlueBird has confirmed the expected release date is q3/q4 of 2023. They have also confirmed that they are developing both a freighter and passenger variant of the single-isle jet, the passenger variant will come first followed by the freighter expansion. The freighter and passenger jets will be two separate packages according to the team.  The team have also disclosed that they are aiming for a mid-level simulation, in which every switch and system needed for normal operation will be operable. It will boast a fully custom FMS with full LNAV and VNAV capability. The team have also confirmed a full virtual cabin will be in the aircraft.  You can watch the video here: </summary>
    <published>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbkden1</id>
    <title>FlightBeam Updates KDEN to V1.1.0</title>
    <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbkden1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f2539d76f9542bb9be11f7_eba5cc_996d6fd0592741c498f891efdfd19e71_mv2.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="710378"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam has updated its Denver airport scenery to version 1.1.0! The new update brings a host of new features and improvements, including the new west side expansion with new gates (concourse B) It also incorporates the new and improved gen5 jetways from Flightbeam for added immersion.  The update is free to those who own the airport scenery and is a massive enhancement to the original scenery, this update brings Denver to the highest possible level of accuracy.  Full changelog:  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwsfar</id>
    <title>Realworldscenery Releases Fairbanks International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwsfar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f3eede681ebde1bcedc025_fair1-min.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1115507"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Realworldscenery has recently released their rendition of Fairbanks International Airport (PAFA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Fairbanks (Alaska), the smallest city in the country with regularly scheduled non-stop international flights.  The airport’s history dates back to 1951, when it replaced Ladd Army Airfield as the gateway to Fairbanks, serving as Alaska Airlines’ main hub up until 1967 when they moved to Anchorage, yet keeping the Anchorage - Fairbanks service. It was also an important stopover for Braniff International, Pan American World Airways, American Airlines, and Western Airlines in the 60s and 70s. To conform with the current TSA standards, the original terminal (from 1948) was entirely demolished and replaced by a brand new one in late 2009, featuring better design and security, an extra jetway bridge (six instead of five), handling an average of 1 million passengers per year.  It’s the hub for Everts Air, operating scheduled and charter airline cargo all across Alaska and Canada with a fleet of classic aircraft, including the C-46, the Douglas DC-6, and the Douglas MD-83. It also hosts Warbelow’s Air Ventures and Wright Air Service. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom-made buildings, performance-friendly optimization, and a realistic taxiway layout.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.58, requiring at least 1.3 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/salber</id>
    <title>Salvuz Releases Bergen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/salber" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f3fbca8a0b4eb5c41a7929_sal1-min%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3619390"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Salvuz has recently released their rendition of Bergen Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Norway with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Dating back to the early 1950s, Bergen Airport was partially funded by the municipalities of Bergen and Fana with 4 million Norwegian kroner, securing the construction of a terminal and a 1,460-meter-long runway. NATO funded an expansion in 1953, warranting a 2,440-meter-long runway instead. When the first flight landed at the airport in mid-1954, only 800 meters of it were complete. It was a chartered flight from Bergen to Oslo, transporting a local football team.  It’s a hub for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe, with an extensive domestic and intra-European network. According to 2014 data, Scandinavian Airlines had 46% of the market share for domestic flights, Norwegian had 38%, and Widerøe 15%. International-wise, Norwegian led the way with 36%, SAS had 23%, and KLM with 18% (with a single route to Amsterdam).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, sporting handcrafted buildings and facilities with detailed interiors, PBR texturing in 2K or 4K, two custom jetway models, precise terrain markings according to the latest charts, sloped runways with accurate altitude profiles, and parking stands as per latest AIP charts.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.24, requiring at least 1.6 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
