<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-07-05T18:26:02.841845+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teiwjn</id>
    <title>Threshold Exclusive: Interview with Jorg Neumann at Flight Sim Expo 2023</title>
    <updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teiwjn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649b7ae278a746c25b357ea3_IMG_3855.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1180721"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft’s presentation on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 was the most well-attended announcement at Flight Sim Expo 2023. It has been almost three years since they released the platform, and everyone is excited about the upcoming MSFS 2024. I had the privilege to sit down with Jorg Neumann, head of Microsoft Flight Simulator, to talk about the recently announced simulator. ‍ Threshold: This is your first time at the Flight Sim Expo. How are you liking it so far? ‍ Neumann: It’s wonderful. We often go to big games shows—like back in the day E3 or Gamescom—with like tens of thousands of people, but this is more focused. It’s a single group of people who share a hobby and you can feel that they love it. Everyone is incredibly friendly and encouraging, and it feels like a community that’s very healthy. We’re very happy to finally be here for the first time. ‍ Threshold: When you envisioned Flight Sim 2024, what was the overall goal that you wanted to achieve? ‍ Neumann: Flight Sim is a platform, right, and we want to empower people. That’s actually the number one thing we try to do. Because the creator community that has formed is critical. It’s absolutely critical to the success of this field.  ‍ Threshold: What in particular do you want Flight Sim 2024 to address? ‍ Neumann: The sheer amount and size of addons. It was probably unexpected how much has been created already. We are now counting over 3,000 addons, with about 100 a week. We know that we need to enable that for the long haul. ‍ Threshold: What is the main challenge? ‍ Neumann: Flight Sim 2020 was just never conceived for the amount of data that’s coming in. And then on top of that, I promised that we would do monthly updates, and I’m totally determined to keep doing that. I should have just looked at the tally of gigabytes going up month over month over month. We’re now at 300-something gigabytes. We just plotted this out and said: ‘Holy moly, we’re going to be at 1 terabyte soon, and then we’re going to be at 2 terabytes, and nobody can download this stuff anymore.’ It's crazy! ‍ Threshold: How are you addressing that? ‍ Neumann: We knew we needed to make an architectural change that basically offloads more to the cloud, because you can stream infinitely, the ecosystem is no longer limited. Right now we are running out of memory sometimes. When a highly complex plane comes in, like a PMDG plane, it’s so detailed. We run into limitations, and I don’t want those limitations to keep the sim from being the best it can be. So we’ve changed the architecture fundamentally to go to a thin client. That enables groups like PMDG to make infinitely detailed planes. It sets us up for the long term. ‍ Threshold: There have been questions about access for addon developers, for access to different APIs. As an example, with MSFS 2024, would weather radar APIs be available for developers? ‍ Neumann: The weather radar is technically a little bit outside what I know specifics on, but as far as I understand what they’re asking for, we don’t have it. It’s not like we are the jerks who don’t want to give access to something, we just don’t have the memory. I believe it’s because, like I just said, we’re running out of resources. To have the weather for the entire platform, there’s nothing to be shared at this moment. I have to defer to some of the experts on the team to talk about this more, but the intent is always to empower people to do their best work. So every time you see us as not doing something, there’s a technical reason for it, not a political one. ‍ Threshold: Thank you, and I know we’re all looking forward to getting a chance to fly MSFS 2024. Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is shaping up to be a promising new simulator that will undoubtedly change the world of flight simulation!  ‍ Threshold will keep you updated with all things MSFS 2024, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fserrn</id>
    <title>FSExpo Reports Record Numbers for 2023 Event!</title>
    <updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fserrn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649b945c4a02e1701cb803ff_Z8A0350.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1541807"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. ‍ ‍ Just this past weekend, more than 1,900 flight simmers, exhibitors, and pilots descended on hot and humid Houston, Texas for Flight Sim Expo 2023! Attendees hailed from 30 countries and 5 continents, with over 70 exhibitors being present for a hands-on experience showcasing home flight simulation and many aspects of real world aviation! ‍ The event took off on Friday, June 23 with a series of product announcements that included announcements of upcoming hardware from Thrustmaster, the new Ford 4-AT Trimotor from Microsoft Flight Simulator, a multitude of new hardware products including the new Delta Flight Displays from Honeycomb, and a further update on what will be included with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024! A few developers made their announcements via video reveal, including A2A Simulations with their upcoming Comanche 250, and the A300-600 by iniBuilds. ‍ On Saturday and Sunday, attendees had the chance to explore the exhibit hall and try the latest and greatest in flight simulation technology, including virtual reality devices, yokes, joysticks, and even GPS replicas. Along with many flight simulation developers being at the Expo, many content creators were there, with Jeff Faviagno, Chewwy94, Cpt. Canada, Swiss001, BluGames, and XP72 were all present. ‍ During all this, seminars were held and featured a variety of community based content. Highlights include a panel about the business of flight simulation, a panel on content creation, a home cockpit building workshop, and several ‘getting started’ seminars to help newcomers find their wingsEven though the show is now over, you can watch all 30 of the seminars in high definition. Visit flightsimexpo.com to see the full list of content available, and to purchase instant access for just $15. The content will be available for on-demand viewing until July 31st, and every purchase helps support the event in future years.   ‍ “Over the next few weeks, we look forward to connecting with attendees, exhibitors, sponsors, and other developers from around the community to prepare for our next show,” says organizer Evan Reiter. “Please be on the lookout for surveys and meeting invitations in the coming days!”   ‍ Flight Sim Expo is always an exciting time for flight simulation, and Threshold will keep you up to date on all the developments from there, so stay tuned! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/emidms</id>
    <title>Pyreguee Further Previews East Midlands for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/emidms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649ba41091eec74097223244_355666790_638982674915606_3915251955605815913_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="110318"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍Pyreguee Dev Co. has just recently showcased new images previewing their exciting rendition of East Midlands Airport for MSFS. ‍ In a tweet, Pyreguee showed these exciting images, stating that it will be “The most sophisticated, state of the art piece of scenery engineering for any flight simulation platform.” He also addressed the hype surrounding the release with the caption of: “You just wait sunshine, you just wait.” ‍ These images showcase exciting features for the highly anticipated release. Custom road textures, custom grass and foliage placement, 3D Tower, Custom Building PBR, and more!  ‍ ‍ Although this amazing scenery has not been released yet, Threshold will keep you updated whenever it does, so stay tuned!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddrglw</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Gdańsk Lech Wałęsa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddrglw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649c71826918fc19dcb4d2f2_epgd1%5D.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2100848"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Gdańsk Lech Wałęsa Airport (EPGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Tricity metropolitan area in the Pomeranian Voivodeship in Poland. It’s the third busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1973 to replace the old Gdansk airport, deemed too small and expanding was impossible because of the many neighborhoods surrounding it.   It has two terminals, but only one is fully functional (T2). Terminal 1 was built in 1993, currently utilized for departures to non-Schengen countries like Great Britain and Ireland and holiday destinations such as Egypt, Morocco, etc. Terminal 2, the newest one, was built in 2012 and handles all the arrivals, with an overall area of 54,000 square meters, 25 check-in desks, and five jet bridges. It’s able to take up to 6 million passengers a year.  There are plans to expand Terminal 2 in the near future (work is underway) and add CAT3b ILS, allowing pilots to operate even when the visibility is poor and perform an autoland if need be.   It’s a base for WizzAir and Ryanair, flying people all over Europe. The visitors’ list includes Eurowings, Finnair, KLM, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, and Swiss International Air Lines.  The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, featuring an updated layout, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, fully modeled terminal buildings with their respective interior, 3D passengers, custom night lighting, animated trains, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.71, requiring at least 1.44 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/heatblur-and-india-fox-echo-shows-off-the-upcoming-f-14-for-microsoft-flight-simulator</id>
    <title>Heatblur and India Fox Echo shows off the upcoming F-14 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/heatblur-and-india-fox-echo-shows-off-the-upcoming-f-14-for-microsoft-flight-simulator" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649cb4b13cb42f99ca892b1e_322711352_909652780032116_7616951447470126904_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="508032"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A teaser video of the F-14 Tomcat still in development was recently released by Heatblur and India Fox Echo, known for their meticulous attention to detail in aircraft systems, flight dynamics, and visual models in Digital Combat Simulator. The team's focus on detail is now being carried over to Microsoft Flight Simulator. Although the project was announced on January 23, updates on its progress have been scarce until recently, when Heatblur uploaded a video to Facebook and YouTube showcasing their stunning cinema work, leaving fans excited for the release of the F-14 in Microsoft Flight Simulator. For those interested in learning the Tomcat, it is currently available for purchase in the DCS store and is well worth the investment despite its steep learning curve in terms of systems and flight model. Make sure to stay tune to Threshold for more information regarding progress and news for the F-14 for Microsoft Flight Simulator!    If you're curious of Heatblur's flight model development for DCS this is well worth the read!                                                                                      </summary>
    <published>2023-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/erj195</id>
    <title>Flight Procedures Simulations provides details regarding their upcoming EJET</title>
    <updated>2023-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/erj195" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649d78e0de75e9690e9ca348_FPSE-195%20-%20Emb195_5.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="763527"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Procedures Simulations' Ricardo Bolognini has announced that the Embraer 195 for X-Plane 12 will be released soon. This mid-range regional jet, designed by the Brazilian aerospace company Embraer, can seat up to 124 passengers and made its first flight in December 2004. The Embraer 195 series has been wildly successful with 172 airframes built due to its low operating costs per seat mile and maintenance. The E195 also know as the (Jungle Jet) has an average range of around 2600 miles cruising around 480 knots. ‍This aircraft model has detailed features including proper antennae, drains, and vents, realistic wing flex, and customized external lighting. The interior has updated graphics and redesigned panels with new buttons and knobs.‍‍ Custom Systems are detailed in this list from Flight Procedures Simulations. •Brake system with autobrake and antiskid. •Functional gear steers system. •Hydraulic system logic. •Electrical system logic. •Bleed system Logic. •Air Conditioning system logic. •Advanced Advisory System logic with more then 100 messages logic. •Lights switch test system. •Fire test system. •Fire dish with bottles system. •Display brightness. •Wipers with speeds and real recorded sounds.‍The flight model has been enhanced with a custom Fly By Wire System that offers protection during flight by limiting control laws based on the FMS Protection System Logic. Additionally, the improved flight model calculates various advanced flight parameters such as engine thrust, fuel consumption speeds, and flight performance. To read the entire XP-12 update change log see the X-Plane.org post here. Make sure to keep an eye on Threshold for additional news and release of this aircraft! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inistn</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases London Stansted Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inistn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649f0e17754cb3f2a1673295_stn1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="516236"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of London Stansted Airport (EGSS) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in the UK after Heathrow, Gatwick, and Manchester, with a yearly average of 23 million passengers.  Stansted was originally a bomber airfield and maintenance depot for WW2, inaugurated in 1943 by the Royal Air Force and shared between them and the USAF.  Twenty years after the war, Stansted was embraced by holiday charter operators looking for a cheaper alternative to Gatwick and Heathrow. It resulted in fast growth, leading to a new development plan in the mid-80s to expand the airport’s capacity to 15 million passengers a year.  Construction work started in the late 80s at the cost of roughly 100 million pounds, adding a railway branch to the airport. It won the European Union Prize for Contemporary Architecture in 1990.  A new expansion program followed between 2007 and 2009, adding 5,900 square meters of terminal area. A few years later, in 2013, the terminal underwent a redevelopment plan to modernize the airport further.  The airport is a Ryanair, Jet2.com, and TUI hub, flying people across Europe and North Africa. It’s mostly a low-cost carrier airport, with the eventual seasonal presence of British Airways and Lufthansa.  Stansted is also widely used for cargo, visited by Asiana Cargo, Cargolux, China Cargo Airlines, China Southern Cargo, FedEx Express, Qatar Airways Cargo, Turkish Cargo, UPS Airlines, and Turkmenistan Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, high-detail terminal buildings, and their respective interiors, a custom GSX profile, custom jetways, LOD optimization on every model, custom static aircraft, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.57, requiring at least 5.86 GB of free hard disk to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mah307</id>
    <title>Microsoft and Aeroplane Heaven Release Boeing 307 Stratoliner for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mah307" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649f154b6943ce735e8ff2e9_strat1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="146905"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Microsoft Flight Simulator team partnered with Aeroplane Heaven to develop the 10th airplane of their “Local Legend” series: the Boeing 307 Stratoliner, the first airliner in revenue service with a pressurized cabin. Its roots date back to 1935, when five of the biggest North American carriers had signed a contract with Douglas to fund the development of the DC-4, with a contribution of $100,000 each and an agreement not to fly other aircraft that were within its expected weight figures. The project was a disaster, leading to the airlines canceling their orders, yet still wishing to buy a large four-engine airplane at one point. Later that same year, Boeing designed a four-engine aircraft based on the B-17, with a larger pressurized part of the fuselage and the same wings, tail, rudder, undercarriage, and engines. Over the following months, the engineers extensively tested the pressurization by coating the fuselage with soapy water and then watching for bubbles indicating an air leak.  Three years later, the prototype was ready to roll, flying for the first time in late 1938 and eventually crashing in early 1939 after a nearly irrecoverable stall that tore off the left outer wing with the engine still attached. The ten occupants were killed that day. After figuring out what caused the accident and coming up with a solution, the program was finally back on track, with the approval to operate commercially in March 1940 and Pan Am being the first customer.  The Stratoliner could cruise at speeds of 350 km/h at 20,000ft, with a crew of six and either 33, 38, or 60 passengers, with a range of 3,846 km. It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for $14.99. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssuktb</id>
    <title>Simworks Studios Announces TBM series and Kodiak 900 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssuktb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649f22b994abe29c14e4e00a_SWS_Kodiak900_Render1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="222688"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios took to their Discord server to unveil the first renditions of their Kodiak 900 and to announce the TBM series for Microsoft Flight Simulator ! ‍ The exterior model for the Kodiak 900 is fully completed and ready to get in the simulator for testing. The 900 model, sharing a lot of features with the previously released 100 model, allows for a swift and efficient setup and testing process, thanks to its practically identical foundation regarding their codebase. This compatibility drastically reduces the initial work needed to get an aircraft up to scratch, leaving more room for refinement and enhancements for their newest addition.  The strength of the Kodiak 100’s codebase spares developers from the need to start from scratch, thus significantly streamlining the development process for the Kodiak 900. The Kodiak 900 will have an improved 3D model, not only in visual appearance but also in terms of performance. ‍ And the exciting news doesn’t stop there ! SimWorks Studios is thrilled to announce the TBM series for MSFS. Following a licensing agreement with Daher back in January, they had gained the rights to recreate the TBM 850, 910 and 960 models. Although the launch is quite a distance away, work on these aircraft will commence in August.  ‍ The upside of this is that the majority of the required avionics will be mostly ready by then. The TBM850’s EFIS40 is notably akin to the PC-12’s, significantly simplifying its integration. Plus the maturity of the G1000 and G3000, along with their new plugin system support, will facilitate the creation of an authentic avionics package. ‍ Importantly, the forthcoming TBM’s will inherit the code base of the preceding Kodiaks and their PC-12. This means a significant portion of the ground work will be completed in advance which will ultimately allow them to focus on other areas. ‍ This is all exciting news and although no price or release date has been announced, Threshold will keep you informed with all this once it becomes available. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ae3302</id>
    <title>Aerosoft A330 Trailer Released</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ae3302" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649dcdc5b9760918c8461994_aerosoft%20330.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="618639"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft, a popular development group for most major flight simulators since FSX, has sent ripples of excitement through the sim aviation community by releasing an exciting trailer showcasing their much-anticipated Airbus A330 for MSFS. The trailer, unveiled yesterday on the group's youtube channel, offers an exciting glimpse into the immersive experience that awaits flight sim pilots.  The trailer boasts some of the features we can expect. This includes; Accurate sounds, stunning exterior visuals and the much-anticipated EFB that Aerosoft has developed. The trailer shows that an effort has not been spared throughout the internal and external models.  ‍ Although no release date was provided in the trailer, the flight sim community is informed that the aircraft will release “soon” This is certainly an exciting time for Long Haul sim pilots who have been eagerly awaiting a new wide-body jet to traverse the globe in.  Threshold Will keep you informed on developments around the A330 and possible release dates, but for now… enjoy the trailer below! </summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmpbi</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Announces Palm Beach International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmpbi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649f3a504646220360145673_pb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="240981"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently announced the development of Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Miami metropolitan area and Port St. Lucie metro area with a yearly average of 6.6 million passengers.  ‍ It was opened in 1936 as Morrison Field, eventually becoming an important training airfield during World War 2 and operating as a staging base for the Allied invasion of France in 1944, with aircraft departing Palm Beach towards England in preparation for the D-Day.  ‍ After a brief return to being a civil airport, the airport was once again utilized for military purposes in the early 1950s as Palm Beach Air Force Base, training nearly 23,000 airmen during the Korean War. ‍ The Air Force Base was closed in 1962, and Palm Beach was back to being just a civilian airport.  ‍ Currently, the airport has 32 gates and three concourses. Concourse A houses Bahamasair and Silver Airways; B houses Air Canada, American Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines; C, on the other hand, holds Delta, Frontier, JetBlue, and Spirit. ‍ There’s no information regarding features, pricing, or availability yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbsmf</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Sacramento International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbsmf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/649fa68662f546d6e10b3ff5_sm1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="643152"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of Sacramento International Airport (KSMF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the busiest airports in California with a yearly average of 12 million passengers. ‍ The airport opened in 1967 as Sacramento Municipal Airport, with an 8,600 ft runway. It was the first purpose-built public-use airport west of the Mississippi. ‍ In 1998, a new terminal - Terminal A - was built, followed by its subsequent renaming to Sacramento International Airport. The first international flight happened in 2002 when Mexicana started a nonstop route from Guadalajara.  ‍ The current layout consists of two terminals with 32 gates in total. Air Canada, American, Delta, and United operate out of Terminal A, and Aeromexico, Alaska, Frontier, Hawaiian, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, and Volaris operate out of Terminal B. ‍ Developed by Orbx’s indie Matteo Veneziani, the upcoming SMF will feature detailed ground markings and textures, animated jetways with sounds, dynamic airport lighting, custom airport clutter, custom ground service equipment, an animated train, basic terminal interiors, and orthoimagery of the airport area. ‍ There is no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pacslc</id>
    <title>PACSIM Releases Salt Lake City International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pacslc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a095339fd69120a91b39e4_slc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="162154"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PACSIM has recently released their rendition of Salt Lake City International Airport (KSLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Utah with a yearly average of 25 million passengers. The airport was built on Basque Flats, a wide flat area on the Salt Lake Valley that was deemed appropriate for constructing a landing strip. In that same year, it held the Great International Aviation Carnival, with the presence of many aviation pioneers, including Glenn Curtiss and his newly invented Seaplane that took off from Salt Lake in front of 20,000 spectators, making international headlines. Nine years later, the United States Postal Service began flying mail to SLC, stimulating the city’s administration to further improve the infrastructure by buying a plot of land near the airport and building a hangar and other facilities.  The first terminal was built in 1933, costing $52,000.  With WW2, the airport became a USAF base, eventually getting a third runway. The post-war results were primarily positive, with 42 weekday departures in 1957. By 1960, a new terminal was needed, and Brazier Montmorency Hayes &amp; Talbot took the challenge to design it. Seven years and 8 million dollars later, it was ready to roll. That’s also when Salt Lake City got granted its international status, with a direct flight to Calgary. With the airline deregulation in 1978, SLC became a hub for Western Airlines, which had the same Brazier Montmorency Hayes design and build a terminal for them, with murals by artist LeConte Stewart.  In 1987, Western Airlines merged into Delta Air Lines, with Salt Lake City remaining as one of their major hubs. A redevelopment program was started in 2014 to modernize the airport, gradually replacing its old infrastructure. It was funded by airport funds, passenger charges, and federal grants. The first phase of the new terminal was opened in 2020, with Concourse A sporting 25 gates and B with 21, both connected by a mid-field underground tunnel.  As mentioned, SLC is a Delta Air Lines hub, flying passengers worldwide, directly or indirectly connecting via other hubs. They have 57.12% of the current passenger market share, followed by SkyWest with 18.77% and Southwest with 11.17%. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom animated jetways, sharp PBR textures, VDGS on every gate, high-resolution orthoimagery around the airport, hand-placed vegetation, performance-friendly optimization, wear and tear on runways, taxiways, and aprons, and more. It’s available on their official website for roughly $25.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwcos</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Colorado Springs Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwcos" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a1e5ddf88f5d4aa493abfe_cos1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="706097"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Colorado Springs Airport (KCOS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Colorado with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1927 on 260 hectares of land seven miles east of Colorado Springs, initially featuring two gravel runways. During its initial decade of operations, it was mainly a stop for mail routes flying from Cheyenne, Wyoming, to Pueblo, in Colorado.  True regular passenger service would only come in 1937, when Continental operated a route from Denver to El Paso, stopping in Colorado Springs. In 1943, Braniff also added the city to their destination list.  The first passenger terminal was built in 1942, using a modern art deco style. Passengers would only get to use it properly after the war, as the army took control of the airport during that period.  In 1966, another terminal was built and expanded in 1980 with six new gates.   Thirty years later, with the growing demand for air travel, the city approved a new terminal with 26,000 square meters of total area and 12 gates. In that same decade, a five-gate concourse was built on the main terminal's east side.  They have been trying to expand service since the 1980s, with the best figures rounding up at around 5 million passengers in 1996. In late 2020, Southwest Airlines announced they would begin serving the airport in 2021, which has helped increase the yearly traffic figures.   With the recent growth, the airport administration plans to expand the airport by doubling the number of gates and relocating the control tower.  As of 2022, Southwest Airlines holds most of the passenger market share with 49.84% of the traffic, followed by SkyWest with 23.08% and American Airlines with 14.05%.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, custom ground markings, animated jetways, a detailed terminal interior, landside buildings, and FSLTL compatibility.  It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.67, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/twdcle</id>
    <title>TearWear Designs Releases Cleveland Hopkins International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/twdcle" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a1f00bcfd749e0381460f3_cle1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1776915"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane.  TearWear Designs has recently released their rendition of Cleveland Hopkins International Airport (KCLE) for X-Plane 12, the busiest airport in Ohio with a yearly average of 8.5 million passengers.  Founded in 1925, Cleveland Hopkins International was one of the first municipality-owned airports in the United States, the first airport to ever have an air traffic control tower, the first with a ground-to-air radio control system, and the first to feature a night lighting system. It’s one of the most historically relevant airports in the world. It was also the first airport directly connected to a local or regional rail system and the first to implement a two-level terminal design separating arrivals from departures.  The airport consists of a two-level passenger terminal, built in the late 70s and renovated in 2016, with four concourses, although only three are currently in use. Concourse A houses Frontier, Spirit, charter flights, and all international arrivals. Concourse B, on the other hand, houses Southwest and Delta. C, the last of the operational concourses, hosts Air Canada Express, Alaska, American, JetBlue, and United. Passenger market share-wise, United leads with 23%, followed by Frontier with 13.76% and Southwest with 12.61%.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as of 2023, with custom-made objects, an intricately designed passenger terminal, true-to-life texturing, a custom mesh designed for compatibility with Ortho4Xp, hand-placed autogen and vegetation, SAM jetways and marshallers, performance-friendly optimization, and a custom prebuilt ortho tile.  It’s free on the X-Plane.Org Store, requiring at least 3.5 GB of free hard disk space to install (the airport alone takes 1.5GB, and the orthos need an additional 2 GB). ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/katefb</id>
    <title>KatiePilot Announces efbPro, an Innovative Standalone EFB</title>
    <updated>2023-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/katefb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64a335c131e338850d3e01f6_katiecover-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="908994"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. KatiePilot, the real-world Airbus pilot Twitch streamer and creator of the highly acclaimed Fenix Simulations Electronic Flight Bag (EFB), is now introducing efbPro, an innovative standalone EFB that goes beyond being a mere tool. With its ecosystem and customizability, it aims to provide a truly immersive and realistic flight simulation experience. The upcoming EFB will be fully customizable, based on real-world units, with the ability to change the background and accessibility settings and even manage its apps (efbPro will have an app store). It will also feature full SimBrief integration, weather monitoring and visualization for situational awareness, aircraft performance calculation, a built-in PDF reader for FCOMs, etc. efbPro is claimed to be entirely standalone, compatible with any sim or device, whether a tablet, a laptop, or a second monitor. Some of the apps will feature direct integration with MSFS, though. The app will be free, but developers may charge for specific apps on efbPro’s app store. There’s no release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
