<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-05-19T18:21:12.372572+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/100btu</id>
    <title>OneHundred Simulations Releases Tucuruí Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/100btu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645d4c0da28b72251e7164bf_sbtu1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="883648"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. OneHundred Simulations has recently released their rendition of Tucuruí Regional Airport (SBTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Tucuruí in Pará, Brazil.  Recently renovated, the airport got the green light to operate commercial flights in 2021 after a decade of inactivity. It was closed in 2015 because its infrastructure was deemed improper for any commercial operations, creating a significant hassle for the locals who depended heavily on the airport.   A hydroelectric plant nearby (Usina Hidroelétrica de Tucuruí) also weighed a lot on the decision to reactivate the airport, given they would have no way to get aerial rescue without an operating landing strip. On top of that, when the city’s hospital had to transfer patients to a bigger city, they had to drive for over 8 hours. It was judicially reopened in November 2021.  The airport is relatively modest, with a 2,000-meter runway and a single passenger terminal, albeit with all the required bits for commercial operation.  It’s served by Azul Conecta, with daily C208 flights to Val de Cans International Airport (SBBE).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Tucuruí Regional, with custom 3D objects, high-detailed textures, realistic ground layout, PBR texturing, and custom ground textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.75, requiring at least 45.79 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spcapa</id>
    <title>SDProjectsCO Releases Apartadó Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spcapa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645d538e87d941955234366e_apa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="757137"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SDProjectsCO has recently released their rendition of Antonio Roldán Betancur Airport (SKLC), serving the town of Apartadó in Antioquia, Colombia, with a yearly average of 210,000 passengers.  The airport was named after Antonio Roldán Betancur, a Colombian politician who served as Governor of Antioquia in the late 1980s. The airport was built in the late 1960s to early 1970s, primarily to serve the needs of the local population and to facilitate the transportation of goods and people in and out of the region.  The airport had a single dirt runway and elementary facilities in the early years. Over time, the runway was paved, and a small terminal building was constructed. However, the airport remained relatively small and basic, serving mainly as a regional airport with limited flights to other cities in Colombia.  In recent years, the airport has seen some improvements and expansions. In 2014, the runway was extended to accommodate larger aircraft and the terminal building was renovated and expanded to improve passenger comfort and service. The airport now has a modern terminal building with check-in counters, waiting areas, and other amenities.  EasyFly serves it with a route to Medellín - Olaya Herrera, and SATENA with two routes: Bogotá and Medellín - Olaya Herrera.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail 3D model of the main terminal, PBR texturing, custom night lighting, custom ground textures, a true-to-life airport layout, and custom ground clutter.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.95, requiring at least 123.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aau2be</id>
    <title>Working Title Releases Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 2 Beta for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aau2be" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645de8a72d16b421bb8457b4_scot1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3587664"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Working Title has recently released the first beta patch of the Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing issues with the Garmins (G3000, G5000, GNS430W, and GNS530W), bringing a complete overhaul of the avionics on the Boeing 787-10 and 747-8i, and more.   The highlight of the update is the overhaul on the default Boeings, bringing accurate fonts, look, functionality, and feel, with advanced flight plan support, integrated checklists on the MFD, performance-based VNAV with idle descent capabilities, RNP/ANP indications, functional GPS and IRS navigation systems, fully featured autopilot with autoland, flare, and rollout modes, a fully featured autothrottle system with correct AT modes, and much more.  The 787-10 also gets a revised soundscape, a HUD overhaul with nearly all real-world symbology, and a brand new fly-by-wire system accurately replicating the real-life counterpart.   They have also made sure to list some limitations, including the lack of an EFB on the 787 for performance calculations, the pedestal CDU on the 747 mirrors the left CDU for performance reasons, and issues with the electrical and fuel system on the 747. The complete list of known issues accompanies the changelog below:  Garmin G3000 / G5000 Garmin GNS430W / GNS530W ‍ WT21 ‍ ‍ Boeing 787-10 / Boeing 747-8i ‍ Cessna Citation Longitude ‍ Daher TBM 930 ‍ If you want to learn how to install the beta branch, please refer to the official guide here. Images are courtesy of SCOTSGOD. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vustuc</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Tucumán International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vustuc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645e8c6a055cc2edf6551b15_tucu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1691680"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Teniente General Benjamín Matienzo International Airport (SANT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of San Miguel de Tucumán in Argentina, with a yearly average of 500,000 passengers.  Built in the early 1980s and inaugurated in 1986, replacing the older Tucumán airport, which sat right in the center of the city, with no room to expand in length (and it only had a 1,600-meter runway), and with noise abatement restrictions creeping in, they had no choice but to close it.  The new airport features four departure gates, two arrival gates, immigration services, and the second-largest cargo terminal in Argentina.   It’s named after General Benjamín Matienzo, who died trying to fly over the Andes to Chile.  In September 2017, the single runway was extended from 2,900 meters to 3,500 meters, making it the second-longest runway in the country.   It’s served by Aerolineas Argentinas (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Córdoba (AR), Puerto Iguazú, Salta, San Carlos de Bariloche, São Paulo–Guarulhos), Andes Líneas Aéreas (Cayo Largo del Sur), FlyBondi (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque), and JetSmart Argentina (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Buenos Aires–Ezeiza).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality model of the main terminal and its interior, a fully modeled control tower, custom ground textures, a true-to-life ground layout, and correct parking positions in the commercial apron.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.92, requiring at least 194.35 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siachi</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Chiang Mai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siachi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645ea14a96754f91728d2e64_vtcc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="612925"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Chiang Mai International Airport (VTCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Thailand with a yearly average of 11 million passengers.  In the early days, the airport was a small airfield used primarily by the Royal Thai Air Force. In the 1950s, the Thai government recognized the need for a larger airport to serve the growing city of Chiang Mai and decided to expand the airfield. In 1954, the airport officially opened to commercial traffic, with Thai Airways operating the first scheduled flight to Bangkok.  Over the next few decades, Chiang Mai International Airport underwent several expansions and renovations to accommodate the increasing number of passengers and airlines. In 1995, a new international terminal was built, which increased the airport's capacity to handle more international flights.  The most recent expansion dates back to 2014, when Airports of Thailand (the operator) expanded the apron for larger aircraft, enlarged the terminal (international arrival hall and domestic departure hall) and made it a 24/7 airport.  It's a focus city for Bangkok Airways (Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Koh Samui, Krabi, Phuket), Nok Air (Bangkok–Don Mueang, Ubon Ratchathani, Udon Thani), Thai AirAsia (Bangkok–Don Mueang, Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi, Beijing–Daxing, Changsha, Da Nang, Hangzhou, Hanoi, Hat Yai, Hua Hin, Hong Kong, Khon Kaen, Krabi, Macau (resumes 1 July 2023), Phuket, Singapore, Surat Thani, Taipei–Taoyuan), and Thai Smile (Bangkok–Suvarnabhumi). The visitors' list includes Air China, China Airlines, EVA Air, Jeju Air, Korean Air, Spring Airlines, and VietJet Air.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3d models for the terminal, control tower, tango squadron museum, cargo terminal, new parking building, and more. The jetways are customized, with normal and glass variants, and it sports custom ground markings, VDGS, custom night lighting, and hand-placed ground objects. The developers also listed some upcoming features that will come free of charge with an update:   It's available on SimMarket for roughly $15.29, requiring at least 173.15 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsshou</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Houston Hobby International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsshou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645ea7e826186b7c73c64eaa_hou1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="193984"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently released their rendition of William P. Hobby Airport (KHOU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Greater Houston with a yearly average of 13 million passengers.  Opened in 1927 as a private landing field in a pasture, it quickly became a full-blown airport. It got its first bits of commercial traffic in the early 30s by the wings of Braniff International Airways and Eastern Air Lines. Seven years later, it was purchased by the city of Houston and named Houston Municipal Airport (it was initially called W. T. Carter Field). A year later, in 1938, it was renamed Howard R. Hughes, responsible for several airport improvements. The name was quickly changed because the regulations didn’t allow federal improvement funds for an airport named after a living person.   With the advent of Houston Intercontinental Airport in 1969, most airlines went to the new airport, leaving HOU with no scheduled traffic. It wasn’t until the 70s, with Houston Metro Airlines, a small commuter airline, that the airport saw the resumption of passenger services. It was a cross-town service from the airport to IAH.   Southwest embraced HOU in 1971, flying nonstop to Dallas Love Field and San Antonio, followed by Braniff and Texas International shortly after to offer some competition.  Currently, Southwest holds most of the market share, flying to over 50 destinations all over North and Central America. It’s also served by Allegiant Air, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, and Frontier Airlines, albeit with a substantially smaller participation in raw passenger volume.  The busiest destinations from Houston Hobby are Dallas Love Field, Denver, and Atlanta, with 380,000, 327,000, and 325,000 passengers each, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality 3D model of the passenger terminal and its interior, custom ground textures, improved high-resolution orthographic imagery, an up-to-date AFCAD (as of 2023), custom taxiway signs, handmade PBR textured buildings, and the Hobby Airport DoubleTree Hilton.  It’s available on Contrail for roughly $18.98, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Tang0 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pilda7</id>
    <title>PILOT'S Showcases Upcoming Dash 7 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pilda7" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645ff7accbd9ed6df12967bf_dash1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="351879"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PILOT'S GesmbH has recently published a couple of work-in-progress screenshots of their upcoming de Havilland Canada Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This classic turboprop regional airliner preceded the popular Dash 8. First flown in 1975, the Dash 7 is a "Twin Otter but larger and with four engines," with oversized fan blades that would rotate at a slower speed to emit as little noise as possible, complying with the noise restrictions that were starting to creep in. It could carry up to 50 passengers, with a service ceiling of 21,000 feet, and 690 nautical miles of range, all powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-50 turboprop engines, with 1,120 hp each. As of July 2018, 17 Dash 7s were still flying around the world with six different operators. However, the list of former operators is substantial: sixty civilian operators and three military operators. PILOT'S rendition is "nearing release," according to the developers, followed by a collection of screenshots showcasing the interior and exterior of their upcoming product. They claim to be continuously fixing bugs and tweaking the aircraft's behavior to match reality, with one more beta cycle to go until it's ready to release (according to their prediction).  Some screenshots also show the recently implemented TDS GTN integration, which adds modern navigational features to this almost 50-year-old regional airliner. There's no release date and pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed!Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pxbdev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pxbdev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64602cb6154231df36c97570_ran1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1908166"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo, PMDG’s Founder, has published another development update for Microsoft Flight Simulator regarding an upcoming patch for the 737 lineup and its eventual release on Xbox, more info on the EFB, and more.  The forum post begins with Randazzo explaining an issue with his internet connection, which has delayed both the update on PC and the 737’s arrival on Xbox, which are set to release soon. They plan to release a complete set of micro-updates for the 737 next week, including the aforementioned AFDS improvements, a few more fixes and tweaks, and the mitigation of a long existing bug with the V-speed computations misapplying corrections for head/tail wind components.  Randazzo also reminds everyone that the marketplace update will take longer due to Asobo’s approval process. His estimation for the rollout is either May 18 (the most favorable outcome) or May 25. The same applies to the Xbox version, which was pushed simultaneously.  Still on that Xbox note, Robert says that the 737 for Xbox won’t have any extra liveries to begin with, as their original plan was to wait for the liveries to be approved first, but they saw lots of feedback on their forum from the console simmers that would not mind an early release without any livery packs for the time being. Liveries of which, to no fault of their own, will cost $4.99 per pack (the in-game marketplace does not allow for free content, and that price tag is the minimum value).   The Universal Flight Tablet is still being worked on, with work going on refining the PERF process and refinement on native mapping features for non-Navigraph subscribers while also working hard on the Navigraph integration for Navigraph customers. They also made sure to explain once again why it has been taking so long to come out, bringing up how it’s a sandboxed environment and the communication between that environment and the “external world” is a little bit complicated.   They finish the UFT news bit with the information that an external-to-PMDG developer is working on adding extra functionalities, “showing what the tablet is truly capable of.”  Its initial release is said to bring a “number of features,” with more to come. “Navigraph and Simbrief users will be pleased by the care that has gone into ensuring a nice, tight weave between our technology and theirs,” said Randazzo.  ‍ The DC-6 update has been pushed to the marketplace, and the expected date is the same as the 737’s update. Either May 18 or May 25. Non-marketplace owners will get a micro-update this week incorporating these changes, which, according to Randazzo, should be transparent.  The development update ends with more information on the 777, which is progressing nicely, and they claim to be very happy with how things are going.  The 737 Lineup and the DC-6 are available on the PMDG Shop and in the MSFS Marketplace (partially).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/impbas</id>
    <title>Impulse Simulations Releases Alice Springs Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/impbas" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646164f2d552a3e442eae580_alice1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1191556"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Impulse Simulations has recently released their rendition of Alice Springs Airport (YBAS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Alice Springs, Australia, with a yearly average of 600,000 passengers.  The airport, originally named Seven Mile Aerodrome, was built in the 1940s by the Australian Department of Defence and used by the Royal Australian Air Force and the USAF during World War 2. It was an important refueling and staging facility run by No. 57 Operational Base Unit. It only got its current name way after the war, in 1958.  As a curiosity, it has the first large-scale aircraft boneyard outside of the United States. Operating since 2014, the Asia Pacific Aircraft Storage offers a dry and safe environment for long-term storage of airplanes, be it a functioning plane but not in use or decommissioned units that will be scrapped for parts.  It is served by Airnorth (Darwin, Katherine, Tennant Creek), Alliance Airlines (charter), Qantas (Adelaide, Brisbane, Melbourne, Sydney), QantasLink (Adelaide, Darwin), and Virgin Australia (Adelaide, Brisbane, Darwin).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with realistic ground &amp; apron texturing, custom night lighting, a partially replicated cafe interior, full PBR texturing, custom animations, custom vegetation &amp; grass, a detailed static graveyard, over a hundred custom-modeled objects and buildings, custom taxiway signage, 20,000 hand placed objects, and more than a hundred custom assets.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $19.90, requiring at least 3.34 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ecusey</id>
    <title>EcuaVirtual3D Releases Seymour Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ecusey" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64616d05f2e7e27fe82cc9b6_segs1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2491329"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. EcuaVirtual3D has recently released their rendition of Seymour Galapagos Ecological Airport (SEGS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Baltra, one of the Galápagos Islands in Ecuador. It’s the third busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 500,000 passengers.  The airport was originally built by the United States during World War II as a military base for surveillance of the Pacific Ocean. After the war, the airport was used mainly for commercial traffic (and as a stopover for flights between South America and North America). It was eventually handed over to the Ecuadorian government in the 1960s.  In the 2000s, it was renovated to meet the requirements of the increasing number of tourists visiting the Galapagos Islands, designed with an eco-friendly concept, keeping in mind the fragile ecosystem of the Islands. The new terminal, built with recycled steel tubes from oil drilling operations in the Amazon, uses clean, renewable technologies such as solar energy, wind farms, and seawater desalination. It became the world’s first “green” airport in 2012.  The airport was named after British naval officer and scientist Sir Seymour de Ricci, who visited the Galapagos Islands in the early 1900s and contributed significantly to the scientific knowledge of the region.   Due to its location in a sensitive ecosystem, the airport has implemented strict regulations to minimize the impact of air traffic on the environment. For example, the airport uses solar panels to generate electricity and a rainwater harvesting system to conserve water. The airport also has a waste management system to minimize the impact of garbage on the environment.  It’s served by Avianca Ecuador, Equair, and LATAM Ecuador, with direct flights to Guayaquil and Quito.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a faithful replica of the terminal, custom taxiway signage, custom static objects, HDR lighting, custom textures with ambient occlusion, custom approach lighting systems, and a custom mesh around the airport.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.38, requiring at least 112.20 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/3dvbre</id>
    <title>3DVirtualSim Releases Brest Bretagne Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/3dvbre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6462001d777e1641f994a284_brest1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1566690"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. 3DVirtualSim has recently released their rendition of Brest Bretagne Airport (LFRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Brest in western France with a yearly average of 1 million passengers.  The airport’s origin dates back to World War I when the US Army built two airship hangars, which were abandoned right after the war until the late 1930s when it also got an airstrip. The air base, though, didn’t survive World War 2, with its infrastructure being destroyed by air raids, rendering it practically useless.   Rebuilding efforts only took place in the early 1950s, with the airport being reopened for commercial use in 1952, connecting Brest to Ouessant and Paris by the wings of Air Inter.   With the popularization of air travel and the consequent increase in passenger volume, the airport underwent a huge expansion project in 1986, followed by a runway extension six years later, transforming the airport into a diversion ground for transatlantic flights. By 1989, the airport was averaging 500,000 passengers a year for the first time.  In December 2007, they inaugurated a brand new terminal, with 22,000 square meters of total area, able to accommodate up to 1.8 million passengers a year, with two wide-body jetways and fourteen stands for medium and small aircraft. It’s shaped like a manta ray.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, an intricately modeled interior, dynamic jetways, reworked aerial imagery to match Bing’s colorimetry, realistic ground textures, and custom night lighting.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.62, requiring at least 1.39 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barcro</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Crotone Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barcro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6462a8074c4eafe8cc08d61f_crotone1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4112978"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Crotone-Sant’Anna Airport (LIBC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a domestic airport serving the city of Crotone in Calabria (Southern Italy) with a yearly average of 169,780 passengers.  The airport was built in 1941 to support the war industry with air transport of nitric acid and nitrates required to manufacture explosives originating from the chemical plants of Montecatini and Pertusola Sud, both close to Crotone. Two years later, in 1943, the entire airport was destroyed by 50 B.24 bombers.  Twenty years later, it became an operational base for ITAVIA, flying passengers to Ciampino and mail to Fiumicino (both are Rome airports). The advent of Lamezia Terme Airport slowly killed the flights, eventually leading to the closure of their Crotone base in 1979.  In 2012, the airport was upgraded with an ILS system, allowing for safe operation even during bad weather conditions and poor visibility. Three years later, the airport’s management company filed for bankruptcy, with the airport ceasing operations a few months after.  In 2017, Calabrese Airport Company took the helm, reopening the airport for flight operations in November, with Ryanair reactivating their scheduled flights in 2018. They are the only airline operating at Crotone, with flights to Venice, Milan, and Bologna.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom 3D model of the terminal, custom ground markings, and custom clutter.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.42, requiring at least 59.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kausms</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Austin-Bergstrom International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kausms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646464daa73d03d922288f23_319289_16.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1479017"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer FeelThere has released their rendition of Austin-Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport features everything from high quality PBR textures to customized lighting in the terminal and ramp areas. According to the developers, the scenery recreates in detail more than 50 buildings of its real life counterpart, including two passenger terminals furnished with animated jetways and three helipads. In addition, the product will include custom “ground polygons including realistic decals, dirt, taxi lines and surfaces”, as well as accurate signage for parking spots and taxiways across the airport. Austin-Bergstrom International Airport is the major airport for the city of Austin and is the third busiest airport in the state of Texas. It offers destinations across the U.S, Central-America, the Caribeans, and Europe, serving airlines from Southwest to Lufthansa. Currently, the scenery can be purchased on simMarket for EUR 13.99 or $15.22 USD, excluding any sale taxes that may incur. The developers recommend at least 650mb of free disk space to successfully download and install the product.</summary>
    <published>2023-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/olcyv2</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases London City Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/olcyv2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64648090e673f7710cdeb843_v21-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1377229"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their updated rendition of London City Airport (EGLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing an updated layout, better models and textures, and more.  The first version came out during the early stages of Microsoft Flight Simulator when developers were still getting acquainted with the SDK and its potential. V2 brings the new airport layout, the parallel taxiway, new parking stands, and the remote digital control tower, along with refined 3D models, textures, and more.  London City is the fifth busiest airport in London, with a yearly average of 5 million passengers, mainly served by British Airways, with many intra-European destinations such as Amsterdam, Barcelona, and Zürich. The visitors' list includes ITA Airways, KLM, Loganair, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Luxair, and Swiss International Air Lines.  The scenery was rebuilt from scratch, bringing an accurate rendition of London City Airport with HD textures, PBR, crisp aerial imagery for the surroundings, an updated custom groundpoly, performance-friendly optimization, improvements on the main terminal, remote digital control tower, and more.  It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.06, requiring at least 3.70 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navavi</id>
    <title>Navigraph Releases Avionics Plugin for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navavi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6466a9aa449bd11e4515599e_chart1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="56282"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Navigraph has recently released their Avionics Plugin for Microsoft Flight Simulator, improving the Garmin G3000 and G5000 experience in the simulator with seamlessly displayed charts, SimBrief integration, and more.  The new chart integration aims to reduce workload and enhance situational awareness. It allows the customer to display specific sections of the chart and bring them to multiple displays within the flight deck, with lots of customization.  Although only compatible with the G3000 and G5000 for the time being (TBM 930 and Cessna Citation Longitude, respectively), Navigraph plans to integrate charts into more units in the future, like the G1000 NXi and the CJ4 Pro Line 21. It’s also available for integration by Xbox aircraft developers and soon available on the console and PC versions of the HJet and SF50 Vision Jet from FlightFX.  It’s available right now for Navigraph Ultimate subscribers. Please refer to their blog post for guidance on how to set everything up. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsdxin</id>
    <title>BRsimDesigns Releases Embraer E121A1 - Xingu II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsdxin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6466b0dcec2bb52a947f5e1a_xingu1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3817266"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BRsimDesigns has recently released their rendition of the Embraer E121A1 Xingu II for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an upgraded version of a twin-turboprop fixed-wing aircraft developed and manufactured in Brazil by Embraer in the mid-70s.   The E121 was the “first child” of Embraer’s 12X Project, which aimed to develop cutting-edge pressurized turboprop aircraft for civil and military use.   The Xingu was an upgraded EMB-110 Bandeirante, using the same Pratt &amp; Whitney PT6A engines but with a sleeker fuselage and cutting-edge technology (for the 70s/80s).  BRsimDesigns modeled the upgraded version of the Xingu, named E121A1 Xingu II, introduced in September 1981. It was slightly more silent and a bit more powerful, thanks to the pair of PT6A-135 engines, cruising at 380 km/h, with a service ceiling of 28,000ft and 660 nautical miles of total range.  Their rendition for MSFS brings a detailed model, internally and externally, making use of 4K and 8K texturing, including eight liveries, a KAP140 autopilot, WT GNS530 integration (also compatible with the PNS GTN750, payware), custom NAV/COM/DME/ADF/Transponder panels, a limited weather radar, a custom coded pressurization and AC system, an EFB, and more. The complete feature list follows down below: Visuals:- 8 Liveries (Including two Brazilian Air Force and two French Air Force liveries)- Detailed external model- Detailed cockpit model- Detailed 3D instruments- Detailed 4K and 8K textures- Detailed passenger cabin   Autopilot/Navigation:- KAP140 Autopilot- GSN530 GPS (Working Title GSN530 necessary)- PMS50 GTN750 (Externally Integrated)- Custom NAV/COM/DME/ADF/Transponder panels- Weather Radar (limited by API)   Warning System:- Custom integrated warning system   Anti-Stall system:- Stick Shaker- C.A.A (AOA Control System)   AC/Pressurization:- Custom coded AC system (With auto and manual control)- Custom coded pressurization system (With ventilation and pressurization mode)   EFB:- Controls: Chocks, GPU, doors, weight and fuel   Checklist:- MSFS checklist menu- EFB checklist page- PDF checklist   MSFS Effects:- MSFS icing effects- MSFS particle effects   Customizations (Controlled by EFB):- Airplane Registration (With the exception of Air Force liveries)- 2 glareshield options (New and Old)- 2 panel color options (Blue and Beige)- Fuel Panel Indicator (Magnetic indicator or Lights)- Shades for the cockpit side windows- Baggage objects shown according to the loaded baggage weight-  WT GNS530 and PMS50 GTN750- Save and autoload system for customizable options   Lighting:- Custom cockpit flood light- Custom passenger cabin light- Custom glareshield light- Custom and individual spot lights for every instrument- Custom landing, taxi, nav, beacon and inspection light   Custom Sounds:- Knobs- Switches- Warning- Autopilot- Stick Shaker- Oxygen Test- Fuel Pumps- Engine Ignition   Notes:- For the engine sounds to work, it is necessary to have the Default Asobo KingAir350 installed in your Microsoft Flight Simulator- This add-on is not study level. However, normal operations are simulated.- It is recommended to start the airplane in Cold And Dark state.- It is recommended to load fuel and weight using the EFB.- Not tested for Virtual Reality (VR)  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.49, requiring at least 708.95 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
