<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-09-27T18:22:35.075151+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzmilf</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases Milford Sound Region for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzmilf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6501e23ca11f85e513f04b31_milf.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3013932"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NZA Simulations has recently released their rendition of the Milford Sound Region for Microsoft Flight Simulator, comprised of 8 airstrips: Milford Sound (NZMF), Martins Bay Aerodrome (NZMJ), Big Bay Beach Strip (NZQU), Cascade Lagoon Airstrip (NZ31), Hope River Aistrip (NZ32), Hollyford Track Airstrip (NZ34), Cascade Station Aistrip (NZ35), and Quintin Lodge Airstrip (T004).  ‍ The package features an accurate rendition of eight airfields in the Milford Sound Region in New Zealand, with fully 3D modeled terminals, hidden adventure locations, multiple points of interest, 76 animated custom watercraft, custom animal and bird life, biome enhancements, custom water masking, mountain texture improvements, animated rivers and waterfalls, and more.  ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $21.86, requiring at least 2.19 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse024</id>
    <title>FSExpo 2024’s Location Unveiled</title>
    <updated>2023-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse024" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/5d47269777c5819a23cbedb5_Image11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1240912"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The FSExpo organizers have unveiled the results of the community-wide survey to decide on the next location, published in a press release that follows below, along with the dates: ‍ LAS VEGAS – September 14, 2023 – Flight Simulation Association (FSA) is excited to announce that FlightSimExpo 2024 will be held June 21-23, 2024 at Tropicana Las Vegas - a DoubleTree by Hilton. The location was selected following a community-wide survey in which more than 500 simmers selected Las Vegas as their top location choice.  ‍ “We are excited to bring FlightSimExpo back to Las Vegas,” said Evan Reiter, FSA co-founder. “The space at Tropicana is perfect for our event, while the destination offers a great backdrop for families, resort-seekers, and those who love gaming and entertainment.”  ‍ FlightSimExpo is one of the world’s largest dedicated flight simulation events and has welcomed more than 5,000 attendees to shows in Las Vegas, Orlando, San Diego, and Houston since 2018. The expo features developers from across the community, including representation from the four of the five most popular simulation platforms: Microsoft Flight Simulator, X-Plane, Prepar3D, and Infinite Flight ‍ FSExpo 2024 will kick off on Friday, June 21 with a series of product announcements and reveals from community developers. Then, over the weekend, in-person attendees will have access to a 40,000 square foot exhibit hall featuring the latest in home flight simulation technology. Developer roundtables and educational seminars will take place throughout the weekend. As in previous years, simmers will be able to watch portions of FlightSimExpo from anywhere with the event’s Online-Only registration. The 2024 venue is centrally located on the Las Vegas Strip and features an award-winning pool, spa, fitness center, and more. FlightSimExpo attendees will have access to a special average room rate of just $188/night over a threenight stay—including all taxes and resort fees. When booked as part of FlightSimExpo’s special room block, the stay includes free self-parking, WiFi for up to 5 devices, 2 bottles of water, unlimited fitness center access, and more. ‍ “Save the dates, start thinking of plans, but please don’t lock travel in yet,” says FSA’s Phil Coyle. “As always, we are working to secure airfare and car rental discounts along with awesome add-on activities on Thursday, Friday, and Monday for our attendees. You’ll want to have the full picture before you start booking.”  ‍ ‍  The organization will publish more information about hotel options, attractions, and travel later this year. Attendee registrations will open in December, and people are welcome to join their Discord server to share ideas, feedback, and suggestions.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drepaa</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Studios Releases Palo Alto Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drepaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6505f012de11be490fb059ab_palo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1943875"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Dreamflight Studios has recently released their rendition of Palo Alto Airport (KPAO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the city of Palo Alto in California.  ‍ The airport was built between 1934-1936, replacing the former Palo Alto airport (adjacent to Stanford Stadium). It covers an area of 41 hectares, with a single 743-meter-long runway. ‍ It houses various repair shops and four flying clubs: Stanford Flying Club, West Valley Flying Club, Sundance Flying Club, and Advantage Aviation Flying Club. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with high-resolution PBR textures, custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.60, requiring at least 150.13 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/darx26</id>
    <title>Dark Space Updates xEnviro for X-Plane 12.06</title>
    <updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/darx26" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6505f92efbbb8e2f46cc7e9d_xenviro.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1724659"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Dark Space has recently updated xEnviro to work with X-Plane 12.06r3, following up on a bigger update from late August that added a series of enhancements to both X-Plane 11 and 12.  Update 1.26 brought dithering technology to reduce sky banding, X-Plane 11 compatibility, in-cloud light scattering, and 1.27 warranted the compatibility with the latest version of X-Plane 12.  The developer team says they are actively working on reintroducing the features that were held back during the transition from X-Plane 11 to X-Plane 12. The following updates aim to reflect that. ‍ xEnviro is available on its official website, Threshold Store, and X-Plane.Org for $69.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aricea</id>
    <title>Arif Studio Releases Chicago Executive Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aricea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650601bef9412547ee6dd6de_chica.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1679752"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Arif Studio has recently released their rendition of Chicago Executive Airport (KPWK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public airport serving northwestern Chicago with a yearly average of 108,000 aircraft movements.  It opened in 1925 as Gauthier’s Flying Field in the village of Wheeling (Cook County, Illinois), purchased and developed by George J. Priester in 1953, who installed paved runways, lighting, hangars, and an ATC tower. It was then sold in 1986 by George’s son, Charlie, to the city of Prospect Heights and Wheeling, when it was renamed Palwaukee Municipal Airport. ‍ The current name was given in late 2006 after trustees from the village voted to approve a name change, better positioning the airport as a private aviation gateway to Chicago due to its proximity to the city. ‍ ‍ According to 2022 data, 80% of the yearly movements correspond to general aviation traffic, 20% to air taxi, and less than 1% are military. There are 296 aircraft based at the airport. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a recreation of all the hangars, numerous static objects, landside buildings, non-PBR texturing for file size optimization, custom night lighting, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.52, requiring at least 31.18 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/attkaj</id>
    <title>ATTBEN Releases Kajaani Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/attkaj" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6508b098070dcbe60c54dae7_kaj.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="305779"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  ATTBEN has recently released their rendition of Kajaani Airport (EFKI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Kajaani town in the Finnish region of Kainu, with a yearly average of 85,200 passengers.  The airport was built in 1939, but the official opening only happened 17 years later because of World War 2 and its short-term economic consequences.   ‍ It has been majorly domestic, with a healthy start followed by a decline in the 1980s as a direct consequence of the economic recession and airline industry deregulation.  ‍ The 90s brought a “revival” with the popularization of low-cost carriers and the growth of the tourism industry in Finland.  ‍ A new - environmentally friendly - terminal was built in the early 1990s, designed to be energy-efficient and sustainable. It won the Finavia Airport of the Year the following year and went on to win again in 1999 and 2007. ‍ Finnair serves it with a flight to Helsinki-Vantaa. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, a detailed interior environment, custom baggage carts, custom clutter, a true-to-life runway profile and elevation, custom night lighting, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.72, requiring at least 1.81 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkskan</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Kangerlussuaq Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkskan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6509f3a25549e48989711999_kang.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1197811"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released their rendition of Kangerlussuaq Airport (BGSF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the settlement of Kangerlussuaq in the Qeqqata Municipality in Greenland with a yearly average of 133,481 passengers. ‍ It was built in the early 1940s during the US occupation as Bluie-West 8, which was later renamed Sondrestromfjord Air Base. ‍ Transatlantic civilian flights started to use the air base for refueling in the mid-1950s, starting a trend that lives on to this day, yet mostly among general aviation pond crossers.   It’s a hub for Air Greenland, although they plan on moving their hub away from it as the permafrost under the airport is melting and causing significant damage to the runway, which will be closed to major commercial traffic in 2024. There are plans to build new airports at Tasillaq and Ittoqqortoormit.  ‍ The scenery package also includes renditions of Sisimiut, Maniitsoq, Qaarsut, and Aasiaat, with detailed buildings, accurate terrain, and more. Kangerlussuaq, the main dish, features detailed terminal interiors, custom satellite imagery covering the airport and the city, real-world elevation data based on LiDAR scans, the entire town of Kangerlussuaq with its 150 buildings, custom ground poly, realistic night lighting, 3D snow and icebergs depending on weather condition, custom visual effects, and AI compatibility. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.12, requiring at least 5.73 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/airgsa</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases General Santos International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/airgsa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6509fa6441dadd89f318e7dc_santos.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1791008"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airwil Sceneries has recently released their rendition of General Santos International Airport (RPMR) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the greater area of Soccsksargen in the Philippines with a yearly average of 768,000 passengers. ‍ Built for the 42nd annual Palarong Pambansa (National Games), which was held in South Cotabato and General Santos at the time, the airport was going to be the largest in Mindanao (the second largest island in the Philippines), partially funded by the USA with a 47.6 million USD grant.  ‍ It opened in 1996 and has become the largest airport in Mindanao, aiding the region's rapid urban development and multiplying its yearly growth rate. ‍ The airport was upgraded for the first time between 2017-2019, which consisted of a major facelift and modernization of its infrastructure, which had yet to be touched since its opening in 1996. ‍ The airport is served by Cebgo, Cebu Pacific, PAL Express, and Philippine Airlines.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with more than a hundred custom objects, a highly-detailed landside, custom ground textures, custom orthoimagery, custom landside, Filipino houses and vehicles, and more. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $10.65, requiring at least 1.87 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/susbri</id>
    <title>SuperSonic Releases Brindisi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/susbri" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6509ffdfa8a59d672c0b4b51_bri.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1263175"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SuperSonic has recently released their rendition of Brindisi Papola Casale Airport (LIBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 20th busiest airport in Italy with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. ‍ Built as a military airbase in the 1920s, commercial traffic only started a decade and a half later with Ala Littoria, a government-owned airline based in Rome. It collapsed after World War 2, becoming the now-defunct Alitalia. ‍ The airport retained its military status until 2008, despite maintaining its military facilities to this day, although referred to by a different name: Military Airport Orazio Pierozzi. The civil name (Papola Casale) was given after Antonio Papola, a deceased Italian aviator with tight bonds to the city. ‍ The airport is served by many airlines during the summer season, with Ryanair, AlbaStar, easyJet, Eurowings, ITA Airways, Swiss, and WizzAir being the few to offer routes all year long. The seasonal visitors’ list includes Aer Lingus, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Volotea, and Vueling.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom aerial imagery, a highly-detailed terminal building with its interior, custom landside, custom ground textures, PBR textures, custom night lighting, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.66, requiring at least 928.44 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsddje</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Djerba Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsddje" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650a04d5eacab46124922822_dje.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2192113"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Zarzis International Airport (DTTJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Djerba in Tunisia with a yearly average of 1.7 million passengers. ‍ It was inaugurated in 1970 and has contributed to the growth of tourism in the region, becoming an important seasonal destination for Europeans.  ‍ It’s seasonally visited by Air France, BH Air, Brussels Airlines, Discover Airlines, Edelweiss Air, European Air Charter, Luxair, Neos, Nouvelair, Smartwings, Swiss International Air Lines, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Germany, TUI fly Netherlands, Tunisair, and Tunisair Express. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date layout, custom night lighting, animated jetways, reflective textures, GSX compatibility, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.12, requiring at least 1016.41 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skysna</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases John Wayne Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skysna" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650b6f1b61ccf9936e496088_sna.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="627175"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Skyline Simulations recently released the X-Plane 12 version of their John Wayne Airport (KSNA), serving Orange County with a yearly average of 11.3 million passengers.  ‍ It started as an airstrip in 1923 and was purchased by the County of Orange in 1939, which has owned it ever since.  ‍ After a brief period of Military usage during World War 2, it was returned to the County with the condition it remained open for all kinds of aviation uses. ‍  A passenger terminal was built in 1967, with 2,000 square meters of total built area, accommodating up to 400,000 passengers annually. It was expanded in 1974, 1980, and 1982, adding 700 square meters. ‍ Eight years after the last terminal expansion, the Thomas F. Riley Terminal replaced the aging terminal with a 31,390 square meter facility that could handle millions of passengers. ‍ It was then further expanded in 2011, part of a $543 million project that added a new terminal C with six additional gates and a new parking lot. ‍ Air Canada, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JSX, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with UHD textures, detailed 3D modeling, PBR materials on every building, custom orthoimagery, thousands of custom static objects, custom night lighting, ground traffic, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.68, requiring at least 678.37 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/magtij</id>
    <title>MagMexico Releases Tijuana International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/magtij" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650e0cbbf533d63a8b75d3a5_tij.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3132387"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MagMexico has recently released their rendition of Tijuana International Airport (MMTJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the San Diego-Tijuana transborder agglomeration with a yearly average of 12.3 million passengers. ‍ It was inaugurated in 1951 as “Aeropuerto Federal de Tijuana,” with a 2000-meter long runway and a single passenger terminal, that was eventually replaced in 1970 by a much bigger one, part of a $8.7 million project that also included a runway lengthening. ‍ In the 1980s, Tijuana was the fastest-growing city in Mexico, which led to further expansions in that decade. ‍ The airport was privatized in 1995, becoming part of the Pacific Airport Group, which consists of 12 airports, with its headquarters in Guadalajara.  ‍ Under the new helm, it was expanded and renovated in 2002, with many changes to accommodate the Boeing 747. By then, Tijuana was one of the most important airports in Mexico. ‍ A cross-border express bridge was inaugurated in late 2015, allowing passengers to access the airport directly from the United States, with a North American terminal. ‍ Aeroméxico, American Eagle, Calafia Airlines, Mexicana de Aviación, Viva Aerobus, and Volaris serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, animated jetways, dynamic lighting, detailed hangars and buildings, custom ground textures, precise AFCAD, static aircraft and vehicles, animated radar facilities, native volumetric grass and vegetation, and more.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.26, requiring at least 1.24 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxdua</id>
    <title>FlightFX Releases DuPage Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxdua" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650e1b6110149496041872e2_dupage.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1966346"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has recently released their rendition of DuPage Airport (KDPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the city of West Chicago, Illinois, with a yearly average of 135,000 aircraft movements. ‍ It was built on former sheep-grazing land in the late 1920s by two Chicago entrepreneurs, and the U.S. Army eventually requisitioned it during World War 2 for training purposes. They built hangars and paved two runways, activating it in 1943. The hangar and the runways still exist, although one of the runways is now a taxiway. ‍ Howard Aircraft Corporation opened a factory across the road a year later, in 1944. They built more than 500 aircraft for the military, which was then pushed across the street for testing at the airport.  ‍ The airport was sold back to the county for $1 after the war, followed by a post-war boom that led to a new control tower, a new runway, and expansion plans that only came to fruition almost four decades later. ‍ Midway’s example (being unable to grow because of urban development around it) made the administration hurry to purchase more surrounding land and make it bigger, taking it from 360 hectares to 1,100 hectares by 1992, warranting control over all the property surrounding the runway complex and providing a larger buffer zone.  ‍ It has an FBO offering fuel, parking, de-icing, catering, lavatory services, and a little passenger terminal.  ‍ 95% of the yearly traffic corresponds to general aviation, 4% to air taxi, and less than 1% to military traffic. There are 255 aircraft based at the airport. ‍ They recently opened a U.S. Customs and Border Protection (C.B.P.) facility on the first floor of the DuPage Flight Center FBO. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, built in coordination with the DuPage Airport Authority, with on-site photography of all major facilities used for reference, custom ground textures, high-resolution photographic textures, custom night lighting, interior modeling of key structures, in-hangar parking spaces, static G.A. and corporate aircraft, reworked landscaping, and ambient lighting improvements. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $14.75, requiring at least 2.92 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdbl2</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Delays Block 2 Release for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdbl2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6358191032e01e7ba85063f3_fenix1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3158078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aamir Thacker, Fenix Simulations’ CEO, has made an announcement on their Discord regarding the upcoming IAE update for their A320 add-on, initially scheduled for release in September.  After progressing quickly with the CFM external engine model, they have decided to delay the release of the Block 2 update so that users can get both engines with the new model instead of just the IAEs as previously planned.  Their work on the IAE model made them more familiar with external engine development and significantly sped up the process with the CFMs. The new timeframe for the Block 2 update with both engine models is sometime in October.  They have also confirmed an entirely rebuilt cabin for Block 2, with more detail, increased performance, and a lower VRAM footprint. ‍ The Fenix A320 is available on their website for roughly $60.98, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfszgg</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studio Releases Guangzhou International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfszgg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6511e05c253a653b1b073f1c_zggg1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="101762"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WF Scenery Studio has recently released their rendition of Guangzhou Baiyun International Airport (ZGGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Guangzhou and Foshan with a yearly average of 40.2 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in China. ‍ The airport opened 19 years ago, replacing the former Baiyun Airport (from 1932), which was deemed too small for the predicted passenger figures and unable to be expanded because of urban development around its area. It was built 28 kilometers north of the city, making it immune to curfews and noise restrictions, thus allowing it to operate 24 hours a day.  ‍ It features two terminals, with Terminal 1 having three concourses and Terminal 2 - opened recently - being one of the world’s largest terminal facilities with 808,700 square meters.  ‍ It’s a hub for 9 Air, China Southern Airlines, FedEx Express, Hainan Airlines, and Shenzhen Airlines. As the busiest airport in China, the visitors list is quite substantial and mainly from Asia.  ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, animated jetways, dynamic lights, custom ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $25.31, requiring at least 5.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Tang0 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inisou</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Southampton Airport and Release Date for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inisou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6511e0073d60b921fbc5fc5f_image.thumb.png.c3abacbb5482daf71e74dbc25a66cf24.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1003571"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has announced that their next project is Southampton Airport (EGHI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. After initially teasing their next project a few weeks ago with a few screenshots, many eagle-eyed simmers in the community deduced that it was Southampton in the United Kingdom. That was officially confirmed today with a post by iniBuilds on their forum.  Southampton Airport was originally built in World War 1 for the Royal Flying Corps, and in 1917, was handed over to the United States Navy Air Service for a short period of time. It also served in a critical role for ground and air training for the Royal Navy in World War 2. It was also the site of the first flight of the Supermarine Spitfire. In the modern era, the airport is a hub for regional and international travel, and is home to many airlines including British Airways, easyJet, Aer Lingus, and Loganair. It also serves many operations to and from the Channel Islands. In their announcement, iniBuilds said that: “We have gone into extreme detail into this scenery and you can see that we have covered a lot of detail in all areas of the airport.” They also provided an explanation on why they picked Southampton, mainly because many on their scenery team, including their Head of Scenery Development are based in Southampton. Also in their announcement, iniBuilds provided a list of features that can be expected with the upcoming scenery, which include: ‍ They also included a trailer for the airport:  ‍ The scenery will be released on Friday, September 29th with a price of £12.99 excl. VAT, or $15.86 USD. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
