<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-03-26T18:21:54.313960+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oten12</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases True Earth GB North for XP12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oten12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fd1b44c3e6c688ee8edcd7_434074982_407847091893285_6361718592333214804_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx have just posted previews for another TrueEarth product for X-Plane 12. In an announcement, they posted a few teaser screenshots of their current project: TrueEarth Great Britain North for X-Plane 12. Orbx has developed numerous sceneries for all sorts of simulators, ranging from X-Plane 11/12, Prepar3D, Microsoft Flight Simulator, to lesser known sims, such as Aerofly and Tower! Simulator 3. This is their eighth product in the “True Earth” series for X-Plane, and is the first for X-Plane 12. This is also a continuation of their Great Britain True Earth products, being very popular in X-Plane 11. According to Orbx, the region will contain Scottish Highlands, the beautiful Lochs, the Outer Hebrides, the Shetland Islands, and the Isle of Man.  ‍ There is no fixed release date, however Orbx have said that “it’s around the corner”, but whenever they do announce a release date, Threshold will keep you informed, so stay tuned for more information!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777223</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777223"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fd58aa23906046ffbef014_Screenshot_2024-03-22_at_4.05.03_pm.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has published the first development update since the variant reveal of their upcoming 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with information on 737 updates for the marketplace version and a brand new 777 preview image (which is the cover of this article). Their 737 lineup is finally version matched across all platforms, all on 3.00.0091, the update which brings many memory improvements that significantly impact the product’s overall stability. That also means the Xbox version finally features the Ultimate Flight Tablet, albeit with some limitations: the data entry requires a keyboard to function, as the on-screen keyboard does not transmit data into the simulator in a way that the keystrokes could be captured by the add-on, which makes filling out the fields an impossibility.  They will be working on implementing a functional on-screen keyboard, but the turn-around time for beta builds on console is prolonged, which makes the experimenting take a lot longer than it would on PC. For now, having a keyboard attached to the console is the only way to interact with the tablet appropriately. As they have been busy with the 777 development, the 737 updates have halted, but they will pick it back up once the 777 is released. Updates will come if SU15 introduces any change that could break the 737 family. The 777-300ER is going through the final stage of development, where they ensure everything is polished and working accordingly. Randazzo even says they could theoretically launch the plane as it is right now, and people would be overwhelmingly happy with it. Still, they want to ensure everything is perfect before pushing the button.  They are working on getting the modern navdata conversion into beta testing, along with the lateral path guidance improvements made possible by Navigraph’s current format.  The 737 family can be found on their website or in the MSFS Marketplace, and the price ranges from $34.99 to $69.99, depending on the variant. The pricing for the upcoming 777-300ER has not yet been revealed.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwpbi</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release Palm Beach International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwpbi"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fdcd0c168135245b29c196_palm1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld &amp; AmSim have recently released their rendition of Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Miami metropolitan area with a yearly average of 7.7 million passengers. It opened in 1936 as Morrison Field, eventually becoming an important training airfield during World War 2 and operating as a staging base for the Allied invasion of France in 1944, with aircraft departing Palm Beach towards England in preparation for D-Day.  After a brief return to being a civil airport, the airport was once again utilized for military purposes in the early 1950s as Palm Beach Air Force Base, training nearly 23,000 airmen during the Korean War. The Air Force Base was closed in 1962, and Palm Beach was back to being just a civilian airport.  Currently, the airport has 32 gates and three concourses. Concourse A houses Bahamasair and Silver Airways; B houses Air Canada, American Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines; C, on the other hand, holds Delta, Frontier, JetBlue, and Spirit. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution custom ground textures, custom ground markings, parallax windows, animated jetways, and fully modeled buildings and objects. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.09, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniltn</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases New Mystery Airport</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniltn"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fe325ce0ae1a7c32c0a08a_433095249_18042843742709728_5876284696907720379_n.jpg.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds have posted a preview of their new work in progress scenery on their Instagram today. The picture shows a garage followed by a sign saying “Terminal Car Park 2”. Threshold did some digging and found that this render resembles the Car Park next to London Luton Airport. This garage suffered a fire in 2023 and since then has been closed to the public. Situated north of London, and considered to be one of London’s 5 major airports, London Luton Airport (EGGW) is one of the biggest hubs for low-cost airlines, used mostly by Ryanair and EasyJet, and during the day, this airport sees over 170 movements. In 2022, Luton reached a record number of over 13.3 million passengers, which is more than 9 million passengers compared to a year earlier.  ‍ iniBuilds has not announced a release date, pricing, or even confirmed that it is indeed London Luton yet, so stay tuned for more information - Threshold will keep you informed! </summary>
    <published>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftrcvg</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Cincinnati International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftrcvg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fe35cf3549dba860aa34f5_26.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky International Airport (KCVG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Cincinnati is a global cargo hub for DHL Aviation, Kalitta Air, Atlas Air, ABX Air, and Amazon Air, placing it 6th for the busiest cargo hub in the USA, and 12th in the world. Opened in 1944 as a training airport during WWII, the airport got its first passenger terminal two years later, with the first arrival being an American Airlines DC-3 from Cleveland. In mid-1980, CVG became one of Delta’s hubs, increasing yearly airport operations by 200.000, and doubling passenger volumes by to 20 million passengers handled per year. During its peak in 2005, CVG handled more than 600 flights a day. The airport consists of four runways (three parallel and one perpendicular), a single terminal and two concourses, Concourse A - that has 23 gates, and Concourse B -with 28 gates. CVG also serves as a third biggest world hub for DHL (The other two being Leipzig-Halle and Hong Kong) and as a main shipping hub for Amazon Air operating with more than 50 767-300/200F. FeelThere’s rendition of Cincinnati International Airport includes the following features: This scenery is available on SimMarket for $19.50USD and takes only 1.03GB of space on disk. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news, reviews, and editorials!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x12tro</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Saint-Tropez Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x12tro"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ff4f235ff9337f7fefc9d2_tropez1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of The Airport of the Golfe of Saint Tropez (LFTZ), serving the commune of Saint-Tropez, France, with a yearly average of 7,000 to 10,000 passengers. It was built in 1964 by Count François Gazeau and Marc Den Bosch as a strip of land stretching between the then national road and the river. The land belonged to Charles Boyer de Fonscolombe, who agreed to rent it out to François and Marc in memory of Saint-Exupéry, who happened to be one of his close cousins. In the early 1980s, Charles Boyer entrusted the airport’s operation to a management company, which further developed the airport in the 1990s to provide the region with an adequately structured airport. In that same decade, the runway was made public after an agreement with the state, remaining open 365 days a year for daylight operations only. A new passenger terminal was built in 1995, significantly increasing the passenger handling capabilities and adding a bar.   It’s mostly a general aviation airport, which accounts for most of its yearly aircraft movements. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with revised lighting, PBR reflections, custom ortophoto, custom vegetation, weather effects for wet, snow, and ice, revised autogen, reworked static aircraft (togglable), and more. It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $13.64, requiring at least 1.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/otegbn</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases TrueEarth Great Britain North for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/otegbn"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009029280503a7ed21365c_65de834726853.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has released their first TrueEarth scenery for X-Plane 12, Great Britain North. TrueEarth consists of high-quality, color-edited photoreal imagery, using specially made autogen technology for X-Plane. This addon covers 40,415 square miles of hand-corrected imagery covering the entire central region, as shown below in the coverage map. Scenery consists of: the Scottish Highlands, the beautiful Lochs, the Outer Hebrides, and the Shetland Islands. It includes many VFR landmarks, such as castles, monuments, bridges, and ancient ruins. Apart from the “ancient” landmarks, GB North also has urban cities - Glasgow and Edinburgh. Key features of TrueEarth Great Britain North are: This scenery can be bought from the Orbx Store for roughly $29.30, requiring at least 118.93 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned for more flight sim news on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winwng</id>
    <title>WINWING Reveals Pre-Order Date for A320 FCU</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winwng"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660091f91a2014d31b525b1d_FCU_PC_homepage_fff.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. WINWING, a well-known hardware producer in the mil-sim community has recently expanded into the civil flight sim community with their newest product - a full-size A320 FCU. Known for their hardware, they have established themselves as a high-quality producer of HOTAS, MIP (Main Instrument Panel), rudder pedals, and Joystick grips for various fighter jets. ‍ Showcased a couple of days ago on their YouTube channel, WINWING unveiled the launch of the Full-size FCU for A320. In the trailer, along with the Flight Control Unit, we could notice that EFIS and glare wing are also present in the trailer. Along with the video, the price was also revealed: ‍ On their Facebook page, they have unveiled the pre-order date: March 27 at 02:00UTC. They have also disclosed an expected shipping date - which is supposed to be in early May. ‍ The trailer shows that the FCU backlighting can be adjusted, and WINWING claims that it is auto-synced with the plane. All the knobs have the recognizable Airbus push-pull mechanism and the look of the knobs is very similar, if not the same, as in real Airbus.  ‍ The screen panel features two orange integrated LCDs, with realistic segment code.  ‍ One thing that caught my eye, the EXPED button (button under the ALT knob) seems to be missing. It turns out that WINWING decided to make the button unmarked, but still functional. The user can change its functions to their choice (FD, LS, and CSTR buttons are just some of the countless options the user can adjust to their liking). ‍ The third button in the row below, it is a solid color surface. On the WW FCU, it is still a functional button, just styled in this way. Because in reality, the original 320 button is also like this, and the rapid climb and descent function is basically prohibited by airlines for normal use. ‍ It seems that there are more Airbus products in development, in addition to the FCU. Later on in the trailer, EFIS panels and glare-wings are unveiled. Although it is unknown when will these two be released, or what their price will be, we can be sure to expect them in the A320 product lineup. Interestingly enough, this isn’t WINWING’s first Airbus product, as a quick look at their store shows that they also offer A3XX sidestick, which explains why the sidesticks are also colored, along with the glareshield. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news, reviews, and editorials! ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtama</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Rick Husband Amarillo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtama"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009942e58895107b3796aa_Banner-Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam just released their rendition of Rick Husband Amarillo International Airport (KAMA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Amarillo, Texas, with a yearly average of 670,000 passengers. It has been named after local astronaut Rick Husband, whose statue can be found inside the airport ( and accurately represented in the scenery). The airport serves many popular destinations with a total of four different commercial airlines. Allegiant, American, Southwest, and United are the ones flying out of Amarillo. They fly to the likes of Dallas/Fort Worth, Austin, Las Vegas, and Denver, to mention a few. Yearly just around 800,000 passengers travel through the airport of Amarillo. ‍ The scenery has lots of features like PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, custom pavement, custom jetways and many more custom objects, like passengers and terminal interiors. The scenery is now available on SimMarket for roughly $16.50USD and takes up around 1.03 GB of space on disk. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctlapa</id>
    <title>VATSIM Confirms The Airports for Cross the Land: Asia Pacific</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctlapa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009a41e36708a2da90408f_APAC.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. VATSIM just announced airports for Cross The Land: Asia Pacific Westbound edition in April on their Twitter account. This event involves the Australian and South Eastern Asian airports. ‍ Cross The Land is one of the biggest events on VATSIM, and just recently it got an expansion. Along with the Europe-MEA edition, CTL now has the Americas edition, where pilots fly from Northern American airports to South America, and the Asia Pacific edition, which brings the Australia-SE Asia connection.  ‍ The airport list for this year’s CTL: Asia Pacific is smaller than expected, only 6 airports were chosen, three in Australia and three in Asia: ‍ As of the posting of this article, no information about slot booking has been disclosed. Any new information will be posted on the Cross the Land Discord server and Twitter, as well as on Threshold! If you are interested in learning more about VATSIM, you can visit their website here. ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdplhr</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases London Heathrow Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdplhr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009dfee9eefa0b6ca2a6dd_deathrow1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently released their freeware and open-source rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, serving Greater London with a yearly average of 80 million passengers. London Heathrow is the eight-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprehending international travel, and the remaining 6% is strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it. The scenery features custom orthoimagery, custom ground textures, 3D grass, SAM jetways, VDGS, custom buildings, realistic dirt and grunge, and more. Its open-source nature warrants constant improvement, and ZDP has already shared a list of future futures, including more custom buildings, a Concorde static model, improved clutter, improved ground markings, improved vegetation, and more. ‍ It’s available for free on the Threshold Forum. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsapar</id>
    <title>FSA Announces 60+ Confirmed Partners for June’s FlightSimExpo</title>
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsapar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6601c95965684f346ca40009_fse1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a livestream, Flight Sim Association confirmed more than 60 hardware, software, training, and community organizations are participating in FlightSimExpo 2024, which is set to take off in June.  Phil Coyle, FSA's co-founder, says it's just the beginning, as there's still three months to go and plenty of time left for more partners to get involved. Perspective exhibitors can learn more at FSExpo's website; the deadline is May 31st. Attendees are encouraged to register before April 1st to get the year's best prices. The event registration includes in-person and online seminars, a free drink and appetizers at Friday's Attendee Welcome Reception, exhibit hall access on Saturday and Sunday, and more. FSA members are eligible for special pricing conditions. The partner list includes Navigraph, Orbx, Got Friends, Blackbird Simulations, Aerosoft Flight, Lockheed Martin Prepar3d, X-Plane (Laminar Research), SimFab, WinWing, SKALARKI, and Virpil Controls. The complete list is available on their website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bouukh</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases UK Helipads Pack 2 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bouukh"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6601ce44ddba9dec7064e36f_ukh1.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released their second package of UK Helipads for X-Plane 11 and 12, including five helipads spread across the United Kingdom, created in exceptional detail and featuring full XP12 compatibility.  The package features the helipads of Almondsbury (an NPAS and Air Ambulance base near Bristol), Brook Farm (a maintenance-centered helipad near Milton Keynes), Castle Air Liskeard (Run by Castle Air, a luxury helicopter fleet operator), Penzance Heliport (a newly opened and bustling site in Penzance), and Tresco Heliport (located near Penzance, on the island of Tresco. It’s highly scenic and very close to the Abbey gardens). ‍ The package features a high-detailed rendition of each helipad, with full XP12 optimization, dynamic weather effects (XP12 only), PBR textures, 3D vegetation, dynamic lighting, accurate custom static clutter, custom static vehicles, up-to-date layouts and locations, and a performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the Boundless Store for roughly $13.89, requiring at least 1.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmmyr</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Myrtle Beach International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmmyr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6601d313baf70c24890cd71f_myr4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Myrtle Beach International Airport (KMYR) for X-Plane 12, serving Myrtle Beach, South Carolina, with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers. It was built on property from a former air base, transferred by the government through the Surplus Property Act. Initially, the city of Myrtle Beach did not want to use the property for an airport, but the funds had to be used for an airport, which meant they funded Horry County Airport instead for 18 years. It wasn’t until 1977 that the city annexed the area of Myrtle Beach Airport, with the airport and the Air Force Base sharing the same runway until 1993 when the AFB closed, and the portions of the former military flight line were turned over to the County. Myrtle Beach became an international airport in 1996 and got a brand new passenger terminal for that exact purpose. Twelve years later, it underwent two major renovation projects to modernize the infrastructure. It’s currently undergoing expansion work, with six new gates being added to Terminal A, bringing the total number of gates to 18 and significantly increasing the traffic handling capabilities. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, Avelo Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines currently serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, custom autogen, high-resolution PBR ground textures, animated car traffic, 4K textures, 3D grass, color-graded satellite imagery, HDR night lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on the Verticalsim Shop for roughly $14.99, and X-Plane 11 users are eligible for a $9.99 upgrade fee.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boureu</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Reus Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boureu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6602d1cb436d0b2858ef8e9f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has just released their rendition of Reus Airport for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. The Spanish airport serves the city of Reus and has a yearly average of just over 1 million passengers. Located about 88 kilometers southwest of Barcelona, Reus Airport opened all the way back in 1935. The airport was used as a Republican base during the Spanish Civil War. After the war, the airport became a Spanish Air Force base. In the late 1990s, the airport became fully civilian, and has since been the destination for those who seek the sun. The airport has and is being served by airlines like Ryanair, TUI, and Jet2. The last few years, the yearly amount of passengers has seen a big rise, and the airport is becoming an increasingly more popular holiday destination for those wanting to visit the Spanish coast. The scenery has lots of features with the most noticeable of them being up to date Ortho imagery, 4K PBR Terminal &amp; Airport buildings, 3D vegetation, HD custom clutter objects, Animated airport ground traffic, 4K custom ground textures and fully accurate ground markings. According to Boundless, the airport has thousands of accurately placed objects and textures. Reus Airport is now available on the Boundless Store for £15.99GBP, or roughly $20.25USD and takes up around 970 MB of space on disk. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hrsu</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Yeosu Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hrsu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6602d64ad944e801f0324953_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has just released their rendition of Yeosu Airport (RKJY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The South Korean airport serves the city of Yeosu and has a yearly average of just under 650,000 passengers. Located in Yeosu, South Korea, Yeosu Airport opened on 23 May 1972. The airport is served by airlines like Asiana Airlines, Jin Air and Korean Air. These three airlines give the airport a total of two destinations, Jeju and Seoul-Gimpo. The scenery has lots of features with some of them being sloped runway, accurate simulation of Yeosu Airport, hand-made ground textures, dynamic airport lighting and highly detailed models of all airport buildings, objects and surroundings. Yeosu airport is now available on Orbx for $18.85AUD and takes up around 3.37 GB of space on disk. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
