<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-01-31T18:28:41.982035+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inipvd</id>
    <title>IniBuilds Teases Rhode Island T.F Green International Airport</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inipvd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6793c42dddab1ca4d22dabc3_Rhode_Island_T._F._Green_International_Airport_sign.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Renowned developer IniBuilds has recently teased its next project: Rhode Island T.F. Green Airport (KPVD), through a story on its Instagram and Facebook pages  T.F. Green Airport is located 10 miles south of Providence, Rhode Island, the primary city it serves. The airport features two runways and accommodates approximately 3.5 million passengers annually. ‍ The airport, named after former Rhode Island governor Theodore Francis Green, opened in 1931 and was rebuilt in 1966. It now primarily serves the East Coast. ‍ IniBuilds is one of the leading developers in flight simulation. They have created the A330-300 and Airbus Beluga for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Additionally, they have developed several classic Airbus aircraft for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and X-Plane 11. ‍ Details regarding features, compatibility, and other specifics remain unknown.  ‍ For further updates on T.F. Green Airport, iniBuilds, and more, stay tuned to Threshold! ‍ Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x-plane-12-1-4-released-in-public-beta</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12.1.4 Released in Public Beta</title>
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x-plane-12-1-4-released-in-public-beta"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6793da062f37a769aea67c68_Flightlessons_Title_6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The latest version of Laminar Research’s X-Plane, 12.1.4, is now available in public beta. This update, known as the flight lessons update, introduces numerous quality-of-life improvements, along with new flight lessons. ‍ Flight lessons Version 12.1.4 introduces new flight lessons for beginners. Users will be guided through four introductory lessons in the Cirrus SR-22 before moving on to the Lancair Evolution. All of this is led by Austin Meyer, the creator of X-Plane. ‍Camera updates The new build introduces a new physics-based camera option. According to Laminar Research it will simulate the forces experienced while flying a real aircraft. The new camera system is primarily focused on enhancing the interior view, however a new hand-held camera mode has also been added for external views. Scenery Salzburg Airport (LOWS) has undergone significant improvements, particularly in its local autogen, which has been enhanced considerably. Additionally, the Red Bull hangars and Salzburg Castle are now featured.  ‍ Parts of southern Germany, northern Italy, and Austria are now the demo area, with Salzburg being the location for the new flight lessons. ‍ In addition Barra Airport (EGPL) has also been updated. The Scottish airport is known for its unique runway—or lack thereof. Safe Mode Laminar Research is introducing a "safe mode" feature. This allows plugins to be isolated without needing to delete them manually one at a time when searching for the source of a crash. Additional improvements were made, including new library objects and enhancements to the G1000 with the introduction of the SAR function, along with other general updates. ‍ Refer to the X-Plane blog post for further details on the update. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw737</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases PMDG 737NG Sound Set for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw737"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67943969ef071b7748080568_boris5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Boris Audio Works has recently released their long-awaited sound set for the PMDG 737 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The set brings meticulously engineered sound captures from the cabin, engines, environment, and more. Recorded with state-of-the-art audio equipment from a real 737NG airplane, Boris Audio Works’ latest product promises a comprehensive audio package with a clear engine, cabin, fans, pack, ground roll, buttons, hydraulic pump sounds, and cabin chatter for extra immersion. Furthermore, the package also features a headphone simulation with noise canceling for those who aim to get a more realistic audio experience during their virtual journeys. The complete feature list follows below: The product is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.47, requiring at least 391.17 MB of free hard disk to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737112</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup &amp; Shares 747 Previews </title>
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737112"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679444116a9bb190466e481a_randy.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a new development update for their current and future products, including a new 737 lineup update, a 777 product line (new and upcoming variants), and a 747 Classic project. The 737NG lineup has been updated to v3.00.0112. This update primarily focuses on fixing the ongoing issues with the Universal Flight Tablet, trying to reduce or wholly eliminate the eternally spinning PMDG logo bug. Minor fixes on other fronts also further refine the product’s stability. ‍ Their main plan for the 737NG lineup was to stabilize it further, and their focus has now shifted back to their upcoming products. Extra effort will eventually be put into the revamped version for MSFS 2024, with new model upgrades, sounds, and an entirely new sound engine. ‍ The 777-200ER is still being readied for beta testing. Its release is planned to be MSFS 2020 only at first and then a free upgrade to MSFS 2024 later. The 200LR, which is set to come right after, will follow the same order. ‍ Regarding the upcoming 747 project, PMDG is still unsure whether the first to be released will be the -100 or the -400, as both are advancing as core development projects. Work has sped up quite significantly since they moved part of the 777 development team to the project. ‍ They have also previewed part of the modeling work on the 747-100s cockpit, reinforcing that wear, tear, and proper labeling have not yet been added.  Given the 747-100s manual nature of systems management, they will implement a virtual copilot and virtual flight engineer to help manage their systems efficiently and realistically, albeit with an option to disable them if desired. PMDG claims it’s still “too soon” for 747-400 cockpit previews, but the systems simulation work is well advanced. ‍ The 747-100 previews are the first to deviate from PMDG’s usual modus operandi: instead of sharing images only when the product is nearly finished / ready for testing, they show it early in its development stage. ‍ Their product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdsu1</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Optimistic Statement on MSFS 2024 SU1 Public Beta Compatibility </title>
    <updated>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdsu1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6700743a43d6279dcc6fba41_randy3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Robert Randazzo, PMDG's CEO, recently made an announcement post in their forum with further information on how their product line is faring with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024's latest public beta update and where they now stand regarding the eventual compatibility upgrade. They built the triple 777 in MSFS 2024 using the latest SDK, and it ran in a "mostly stable fashion" with debuggers attached. The airplane operated through an entire flight, and the many issues that showed up in the process were cataloged. They will be addressed starting next week to warrant the best experience possible. That means they have removed the "blockers" that were preventing them from starting work on the compatibility upgrade, and now they can finally begin the process. ‍ While it does run in MSFS 2024 already, it's not truly usable yet as many things don't work properly and require further adjustment. ‍ In Randazzo's words, their optimism needle for MSFS 2024 has "moved to the mid position," and PMDG looks forward to bringing its simulation value to the new platform.  ‍ PMDG's product lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/grutbf</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Grumman TBF Avenger for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/grutbf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6795c3d361a267f1da7cc5f4_avenger5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of the Grumman TBF Avenger for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This WW2-era airplane was developed for the United States Navy and Marine Corps and eventually adopted by many air and naval aviation services worldwide. It was designed in 1940 to replace the Douglas TBD Devastator, offering an airplane that was very much in line with the technology adopted by the Axis forces at the time, in complete contrast to the Devastator, which was considered obsolete by 1939. The Avenger was designed to easily fit in aircraft carriers, with easily stowable wings that allowed way more airplanes to fit in the same carrier.  With a maximum speed of 447 km/h, 1456km of total range, and a service ceiling of 22,600 feet, the mighty Avenger was one of the most iconic World War 2 bombers, permanently changing naval warfare.  Crafted with Paul Bennet’s expertise (an aerobatic pilot who happens to own one of the last airworthy Avengers), the add-on features realistic aerodynamics, high-quality sounds, high-quality 3D modeling and texturing, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $17.68, requiring at least 2.23 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cp2020</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Announces ChasePlane for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cp2020"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67980a55024e3305b1018fc0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 has recently announced that ChasePlane will soon be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. They have released a video teasing this exciting new camera plugin, after releasing an initial teaser video on their social media pages which is unfortunately now gone. ChasePlane was widely recognized within the Prepar3D community and was considered a must-have tool for many flight simulation enthusiasts. Since the launch of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, there has been a strong demand for this plugin; however, development faced challenges due to the limitations of the original camera API. Thankfully, it appears that these issues have now been resolved, and the plugin will soon be ready for users. The teaser and announcement video revealed that the upcoming plugin will offer a fully customizable camera system for MSFS and will incorporate real physics as well as view sharing, and various modes like FlyBy and Cinematic Mode. While no specific release date or price has been provided, the video concludes with a message stating "coming soon," suggesting that the release is not far off. ‍ We will keep you updated as more information becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hcak</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Akron-Canton Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hcak"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6799508b8ef5699f6a6d0ec7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly2High has recently launched its version of Akron-Canton Airport (KCAK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Situated in Ohio, the airport serves the cities of Akron, Canton, Cleveland, and Massillon. Each year, the airport welcomes nearly 700.000 passengers. The airport opened in 1946, initially intended for defense purposes during World War II, although its construction was delayed. In 1948, passenger flights began operating at the airport. The first terminal was established in 1955 and underwent expansions in 1962 and 2020. Today, the airport accommodates passenger airlines such as Allegiant Air, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, and United Express, along with the cargo airline Castle Aviation. These airlines offer destinations including Chicago, Las Vegas, Los Angeles, and many more. The scenery features a highly detailed rendition of the airport, main terminal interiors, custom jetways, custom lights, and more. The newly released scenery requires 3.9 GB of disk space and is available on iniBuilds for $15.59. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsogal</id>
    <title>FSoares Previews Upcoming Galeão International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsogal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6799bd57d8d9954f53198017_gig1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSoares has recently teased the development progress on his Rio de Janeiro/Galeão International Airport (SBGL) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is the main airport serving Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with a yearly average of 14.5 million passengers. It was opened in 1952 on top of a preexisting Brazilian Air Force base that was utilized by international long-haulers, which were too heavy and too large for SBRJ’s (Rio’s domestic airport) 1300m runway. With the ever-increasing international demand, they finally built a passenger terminal, which was progressively expanded until 1977. A new terminal building was opened that year, and all scheduled passenger traffic was transferred there. It’s still in use today as Terminal 1. Terminal 1 was first renovated in 1991 in preparation for the United Nations Earth Summit (held in 1992), and its annual capacity increased to 7.5 million passengers. Eight years later, Terminal 2 was opened, with 24 jetways and a capacity of up to 7.5 million passengers yearly. ‍With the imminence of the World Cup and the Olympic Games in 2014 and 2016, respectively, Infraero (the airport’s former manager) unveiled a $431 million upgrade and expansion plan for Galeão, including the renovation of Terminal 1, the completion of Terminal 2, and the expansion of the parking lots. The new concessionary revised the plans and included a new pier with 26 jetways, a new apron for 97 aircraft, and 2640 parking spaces. The $400 million sum quickly jumped to $800 million instead. Aerolíneas Argentinas, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, Azul, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Flybondi, Gol, Iberia, ITA Airways, JetSmart Argentina, JetSmart Chile, KLM, Latam Brasil, Latam Chile, Latam Peru, Lufthansa, Paranair, Sky Airlines, TAP, United Airlines, and Voepass serve it. ‍ There is no information on features, pricing, or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrbir</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2025 Receives Record-Breaking Initial Registrations</title>
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrbir"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665de94849a2f1d685a19e71_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The organisers of FlightSimExpo 2025 have announced a record number of initial registrations for the event. Over 500 people have already registered for the expo, which will take place in Providence, RI, from June 27th to June 29th. The current ticket prices for the event are valid until March 1st.  ‍ Here are the ticket prices by category: ‍ - Non-FSA Members: $80 - FSA First Officers: $72 - FSA Captains: $64 (The first 250 FSA registrants will receive a special price of $50.) ‍ All tickets include access to seminars and exhibition halls from Friday to Sunday, as well as recordings of the sessions. ‍ For virtual access to seminars, the fee is $15, which is free for FSA Captains. For the latest updates on discounts and information related to travel and logistics for the expo, please visit the FlightSimExpo website. The best ticket rates for FlightSimExpo 2025 are available until March 1st and can be purchased online. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lisvra</id>
    <title>Lisium Releases Riga International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lisvra"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679b0f7cb8872e8bab39f912_riga1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Lisium has recently released their rendition of Riga International Airport (EVRA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 (full compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will come shortly). The airport serves Riga, Latvia, and has a yearly average of 6.6 million passengers. It was built in 1973 to replace Spilve Airport, which was deemed outdated and unable to accommodate the projected passenger figures for the next few decades. The passenger terminal was expanded twice (2006 and 2016), gradually increasing its passenger handling capabilities to ensure the airport could keep up with the ever-growing demand. It’s a hub for airBaltic, Norwegian Air Shuttle, SmartLynx Airlines, RAF-Avia, and Ryanair. British Airways, Finnair, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Skyline Express Airlines, Smartwings, Turkish Airlines, and Wizz Air also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom PBR materials, parallax interiors, an up-to-date ground layout, highly detailed models, and accurately modeled interiors.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.75, requiring at least 1.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da4xls</id>
    <title>COWS Releases DA40-XLS for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da4xls"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c4be2e4cdede0dcd9c1d4_moo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS has recently released their long-awaited rendition of the DA40-XLS for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. With over 2,200 built, it is one of the most popular trainer aircraft in existence. Their rendition reproduces the XLS variant, which is a “deluxe” version of the DA40 with a full Garmin G1000 suite, WAAS (Wide Area Augmentation System), TAS (Traffic Alert System), and more. The add-on features a high-fidelity model with high-resolution textures, an accurate model based on reference imagery, properly placed placards, true-to-life performance and handling based on over 1000 hours of testing from real-world pilots, a full suite of custom systems with fully customizable circuit breakers, EIS and cylinder physics simulation, custom combustion simulation for startup, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ The add-on is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $25.02, requiring at least 1.30 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avapia</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces Release Date for Upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avapia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c91d63c4ee07a49406e99_pia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightFX recently announced a release date for their upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, along with the release of a launch trailer and pricing information. The Piaggio Avanti II is an evolution of the Piaggio Avanti, originally introduced in late 1990 after four years of flight testing. The original concept goes even further back to 1979, when engineering studies started, and design choices were tested in wind tunnels in the subsequent years by Professor Jan Roskam from the University of Kansas and Professor Gerald Gregorek from Ohio State University. The final design choice was finally made in 1982, with the fuselage development starting a year later. The first prototype only took off in 1986, with the Italian certification to come in early 1990. The Avanti II got certified in late 2005, featuring an uprated Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-66B turboprop engines, flying faster and more economically, and a new Rockwell Collins glass cockpit set. With 70 planes ordered in the first few months after the certification, the fastest civilian turboprop twin (according to Flying Magazine) was rather successful. The add-on promises a faithful recreation of the Piaggio Avanti II. It will be available in the MSFS Marketplace for $24.99 next Thursday (06/02).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2uni</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases University of Illinois Willard Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2uni"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c96d1974e436502d15024_uni1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 Scenery recently released their rendition of the University of Illinois Willard Airport (KCMI), serving the Urbana metropolitan area, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020.  While it was dedicated in late 1945, airline flights were to start nearly a decade later, in 1954, albeit in a very barebones manner, as the passenger terminal was only erected in 1960. By the late 1960s, Willard was the second-busiest airport in the state. However, it crumbled within a decade after the Airline Deregulation Act of 1978. Airlines found service to smaller airports inefficient and expensive. Airfares went up, whereas they went down at bigger airports like Chicago O’Hare, quickly killing the demand and leading many airlines to leave the airport altogether. A new passenger terminal was built in the late 1980s and remains used today. Until eleven years ago, the airport was home to the University of Illinois Institute of Aviation, which was voted by trustees to be closed in 2011, and everything was transferred over to Parkland College in 2013 so that the enrolled students could complete their courses.  Parkland College still operates the airport, providing an annual subsidy of $433,000. It’s currently served by a single airline, American Eagle, which flies passengers to Chicago O’Hare and Dallas/Fort Worth.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with full-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, performance-friendly optimization, custom vegetation, PBR materials, custom static aircraft, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.84, requiring at least 70.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mci224</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Kansas City International Airport V2 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mci224"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c9bb1bd800d775e97af72_kanser1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TropicalSim has recently released an updated version of their Kansas City International Airport (KMCI) V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport is the second busiest in Missouri after St. Louis, with a yearly average of 9 million passengers. The newly released version brings the airport layout up to current standards, with the new single terminal opened in 2023 that replaces Terminals B and C, with 40 gates in total. It also uses new SDK features such as the new LOD system, night lighting improvements, and ground layout edits to match the latest satellite imagery, excludes, and vegetation.  Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express currently serve it. SWA has the majority of the market share, with 45.43% of the traffic figures, followed by American and Delta, which have 14.27% and 14.08%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the new airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, native MSFS24 night lighting, PBR texturing, custom jetways, and a custom interior. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.91 and requires at least 457.73 MB of free hard disk space to install. V2 for MSFS 2020 owners are entitled to a free upgrade, and V1 owners can purchase the new scenery for a discounted price of $17.28. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rafhon</id>
    <title>IM Scenery Releases RAF Honington for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rafhon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679ca2f0e51d1bb0e7efbc6f_hon1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IM Scenery recently released their rendition of RAF Honington (EGXH), a Royal Air Force station in Suffolk, England, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024.  Construction started in 1935 and was undertaken by John Laing &amp; Son, an investment group now known as John Laing Group, which boasts 177 years of history. The opening occurred two years later, nearly right in time for the beginning of World War 2. Based in Honington at the start of the war, the IX Squadron ran the first British bombing raid of the Second World War, attacking the Kriegsmarine in the Baltic. In 1942, the airfield was transferred to the United States Army Air Forces and upgraded to a class A Bomber base. It was eventually transferred back to the RAF once the war was over, primarily utilized by the RAF Transport Command and later by the RAF Bomber Command in 1949. In the 1950s, a 9,000 ft concrete runway was built and completed in 1956. In the 1980s, it was selected to become a base for the RAF’s Panavia Tornado fleet, with the IX Squadron being reformed there and becoming the world’s first operational Tornado squadron. ‍ In mid-1992, it was decided that Honington would become an RAF Regiment Depot, with the Tornado fleet wholly leaving the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully custom objects with PBR textures, custom night lighting, custom ground poly, custom terraforming, and custom static aircraft. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $8.30, requiring at least 712.1 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
