<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-03-08T18:26:05.362280+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msf225</id>
    <title>MSFS Antonov 225 Released</title>
    <updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msf225" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dac683833efb0722aeb239_BANNER.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="938152"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The flight sim world is abuzz with excitement following the release of the AN225 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The AN225 Mriya, which means "Dream" in Ukrainian, is the world's largest aircraft and has a fascinating history. The INI Builds team along with Microsoft Flight sim has meticulously recreated this sorely missed behemoth of the skies in stunning detail, giving players the chance to experience what it's like to fly this iconic aircraft. The AN225 was originally designed in the Soviet Union in the 1980s as a heavy-lift transport aircraft for military and civilian use. The AN225 was used to transport the Soviet space shuttle, Buran, and was still used up until last year for heavy cargo transport, it was unfortunately destroyed in the ongoing Ukraine war. INI Builds has captured the essence of this aircraft in their simulation, from its massive wingspan to the distinctive six engines that power it. Pilots who purchase the MSFS/ INI Builds AN225 can experience the unique challenges of handling such a large and powerful machine. With great flight physics and attention to detail, the AN225 is sure to become a favourite among flight simulator pilots. MSFS have stated that 100% of the funds received from pilots who purchase the AN225 will go toward the cost of rebuilding the real aircraft.  You can pick up the AN225 on the MSFS store for just $19.99 </summary>
    <published>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmturku</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Release Turku Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmturku" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe4be8203726cd29d4475c_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1031717"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations have released their latest scenery for Microsoft flight simulator. Turku airport is the oldest civil aviation airports in Finland and is currently one of the busiest commercial airports in Finland.  The scenery features:  The new scenery can be purchased from Contrail, Orbx or a host of other flight sim software retailers for $15.00 USD.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p4dfrf</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Update FreedomFox </title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p4dfrf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe4e6b798481dc75dc5325_1_Lqh07qrYDamZlcMOrcAdbw.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="53390"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has updated its FreedomFox, which is based on famous pilot Trent Palmer's modern bush aircraft, the MSFS version now features a brand-new realistic suspension among other impressive changes.  Parallel42 have said:  “We’ve completely revamped the suspension, and you’ll finally get to feel what it’s like to taxi in a bush plane with big bad tires. Landings? You may need to refine those approach speeds, but you’ll certainly be happy to do so. It’s now ALIVE”  The full changelog includes:  NEW IMPROVED ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dhc4</id>
    <title>Asobo Release Local Legend 8: DHC-4</title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dhc4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe533607d16d3165f860c0_MSFS_LocalLegend_Caribou_08-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="233908"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo Studio, the developer behind Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS), has just released its latest update, Local Legend 8. This update includes several exciting new features, including the highly anticipated addition of the de Havilland Canada DHC-4 aircraft. The DHC-4, also known as the "Caribou," is a versatile transport aircraft that was widely used by the military and civilian operators for various missions, including transporting cargo and personnel to remote and rugged locations. With the addition of the DHC-4 to MSFS, pilots can now experience the unique flying characteristics of this classic aircraft and explore even more of the world within the simulator. The Local Legend 8 update is now available for all MSFS users to purchase through the MSFS store for €14.99, and pilots can start flying the DHC-4 and exploring the new features right away. Asobo Studio is committed to continually improving MSFS, and we can't wait to see what they have in store for the future. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbern</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Bern Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbern" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe8daf9bc7eecf5f10aa2d_bern1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="450221"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of a Bern Airport (LSZB) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a regional aerodrome serving the capital of Switzerland, averaging a little under 200,000 passengers a year. It was established in 1929 by Alpar Bern Flugplatzgenossenschaft, which operated many routes out of the airfield until the war, making a brief return afterward but eventually ceasing operations in 1947 and being bought out by Swissair.  With a 1,720-meter-long paved runway dating back to 1950 (and a 650-meter-long grass runway), it's long enough for most private jets and regional airliners (and a proper glider playground).  It’s served by four airlines: Helvetic Airways (Antalya, Heraklion, Kos, Larnaca, Palma de Mallorca, and Rhodes), Lübeck Air (Lübeck),  SkyAlps (Olbia, seasonally), and Swiss Flight Services (Elba, also on a seasonal basis). The scenery is developed by an independent developer, Massimiliano Addante, an ex-FSDT scenarist, and it features an accurate representation of the airport with custom ortho and projected mesh, static helicopters and GA aircraft, and crisp 4K &amp; 2K PBR textures. ‍ Orbx claims it’s releasing soon, with no exact date or pricing mentioned. Shout out to Poptart for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hhav</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Haverfordwest Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hhav" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6400d4796af601e59b4244d8_wales.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="297253"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Haverfordwest Airport (EGFE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a minor airport in Rudbaxton in Pembrokeshire (southwest Wales). It’s built on what once was RAF Haverfordwest, a WW2 airfield that operated for two years.   It has been serving as a civil airfield since the 1950s when the Pembrokeshire City Council bought the site. The airport has been CAA-licensed since 1974 (ordinary license) allowing flights for the public transport of passengers or flying instruction as authorized by the licensee (the city council).  The scenery features an accurate replica of the airport, with detailed modeling of the terminal, custom static aircraft, custom runway markings, animated flag, animated 3D passengers, and textures based on real-life reference imagery. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.60, requiring at least 692.13 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orxber</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Bern Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orxber" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6401f17f65d8087da0874eea_be1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1405606"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Bern Airport (LSZB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Capital of Switzerland with an average of 200,000 passengers a year.  Established in 1929 by a local airline (Alpar Bern Flugplatzgenossenschaft), it operated a couple of routes up until World War 2, when it stopped operations on a temporary basis, returning as soon as it was over, yet closed in 1947 and the company got bought out by Swissair.  The airport has two runways, paved and grass. The paved runway is 1,720m long, making it enough for general aviation aircraft, regional airplanes, and even some narrowbodies like the 737-700 and the A319.   It’s currently served by four airlines: Helvetic Airways (Antalya, Heraklion, Kos, Larnaca, Palma de Mallorca, and Rhodes), Lübeck Air (Lübeck),  SkyAlps (Olbia, seasonally), and Swiss Flight Services (Elba, also seasonally).  Brought to life by one of their independent developers, Bern Airport’s rendition features detailed modeling, custom orthoimagery and mesh, static helicopters and GA aircraft, crisp 4K and 2K PBR textures, and custom ground markings.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.81, requiring at least 1.35 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aedpwm</id>
    <title>AeroDesigns Announces Portland International Jetport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aedpwm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640238ec2e5beb54f3f0d646_pwm.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="141011"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AeroDesigns has recently announced their first product for Microsoft Flight Simulator: Portland International Jetport (KPWM), serving the city of Portland in Maine with a yearly average of 2 million passengers, making it the busiest in the state. The airport’s history dates back to the late 1920s when Dr. Clifford Strange needed somewhere to land his JN-4 “Jenny” Biplane. The first commercial service happened a few years later, in 1931, with a Boston-Maine Airways flight from Portland to Boston. The airfield was later purchased by the city and renamed to Portland-Westbrook Municipal Airport, which explains its origin code (PWM).  Nowadays, Portland benefits from low-cost carrier traffic such as JetBlue and Southwest Airlines, which helped to rank the airport among the most affordable in the region as of 2011.  Originally intended to be just a port of their KPWM for X-Plane 11, the scenery’s assets were entirely reworked, including ground textures, ground markings, taxi layout, a complete retexturing of the terminal building (externally and internally) with extra clutter to provide even better immersion. It also includes extra work on details such as dirt, extra ground service equipment, etc. AeroDesigns claims there’s no release date as of yet, but they hope to release it in the next few weeks, with work still going on regarding performance optimization and overall refinement. Console compatibility is still unconfirmed. Stay tuned to Threshold for more information on the scenery and all things flight simulation! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mig15b</id>
    <title>Bear Studios Releases MiG-15bis for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mig15b" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64043eaf0eadd548b3e1e117_314375_AC2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1081447"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, Bear Studios released their rendition of the MiG-15bis fighter for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing to the community an unique Cold War era Soviet fighter outfitted with detailed models and animations. According to the developers, the plane is created using real flight manuals of the MiG-15B, as well as reports filed by the United States Air Force. Bear Studios’s MiG, which will be VR compatible, will feature a cockpit that is fully interactive, in depth system, high quality external/internal textures, and lighting effects. The MiG-15, developed by the Soviet Union, is one of the first jet fighters in the world to employ a swept wing design. The fighter saw great success during the Korean War and was later used as the base design for the more advanced MiG-17. The MiG-15bis was a late variant that came equipped with a better performing engine that greatly improved the plane’s  thrust-to-weight ratio. Currently, the plane can be purchased from the JustFlight webstore or SimMarket for $29.99, excluding any sales tax that may incur. The developers recommend users to have at least 690 MB of free disk space to successfully install the product.</summary>
    <published>2023-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p2006t2</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Releases Tecnam P2006T MKII for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p2006t2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640445aaadf834ff700f090b_p2006t_02.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="185518"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio, developers of the Embraer E175 for MSFS, has released the Tecnam P2006T MKII for MSFS. The Tecnam P2006T is an Italian-designed four-seat high-wing, light twin piston aircraft popular in both the private and flight training market.  The Tecnam P2006T is an Italian Designed aircraft that has become popular in the flight training market due to its economical design. Powered by two 100Hp Rotax 912 engines, this aircraft is extremely economical to operate, and its high wing design has made this aircraft popular with both flight schools and aerial photography companies. This aircraft has also found its way into military service primarily as a pilot trainer.  The P2006T by FlightSim Studios features the Working Title Garmin G1000NXI paired with a custom STEC-55X autopilot. Other highlights include: A full list of features can also be found on the store page.  This aircraft is now available from the Aerosoft Store and will cost €29.37 ($31.28 USD). It will require 1.5 GB of storage and must be installed via Aerosoft One.</summary>
    <published>2023-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/toga73</id>
    <title>TOGA Simulations Release Roadmap for 737 and MU-2 </title>
    <updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/toga73" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/5c009821477c692a48d0692d_X-Plane_Screenshot_2018.11.28_-_18.53.52.13.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2896750"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Toga simulations (also known as IXEG) are responsible for the IXEG 737 Classic and the Mitsubishi MU-2 for the Xplane platform. Since the release of Xplane 12, many have been keen to find out what the future of these two aircraft would hold.  In a recent development update posted on the X-Pilot Forums, developer Tkyler has explained that the group will unfortunately not reach their previously intended date of March 8th for the IXEG to come to XP12. But has assured eager pilots that work is progressing at “Full Bore” Tkyler has also informed those interested to expect a more informational update in the coming week.  The following roadmap has been provided by the team:  “The roadmap for myself (being both IXEG and TOGA) is to get this port update out, then I'll binge the MU2 for 4-ish weeks, getting it refined for V12 and then take a deep breath/short break and dive into the FMS / VNAV functionality of the 733 while also seeking out other areas to improve throughout the remainder of the year”  It surely seems like an exciting future is on the horizon for both of these much-loved aircraft, Threshold will keep you updated as it progresses!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fvrbsl</id>
    <title>France VFR Releases EuroAirport Basel Mulhouse Freiburg for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fvrbsl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6405eeb44ba586e483483682_bsl1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="349136"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. France VFR has recently released their rendition of EuroAirport Basel Mulhouse Freiburg (LFSB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving three different cities in three countries due to its strategic location near the border tripoint between France, Germany, and Switzerland.   Dating back to the mid-1940s, the airport was part of a Swiss-French plan to build a joint airport, which almost started in the 1930s but was shattered by a looming World War. Once the dust had finally settled, around 1946, they went on with the project, with the French providing the land and the Swiss covering the construction costs. It was officially opened in May of that year, with a provisional runway (1,200m long). The runway saw expansion work in the 50s, 60s, and 70s when it finally reached its current length (3,900 meters).   Basel reached the 1 million passenger/year mark in 1984, doubling down in 1992 and rising to 3 million in 1998 when Swissair inaugurated their service to Newark with their A310s and A330s.   In the 2000s, Swissair started facing financial issues, resulting in the extinguishment of the Newark route, with the company following suit a year later, causing a drop in passenger activity as it was the largest operator in Basel. It wasn’t until 2004 when easyJet embraced the airport as their new base and brought the passenger figures to an incredible 4 million in 2006.   As a curiosity, Basel is one of the few airports in the world operated by two countries and governed by an international convention. The airport and its HQ are in France, but it features a Swiss customs area and border, with a 2.5km customs-free road to Basel, bypassing French clearance. But it goes even further than that, as the airport building is split in two, with a French and Swiss section under their own rules. It also sports three (!) IATA codes: BSL, MLH, and EAP.  The passenger figures currently sit at 9 million passengers yearly, with a huge part of them transported by EasyJet Switzerland (Basel is one of their hubs), with a massive intra-European network. Corendon and WizzAir also offer their fair share of destinations. It’s also visited by many mainstream European carriers such as Austrian Airlines, British Airways, KLM, and Lufthansa.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, detailed ground markings, photo-realistic 3D buildings, realistic night lighting, custom jetways, custom vegetation, and geo-referenced data.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.76, requiring at least 534.78 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teiscar</id>
    <title>Teikof Studio Releases Scarlett Martínez International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teiscar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6405f56f876c5ca782b74b3c_scar1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3516343"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Teikof Studio has recently released their rendition of Scarlett Martínez International Airport (MPSM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Rio Hato in Panama.  Originally built as an Air Force Base, Rio Hato was of great importance during WW2, helping defend the Panama Canal. It closed not much after the war but was still used as an auxiliary military landing field until the 1990s.  The airport was recently rebuilt using most of the military infrastructure from the 1940s as a baseline to cut costs (yet it still cost 53 million dollars). The runway and terminal underwent rehabilitation, and the Pan-American Highway, which previously crossed the runway, got its tunnel.  It’s named after Scarlett Martínez, a 22-year-old copilot that was on a flight that disappeared for six days in 2000 (it crashed against the Pito Carreto mountain in Comarca Kuna Yala).  It’s served by four airlines: Air Panama, Air Transat, Arrendamientos Aéreos, and Sunwing Airlines (the only one with a fixed schedule to Toronto-Pearson). Most of the other flights are either chartered or seasonal. The airport averages a little less than 70,000 passengers a year. The scenery features PBR texturing, high-quality ground markings with wear and tear, landside buildings, and the Pan-American Highway. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.73, requiring at least 111.14 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ledinc</id>
    <title>LeAeroDesign Releases Incheon International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ledinc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6405fa744ecf3bc18df4c1e3_inch1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="194070"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LeAeroDesign has recently released their rendition of Seoul-Incheon International Airport (RKSI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the largest airport in South Korea and among the busiest in the world, with a yearly average of 70 million passengers!  Incheon opened in 2001 to replace Gimpo International Airport as the main airport in South Korea and handle the extra international air traffic that the former airport was unable to (as seen during the 1988 Olympics and the early 90s). Construction work started in 1992 on reclaimed land between Yeongjong Island and Youngyu Island, taking eight years to finish and facing an economic crisis delay.   It is the main hub for Korean Air, Asiana Airlines, Jeju Air, and Polar Air Cargo. The current record figures revolve around 71 million passengers a year, with Korean Air being responsible for 26% of the market share, followed by Asiana Airlines and Jeju Air with 18.04% and 8.09%, respectively. Destination-wise, Hong Kong is the busiest, with 3,149,768 passengers, followed by Osaka-Kansai (2,840,003), and Tokyo-Narita (2,783,677).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Seoul-Incheon, with highly detailed 3D models, highly-detailed 3D markings, PBR optimization, photorealistic terrain, high-detail taxi lights with realistic light visibility angles, enhanced 3D lighting, correct localizer &amp; glideslope path, realistic pushback procedures and VDGS (GSX Pro dependant).  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $23.34, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfshah</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Frankfurt-Hahn Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfshah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6407aaf8b972a00dd4a4ca78_hah1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2625063"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Frankfurt-Hahn Airport (EDFH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the low-cost oriented gateway to the Rhineland. ‍ Hahn dates back to the early 1950s when it was founded by occupying french forces and taken over by the USAF a year later, where it initially hosted the 7356th Air Base Group, responsible for improving the facilities and getting it into an operational state. The USAF made use of the Hahn Air Base up until the early 1990s when it was handed over to Germany. The German government decided to transform the Air Base into a civil airport to alleviate the traffic at Frankfurt International Airport.  Nowadays, the airport averages around 1.3 million passengers yearly, served by either Ryanair or WizzAir, the two low-cost giants that operate in Hahn. The Irish carrier offers seventeen fixed destinations (and fifteen seasonals), and the Hungarian sports eight destinations.  As a curiosity, Frankfurt-Hahn recently filed for bankruptcy and sold to a new investor in mid-2022 which ended up not transferring the funds, and now they have signed two preliminary contracts with two new potential buyers, one of them being no more no less than the owner of the Nürburgring.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, custom GSE, custom lighting, custom ground markings, landside buildings, ground clutter, and hangars. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.03, requiring at least 396.14 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jtsrho</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Rhodes International Airport v3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jtsrho" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6407bc154fbab68934a227da_rho1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="306899"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. JustSim has recently released their new rendition of Rhodes International Airport (LGRP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Greece with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  Built in 1977 to replace the old Rhodes Maritsa Airport, which was deemed too cramped for passenger traffic, it covers an area of 60,000 square meters, sporting a single, 3,305-meter-long runway. The airport underwent multiple expansion work over the years, with the most recent one dating back to 2005, consisting of the inauguration of a new passenger terminal.  The airport is now owned by Fraport-Greece, which recently introduced an investment plan to further improve the airport, with a general clean-up, improved lighting, an upgrade to sanitary facilities, free wi-fi, terminal remodeling, a new fire station, more check-in counters, etc.   It’s served by many airlines on a seasonal basis (summer only), including Aegean Airlines (one of the few with a year-long route), Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Lufthansa, Olympic Air, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Transavia, WizzAir, and others.  JustSim’s new Rhodes features better 3D models, improved textures, and excellent landside detail.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.89, requiring at least 1.18 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
