<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-03-04T18:23:26.497484+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzacia</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases Christchurch International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzacia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f8109287c96cd8ec4be544_chr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1118538"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NZA Simulations has recently released their rendition of Christchurch International Airport (NZCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in New Zealand with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. Opened in 1940 as RNZAF Station Harewood (the airport is located in Harewood, a suburb of Christchurch), it got its first bits of infrastructure around six years later, with the construction of a passenger terminal and hangars. The clearance for international operations came in 1950, making it New Zealand’s first international airport. It’s the hub for Air New Zealand, with a significant domestic network covering most relevant cities within the country, including Auckland, Dunedin, Hamilton, Hokitika, Invercargill, Napier, Nelson, New Plymouth, Palmerston North, Queenstown, Rotorua, Tauranga, and Wellington. The coverage also extends to Australia, with Brisbane, Gold Coast, Melbourne, and Sydney. The visitors’ list includes Cathay Pacific (returning in November 2023), Emirates (returning in March 2023), Fiji Airways, Jetstar Airways, Qantas, and Singapore Airlines. In total, there are 18 domestic and 11 international destinations, with 1057 weekly flights as of 2015. The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, with full 3D custom modeling including the surrounding business parks (roughly 300 in total), the runways and apron are built with PBR materials, realistic ground markings, realistic roads, high resolution aerial imagery, terra-formed runway, parking positions setup with correct airline codes, interiors for the main terminal, custom jetway sounds, animated jetways (custom for each gate, matching real life), animated 3D people, animated custom AI vehicles around the airport, and a working surveillance radar. It’s available on the NZA Simulations Shop or OrbxDirect for $25.46/$25.38, respectively. At least 4.27 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wupdnz</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XII: New Zealand</title>
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wupdnz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f81b62f108693de8e05de7_nz1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="326542"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released the 12th World Update, improving New Zealand with seven high-detail cities, multiple points of interest, nine handcrafted airports, new bush trips, discovery flights, and challenges. The new update brings together the latest geographic data, including satellite imagery, aerial photography, and digital elevation models (DEMs), with high-detail renditions of seven cities: Auckland, Christchurch, Hamilton, Nelson, Queenstown, Tauranga, and Wellington.  The complete feature list follows down below: Points of Interest ‍ Handcrafted Airports Bush Trips ‍ Discovery Flights   Landing Challenges ‍ The World Update is available for free on the MSFS Marketplace.   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inbf10</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Bf108 Taifun for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inbf10" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f8cf130fc60bf70eb8cad5_taif1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="374950"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of the Bf108 Taifun for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engine sport aircraft from the early 1930s.   Designed to compete in the 4th Challenge International de Tourisme in 1934, a major aviation event in pre-war Europe held in Warsaw, Poland, the Taifun was then just a prototype called M34, powered by a 247 horsepower Hirth HM 8U V8 engine, which didn’t manage to win the event but impressed with a low fuel consumption rate, good handling and it’s superb take-off/landing characteristics.  The Bf108a, the first variant, took off for the first time in that same year, powered by three different engines (on different airframes): the original Hirth HM 8U, the Argus As 17B with 217 hp, and later units had a Siemens-Halske Sh 14 radial, with 158hp. The Bf108b was a revision whose prototype rocked a Siemens-Halske Sh 14a radial, but the production units had either the Argus AS 10C (237hp) or the Argus AS 10E (266hp).  iniBuilds’ second classic aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator makes use of the latest CFD technology including the primary flight surfaces, control surfaces, and the propeller. It also simulates unique characteristics of the airplane such as the capability of landing as slow as 45 knots thanks to its advanced leading edge slats. Such slow speed allows it to operate on very short runways.  The engine is accurately reproduced with its correct performance and behavior, with a fully modeled and functional fuel system that makes use of the new fuel mechanics offered by the simulator.   A custom electronic flight bag allows for folding and unfolding the wings, opening storage compartments, choosing a custom rain cover, and changing the cockpit labels from German to English and from metric to imperial. It also features a moving map, weather information, a maintenance page, and other settings.  The aircraft is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.01, requiring at least 2.66 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mturku</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Turku Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mturku" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63f9bd57d5c4ba3c1dfad474_turku1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="800719"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations has recently released their rendition of Turku Airport (EFTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Turku in Finland with a yearly average of 450,000 passengers, making it the fourth busiest airport in the country. Located in the airport district in the Maaria-Paatinen ward, which is the most sparsely populated district in Turku and includes half of the city’s area, it was built in 1955 when it was still part of Rusko, becoming part of Turku three years later.  Turku Airport underwent a heavy renovation process in mid-2014 when Finavia spent over 14 million euros on improving Terminal One and the passenger apron. Terminal 2 was closed and demolished a year later after an oil leakage, concentrating the low-cost operations on the first floor of the main terminal. It’s currently served by six different airlines: AirBaltic (Riga), Amapola Flyg (Mariehamn), Finnair (Helsinki), Scandinavian Airlines (Stockholm-Arlanda), Sunclass Airlines (seasonal legs to Gran Canaria and Tenerife South), and WizzAir (Gdansk and Rome Fiumicino). Gdansk is the busiest route as of 2019, with 117,261 passengers, followed by Helsinki and Stockholm, with 100,086 and 86,331, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with updated CGL data, real-world-based terraforming profile, PBR materials, ambient animated objects, custom interior modeling, and custom 3D people. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.86, requiring at least 2.44 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpgib</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Gibraltar International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpgib" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fa87ca5f80df35b501c500_gibby1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2502245"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently released their rendition of Gibraltar International Airport (LXGB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth most extreme airport in the World according to the History Channel’s Most Extreme Airports.    Dating back to early World War 2, it was built as an emergency airfield for the British Royal Navy, with runway extensions to happen later on once some of the land was reclaimed by using rocks from the Rock of Gibraltar (what remained of carving military tunnels).   The airport saw most of its business flourish in the early 2000s when Monarch began flying from Manchester. Iberia, easyJet, and British Airways followed suit not soon after. Nowadays, British Airways and easyJet are the only two airlines serving Gibraltar frequently with routes to London-Heathrow (BA) and Bristol, London Gatwick, and Manchester (EZY), roughing up to 400,000 passengers a year.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models, PBR texturing, a terminal interior with 3D passengers, more than a thousand clutter objects, realistic and functioning runway crossing (cars stop when turning the strobe light on), custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, accurate night lighting, custom taxiway signage, custom ground traffic, and over twenty animations.   It’s available on the RDPresets Store and SimMarket for roughly $21.13/$19.02, respectively. At least 1.3 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p73763</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p73763" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fa932fe014bebc53f436d6_pine1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2595376"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their 737 lineup to version 3.00.0063 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a range of minor fixes and improvements along with an Operations Center update.  In order to update the product, customers have to manually update the Operations Center, as the automatic update system is not working. The instructions are available on the announcement post here.   As previously mentioned, it’s a minor update with improvements to the whole lineup with the intent to "move the quality forward", as stated by the CEO. The complete changelog follows down below:  ‍ After the release of the -900, they claim to focus on general fixes, updates to the existing logic, and merging in the new navdata. Work also continues on the Universal Flight Tablet. They finished off with a note on the MSFS Beta Channel, especially regarding the SU12 compatibility, where it's stated they might hold off on updates until SU12 is out to the public, with an eventual beta channel on the Operations Center that would allow PMDG to push updates to both stable and beta (something for the future after the tablet is out and they are happy with all the pending improvements).   The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600), $49.99 (737-900), and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Pictures are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bwssan</id>
    <title>Borneo Wonder Sceneries Releases Sandakan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bwssan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fb6f9570220e8e9e9d34c1_sanda1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3358680"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Borneo Wonder Sceneries has recently released their rendition of Sandakan Airport (WBKS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Sandakan, the capital of the Sandakan District in Sabah, Malaysia.   Sandakan Airport’s history dates back to World War 2 when the Royal Air Force picked the site to build an airfield but didn’t actually get to do much other than get rid of the vegetation before the Japanese invasion of Borneo. The Japanese Army, on the other hand, needed a refueling stop between the peninsular Malaya and the Philippines, transferring over 1,500 prisoners of war from the UK and Australia to work on the construction. Work started in August 1942 and saw partial completion by December of that same year, when a bomber aircraft landed in Sandakan for the first time, opening it for service.   The runway was recently extended to 2,500m, with an expansion plan that goes all the way back to 2017, with operations commencing in 2019 but delayed due to the pandemic and finally reaching completion in 2022, allowing the operation of popular narrowbody aircraft like the B737, A320, and the A321. Widebody aircraft can also operate on it with payload/range restrictions.   It’s served by AirAsia (Kota Kinabalu, Kuala Lumpur), Malaysia Airlines (Kota Kinabalu, Kuala Lumpur), and MASwings (Kudat, Lahad Datu, Tawau), averaging around 900,000 passengers yearly.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled terminal (including interior), landside buildings, custom ground textures, custom ground markings, and a custom jetway model.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.63, requiring at least 899 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff3206</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Update’s A320 to Version 1.6.1</title>
    <updated>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff3206" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fbb4aac649c1c142244a67_a320%20-%202022-09-05%2022.53.26.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="255023"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor's A320 has been one of the most popular and well-regarded flight simulation aircraft for some time. The latest update to the A320 includes several improvements and fixes that enhance the overall experience of flying the plane. In this news article, we will take a closer look at the improvements and fixes introduced in the update. Cabin Visual Improvements: One of the most notable improvements in this update is the enhancement of the cabin visuals. The update brings improvements to the cabin, which helps to create a more immersive experience. These improvements make the cabin feel more realistic and add to the overall realism of the aircraft. Fixes: The update also includes several fixes which address issues that were present in previous versions of the addon. Some of these fixes are: ‍ Dimmed Cabin Floor Light Stripe: One of the issues addressed in this update is the floor light stripe. The update fixes this issue and ensures that the light stripe appears as intended. ‍ VSW Stuck and Not Moving: Another issue addressed in this update is the VSW stuck and not moving. The VSW (Vertical Speed Wheel) is an essential component of the aircraft, and when it gets stuck, it can cause problems for the pilot. The update fixes this issue and ensures that the VSW operates correctly. ‍ Overspeed Protection Too Aggressive: The overspeed protection in the A320 was too aggressive, which meant that the aircraft would automatically reduce its speed even when it was not necessary. This update fixes this issue and ensures that the overspeed protection operates as intended. ‍ Missed Doors in XP11 Version: In the XP11 version of the A320, some doors were missing. The update fixes this issue and ensures that all doors are present and functioning correctly. ‍ Missed Internal Lights in the Cockpit and Cabin in XP11 Version: Another issue in the XP11 version was the missed internal lights in the cockpit and cabin. The update fixes this issue and ensures that all internal lights are present and working correctly. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msf225</id>
    <title>MSFS Antonov 225 Released</title>
    <updated>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msf225" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dac683833efb0722aeb239_BANNER.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="938152"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The flight sim world is abuzz with excitement following the release of the AN225 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The AN225 Mriya, which means "Dream" in Ukrainian, is the world's largest aircraft and has a fascinating history. The INI Builds team along with Microsoft Flight sim has meticulously recreated this sorely missed behemoth of the skies in stunning detail, giving players the chance to experience what it's like to fly this iconic aircraft. The AN225 was originally designed in the Soviet Union in the 1980s as a heavy-lift transport aircraft for military and civilian use. The AN225 was used to transport the Soviet space shuttle, Buran, and was still used up until last year for heavy cargo transport, it was unfortunately destroyed in the ongoing Ukraine war. INI Builds has captured the essence of this aircraft in their simulation, from its massive wingspan to the distinctive six engines that power it. Pilots who purchase the MSFS/ INI Builds AN225 can experience the unique challenges of handling such a large and powerful machine. With great flight physics and attention to detail, the AN225 is sure to become a favourite among flight simulator pilots. MSFS have stated that 100% of the funds received from pilots who purchase the AN225 will go toward the cost of rebuilding the real aircraft.  You can pick up the AN225 on the MSFS store for just $19.99 </summary>
    <published>2023-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmturku</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Release Turku Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmturku" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe4be8203726cd29d4475c_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1031717"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations have released their latest scenery for Microsoft flight simulator. Turku airport is the oldest civil aviation airports in Finland and is currently one of the busiest commercial airports in Finland.  The scenery features:  The new scenery can be purchased from Contrail, Orbx or a host of other flight sim software retailers for $15.00 USD.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p4dfrf</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Update FreedomFox </title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p4dfrf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe4e6b798481dc75dc5325_1_Lqh07qrYDamZlcMOrcAdbw.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="53390"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has updated its FreedomFox, which is based on famous pilot Trent Palmer's modern bush aircraft, the MSFS version now features a brand-new realistic suspension among other impressive changes.  Parallel42 have said:  “We’ve completely revamped the suspension, and you’ll finally get to feel what it’s like to taxi in a bush plane with big bad tires. Landings? You may need to refine those approach speeds, but you’ll certainly be happy to do so. It’s now ALIVE”  The full changelog includes:  NEW IMPROVED ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dhc4</id>
    <title>Asobo Release Local Legend 8: DHC-4</title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dhc4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe533607d16d3165f860c0_MSFS_LocalLegend_Caribou_08-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="233908"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo Studio, the developer behind Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS), has just released its latest update, Local Legend 8. This update includes several exciting new features, including the highly anticipated addition of the de Havilland Canada DHC-4 aircraft. The DHC-4, also known as the "Caribou," is a versatile transport aircraft that was widely used by the military and civilian operators for various missions, including transporting cargo and personnel to remote and rugged locations. With the addition of the DHC-4 to MSFS, pilots can now experience the unique flying characteristics of this classic aircraft and explore even more of the world within the simulator. The Local Legend 8 update is now available for all MSFS users to purchase through the MSFS store for €14.99, and pilots can start flying the DHC-4 and exploring the new features right away. Asobo Studio is committed to continually improving MSFS, and we can't wait to see what they have in store for the future. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbern</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Bern Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbern" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63fe8daf9bc7eecf5f10aa2d_bern1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="450221"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of a Bern Airport (LSZB) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a regional aerodrome serving the capital of Switzerland, averaging a little under 200,000 passengers a year. It was established in 1929 by Alpar Bern Flugplatzgenossenschaft, which operated many routes out of the airfield until the war, making a brief return afterward but eventually ceasing operations in 1947 and being bought out by Swissair.  With a 1,720-meter-long paved runway dating back to 1950 (and a 650-meter-long grass runway), it's long enough for most private jets and regional airliners (and a proper glider playground).  It’s served by four airlines: Helvetic Airways (Antalya, Heraklion, Kos, Larnaca, Palma de Mallorca, and Rhodes), Lübeck Air (Lübeck),  SkyAlps (Olbia, seasonally), and Swiss Flight Services (Elba, also on a seasonal basis). The scenery is developed by an independent developer, Massimiliano Addante, an ex-FSDT scenarist, and it features an accurate representation of the airport with custom ortho and projected mesh, static helicopters and GA aircraft, and crisp 4K &amp; 2K PBR textures. ‍ Orbx claims it’s releasing soon, with no exact date or pricing mentioned. Shout out to Poptart for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hhav</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Haverfordwest Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hhav" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6400d4796af601e59b4244d8_wales.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="297253"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Haverfordwest Airport (EGFE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a minor airport in Rudbaxton in Pembrokeshire (southwest Wales). It’s built on what once was RAF Haverfordwest, a WW2 airfield that operated for two years.   It has been serving as a civil airfield since the 1950s when the Pembrokeshire City Council bought the site. The airport has been CAA-licensed since 1974 (ordinary license) allowing flights for the public transport of passengers or flying instruction as authorized by the licensee (the city council).  The scenery features an accurate replica of the airport, with detailed modeling of the terminal, custom static aircraft, custom runway markings, animated flag, animated 3D passengers, and textures based on real-life reference imagery. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.60, requiring at least 692.13 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orxber</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Bern Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orxber" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6401f17f65d8087da0874eea_be1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1405606"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Bern Airport (LSZB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Capital of Switzerland with an average of 200,000 passengers a year.  Established in 1929 by a local airline (Alpar Bern Flugplatzgenossenschaft), it operated a couple of routes up until World War 2, when it stopped operations on a temporary basis, returning as soon as it was over, yet closed in 1947 and the company got bought out by Swissair.  The airport has two runways, paved and grass. The paved runway is 1,720m long, making it enough for general aviation aircraft, regional airplanes, and even some narrowbodies like the 737-700 and the A319.   It’s currently served by four airlines: Helvetic Airways (Antalya, Heraklion, Kos, Larnaca, Palma de Mallorca, and Rhodes), Lübeck Air (Lübeck),  SkyAlps (Olbia, seasonally), and Swiss Flight Services (Elba, also seasonally).  Brought to life by one of their independent developers, Bern Airport’s rendition features detailed modeling, custom orthoimagery and mesh, static helicopters and GA aircraft, crisp 4K and 2K PBR textures, and custom ground markings.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.81, requiring at least 1.35 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aedpwm</id>
    <title>AeroDesigns Announces Portland International Jetport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aedpwm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640238ec2e5beb54f3f0d646_pwm.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="141011"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AeroDesigns has recently announced their first product for Microsoft Flight Simulator: Portland International Jetport (KPWM), serving the city of Portland in Maine with a yearly average of 2 million passengers, making it the busiest in the state. The airport’s history dates back to the late 1920s when Dr. Clifford Strange needed somewhere to land his JN-4 “Jenny” Biplane. The first commercial service happened a few years later, in 1931, with a Boston-Maine Airways flight from Portland to Boston. The airfield was later purchased by the city and renamed to Portland-Westbrook Municipal Airport, which explains its origin code (PWM).  Nowadays, Portland benefits from low-cost carrier traffic such as JetBlue and Southwest Airlines, which helped to rank the airport among the most affordable in the region as of 2011.  Originally intended to be just a port of their KPWM for X-Plane 11, the scenery’s assets were entirely reworked, including ground textures, ground markings, taxi layout, a complete retexturing of the terminal building (externally and internally) with extra clutter to provide even better immersion. It also includes extra work on details such as dirt, extra ground service equipment, etc. AeroDesigns claims there’s no release date as of yet, but they hope to release it in the next few weeks, with work still going on regarding performance optimization and overall refinement. Console compatibility is still unconfirmed. Stay tuned to Threshold for more information on the scenery and all things flight simulation! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
