<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-05-05T18:27:57.291640+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737rel</id>
    <title>PMDG On Approach to Release for 737-700; Remains Tight-Lipped On Release Date</title>
    <updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737rel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625d54e2d60a955d6adc601f_ayo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="906428"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG is reaching the end of the tunnel in the development of their hotly-awaited 737-700NG3. On their forums, Robert Randazzo detailed that the team remains bullish for a timely release, but is still reserved on setting a concrete release date due to several factors adding “ambiguity” to the project’s completion, and the upcoming Sim Update 9 from Asobo additionally brings more uncertainty to the add-on’s stability with potential issues that is unforeseeable. Randazzo explained that a lot of logistics are involved in preparation for enabling the team to adapt to SU9, one of which is ensuring a stable testing environment to avoid a “negative initial user experience”. A lot of details are yet to be finalised, including the release date which not even the team has a concrete answer internally, there is an “entire evaluative process” taking place to pinpoint a date. That said, RSR reassured that the product’s launch will not be a surprise drop in store, a release date with possibly an approximate time of day will be announced prior to the release. As the team approaches the final leg of the 737-700’s development, Randazzo optimistically said that things will become much more exciting between now and the product’s release. The embargo will be lifted so testers of the add-on can share and provide additional new insights into the product, streamers who got ahold of the aircraft will have their embargo lifted as the plane is released.  To kickstart the beginning of the hype building, the team is currently releasing a series of walkthrough videos on the 737-700 on their YouTube channel, with an introductory video published already (embedded on top). A few hours ago, another video is published detailing the Tow Out and plans after the release of the aircraft: More videos will steadily be published in the coming days and weeks. Moving on, Randazzo has shifted to discussing the sounds that are developed for the add-on. Armen, who is principally behind the soundset, has been developing a “sound-scape” to match the visuals and systems fidelity of the rest of the aircraft. Stressing that the sound engine that MSFS used is “unlike anything they have every[sic] had the opportunity to work with”, to which Armen has used the engine to its full potential. Randazzo wraps up the update by assuring that this will be a monumental release, both for the team and the flight sim community; the talent behind Vin and Jason to develop the most visually, and technically faithful 737 for MSFS combined with the delightful sonic experience from Armen that brings the bird to life. To read the original update, visit their forums.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrfam</id>
    <title>Pyreegue &amp; Family is Safe and Well; Development Still Going Strong</title>
    <updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrfam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625ec87a2e2ad36e5e3e0292_owo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1616642"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Ukrainian developer Pyreegue has dropped an update providing a short raincheck on his whereabouts and his family in light of the Russian Invasion of Ukraine. The war brought much disruptions to the developer's (and many others) way of life, fortunately, the developer confirmed that he and his family are safe. As things are beginning to settle down for Pyreegue - he is now back to work on his current projects for MSFS. The developer assured that he has not fallen behind in his commitment to his projects regardless of the happenings around the flight sim community in that extended period of time. For this update, the developer is previewing some of the new modeling for current scenery projects and a reworked set of static aircraft: Wrapping up the weather update, Pyreegue thanks everyone for their support, including Orbx, who has put effort to support Ukrainian developers hosting their products on their store.  “Once again, I can’t thank you enough for being there in my time of need, for what you guys and the team at Orbx did to help me overcome this misery, I wouldn’t be where I am today without people like you. Thank you.” For the original update with more pictures, visit the forum thread comment.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bnddub</id>
    <title>Boundless Simulations Confirms Release Date for Dublin</title>
    <updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bnddub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625ecb12fd7f46025a6de66b_uwu.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="285355"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless Simulations has confirmed the date that they will be releasing their “most ambitious project yet” which is Dublin Airport. According to the scenery developer, they are “well on track” and are aiming to bring the scenery to their store on Friday, May 13th. Boundless has ramped up their effort to increase product quality by implementing more detail than ever before, in line with most modern scenery releases of today, the scenery will be laid with up to date satellite imagery sourced near the end of last year along with a detailed terminal model containing interior modelling for added depth. Boundless now employs the popular SAM plugin to animate its custom jetways. Finally, the rest of the landscape is decorated with custom vegetation. Here is the full feature list: This release date is provisional but one that Boundless “intend to stick to”. The developer has also confirmed that the product will cost £19.99 which is “cheaper than any other alternative payware Dublin scenery”. There has been no word on whether they will be selling it on any other broker's website other than their own just yet. Nonetheless, we’ll keep you in the loop on further developments to this project. Stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sbwapl</id>
    <title>SimBitWorld Teases A Pilots Life V2 Screenshots</title>
    <updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sbwapl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625ee30eeb0310b9de2a5e55_APL01.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="202953"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimBitWorld, developers of "A Pilots Life" have posted a new showcase on their Facebook page regarding the next generation of the plugin. With a complete overhaul of features and new additions coming in the near future. The company CEO, Ovidiu has teased various features of APL v2 for the past few months, showcasing various UI overhauls along with features making a reappearance in the new version, alongside new features that will be making an appearance. The team is expecting a release sometime in spring or summer of this year. A Pilots Life provides users an immersive experience into the world of a commercial airline pilot. Whether it be in regards to passenger or cargo operations, the plugin provides and tailors to the user. You make your way up through the airlines, completing routes, with various aircraft. As you gain experience, you have the option to move to more major carriers, and have the option to earn more virtual money. No complete feature list has been provided at this time. The project is currently in its beta stage of development, and Ovidiu is planning on making his deadline for release, which he has yet to disclose.  You can purchase A Pilots Life over on the simMarket for a limited discount price of €8.38, after which the product sells for €16.75</summary>
    <published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p737ea</id>
    <title>PMDG Outlines Early Adopter Model for MSFS 737</title>
    <updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p737ea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625fa99cc9935bf720cf1049_Screen%20Shot%202022-04-20%20at%201.34.51%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="865174"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, PMDG published a lengthy blog, detailing its plans for the release of its much anticipated 737NG series for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Through the blog, the developers explained in detail the Early Adopter model they will utilize for their upcoming products and outlined a general release plan for its 737s. According to PMDG, the Early Adopter model will be implemented for the first time to give the developers additional time to fully master the new technologies brought by MSFS, allowing them to gradually implement features that they couldn’t provide in the past. In the Early Adopter Period that starts with the initial release of the -700, “new features, bug fixes, model and texture improvements, performance optimizations, and increasing MSFS integration will be rolled out in update intervals spaced approximately two weeks apart”. During this time, the -600, -800, and -900 will also be released, with new updates being made available to all four variants simultaneously. In total, the developers expect this period to run a total of 24 weeks, ending around 6 weeks after the release of the -900, though it may be extended if needed. The developers stressed that the airplanes will be fully functional during this time and this period will enable them to “expand it beyond the initial capabilities delivered”. Additionally, PMDG will be providing a list of features that it will add/optimize, including ones that are currently unachievable due to SDK limitations. The list will be kept up-to-date with the roll out of each new version.  After the Early Adopter Phase, the aircraft will enter the continued maintenance phase where PMDG will shift focus away from developing new features and instead provide regular compatibility/stability updates, turning to the development of its next product - the 777 series for MSFS. Currently, PMDG has not yet announced a firm release date or pricing for the 737NG series. However the developers stressed that the Early Adopter phase will not affect the price of the aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fxhjgh</id>
    <title>FlightFX and Marwan Gharib Reach Publishing Agreement; Sets Release Price</title>
    <updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fxhjgh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/626031e594fa2d45d22fec2c_HJetCoverCompressed.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="848056"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After 3 years of development, Marwan Gharib has reached an agreement with FlightFX to publish his rendition of the Honda Jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with also coming to a decision on a set release price. In a document provided by Nick Sdoucos from FlightFX, he expressed his optimism for the future of the product: The document further explains changes that will further be happening. The HJet Discord will migrating over to the FlightFX discord , and will be giving the option to users to obtain roles and follow the project further as updates and release. Nick then explains that: The announced price of the Honda Jet is to be $24.99. As of today's announcement, no release date has been officially announced, however the official release date will be coming within the next 1-2 weeks. You can check out the FlightFX Discord for further developments on the Honda Jet. Threshold will keep you updated on any further developments out of FlightFX.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerbru</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Brussels Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerbru" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/626237e8e33d771b107df3ec_ebbr-msfs_07.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="115258"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Bringing attention to detail, Aerosoft has released its highly awaited visual rendition of Brussels International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release adds to the ever-increasing catalog of major airports that Aerosoft has pushed out. Dating back to the early days of the German Luftwaffe occupied the area and operated the area as a backup airfield. After the war in the 1960s, the airport received multiple hangers with then receiving cargo ramps in 1976 and passenger terminals in 1994. Brussels received about 23 million passengers in about 2019 pre-COVID-19. With an all-inclusive feature list, Aerosoft has provided content that all users will enjoy. Starting off, a complete layout of Brussels Airport with detailed modeling has been provided alongside, custom jetways and correct terminal variations included. Next, accurate lighting along the airport grounds and ground textures have all been modeled and included. You may view the full feature list on Aerosoft’s website. If you are interested in picking this scenery package up for yourself, you can pick it up over on Aerosoft’s website and sells for €20.97. If you are interested in Aerosoft’s catalog of other sceneries, you can visit their website and take a look. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bos423</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Boston for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bos423" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62647d088afa9786a7fa2346_kbos1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="586532"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer FlyTampa has released their rendition of Boston International Airport for MSFS2020. The scenery delivers entirely accurate airport buildings, interior, and layout.  Boston Logan International Airport serves the Boston metropolitan area in Massachusetts. It's the 16th busiest airport in the United States, having served nearly 42 million passengers in 2019. Logan airport is a hub for both Cape Air and Delta Air Lines and a focus city for JetBlue. Numerous international airlines serve the airport, including Azores Airlines, Emirates, Cathay Pacific, El Al, etc. Boston airport features six runways, ranging from a small GA to a full-size, ten thousand foot runway. FlyTampa Boston for MSFS contains the following: You can purchase Boston for MSFS on the FlyTampa store for $18.99. It'll consume approximately 2.3GB of space after download. Make sure to keep in touch with Threshold regarding future FlyTampa news and releases.  </summary>
    <published>2022-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crj900</id>
    <title>ADSimulations Releases CRJ-900 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crj900" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62659834622da42c8ec57d03_crj91.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="167217"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer ADSimulations, known for releasing the CRJ-700 for X-Plane 11, has published a sequel to the aircraft series with their new CRJ-900. The -900, first announced in early April, is an extended variant of the CRJ series. The aircraft features "basic systems" but will contain "deeper systems" in subsequent updates.  The Mitsubishi CRJ-900 is an extended variant of the CRJ-700 base model in the Bombardier Aerospaces' regional jet product line. It features 1,553NM of range, can accommodate up to 90 passengers, and cruises at Mach 0.82. The plane is used in various environments worldwide, though it can be found in excess with American, Delta, Lufthansa Cityline, and SAS. ADSimulations CRJ-900 has an extensive feature list, so here's a layman's version of it: ADSimulations previously mentioned that the ensuing release of the CRJ-900 will be an update to their existing CRJ-700 product.  If you're interested in purchasing the ADSimulations CRJ-900, you can do so on the X-Plane.org store for $49.95.  edit: CRJ-700 customers can get the CRJ-900 for 30% off. Please find the discount coupon in the original CRJ-700 invoice at the store.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md8042</id>
    <title>Leonardo SH Announces Maddog Release Date for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md8042" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6266d97b7e1473943f19a975_promo.thumb.jpg.a68be8be4eaafaf8a434f3bd11cb44bd.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="85477"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stefano from Leonardo Software House has taken to the team's forums to announce that the Maddog X will be releasing on April 30th. The plane will be available via SimMarket only, for 75 Euros. He also mentioned that the aircraft would deliver with an EFB, which was not initially planned in the feature list, and a new 3D model for the passenger cabin.  Leonardo posted an update approximately a month ago detailing the features that users should expect in the MD-80: Fly the Maddog X MSFS version 1.0 will include: - MD82 with -217A engines, PAX Cabin 162Y, and Honeywell FMS for NAV/VNAV/ACARS; - Flight model and engines performances tested and matched against real aircraft performance tables; - All systems/avionics/tests etc., fully implemented as in the P3D version, including failures/INOPs feature, fully dimmable integral and flood lightning, working TCAS and EGPWS terrain mode; - New FMS Services page for controlling DOORS/STAIR, External power, fuel loading, etc.; - Fully integrated with MSFS ecosystem (jetway, catering, baggage loader, etc...); - Integration with PFPX/SimBrief via Load Manager and retrieval of OFP data via the ACARS system; - Livery manager and aircraft settings configurable for different aircraft; - Livery-based cockpit color (pink, blue or gray) and main panel variations (including placards and speed bugs); - Can be installed in the same machine with Fly the Maddog X for P3D; Configurable options from Load Manager:  - Panel state when starting simulation (Cold &amp; Dark, Ready at Gate, Ready for Takeoff...); - Weight &amp; Balance and route planner; - Load Manager units (Kg/mbar or Lbs/InHg); Aircraft options: - Cockpit units (Kg/mbar or Lbs/InHg); - PFD flight director style (cross bar or single cue), rising runway, ND wind arrow, ground speed, and aircraft map symbol, HDG UP or TRK UP option; - PFD wired to opposite NAV; - Armed altitude as FL and AutoArm altitude option; - Gear waring inhibit above 1500ft AGL; - Always play aural when autopilot disconnects; - Auto brake system; - Three VOR instrument versions: VOR/ADF/DME, VOR/ADF and VOR only; - Two altimeter versions: DUAL/SINGLE knob; - Optional TAS/SAT indicator; - Flat or Cone tail; Simulator options: - Enable failures; - Autopilot disconnect when flight controls move; - Automatic update of aircraft weight and cg; - Automatic fuel loading; - Enable PM calls; - Sync CM1/CM2; - FSUIPC compatibility mode; - Maximum luminosity of all cockpit lights and instruments (flood, integral, LED, LCD and CRT); - Failures probability, separated for LIGHT, MEDIUM, and DANGEROUS; - INOP systems according to MEL; Unfortunately, the team hasn't shared any additional information with us, but Threshold promises to keep you updated with new development sourcing from Leonardo SH!</summary>
    <published>2022-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrden</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Previews Denver 2.0 in X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrden" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6268218ff2a1995b5bd087a5_rs%3Dw_1280%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="235211"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has taken to their Twitter page to showcase previews of X-Codr Designs Denver 2.0 in X-Plane 12, an upcoming free update to the popular airport. The developer’s version two rendition of Denver is set to release with a multitude of exciting changes, these include the new terminal expansions, improved ground textures, revamped terminals, and more. You can view the full feature list below. It was also confirmed by the developer that they still plan on supporting X-Plane 11. As well according to X-Codr, they don’t believe that the X-Plane 12 version of the airport will require a separate download, as the X-Plane 11 version should ignore the X-Plane 12 features. Due to the strict NDA still in place for Laminar’s new simulator, the developer has stated that they won’t be making an official announcement on the forums until X-Plane 12 releases. As well, X-Codr Designs has assured users that progress on Sedona is still developing nicely, and will not be affected by Denver. It was also said that work has finished on the rocks, and the airport will be started, with previews coming soon. In the meantime, you can purchase Denver for X-Plane 11 via the X-Plane.org store for $29.95. As well, make sure to check out the source post for this article via the developer’s website, and join their discord for further information.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aseddf</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Previews Frankfurt (EDDF) for X-Plane and MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aseddf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6268e1178ebb2158d1285799_279167905_1891709774361480_3580936102275275336_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="63342"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Aviotek Simulation Software has published a short update on its upcoming Frankfurt Airport scenery for both X-Plane 11 and MSFS. The brief blog provides the community with a glimpse into the scenery’s progress and showcases new previews. According to the developers, they are trying to “integrate and include as many details as possible, as well as some unique features never seen before”, a process that will “take way longer than expected sometimes”. Therefore, at the current stage, it is impossible to estimate how much longer the team needs to complete the airport. From the previews accompanying the post, it is clear that the modeling for the passenger and cargo terminals, towers, and hangers are mostly complete. A few ground vehicles ranging from buses to pushback trucks are also showcased. In a previous post, the developers has revealed that the scenery will come with high quality PBR textures and custom animations for both simulators, promising to provide in-sim previews as soon as possible. Currently, the developers are yet to announce a release date or pricing for Frankfurt Airport. Based on Aviotek’s previous products, the scenery will likely cost between $18 and $26 USD. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vermyl</id>
    <title>VerticalSim Releases Myrtle Beach International Aiport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vermyl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6269ad28c1744ed28d15fd52_MYR_4-uai-2064x1140.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="387250"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Verticalsim has released the highly anticipated Myrtle Beach (KYMR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. This scenery is not just the airport of the South Carolina city but it comes with the surrounding hotels too. Being used as an army base until 1948, the city of Myrtle Beach decided there was not a need for an airport in the area, though funds were allocated. With the land being annexed in 1977, the property was used as a join civil-military airport, though it severely limited the number of civilian flights. Years later in 1996, the airport gained international status with new terminals with an influence from the local beaches. The airport served over 2.4 million passengers in 2018, being the second busiest airport in South Carolina. The product comes with many features that portray the quality work of Verticalsim. Starting off, the 2022 layout of the airport is included along with proper taxi signage. Custom jetways compatible with the SAM plugin are also a part of this package. Some hotels outside the airport grounds have been modeled to add extra depth to the surrounding area.  If you are interested in picking this visual rendition of Myrtle Beach for yourself, you can find over on the simMarket store, and sells for $13.87. If you are interested in other various scenery packages developed my Verticalsim, you can check out their website to view the assortment of sceneries for XP11 and MSFS.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfs146</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases BAE146 for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfs146" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6270bcfd62dd5bfd6de0f2d1_146-professional-microsoft-flight-simulator_28_ss_l_220429142732.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="239780"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has pushed out their BAE 146 into Microsoft Flight Simulator after an extended period of development for the past year. The development came to a close after the past few days as the team went all hands on deck to wrap up development, and it is now out and about for all flyers to enjoy. This aircraft comes in eight variants which, they include: The regional jet is one that dates further back than the modern glass cockpits we know today, as such the design of the flightdeck may seem daunting to the novice or inexperienced - to address this, Just Flight has followed several other aircraft developers in publishing support materials including a 258 page manual detailing the systems across the add-on, a a 6 part video series on YouTube that goes through a full flight cycle for a BAE146 is also produced.  One other major addition in the aircraft, as an EFB, which is one of the first aircraft packages to ship with a in depth EFB. Its features can vary from fuel quantity in the aircraft, to making notes on a scratchpad, to adjusting ground services. The EFB adds accessibility to all users. A list of the EFB’s capabilities can be found on the product page on Just Flight’s website. Each variant also comes with a multitude of liveries. This is just the tip of the iceberg of how much work the team has done to make this aircraft amazing. You can find a full list of included liveries on the Just Flight Store as well. If you are interested in picking up this aircraft, it is on sale on Just Flight's store and sells for $64.99. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfsp22</id>
    <title>TFDI Design Publishes Spring 2022 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfsp22" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6270d2652429a82fb82754b1_MD-11%20Interior.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="427767"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Known developer for PACX and smartCARS, TFDI Design has published a Spring 2022 development update on their forums page. This update covers the continuous progress on their rendition of the MD-11, alongside developments for PACX, smartCARS 3, and updates for their sister company JetStream Radio. The team touched base that further modeling and texture work has continued along with progress on the systems and auto flight systems. Various engine variations have begun development with the PW Engine variant. The team expects to make great progress in the coming months. At the beginning of the update, the team addressed PACX’s latest update and its successes. Features like an IFE that tracks your flight, lets you access JetStream radio, and more were added to help add to the overall experience of the application. ‍ ‍ The team for the upcoming smartCARS 3 programs has begun finalizing the UI and adding more accessibility to virtual airlines that want to tailor to their pilots, in their own communities. It will improve the overall dynamic of the widely used program. ‍ In this section, it was addressed that the radio station is now “front and center” in the PACX IFE. With also the announcement of launching a new station to include a catalog of music from the 90s to now. ‍ If you would like to read the update in its entirety, you can visit the TFDI forums for more information. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iapdu</id>
    <title>Indiafoxtecho Announces New Projects and Publishes Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iapdu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6271d3009fdabc4c5d46a0b0_279572045_5661152563898158_7587075841842710172_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="412870"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Last week, aircraft developer Indiafoxtecho published a lengthy post on its Facebook page to announce new projects and bring development updates on existing ones. First off, the developers confirmed that their next project will be the Tornado for Microsoft Flight Simulators. Both the IDS and IDS-MLU will be developed, with the legacy IDS serving as the baseline model. Additionally, the developers hinted that “the GR1, ECR and possibly the ADV variant” will also be developed, though the feasibility of an ADV variant will be dependent on the resources available to the team.  A few previews depicting the plane’s  exterior modeling were also published with the post, though the developers warned that they were taken at preliminary stages of development and will be drastically improved later on.  	In addition to announcing the Tornado, the Indiafoxtecho also touched on the progress of their other products. According to the developers, the Aermacchi M346, which will use native MSFS FCS flight model, now has a completed HTML5/JS HUD , but is experiencing slight delays in texturing and system programming. The aircraft should be ready for beta testing in the coming weeks. As for the Eurofighter Typhoon, the developers has decided to model the plane from scratch since they are not satisfied with the commercial meshes and P3D model they originally planned to use as a starting point, a process that will take considerably more time to complete. Finally, the developers talked about bringing the team’s projects to DCS. They revealed that DCS development entails much more work than that for other simulators, requiring extensive planning and research beforehand. Therefore, their DCS team is currently only focused on “bringing the MB.339” to the market. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
