<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-04-14T18:21:43.883747+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfsbri</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Brindisi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfsbri" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/642b00b51952f320ea32f29a_brin1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3021451"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Brindisi Papola Casale Airport (LIBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 20th busiest airport in Italy with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  First established as a military airbase in the 1920s, it saw commercial traffic action for the first time in 1934 with Ala Littoria. This government-owned airline resulted from merging four Italian airlines (SAM, SANA, SISA, and AEI), offering a single destination: Rome. The airline collapsed after the war and became Alitalia (also defunct), then called Aerolinee Italiane Internazionali. Under the new name, they also added a new destination to the roster: Catania.  The airport retained its military status until 2008, despite maintaining its military facilities to this day, although referred to by a different name: Military Airport Orazio Pierozzi. The civil name (Papola Casale) was given after Antonio Papola, a deceased Italian aviator with tight bonds to the city.  The airport is served by many airlines during the summer season, with Ryanair, AlbaStar, easyJet, Eurowings, ITA Airways, Swiss, and WizzAir being the few to offer routes all year long. The seasonal visitors’ list includes Aer Lingus (starting in May 2023), Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Volotea, and Vueling.   The scenery features custom airport buildings, landside buildings, custom ground service equipment, custom night lighting, glass effect on windows (buildings, terminal, and vehicles), custom ground textures, and an up-to-date layout. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.40, requiring at least 721.84 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ixeg12</id>
    <title>IXEG Reveal 737 Classic info For XP12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ixeg12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/642c4cfa2fbed5c32f51db42_11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="181524"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. IXEG and X-Aviation have recently taken to the X-Pilot forums to announce new features and more information for the IXEG 737 Classic aircraft, which was initially released for XP11.  The IXEG has long been a bar-setter in simulation standards but has undoubtedly been showing age with the new generation of flight simulators such as X-Plane 12 and MSFS and their aircraft. Much to the delight of 737 fans, we now have much more information on the upcoming improved version of the 737 Classic.  Cameron of X-Aviation started the announcement with the reveal of an upgrade price, for most customers, the price of the updated 737 will be $14.95 while for those who have purchased the IXEG X-Plane 11 model on or after February 7th 2022, the update will be free. This has caused some tension among long-standing X-Aviation customers in the community who had an understanding the upgrade would be free for all customers, Cameron goes on to clarify this more in the announcement post.  The main new features which pilots can expect to see are as follows:  After the initial release of the update, the team will focus on the following areas:  To read more about the announcement you can follow the link! </summary>
    <published>2023-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdsaa</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases Santa Ana Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdsaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/642df97730812ce69b9964e5_sta1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="862850"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Colombian Virtual Design has recently released their rendition of Santa Ana Airport (SKGO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Cartago in Colombia with a yearly average of 10,000 passengers.  The airport was built in the 1940s by the Colombian Air Force and later opened to civilian air traffic. It was initially used for PPL training, known as a cradle for great pilots, but it eventually embraced the commercial airline world as the main regional airport for the Valle del Cauca department.   It underwent expansion work in 2011, increasing the passenger capacity at the terminal to 180 people in the boarding area and adding metal detectors.  Cartago was adopted by many airlines around the region for ideal weather conditions throughout the year, along with a runway long enough for most aircraft, which any other airport in the area doesn’t offer.   It’s served by EasyFly and Satena, with two daily flights to Bogota.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with realistic ground markings, updated ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, and custom ground clutter.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.08, requiring at least 37.44 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simhea</id>
    <title>SimHeaven Updates XP12 Scenery to V2.2</title>
    <updated>2023-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simhea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/642f1c7de0b42f721e77b3d6_12.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="216959"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimHeaven has recently updated its X-World America and X-World Asia scenery packages for X-Plane 12. The updates bring some fixes and additional features to the packages. While both packages' main points of change are similar in the latest update, there are some small differences.  X-World America changelog:  v2.2 Fixes X-World Asia changelog:  V2.2 ‍ Fixes ‍ You can find out more about the latest updates on SimHeaven.com ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbgot</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases Gothenburg Landvetter Airport Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbgot" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6430a09ed7ce842630c4c9cc_go1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="748992"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently posted on “The Arlanda Journal,” their page for reporting the development progress on their rendition of Stockholm-Arlanda for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with information on an upcoming update for their Gothenburg Landvetter Airport (ESGG) scenery, also for Microsoft Flight Simulator.   Gothenburg Landvetter is the second largest airport in Sweden, averaging 7 million passengers per year. It was inaugurated in 1977 by King Carl XVI Gustaf, replacing Torslanda Airport, deemed too small to handle the traffic demand.   It’s a focus city for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, SunClass Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic, sporting a sizeable inter-European route network. The visitors’ list includes major European carriers, like Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, and Swiss.   Orbx claims they are hoping for a quick release, with testing underway. They highlight the addition of animated airside traffic, with variable intensity according to the time of day and with smoothness in mind. Other than that, they also mention the implementation of snow banks that only appear under certain conditions. The rest of the feature list includes animated jetways, functional and correct VDGS for all parking spots that got them, ground texture enhancements, interior enhancements, custom approach light objects, snow trucks when it’s snowing, updated GSE and clutter, static business jets (optional), new Scandic hotel, the new terminal, and a GSX profile.   While the update is not out yet, Orbx’s Gothenburg can be found on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.18 (on sale for 13 days), requiring at least 5.46 GB of free hard disk space to install. The update is going to be entirely free for previous owners. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbytv</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Tivat Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbytv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64318d8f08ce444be36801dc_tv1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1691782"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Tivat Airport (LYTV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Montenegro with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers (pre-pandemic).   The airport was originally just a grass airfield in 1957, with a small apron and a terminal building. Most traffic was strictly domestic for the first decade, with DC-3s and II-14s. The first modernization began between 1968 and 1971, with an asphalt runway, a bigger apron, extended taxiways, and a substantial terminal expansion. An earthquake eight years later forced them to refurbish it again, with increased dimensions to fit widebody aircraft. After an ownership change in 2003, the airport had another major modernization, with an improved terminal.   In the early 2010s, the administration realized the current terminal would not hold up with the gradual increase in the yearly average, so planning and building a second terminal, inaugurated in 2018 by their Prime Minister.   Most of the traffic is seasonal, peaking in the summer. Many airlines from all over Europe are visiting, including Austrian Airlines, easyJet, Edelweiss, Eurowings, LOT, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Transavia, and Turkish. Air Montenegro and Air Serbia are the only ones offering all-year-long coverage with a route to Belgrade.    Developed by one of their indies (Rasha Tucakov), the scenery features a high-detail rendition of Tivat Airport, with detailed terminal interiors, parallax windows, custom apron and runway textures, custom library objects, and many custom points of interest on approach.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.44, requiring at least 1.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmslie</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Teases Liège Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmslie" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6432ec877e107c7279a261b7_lie1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1013682"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations has recently teased the progress on their rendition of Liège Airport (EBLG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 5th biggest cargo airport in Europe and 22nd in the World.   Originally a military airfield, it was used by the Germans during World War II as a base for their Luftwaffe aircraft. After the war, the Belgian Air Force used the airport until the 1960s, when it was converted into a commercial airport. In the 1980s, Liège Airport became known for its cargo operations and became a major European freight transport hub. Today, the airport is one of the largest cargo airports in the World, handling over 900,000 tons of goods each year and serving as a vital link in the global supply chain.  TUI fly Belgium is the only airline offering scheduled flights to and from Liège, with routes to Alicante, Gran Canaria, Málaga, and Tenerife-South. The traffic figures sit at less than 400,000 passengers yearly.  The developers have been showcasing the scenery on their Facebook page, with many screenshots of the terminal interior, cargo area, and some of the cargo apron. A selection of these screenshots will be posted alongside this article.  There’s still no pricing and release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbslan</id>
    <title>DarkBlueScenery Releases Lanzhou-Zhongchuan International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbslan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6432f2c2cd9a78d4ea506bd9_lan1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2695349"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DarkBlueScenery has recently released their rendition of Lanzhou-Zhongchuan International Airport (ZLLL) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, serving Lanzhou in China with a yearly average of 7 million passengers.   Inaugurated in 1970, Lanzhou Airport is the Chinese airport furthest from the center of the city it serves, at an incredible 71 kilometers away from downtown. Such distance is explained by the area’s geography, which doesn’t offer many options.   The first expansion project started in 1997, increasing the airport’s passenger handling capabilities to nearly 5 million a year. It held up well until the early 2010s when the operator finally saw the need to expand it again with a brand-new terminal. Terminal 2’s construction began that same year, opening five years later.  With traffic projections nearing the 10 million passenger ballpark shortly, they have decided to expand again with a brand new terminal currently under construction. The work started in 2019, costing 31.69 billion Yuan and a total area three times bigger than both current terminals combined. For such an ambitious goal, they had to demolish an entire town and adjacent villages, totaling up to 10.7 square kilometers of area.  The airport is served by many domestic airlines, including Air China, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Shanghai Airlines, Spring Airlines, and Tianjin Airlines.   The scenery depicts the current stage of the airport, with Terminal 3 still under construction, featuring custom ground textures, custom models for Terminals 1 and 2, a cargo terminal, custom jetways, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.18, requiring at least 384.43 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brno</id>
    <title>Big Radials Release “The Norseman”</title>
    <updated>2023-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brno" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6433e9eb3ee380b69b3e0648_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1780409"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Noorduyn Norseman was designed and built by Noorduyn Aircraft Ltd. A Canadian aircraft manufacturer founded in 1928. The man behind it all was Robert Noorduyn who was previously employed by Fokker before starting his own venture. The Norseman was a very successful project with over 900 aircraft built in the years between 1935 and 1959.  The Norseman is a single-engine bush plane that is best utilised throughout northern Canada and Alaska and is best known for its versatility and robust build quality.  The excellent team at Big Radials have recently released their latest project! The Norseman. The aircraft is for Microsoft flight sim and boasts the following features:  The aircraft can be purchased from the Big Radials website for just under $19.00  Our team currently have their hands on the Norseman, putting it through its paces! A review will follow in the coming weeks, so stay tuned!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spijum</id>
    <title>Spinoza Releases Jumbolair Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spijum" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6434461571cb777131b17fd3_jum1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="869699"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Spinoza has recently released their rendition of Jumbolair Airport (17FL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a private airport in Anthony, Florida, serving an aviation-oriented gated community.  Arthur Jones built the community in the early 1980s, with 220 hectares of total area divided between many smaller lots (1.2 ha each) connected by taxiways to the runways. It is now owned by Jumbolair Development LLC and operated by Robert and Debra Bull.   Jumbolair got worldwide relevance when John Travolta and his wife moved in with their Boeing 707.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the Jumbolair Community, a 3D model of John Travolta’s mansion (including the 707 static), and many custom 3D people (including John Travolta himself).  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.72, requiring at least 175.06 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsxsis</id>
    <title>FSX3D Releases Sisteron-Vaumeilh Aerodrome for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsxsis" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64344c6dc1885a4eb3af5e13_aero1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2007193"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSX3D has recently released their rendition of Sisteron-Vaumeilh Aerodrome (LFNS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a restricted access public airfield on a large plateau between the Durance River and the Southern French Alps.   Built in 1938 as a military airfield by the French Air Force but soon taken over by the Germans during World War II, it was heavily damaged but later rebuilt and used by the French Air Force until 1965. In the decades that followed, the airfield was used for a variety of purposes, including glider training and airshows. Today, it is a popular destination for recreational pilots and aviation enthusiasts and is known for its stunning views of the surrounding countryside and the nearby Alps. Its rich history and scenic location make it a must-visit destination for anyone interested in aviation or military history.  The aerodrome is famous among glider pilots for its infrastructure, weather, geography, and relevance to the glider culture, with over 50 years of history. It has ranked number one among soaring dedicated airfields in France by the French Fédération de Vol à Voile.  The lack of general aviation traffic (more so, it’s highly restricted) makes it perfect for glider pilots looking for a good time.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airfield, with high-quality 3D models, PBR texturing, custom ground textures and taxiways, custom clutter, and realistic hangars.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.90, requiring at least 340.36 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/axoorb</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Owen Roberts International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/axoorb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6435b62acc409bb9f6276a8d_owen1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1711808"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos has recently released their rendition of Owen Roberts International Airport (MWCR) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, serving the island of Grand Cayman with a yearly average of 1.2 million passengers.  The airport is named after Owen Roberts, a pioneer of aviation in the Cayman Islands, responsible for building airfields on all three of the Cayman Islands in the early 1950s at the cost of 93,000 pounds.   The airport has a single runway and two terminals serving international and domestic flights. In recent years, the airport has undergone significant renovations and expansions to improve its facilities and accommodate the increasing number of tourists visiting the island.   It is the hub for Cayman Airways, the national airline of the Cayman Islands, offering flights to Cayman Brac, Havana, Kingston, Miami, New York (JFK), and Tampa. The visitors’ list includes Air Canada, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and WestJet.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled terminal, custom ground textures and weather map, hand-placed dirt, 3D trees &amp; grass, custom night lighting, high-resolution PBR ground textures, animated and functional marshalers (SAM dependant), and custom ground markings.   It’s available on Axonos’ Store for $16.99, requiring at least 529 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aer330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Teases A330’s Interior &amp; EFB</title>
    <updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aer330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6436f9b11f4f8d244861ea3d_ae1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="567800"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently teased more of the A330’s cockpit details, EFB screenshots, and new information on the fully interactive user manual.  They begin with four shots of the cockpit (first one is the article's cover), showcasing the quality of the model and the texturing:   It’s then followed up by multiple previews of the electronic flight bag, showing the many pages of the loadsheet manager, the charts application, and the operational flight plan viewer:  They finish with a preview of their eManual, an interactive manual with text, audio, video, and images covering every aspect of the A330’s operation. Checklists and cockpit flows are also included.  Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft’s Product Manager, has answered a question on their forum about a date with “coming months sounds okay.”  There is still no information on pricing. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdthr</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Release Thruxton for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdthr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/643847748425551b9ad4c863_12.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="712442"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Established in 1917 as a military airfield for the Royal Flying Corps during World War I, Thruxton Aerodrome boasts a storied past. It played a vital role in training pilots for the war effort and later saw use in civil aviation and recreational flying. During World War II, the aerodrome was once again requisitioned for military purposes, serving as a base for the Royal Air Force's 38 Group. Following the war, the aerodrome transitioned back to civilian use and was eventually acquired by the British Automobile Racing Club (BARC) in 1950. The BARC developed the site into a racing circuit that has since hosted numerous prestigious racing series.  Today the Airfield is primarily used for general aviation flying.  Burning Blue Design have faithfully recreated Thruxton Aerodrome and the racing circuit in excruciating detail and it is now available for MSFS!  The feature list includes:   You can pick up your copy of this brilliant scenery from the Burning Blue Design website ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbgla</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates Gothenburg Landvetter Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbgla" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6438f398e19b0ee8e9938263_land1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1600104"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently updated their rendition of Gothenburg Landvetter Airport (ESGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding snow banks during winter, animated jetways, a functional VDGS system, the brand new terminal extension, and more.  Gothenburg Landvetter is the second largest airport in Sweden after Arlanda, with a yearly average of 7 million passengers. It was built in 1977 to replace Torslanda Airport, considered too small for the traffic boom of the late 70s.  It’s a focus city for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, SunClass Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic, sporting a sizeable inter-European route network. The visitors’ list includes major European carriers, like Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, and Swiss.   The new update adds dynamic airside traffic, with its intensity varying according to the time of the day, realistic snow banks that appear during winter, animated jetways, functional and correct VDGS (only on stands that have it in real life), ground texture enhancements, interior enhancements, custom approach light objects, snow trucks when it’s snowing, updated GSE and clutter, static business jets (optional), new Scandic hotel, the new terminal extension, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.38 (on sale), requiring at least 4.80 GB of free hard disk space to install. The update is free for previous owners. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inkjfk</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases John F. Kennedy International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inkjfk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64395559cfeb69693e7b9f76_idle1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="470528"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of John F. Kennedy International Airport (KJFK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in New York City with a yearly average of 60 million passengers. Built on top of an old golf course 74 years ago, the then-called Idlewild Airport had a single 7,365 square meter terminal and six runways. The current name only came to be in late 1963, after John F. Kennedy’s assassination. It also marked the important leap to the busiest airport in the region, beating LaGuardia and reaching a respectable second place overall in the United States. The busiest international gateway to the United States is served and visited by over 90 airlines, covering all the inhabited continents around the globe. JetBlue tops the market share chart, with 28.8% or 15,624,961 passengers, followed by Delta Air Lines and American Airlines, with 28.4% (15,390,437) and 14.5% (7,870,971), respectively. From foreign operators, Air France leads the way with 1.9% of the total market share or 1,025,339 passengers. The scenery features hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life airport landside recreation, accurately modeled and positioned lighting, high-detail models of all airport buildings and objects (and surroundings), accurate taxi signage, an updated layout, custom-built jetways with variations as per real life, a fully animated JFK AirTrain between each terminal, a precise representation of the famous Canarsie Approach, LOD optimization for every model, custom static aircraft (optional), and full compatibility with the iniManager scenery configurator. It also includes a replica of the TWA Hotel with an intricately detailed interior and the Constellation aircraft in TWA colors.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $25.04, requiring at least 4.25 GB of free hard disk space to install. The developers recommend uninstalling Asobo’s hand-crafted KJFK to avoid performance issues.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
