<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-04-16T18:26:31.239707+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/yssyxp</id>
    <title>TaiModels Releases Sydney Kingsford Smith International Airport for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/yssyxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6243ecebb11a4b283982ddf1_Cessna_172SP_G1000-2022-03-247.44.57PM_thumb_c0324458-01fb-4a78-8254-451752e5fb6b%20copy.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="698548"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, scenery developer TaiModels released Sydney Kingsford Smith International Airport (YSSY) for X-Plane 11. The airport, created using 4k textures, custom SAM jetways, and custom ground mesh, will serve as the gateway for pilots looking to visit one of Australia's most well known metropolises. According to the developers, Sydney Airport has been recreated to mirror its real life counterpart. Some notable features of the scenery include high detailed models, interior models for terminal 1 and 2, custom animated objects, PBR textures, and optimizations for best performances. For a complete list of features, check out the product’s store page. Sydney Airport, located only 5 miles away from Sydney’s central districts, is the main international airport that serves the region. One of the busiest airports in Australia, YSSY serves as a hub for international travel, connecting the country to almost every continent in the world. In 2018 alone, the airport handled some 45 million passengers and was nominated by Skytrax as the world’s 20th best airport. Currently, TaiModels’s Sydney Airport can be purchased on iniBuilds’s webstore for £20.99 GBP/$27.50 USD, excluding any sales tax that may occur. The product is supported all three operating systems and the developers recommend the users to have at least 1.86GB of free disk free for successful installation.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/conc331</id>
    <title>DCDesigns Releases Concorde for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/conc331" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62467a4cbbf30f709871b8fd_concorde-microsoft-flight-simulator_2_ss_l_220330095555.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="130917"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aircraft developer DCDesigns has released their rendition of the Aerospatiale Concorde for MSFS2020. The product is accompanied by MSFS native materials, a realistic flight model, and a complete operations manual. While it's unlikely that you don't know much about the Concorde, here's a bit of a history lesson anyway. The Aerospatiale/BAC Concorde is a French-British afterburning turbojet supersonic airliner that operated at a cruising speed of Mach 2.02. Considered a technological marvel, it contains the title of the most successful supersonic aircraft, beating its only "viable" competitor, the Tupolev Tu-144. It initially garnered interest from many airlines, such as Pan Am and Trans World Airlines, but production delays and hesitance regarding the airframes viability as a profitable mechanism led to mass cancellations of orders, leaving only British Airways and Air France to operate the aircraft. The Concorde is still the only "successful" supersonic airliner to date, even though the airframe's last flight took place in 2003. Today, most Concordes are presented at notable museums such as the Intrepid and Boeing museums, existing as figures of an incredible legacy of the past.  Rewinding to the DCDesigns rendition of the Concorde, it's imperative to mention that the developer designed the aircraft intending to simplify the plane so that it is accessible to all users without requiring "intense" studying to fly. Therefore, it's important to keep expectations humble as it doesn't compete with the likes of the FSLabs Concorde, for example.  DCDesigns' Concorde Features: You can obtain the DCDesigns Concorde for MSFS2020 through the JustFlight store for $39.99. In addition, aspiring pilots can check out the release trailer beforehand to get a glimpse of the aircraft in action. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gsxp11</id>
    <title>Stairport Releases GroundService for XP11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gsxp11" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624705641a92f3a612f7b5dd_sam-groundservice-xp%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="138515"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. One of the most anticipated airport environment add-on's has been released. Stairport, in collaboration with MisterX, have released GroundService plugin for X-Plane 11. Being the second plugin of its kind, many XP11 users have looked forward to this product developed by the well known developers. The plugin enhances the various aspects of airport life that has often been neglected in X-Plane 11 for quite some time. While other development teams have included basic ground services in their plugins, this release brings the whole world of ground services to light. With cleaning trucks, to passenger stairs for smaller airports, this plugin provides it all, with high accessibility for users through the SAM3 plugin. With a multitude of features, this plugin provides it all. First, the product does come with a aircraft compatibility list, and a 10 minute demo has been provided to give users a chance to take a dip in the water before purchasing. All aspects of ground services have been included in the package with items such as GPU, cleaning trucks, loaders, and animated passenger stairs being included. X-Plane 12 compatibility is currently under development for the plugin to be ready at the launch of XP12. This plugin by Stairport is available for purchase on the Aerosoft Store with a selling price of $34.99. If you are interested in other products developed by Stairport and MisterX, you can check out their product pages over on Aerosoft Store for Stairport, and the X-Plane.org Store for MisterX</summary>
    <published>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hema20</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Releases Marsa Alam Airport for MSFS2020</title>
    <updated>2022-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hema20" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6247f90c9d29b720c66edf19_hema1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="541258"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds affiliate Chudoba Design has released its rendition of Marsa Alam (HEMA) airport for MSFS2020. The Egyptian airport is faithfully recreated, feature-rich, and moderately priced to add to its offerings.  Marsa Alam International Airport is an international airport, mainly serving as a vacation destination for European leisure travelers. The airport features traffic from many notable airlines, such as easyJet, Edelweiss, Lufthansa, Smartwings, and TUI fly. It served over 1 million passengers back in 2012 and contains a singular, 9800 foot, or 3,000-meter runway. Marsa Alam for MSFS is presented with the following features:  You can purchase HEMA airport for MSFS on the iniBuilds store for 6.99GBP/8.30EUR/9.19USD. The download will consume 158MB of space on your hard drive and 364MB after installation. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ch65up</id>
    <title>Hot Start Pushes Out Challenger 650 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ch65up" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/61c7db088f6818366ca10a5a_01.jpg.dad1a93442e931e0ffc7e416570e9972.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1298071"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The development team behind the renowned Challenger 650 aircraft is back bringing a small bug fix and improvement update for the small business jet. This includes a variety of fixes and minor improvements to make the aircraft more like its real-world counterpart and bring more accessibility to the user. Whilst this update is quite small. It comes packed with a variety of features. Starting off, additions such as click spots for wing inspections for preflight and adding a variety of system support such as OCEAN CLX, ATS LOG, and DEP CLX, but also features a brief update to xPilot SELCAL datarefs. Moving forward, an assortment of improvements have also been made. Datarefs for the "walking mode" and libfail have been enhanced, alongside an enhancement to overnight icing accumulation that follows real-world METAR data. Support for the online network POSCON has been added as well. The large parts of this update contain bug fixes. A multitude of these features are mainly system improvements and bug fixes, along with a variety of FMC and Flightplan system improvements have been made as well.  You can find the full content list of the update by visiting the X-Pilot Forums, and if you are interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can find it over on the X-Aviation Store.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fscytz</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Billy Bishop Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fscytz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624a5a4acb6eec317ae69588_293023_17.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="887872"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The team over at FSimStudios has released their visual rendition of Toronto's Billy Bishop Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release has brought an all-new look to the small regional Canadian airport. Before Toronto Pearson International Airport was constructed, Billy Bishop Airport served as Toronto's main airport. Being built in 1939, the airport served as the main hub for all air traffic. A decade later, the Canadian Government proposed an expansion to the small airport to increase passenger traffic to the area. Later on, with the airport receiving a regional jet ban in 1983, passenger air travel slightly declined. Now in the 21st Century, the airport was approved to receive the Airbus A220 for a limited time. For this release, the team has included a feature list of what is included in the scenery package. Starting off, the package has the current 2022 layout airport and more than 20 accurate handmade models of downtown Toronto have been included. Many helipads for Toronto's hospitals have been included for our rotorcraft friends to fly to. Static Q400s are an option for users to include in their scenery as well. The full feature list is listed below: This scenery is able to be purchased over on the simMarket Store and sells for €13.99. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/w42b24</id>
    <title>Wing42 Releases Boeing 247D for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/w42b24" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624bba48c1d30c8a6d9179d6_wing42_boeing247d_thumbnail-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="355230"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Wing42 has released their rendition of the Boeing 247D aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The older-styled aircraft has been added to the simulator's ever-increasing catalog of historical aircraft. Being introduced in 1933, the Boeing 247 is known for its many technologies, that at the time, were newer to the aviation realm. Features such as the first cantilevered wing, and the retractable landing gear were just the first of many technologies to be revolutionized into many more components of flight. The 247D is the race variant of the aircraft, featuring variable pitch props to increase speed. The aircraft comes packed with many features such as PBR textures being used throughout the entire aircraft. The flight model is accurate to its real world-counterpart and has been verified and tested by real-world pilots. All mechanical systems have been modeled and developed correctly to make the flight deck more accurate for the user. A clipboard that represents an EFB brings much more accessibility to ground services, aircraft load, static elements, and more. You can view the full feature list on the products webpage. This rendition of the Boeing 247D by Wing42 can be found over on their website and sells for $20.47. You can find other products developed by Wing42 on their website as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md1110</id>
    <title>Rotate Updates MD-11 to Version 1.01 </title>
    <updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md1110" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624bd463364207513aee9e5e_md11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="86570"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer Rotate has released a new update for their recently-released McDonnell Douglas MD-11. The update pertains to a few significant issues that users were experiencing after the product's initial release, mainly relating to LNAV and ILS bugs. They've also provided a list of issues the team plans on addressing shortly to complement this update.  Rotate has listed these issues as having been remitted: Users having issues with Mac activation were encouraged to visit this link on the x-plane.org forums to access the workaround.  Sequentially, Rotate has also informed the community regarding the next steps it plans to tackle some remaining substantial issues. The team is currently working on the following:  Active Sky users have also been reassured that the team is investigating issues with the plugin causing the MD11s autopilot to malfunction; stay tuned for a fix as the team is actively working on fix.  Despite its flaws, Rotate has delivered a visually appealing airplane, and hopefully following in the footsteps of their MD-80, evolve into a matured product with a solid simulation. If you're interested in purchasing the MD-11, you can find it on the X-Plane.org store for $83.95. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crj948</id>
    <title>ADSimulations Announces CRJ900 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crj948" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624fe3a082d9c95c7c6151b8_01.thumb.jpg.c53c14e8709c8c846aa98f93835a283c.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="55747"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer ADSimulations has announced their next project for X-Plane 11, the Mitsubishi CRJ-900! The larger CRJ follows the developers growing line of aircraft, following their original CRJ-700 release.  The Mitsubishi CRJ-900 is an extended variant of the CRJ-700 base model in the Bombardier Aerospaces' regional jet product line. It features 1,553NM of range, can accommodate up to 90 passengers, and cruises at Mach 0.82. The plane is used in various environments worldwide, though it can be found in excess with American, Delta, Lufthansa Cityline, and SAS. Unfortunately, ADsimulations hasn't shared any additional information with us except that they'll release the product within the next few weeks, and complimenting the release will be an update to their CRJ-700.  Stay tuned with Threshold, as we'll keep you updated with the latest and greatest from ADsimulations.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kontxp</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Ontario International Airport for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kontxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62521870f27b8619508ec77a_Screenshot_13-1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1002348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, developer Verticalsim released Ontario International Airport (KONT) for X-Plane 11. The scenery, featuring PBR textures, HDR lighting, and custom ground traffic, will serve as a fantastic gateway for pilots who are planning to visit the beautiful state of California or looking for a major cargo hub to fly their new MD-11 or A300. According to the product’s store page, Verticalism’s rendition of Ontario Airport will be based on the latest layout of the airport, including the recently added Fedex ramp. The scenery will feature SAM jetways, highly detailed models, custom lighting, and “usage of LOD’s for optimization”. For a complete list of features, check out the developer’s website. Ontario Airport, located in San Bernardino County, California, is a public airport that serves as both a passenger and cargo hub for the region, as well as the alternative landing site for LAX. It is home to airlines such as American and Delta and cargo carriers such as UPS and Fedex. In 2018, KONT saw some 5 million passengers and an average of 65 flights per day. Currently, Ontario International Airport for X-Plane 11 can be purchased on Verticalsim’s webstore for $24.99 USD, excluding any sales tax that may incur. To successfully install the product, users must download the SAM plugin and have at least 3.51GB of free space on their hard drive.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg41</id>
    <title>PMDG 737 for MSFS Enters the "Home Stretch"</title>
    <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg41" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6253da417c450e0a47cc1efe_image_15778.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437320"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo at PMDG Simulations has taken to the developer's forums to give more insight into the 737 for MSFS development progress. The team is nearing the end of the initial testing phase of the 737-700 and will hold a meeting next week to finalize the release date. (the above photos are sourced from PMDG's March 15th 737 update) Contextual Information PMDG intends on including the MAX product line to complement the Next Generation products. The initial release product will be the PMDG 737-700, which will consist of the passenger, cargo, and BBJ variants of the aircraft, featuring a multitude of winglet styles, configurable options, and PMDG's classic realism. The team will release an additional variant of the 737 product line in approximately six-week intervals, including 737-600, 737-800, and 737-900 for MSFS.  "Customer Driven Ideas" Every 737 variant will be sold separately to allow customers more flexibility to acquire the models they desire instead of purchasing variants in a large package. Another idea touted by customers was that the team intends to treat the release phase of the 737 as if it was early access. Most features will initially be available in the aircraft, but a few features won't be possible to delegate to the product line until the product releases. These product updates will be available in two-week intervals during the initial 24 week release period.  Features That'll Be Added After Release or Excluded Altogether. The aforementioned updates will be available to users at no cost via updates to the products.  What's Included in the 737 Products? Essentially, the aircraft will contain numerous features, with customized performance data, accurate flight modeling, complete flight management, realistic autopilot, and functioning LNAV, VNAV. "How is the performance?" Performance "remains quite good" the 737 should run fine if your setup can already handle other third-party aircraft. Randazzo's rig, featuring an early i9 and 2080Ti, can run the 737 well at default airports. He provided Drzewiecki Design's RNT as an example, which offers 40-45fps with the 737 in-sim, and default airports such as FMEE provide mid-to-low 50s.   Discounts Users should not expect any discount/trade-in or upgrade programs for the 737 product line, except for one scenario. If you purchased the 737 NGXu for P3D when the team offered a transition program for those who desired to buy the MSFS 737 at release, you would receive a $99.99 credit towards purchasing the 737 MSFS product line. This credit offer only applies to those who purchased the NGXu before December 31st, 2019.  Product Pricing is TBA at the Moment Final Thoughts Robert has shifted his focus to recording some videos to showcase the aircraft's depth and features (PMDGs YouTube channel). He mentions that this series will not be a tutorial but rather "serve as small bites of information that will allow you to quickly see the depth of features available to you as a PMDG 737 product line user." Beta testers will be able to share information and media about the upcoming aircraft beginning of next week.  As we all await the forthcoming news from PMDG in the coming weeks, stay tuned with Threshold as we report on all the news originating from the simulator world. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rkch41</id>
    <title>ACO Design Studios Releases RCKH for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rkch41" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6253dee6de4061db98b6db4a_293472_KHH_01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="362497"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer ACO Design Studio has released their second scenery for the new simulator, Taiwan Kaohsiung International Airport! The airport appears to take full advantage of MSFS' landscape, with custom terminals and surrounding environment. Kaohsiung International Airport (RCKH) is the second busiest airport in Taiwan, following Taoyuan. In 2018, it served nearly seven million passengers, with service from air carriers such as EVA, China Airlines, Japan Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines. The airport also serves as a hub for China Airlines, EVA, Uni Air, Mandarin Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan. RCKH contains one runway, at 3,150m or 10,335ft.  You can purchase ACO Design Studios Kaohsiung International Airport on SimMarket for 19.50EUR/21.18USD/16.25GPB. It will also be available on the MSFS Marketplace in May, as Microsoft is still processing the scenery. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rv14fs</id>
    <title>SimWorksStudios Releases RV-14 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rv14fs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62550ca89aaaf9df3572d8a5_RV14-01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="175010"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorksStudios have officially released their rendition of the RV-14 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With a variety of features accessible to users, this aircraft is a keen addition to MSFS's General Aviation market.   Touted as an aircraft with many pristine features, Van's RV-14 features a wide variety of features for real-world pilots to experience. The aircraft ships in two variants, the RV-14, and the RV-14A. Visually the difference is the main variant is a taildragger, whilst the A variant is not. With a high fuel economy, fast speed, and a comfortable flight deck, this aircraft offers much of a pilot's dream.  SimWorksStudios have provided a feature list upon release. Starting, all variants of the RV-14 have been included with 3 different liveries. The 3D model and animations all replicate the real-world aircraft, plus the flight dynamics of the aircraft have been tested by real-world pilots. All MSFS icing and rain effects are compatible with the aircraft. Alongside this, GTNS750 compatibility with both PMS50 and TDS is available. If you'd like the full feature list, you can check it out on the aircraft's product page.  If you are interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can purchase it over at the SimWorksStudios Website, selling for €14.99. If you are interested in other products by the same development team, you can check out their website to view their catalog of products.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/macafs</id>
    <title>Macco Simulations Release Cancun International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/macafs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6256e4f3e5996a22e6d51ed5_MMUN.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1025424"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The team over at Macco Simulations have released their visual rendition of Cancun International Airport (MMUN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With MSFS' beauty, this package enhances the area and the airport for all virtual visitors worldwide. Opening in 1974, the Cancun International Airport has two parallel runways and serves as a hub for Latin America carrier MAYAir, and is a focus city for Volaris and VivaAerobus, offering routes to over 20 Mexican airports, and serves other routes to over 30 countries. The airport is Mexico's second busiest airport after Mexico City, and is Latin America's third busiest airport, with serving over 22 million passengers in 2021. Upon release, the team has provided a feature list of what is included in this package. Firstly, PBR materials have been used throughout the model, with utilizing 4k textures. A basic terminal interior has been modeled, alongside custom lighting and static vehicles across the airport, with the inclusion of fully custom jetways. If you are interested in the full feature list, you can view it below: If you are interested in picking this scenery package for yourself, you can find it over on the Macco Simulations Website and sells for $15.99. If you are also interested in other packages by the team, you can check their product catalog on their website as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bl75u1</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Posts 757 Developmental Update</title>
    <updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bl75u1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62591260ee673a6005c89915_Screen%20Shot%202022-04-15%20at%201.33.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="868480"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, BlueBird Simulations posted the first development blog on its upcoming 757-200/300 series aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The short update brings the latest on the team’s progress, new previews of the aircraft, and a quick glimpse of the developer’s plans down the line. The development update, released 2 months after the aircraft was first announced, revealed that “exterior model (including textures) is around 50-60% complete”. In addition, the developers reported that work on the 757’s systems and flight dynamics are progressing as planned, though they will not be ready to share details on them for another few months. Finally, Bluebird Simulations teased that a new development update will be released every 4 to 6 weeks. BlueBird Simulations’s 757 will feature two variants of the aircraft: the -200 with RR/PW engines and the -300 with RR/PW engines. According to the developer’s website, the aircraft will be equipped with everything from custom-coded systems to 4k PBR textures. Check out a previous Threshold article to learn more about the product. Currently, the developers are yet to announce a firm release date or pricing for the aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmtrfs</id>
    <title>M'M Simulations Releases Tromsø Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmtrfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62599ab136b78adabc54ea22_TromsoCover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="809180"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. M'M Simulations have released their visual rendition of Tromsø Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Touching down in the Scandinavia region, the team has brought their skills to the airport and its surrounding area. Being established in the 1930s, the airport was first operated by Norwegian Air. As the European Theater of WW2 began, the airport began servicing the Junkers Ju-52 for the German Luftwaffe and they began the expansion of the aerodrome. After the war, the Norwegian Air Force took over operations and began adding expansions to the airport. Years later, the Norwegian Parliament approved construction for public passenger services, with the airport opening to the public on the 14th of September, 1964. The team has included a small, but down to the point feature list. Starting, the team has accurately modeled the surrounding area and the airport grounds, alongside accurate terraforming and CGL data. PBR textures have been added, and a modeled interior for added user experience. Ambient animated objects and an upcoming terminal have been all included.  If you are interested in picking this scenery package up for yourself, you can find it over on the simMarket Store and sells for €19.00. If you are interested in any other renditions by the team, you can view their catalog on their website.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
