<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-08-07T18:27:02.407189+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/320232</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates Airbus A320 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/320232"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a41da33330d51949727e3e_installer3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update to their rendition of the Airbus A320 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes bug fixes, improvements, and a new installer. A brand new installer has been developed to speed up their release and update process. It breaks files into smaller parts and only fetches the parts that have been altered, significantly speeding up the whole process. They have gathered comparison data, and the difference is astounding: from 2 minutes and 14 seconds total (download and installation) to 35 seconds (fastest result). They also reiterate that the figures may vary depending on hardware specs and storage speed. The sounds have also seen a rework, with binaural microphone recordings straight from a captain’s headset during a full flight, with cross-referenced ADS-B data to ensure the audio matches the correct phases of the flight. The result, balanced and adjusted accordingly, is much closer to the real thing. They have also improved the over- and behind-wing experience with new N1 bearing recordings, airflow, N2, and behind-intake buzzsaw on the CFM56s. They also have done further sound balancing on IAEs, with new airflow recordings, buzzsaw improvements, and a new window vibration/rattle on both at high power settings. The atmospheric sound model also received its fair share of refinement. Different ambient conditions influence the engine sounds, as demonstrated in the video below, which showcases the difference between a takeoff in the cold and dry versus hot and humid. Last but not least, still regarding sound improvements, Fenix added two hydraulic pump options: Vickers and Parker, as per the real thing (it can be fitted with either), and their subtly different sounds. The systems and flight model were not massively improved due to their strong focus on the upcoming expansion (A319 and A321). Still, they have improved the ADIRU wind simulation, so the airplane gathers wind data through its sensors rather than fetching it through the simulator. The fly-by-wire was made slightly smoother in pitch while retaining precision, and the ground-to-air blend was made creamier. The full changelog follows below: ‍ The Fenix A320 is available on their website for roughly $64.33. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fss727</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Announces Release Date for Boeing 727-200F Add-on</title>
    <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fss727"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a6b1d07204103b480e16cc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio recently shared new information on its Discord about the upcoming Boeing 727-200F add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The developer revealed details about the release date and price of the aircraft. The new 727 by FSS is now set to be released to the public on August 6th at around 08:00 UTC. Originally, the release was planned for the end of July, but the team has decided to delay it slightly to ensure that the aircraft includes all the necessary last-minute updates before the release. Moreover, the team has announced that various content creators, both big and small, will have access to the aircraft on August 1st at 00:00 UTC. This will allow everyone to have a proper look at the upcoming 727 before its public release. It's important to note that the GNS-XLS, initially scheduled for the first release, will be delayed to allow for improvements to the INS system. The GNS-XLS will still be added to the aircraft, but it is expected to be included 1-2 months after the initial release. Lastly, the team has announced that the long-awaited Boeing 727-200F will be priced at $42. The upcoming aircraft will be available in just 8 days, and Threshold will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orgthd</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases MSFS Global Trees HD for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orgthd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a755c101aeca5c1a18e946_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released its newest add-on, MSFS Global Trees HD, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This add-on, created by developer Dmytro Krykunov, aims to enhance realism by replacing all standard vegetation with high-quality specimens. The add-on allows users to customize and shape the landscape in Microsoft Flight Simulator according to their preferences. It offers features such as the ability to manage project data, change vegetation seasons, and replace the default grass. Dmytro designed the add-on to ensure that the biome and its vegetation are vibrant, diverse, and of high quality. MSFS Global Trees HD comes with various features, including high-quality replacement of default vegetation, the option to change vegetation seasons, the ability to replace default grass with six new types of grass, reworked biomes, and a software tool to adjust vegetation seasons and grass types. This add-on requires 2.78 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx for approximately $13.90. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/heca12</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Cairo International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/heca12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a7b13265af9e261ed19cb7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released the X-Plane 12 version of Cairo International Airport (HECA). Following the release of its MSFS version, the team has now launched their rendition for X-Plane 12. Cairo International Airport serves the capital of Egypt, Cairo, and is situated approximately eight nautical miles from the city's central business district. The airport handles an average of 14 million passengers annually. The airport originally opened as John Payne Field Air Force Base during the Second World War. After the war, the airport was taken over by the Civil Aviation Authority, marking the start of its use for civil aviation. It eventually replaced the former Heliopolis Airport. Today, the airport has three terminals and serves as the hub for the airlines EgyptAir, Nile Air, Air Cairo, and Air Arabia Egypt. Additionally, a variety of other airlines operate to and from the airport, providing connections to destinations worldwide. The newly released Cairo International Airport for X-Plane 12 comes with a variety of features, including highly detailed models, SAM animated jetways, high-quality PBR textures on objects and ground, complete autogen around the airport, ground traffic, weather textures, and more. The scenery requires 1.87 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for about $25.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fxsjer</id>
    <title>Fly X Simulations Releases Jersey Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fxsjer"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a7e55a7fe96da13811c771_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly X Simulations has just released its version of Jersey Airport (EGJJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It is located in Saint Peter, Jersey, and connects the largest of the Channel Islands with both domestic and international destinations. Jersey Airport was opened in 1937 when the States of Jersey decided to construct an airport with four grass runways. During the Second World War, the airport was taken over by the Admiralty and used as a Naval Air Station. The Luftwaffe occupied the airport and added concrete taxiways and hangars. In 1952, a tarmac runway was installed which led to the closure of the grass runway. Over the years, the runway has been extended and reached a length of 5.560 feet in 1976, which remains the same to this day. The airport is now a hub for the airline Blue Islands and serves various other airlines including British Airways, Eastern Airways, and easyJet. Annually, the airport welcomes around 1.3 million passengers and handles approximately 17.000 aircraft movements. The scenery package is feature-packed with accurate and highly detailed airport buildings, an extensive and detailed terminal interior, high-resolution custom PBR textures, custom ground markings, and more. The newly released Jersey Airport requires 1.62 GB of storage space, and it is available on iniBuilds for approximately $15.44. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdsvix</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Previews Vitória Airport &amp; City for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdsvix"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a9231acfd405410bb2e675_background72.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently previewed their rendition of Vitória - Eurico de Aguiar Salles International Airport (SBVT) and its surroundings for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Vitória in Espírito Santo, Brazil, with a yearly average of 3.2 million passengers. Originally built in the 1930s, it was not until a decade later that it would get its first passenger terminal and a paved runway. Heavy renovation work, including a new passenger terminal and runway, was carried out in 2005. Although scheduled to be completed in 2007, a series of scandals led to a "temporary" halt for nearly a decade. Construction work only resumed in 2015 and concluded three years later, in 2018, sixteen years after the original planning.  A few years before the resumption of the expansion works, the airport's operator, Infraero, deemed it the country's worst airport. Operated by Zurich Airports AG since 2019, the new airport finally meets international standards and swiftly leaves its dark past behind. Azul (Belo Horizonte, Campinas, Recife), Gol (Brasília, Porto Seguro, Rio de Janeiro, Salvador, São Paulo), Latam (Brasília, Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo), and Voepass (Porto Seguro) serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a highly detailed terminal, city POIs, custom ground clutter, and more.  There's no information on pricing and release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737730</id>
    <title>iFly Shares New 737 Max Previews for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737730"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a9774c93f217c7f163769e_max1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iFly has recently shared another set of images from their upcoming Boeing 737 Max 8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing its flight deck, cabin, and externals. The development state is said to be far along to the point it can already complete a full flight, but it’s not yet in official beta. Other than that, the developers did not share any further information. They have also set up a Discord server to facilitate communication with current and future customers regarding their new product. Furthermore, they uploaded a cabin walkthrough video, from rear to front, into the flight deck. There’s still no information regarding pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/darmal</id>
    <title>David Rosenfeld Previews Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/darmal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a97bf1ae35da8173e5f8c5_mal1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. David Rosenfeld recently previewed the interior work on his rendition of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Milan metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 26.1 million passengers. The site where the airport was built has more than a century of aviation history, with records dating back to 1910 when the Caproni brothers flew their Cal biplane. It became a popular prototype testing site in Italy, eventually leading to its upgrade to an actual airfield.  During that same period, the Caproni brothers decided to build a factory there, and Giovanni Augusta followed suit. It became the largest aircraft production center in the country. The airfield hosted two Royal Italian Air Force squadrons in the following decades.  In September 1943, the German Luftwaffe captured the airfield, building its first concrete runway, which didn't last long: the airfield was heavily bombed during WW2.  With the retreat of the German forces from Italy and the eventual end of the war, the runway was rebuilt and extended to 1,800 meters. A small terminal was built to shelter passengers and cargo from adverse weather conditions. Its official inauguration was in 1948 as Aeroporto Città di Busto Arsizio, and Sabena and TWA were among the first international carriers to serve it. In 1952, now under the control of the municipality of Milan, it was decided that Malpensa would become Milan's international airport, and Linate (Milan's other airport) would handle domestic services.  Milan's main airport needed a respectable terminal, which was built between 1958 and 1962. The runways were also extended and were the longest in Europe at the time.  Even though their original intent was to make Linate domestic-only, major European carriers preferred it over Malpensa because it was closer to the city center, transforming it into a secondary airport for over 20 years.  Things only changed in the 1980s when Linate was forcibly downgraded to domestic, and Malpensa underwent heavy upgrade work. Construction started in 1990, and it only reopened eight years later. ‍It's an operating base for AlbaStar, easyJet Europe, Malta Air, Neos, Ryanair, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air France, Air India, AirBaltic, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad Airways, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. The developer has said that work on the interior is moving forward at full speed, and the goal is to finish it within a few weeks. Then, he is going to focus on the apron. A release date was not shared at the time, but he's aiming for late fall/early winter. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom jetways, custom terminal interiors, custom ground textures, and more. There's no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/maastr</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Maastricht Aachen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/maastr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ac06874de014b56e05e7cc_aachen1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently released their rendition of Maastricht Aachen Airport (EHBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Maastricht in the Netherlands and Aachen in Germany. As of 2022, it was the second busiest cargo airport in the Country, handling 108,000 tonnes of cargo. Plans to build an airport in southern Limburg (near Maastricht) started in 1919, but it didn't come to fruition until much later due to debates with various municipalities over its location and funding. It wasn't until 20 years later that an agreement was reached to back the project financially, but the start of World War 2 put the plans back in the drawer. In early 1945, the USAAF Ninth Air Force decided to build a temporary airfield in the area, using rubble from an unintentionally bombed city to level the area. Its first runway was around 1,700 meters long and reinforced with pierced steel planks. The whole construction work took an impressive two months to complete. Due to its completion closely matching the war's end, there wasn't any combat to speak of being operated out of there. It was rapidly transferred to the Dutch government in early August 1945 and named Beek Airfield. The first terminal was built in 1947, and the main runway was paved two years later, followed by a second runway in 1950. The Dutch Air Force offered help in 1951 to further expand the main runway and add night lighting (which only happened nine years later). Commercial operations greatly expanded in the late 50s/early 1960s, bringing operators such as KLM, Airnautical,Skytours, Euravia, Tradair, and Transair.  In the early 1970s, the airport was expanded again to accommodate larger aircraft. The runway was lengthened to 2,500 meters, taxiways were widened, and the aprons were made bigger.  The 1980s brought a new passenger terminal and ATC tower. The same terminal is still in use today, albeit significantly expanded since. Corendon, Pegasus, Ryanair, and Tarom serve it. Cargo-wise, it's often visited by Emirates SkyCargo, MASkargo, Qatar Airways Cargo, Royal Jordanian Cargo, Rom Cargo Airlines, Saudia Cargo, Turkish Cargo, and Zimex Aviation. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom-modeled terminal, custom aerial imagery, custom static aircraft, custom night lighting, custom taxiway signs, custom ground vehicles, PBR textures, and an up-to-date ground layout as of 2024. ‍ It's available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $13.56, requiring at least 3 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carpvp</id>
    <title>CloudSurf Asia Releases Puerto Princesa International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carpvp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66adfb7c4f131c862f06e6ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CloudSurf Asia has recently released its version of Puerto Princesa International Airport (RPVP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the province of Palawan, Philippines, the airport serves the area of Puerto Princesa. The airport welcomes just over 1.1 million passengers annually. Built by American prisoners of war during the Second World War, the airport was under construction from 1942 to 1944. After completion, the airport was used by Japanese transport aircraft alongside a former grass airstrip located near today's NCCC Mall Palawan. After the liberation of Palawan in 1945, various units from the US Army Air Forces were stationed at the airport. It wasn't until 1947 that Puerto Princesa opened and started with air travel. Since then, the airport has seen a variety of airlines and aircraft, and has also undergone several expansions and improvements due to the increasing demand for air transportation. Today, the airport is an operating base for Air Juan and serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific, Philippine Airlines, and Philippines Air Asia, with nearly 9000 aircraft movements and around 1.1 million passengers yearly. The newly released Puerto Princesa International Airport for MSFS includes a variety of features such as up-to-date airport data, a fully modeled terminal with an interior, full custom objects around the airport, custom ground markings, full PBR textures, and more.  The add-on requires a total of 0.99 GB of storage space and is now available on Orbx, SimMarket, and iniBuilds for approximately $15.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dfkjac</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Releases Jackson Hole Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dfkjac"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66aff06032dddac583208ad5_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Dreamflight has just released its version of Jackson Hole Airport (KJAC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the valley of Jackson Hole, located in the U.S. state of Wyoming, and welcomes just under 1 million passengers annually. The airport was constructed in the 1930s after it was determined that the chosen location would be the best place for an airport in Teton County. In 1943, the airport was designated as a national monument and in 1950 it was incorporated into the Grand Teton National Park. In 1959, the runway was extended to a length of 6,300 feet, which remains the same today. That year, Frontier Airlines became the first airline to operate at the airport. Between 2009 and 2014, the airport's terminal was completely rebuilt and received the American Institute of Architects Honor Award in 2014. Additional improvements were initiated in 2021 and 2022. Currently, the airport serves a variety of airlines such as Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, United Airlines, and more, which collectively facilitate the annual arrival of around 1 million passengers. The newly released Jackson Hole Airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator includes a range of features, such as an accurate representation of the airport, high-quality textures, detailed models, fully detailed interior, custom ground polynomials, realistic night lighting, PBR textures, GSX profile, and more. The entire scenery package requires 1.79 GB of storage space and can be purchased on Contrail for approximately $16.38. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/if73mmp</id>
    <title>iFly Provides More Previews of 737 MAX8 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/if73mmp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66afee6d904d4ddddea5ee05_453720661_906550331515825_3897020728462941253_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In their most recent post on the Flight One Software Facebook page, iFly provides more previews for their highly anticipated rendition of the Boeing 737 MAX8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  Following up on a preview video of the passenger cabin of the iFly 737 MAX, these photos share close-ups of various parts of the cockpit, such as the overhead, pedestal, and cockpit entryway. iFly states that these screenshots were taken during “[...] a departure from KDEN to KSFO at dusk.” Also showcased are shots of the cockpit lighting, large screens, and EFB, among others.  No release date has been announced yet by iFly, but Threshold will keep you informed whenever they do, so stay tuned for that and for more high quality news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksoah</id>
    <title>MK Studios Announces Naha Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksoah"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66aff1bc7ca272c5cc63e54f_naha1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently announced the development and imminent release of Naha Airport (ROAH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Okinawa Prefecture with a yearly average of 21.5 million passengers. The Imperial Japanese Army built the airport in 1933 as Oroku Aerodrome. The United States took it over in 1945, and it was renamed Naha Airport. Scheduled service started two years later with Pan American World Airways and Northwest Orient.  ‍ Refurbishment work began in the early 1950s, bringing the structure up to the standards of the time. ‍ In the early 1980s, the US military transferred control of the airport to the Japanese forces, which then developed the airport. The first major upgrade happened in the 1990s, with a main passenger terminal expansion.  ‍ Further development started in 2008 when the government agreed to expand the domestic terminal and construct a new parallel runway. The expansion required a new international terminal, which opened in 2014, and the construction of the new parallel runway started around that same year. The new international terminal was expanded again in 2016, gaining another 3000 square meters.  ‍ The new runway started operation in 2020 after nearly six years of construction. ‍ It’s a hub for Japan Transocean Air and Ryukyu Air Commuter and a focus city for All Nippon Airways, Japan Airlines, and Peach. Air China, Asiana Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, EVA Air, HK Express, Hong Kong Airlines, Jeju Air, Jetstar Asia, Juneyao Air, Korean Air, Spring Airlines, Starlux Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan also serve it. ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed terminal, various POIs, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom vehicle models, custom runway profile and elevation data, a high-quality terminal interior, custom taxiway labels, and more. There’s no information on pricing yet, but the scenery is set to release sometime next week.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukeghq</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Cornwall Airport Newquay for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukeghq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b0ef7456e31ac2b9724a47_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has just released its latest airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Cornwall Airport Newquay (EGHQ). Located in England, the airport serves the areas of Newquay and Cornwall. Annually, the airport welcomes just over 400,000 passengers. The airport opened in 1933 as a civilian airfield. When the Second World War broke out, the airport was renamed RAF Trebelzue, and it was used to support other bases in the Cornwall area. In 1943, the airfield was renamed RAF St Mawgan and was handed over to the USAAF. After being put under maintenance in 1947, the airport reopened in 1951 as a Coastal Command base. Since then, various aircraft squadrons have operated at the airport, but those operations have since ceased. From 2006, a series of changes and upgrades gradually transformed the airport into a fully civilian airport. In 2008, the airport was officially separated from RAF St Mawgan and rebranded as Cornwall Airport Newquay. Today, the airport serves various airlines such as easyJet, Loganair, and Ryanair, and it is also a hub for the airline Eastern Airways. These airlines, along with others, contribute to the airport's annual 400,000 passengers and just over 19,000 aircraft movements. The scenery offers a range of features, including detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, night effects, airport vehicles, vegetation, PBR materials, static aircraft, and more. The newly released Cornwall Airport Newquay is now available on SimMarket for approximately $16.46. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo111</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Updates San Francisco International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b155ffa00dd012a7b10e3f_sfo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ Flightbeam Studios has recently updated their newly released rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding the all-new high-speed taxiway Tango, new vehicles, and more. Their best-selling product to date has seen its first major update, bringing a series of improvements and additions, which include the new high-speed taxiway Tango, new rescue vehicles, improved runway textures and decals, improved tire markings, new flora, and tire marks on the runway, which were absent on 1.0 due to a blunder (it got swept underneath another layer). The complete changelog follows below: They have also teased what will be in the next update (1.2): custom taxiway lighting, with custom lights (LODded, directional, colored properly, and dynamically lit).  The airport is available on their shop for $19.99, requiring at least 2.57 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/b727ms</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Releases Boeing 727-200F for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/b727ms"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b1fa8571f28db988ba1a32_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio has just released its highly anticipated Boeing 727-200F add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The iconic three-engined cargo aircraft is now available for users to add to its fleet. The original variant of the Boeing 727 was launched in 1958. This new aircraft was developed after the Boeing 707 to meet the demand for short-haul flights. Initially designed as a passenger aircraft, a cargo version was introduced in 1981. The Boeing 727-200F was equipped with Pratt &amp; Whitney engines and had a windowless cabin with a freight door on the front main deck. Since the introduction of the cargo variant, the aircraft has played a significant role for various airlines in cargo operations worldwide. FlightSim Studio's rendition of the 727-200F includes a range of features. The aircraft features a detailed exterior with PBR textures, custom animations, 3D lighting, winglets, and custom liveries. The interior is also highly detailed, with a complete cockpit, custom night lighting, cargo cabin, animated cargo doors, and various cockpit interactions. The package comes with an Electronic Flight Bag, offering users a variety of options and tools. The flight dynamics have been designed by a real pilot to ensure the highest level of realism. There are a total of four navigation options available. Additionally, the aircraft includes comprehensive documentation to assist you in getting started. The newly released Boeing 727-200F requires 5 GB of storage space and is available at Aerosoft for about $42. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
