<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-06-04T18:35:25.330963+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/77f519</id>
    <title>PMDG’s Boeing 777F Now Available for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/77f519"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently made its Boeing 777F fully compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which is now available through the new Operations Center for 2020 owners. After a few days of struggling with SU 2 (as per their last development update), PMDG has finally managed to get the 777F working properly in the new simulator. It is the first of the pre-2024 777s to get compatibility.  Owners of the 2020 version do not need to repurchase the addon, and new purchases will grant you the two versions. Furthermore, PMDG will submit the 777F to the in-game marketplace for intake, a process that is known to take a couple of weeks. The 2020 version also got an update, as it hasn’t been updated in a while, thanks to PMDG being busy with the 777-200ER. The changes include code optimizations, flight model and fly-by-wire improvements, systems updates, and bug fixes, along with new features such as the weight and balance application, and the inclusion of the SayIntentions datalink integration to both the 777-200ER and the 777F.  The 777-300ER is currently in testing for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and might become available later this week, but that will require further evaluation, and it is possible that it will only be ready next week. Regarding their next product, the 777L is being prepared for entry into testing, and they expect that to begin by the end of May. The addon is available at their store for $54.99.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/146x12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases 146 Professional for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/146x12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682df96e16e41561e1b69d06_146-professional-xplane-12_23_ss_l_250515150628%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight, in a partnership with Thranda Design, has released 146 Professional for X-Plane 12. Based on BAe 146, its rendition features eight variants:  146-100/-200/-300, 146-200QC/QT (QC - Quick change, QT - Quiet Trader), 146-300QT, as well as CC.Mk2 and CC.Mk3 (RAF VIP and cargo configurations, respectively). The BAe 146 is a short-haul regional airliner produced by British Aerospace between 1983 and 1994, when its improved version, named Avro RJ, replaced it. 221 146s were made, with the -200 variant being the most popular one, with 116 of them built. Powered by 4 Lycoming ALF 502R-5, it could carry between 70 and 112 passengers, depending on the version (70-82 on -100, 85-100 on -200, and 97-112 on -300), up to 35,000ft, and could cruise at M0.65. Just Flight’s rendition features a detailed exterior model with PBR textures, realistic animations of the lap mechanism, passenger and cargo doors, spoilers, and the iconic tail-mounted airbrake, custom-coded systems, immersive dynamic lighting, 3D sounds, realistic flight dynamic for the each variant, custom condensation and contrails effects, several options for navigation equipment (default X-Plane FMC, custom UFMC and RXP GTN750), as well as manuals and over 40 liveries of various 146 operators across the globe. ‍ ‍MODEL‍ ‍ ‍ COCKPIT ‍ ‍ TEXTURES AND LIVERIES ‍ Included liveries ‍ The 146 Professional for X-Plane 12 comes with a variety of airline liveries from the UK, USA, Australia, Europe and more. ‍ 146-100 ‍ 146-200 ‍ 146-200QC ‍ 146-200QT ‍ 146-300 ‍ 146-300 QT ‍ CC.Mk2 ‍ C.Mk 3 ‍ ‍ SOUNDS ‍ ‍ FLIGHT DYNAMICS ‍ SYSTEMS ‍ Custom-coded aircraft systems with a high degree of complexity and depth, including: ‍ Air-conditioning and pressurisation system: ‍ ‍ Auto-flight system: ‍ ‍ Flight Management Computer (UFMC): ‍        Communication system: ‍ ‍ Electrical system: ‍ ‍ Fire protection system: ‍ ‍ Flight controls: ‍ ‍ Fuel system: ‍ ‍ Hydraulic system: ‍ ‍ Ice and rain protection system: ‍ ‍ Indicating and recording systems: ‍ ‍ Landing gear: ‍ ‍ Navigation systems: ‍ ‍ Oxygen system: Flight crew and passenger oxygen systems with valve and mask deployment controls ‍ Pneumatic system: Realistic bleed air demand from engines and APU, and pneumatic supply to air-conditioning and ice protection systems. APU: ‍ ‍ Doors and stairs: ‍ ‍ Power plant: ‍ ‍ Lighting: ‍ ‍ OTHER FEATURES ‍ The 146 Professional is available for purchase on the Just Flight store for $44.99 and requires at least 5.7GB of disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sbf522</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates SimBrief With New Planning Tools</title>
    <updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sbf522"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682f8512b28460b396118fa3_simbrief1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph recently issued an update to its flight planning tool, SimBrief, adding an advanced thunderstorm avoidance system, a new route calculation engine, and more. SimBrief’s latest version—subscriber-only, though—added a wealth of features that, according to Navigraph, beat real-life dispatching tools even before the update.  With their all-new route calculator, it’s now possible to avoid specific SIGMETs along the way and plan a path around the weather. Furthermore, avoiding temporary flight restriction or ETOPS areas is also a breeze. ETOPS area avoidance makes it easier for people intending to replicate certain ferry flights on non-ETOPS-certified airplanes, providing them with a realistic and safe route.  In addition to these new features, you can now easily add oceanic tracks, instantly preview the route before its generation, choose specific SIDs and STARs from a dropdown list on the route calculator, and visualize them on the interactive map before ultimately picking one. ‍ Non-subscribers have not been forgotten, and they received three new updates: a flight history overhaul, expanded aircraft options, and easier equipment editing. ‍ The update is available right now and accessible through their website or app. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxisaw</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Sabiha Gökçen International Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxisaw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6830ef392ddd872a848df044_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MXI Design has recently launched its version of Sabiha Gökçen International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Serving as Istanbul's secondary international airport, it is also the second busiest airport in Turkey, accommodating over 41 million passengers each year. The airport opened in 2001, created to accommodate the growing number of both domestic and international passengers that Atatürk Airport could no longer handle. Construction of a new terminal began in 2008 and was completed in 2009. In 2023, the airport added a second runway, and there are plans to build new passenger terminals between the two runways. Today, the airport serves over 41 million passengers annually, facilitated by more than 240,000 aircraft movements. It operates as a hub for AJet and Pegasus Airlines, while also serving airlines such as British Airways, Flydubai, Qatar Airways, and many others. The newly released scenery features high-resolution PBR textures and modelling, interior modelling, custom jetways, an up-to-date airport layout, a custom GSX profile, and much more. MXI Design's version of Sabiha Gökçen International Airport is now available on Contrail for approximately $27.28. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cwb103</id>
    <title>flyt Updates Curitiba International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cwb103"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/682a2ec98cde4f7895ea56e2_1250410_20250514215235_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt Simulations has recently updated their newly released Curitiba International Airport (SBCT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update fixes the ILS approach for runway 15/33 (for non-Navigraph users), adds minor quality-of-life improvements, and more. Update 1.0.3 is now available via the in-game Content Manager, fixing the ILS approach for runway 15/33, adding the BR Air service helipad, minor quality-of-life improvements, and minor texture adjustments. The next update, including the apron extension, updated parking stands, and new jetways, is scheduled to arrive in the next few weeks. The scenery is available in the MSFS Marketplace for $12.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmfll</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Cancels Fort Lauderdale-Hollywood International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmfll"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6833a63b82a463bafdc16e6a_lauderdale.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Verticalsim recently posted an announcement on its Facebook page concerning the cancellation of their Fort Lauderdale-Hollywood International Airport (KFLL) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 due to various factors. “This wasn’t an easy decision,” they said, “especially with much of the work already completed, but - after careful reflection - I believe it’s the right one.” The ever-rising expectations for Microsoft Flight Simulator sceneries, their lack of reference material for the airport, and shifting market demands have made the project non-viable and impractical to continue.  ‍ Furthermore, their commitment to delivering high-standard scenery that meets or exceeds expectations would not be compatible with delivering KFLL, as they like to take their time to do things right and never cut corners.  ‍ Verticalsim will now focus on completing Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) and outlining a clear roadmap for 2025, “delivering high-quality airports that I know I can bring the community the right way.” If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aessdr</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes Scenery Development Roadmap for 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aessdr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68362df620c971183c17379c_aerosoftroadmap.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft recently delineated its development roadmap for 2025, which so far comprises a Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) backport to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, optimization work for Frankfurt Airport (EDDF), and a rendition of Paris Charles de Gaulle (LFPG). ‍ Due to popular demand, Aerosoft has decided to backport their newly released Düsseldorf Airport to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. They appear to have found a solution to make the scenery backward compatible, even though it was built from the ground up with the new technology in mind. ‍ All 2024 version customers will get the 2020 version free of charge, and they will ensure it also applies to Marketplace customers. Due to certain core differences, they will be provided as separate installations. ‍ Their Mega Airport Frankfurt is undergoing heavy optimization work, with the LOD levels being revised, improved memory and CPU utilization, optimization of all 3D models and textures, and better balance between LOD and FPS. Furthermore, they will also be working on implementing Terminal 3 and updating the ground layout to reflect the latest changes. The update is going to be free for all current owners. ‍ They have also announced a rendition of Paris Charles de Gaulle (LFPG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 (and maybe 2020, if their backporting process works as intended). They promise a heavily optimized flagship scenery with a large scope, ambition, and transparent step-by-step development process. ‍ Lastly, they announced a rendition of Stuttgart Airport (EDDS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 (which may be backported depending on demand), developed by Jo Erlend and Lukas Vezyroglou. It’s said to be already in development and will feature a highly detailed implementation focused on realism and atmosphere. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfeav</id>
    <title>Microsoft to Attend South America’s First Flight Simulation Exposition</title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfeav"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6836365d2c00ce07f62f40e0_expoav1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Microsoft has recently confirmed its attendance at Expo Aviação Virtual 2025, South America’s first flight simulation exposition. Now, in its second edition—with a much larger scope—it expects up to 2000 visitors within its two-day run and a much larger number of speakers and brands. The first edition welcomed big names in the industry, such as PMDG, Say Intentions AI, Azul Airlines, and popular scenery developers from Brazil (Geardown Simulations, Flyt Simulations). They intended on expanding their international reach for 2025, with Microsoft now confirming their presence. Talks are still in place with other global leaders in simulation and training. Over 14 expert speakers are already confirmed at the event, including many Brazilian aviation figures from both the simulation and real-life spectrum, sharing their experience and knowledge with all the attendees.  The event stands out for their inclusive approach, offering a half-price ticket to attendees who donate one kilogram of non-perishable food, which will be donated to charity. Furthermore, they will be welcoming deaf pilots who will share their stories with the audience.  ‍ Expo Aviação Virtual will be held between November 22 and 23 at Shopping Center 3, Avenida Paulista, 2064, São Paulo. Click here for further information and registration details. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mjc400</id>
    <title>Majestic Software Shares Renders of Upcoming Q400 for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mjc400"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68363a6811e46f74690f1310_q4001.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Majestic Software has made their first public appearance in a long while with five render images of their upcoming Bombardier Q400, a popular turboprop airliner widely used in North America and Europe. Announced during the early days of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, the Q400 project hasn’t seen much tangible information other than the occasional “we are working on it,” but Majestic has finally taken a bold step, showing renders of their project (still not in-sim, though). They say they will be sharing in-sim screenshots when it is permissible to do so. It is also not yet known whether it will be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, 2024, or both, but Threshold will keep you informed. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkeddl</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Düsseldorf Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkeddl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6838767cf2aea972b052dbf4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has just released its version of Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves over 19 million passengers annually, making it the fourth-busiest airport in Germany. Düsseldorf Airport, opened in 1927, did not have any international flights until two years later, in 1929. During the Second World War, the airport ceased civil aviation operations from 1939 to 1948. From 1969 to 1986, the airport underwent various upgrades, including the construction of three new terminals and an extension of the runway. As traffic to the airport grew rapidly, additional expansions were made, including the addition of a railway station and a new parking garage. Today, Düsseldorf Airport serves as a base for airlines such as Condor, Corendon Airlines, Eurowings, SunExpress, and TUI fly Deutschland, while also accommodating a variety of other airlines. The newly released scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, high-quality 3D models and textures, fully modelled terminal interiors, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, and more. Düsseldorf Airport, created by MK Studios, is now available for purchase from Contrail for approximately $20.43. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777529</id>
    <title>PMDG Faces “Turbulence” with MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777529"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67007455f9c93f4f4c4607ef_randy4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently published another development update concerning certain delays related to the 777-200ER and 777F's marketplace launch, the 777W update for MSFS 2024, and more. In Randazzo's own words, today's update "would be done in Captain PA's voice, if that was possible" as PMDG experiences another unexpected "turbulence" affecting the progress of their projects for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. They hit a new roadblock during their marketplace submission of the 777-200ER and the 777F by making an error in the naming convention for the 777 product line in MSFS 2024. This error is present in all of their products and will have to be addressed as it affects product placement and the relationship between the 2020 and the 2024 product versions within the marketplace's ecosystem and their own Operations Center. ‍ Said issue must be fixed in all of their products before submitting to the marketplace again, and they are well aware of what the error is and how to fix it. However, time and testing are required to validate the changes and ensure they don't break anything.  ‍ They plan to spend at least a week testing and then submit the 777-200ER, the 777F, and the 777-300ER to the marketplace one week from Friday. ‍ The 777-300ER's compatibility update, which was supposed to come out this week, has been hit with the naming convention roadblock, preventing it from being rolled out. They anticipate it will be released almost immediately after confirming the fix works for the 777-200ER and the 777F. ‍ Due to all the turbulence, the beta testing process for their upcoming 777-200LR has been delayed until further notice. ‍ An update for the 777 product line has been in the works for a while. It is part of a larger fix they have been brewing, but the naming convention issue has become a priority for now.  ‍ The DC-6 should be entering testing within the next few days, now that PMDG has seemingly addressed their level of detail issues with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ‍ The 737 update project was the topic of their weekly all-hands meeting, where they mapped out the work required to bring the product into MSFS 2024. They have frozen the product scope, and the schedule is based on the remainder of the work required. Their work on the 777 has been stealing all their attention for now, but they will soon return it to the 737. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350111</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683a36256e1b9e9f81f783e6_upsy1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued a significant update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which includes extensive overhauls and refinements across core systems, new features, and more. ‍ Update v1.0.11 comes with new fly-by-wire features, such as the auto de-rotation system, which assists pilots during the landing phase after the main gear has touched down. The system prevents hard nosewheel touchdowns by avoiding any abrupt or exaggerated pitch changes by the pilot, helping improve landing consistency across different weather conditions and pilot landing techniques.  Furthermore, the update also features enhanced GPS jamming, with the satellite signals becoming degraded, blocked, or completely unavailable upon entering a jammed area, impacting navigation accuracy, ADS-B reporting, and position data for the FMS. The A350 heavily depends on GPS for efficient and precise routing, even though it also has IRS and backup navigation sources to fly the route. However, functionality will be severely limited, alerts will be triggered, and a switch to alternate navigation models may be forced. Initially, their GPS jamming system was randomized and not region-specific. In contrast, the new version integrates live data for a much more realistic experience, only jamming where GPS jamming is going on. ‍ They calculate the regions using a system called H3 Geo to convert latitude and longitude into hex cells on a map that correlates the aircraft’s reporting of GPS data in those areas over 24 hours and dynamically updates it so the jammed regions are constantly changing based on real-world data. A throwback feature—present in their A300 and A310 for X-Plane—has finally made its way to Microsoft Flight Simulator, allowing pilots to print take-off data, flight plans, metars, mailbox, and more. They used a combination of 3D animations and show/hide attachments to simulate the print process and placement of the paper on the chart clip in the cockpit.  For Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 pilots, the planned route API is now in working order, making it possible to send and receive the flight plan from the sim FMS and vice versa. The tool built into 2024 uses the official LIDO navigation databases and real-world submitted flight plans to provide accurate routing information. This feature will be utilized in the sim’s career mode in the future. iniBuilds has also added a new condensation effect. The aircraft generates condensation on cockpit windows using the difference between outside air temperature and simulated cabin temperature, building up or dissipating over time depending on the conditions. The windshield heat status is also taken into account, just like the real aircraft. Due to sim limitations, the effect is exclusive to MSFS 2024. They have also added a wide range of new ECAM messages. Some of them were disabled in 2024, though, due to a bug in the simulator. The complete changelog for the update follows below: ‍ v1.0.11Systems⚙️FIXED: MFD approach: selecting via NONE displays [----]FIXED: Latched VDEV behaves like normal DES mode if the speed is reducedFIXED: FPLN erased during go aroundFIXED: After a 2nd go around the approach is no longer in the FPLN bugFIXED: Changing arrival runway but not inserting it still changes the drop down approach optionsFIXED: Duplicate UTC message in F-PlanFIXED: Activating ALTN doesn't clear original DEST dataFIXED: MCDU-FLAN modification in SECFIXED: EDDM 08L/R VNAV issueFIXED: OMDB, RIDAP 2F SID - min speed at DB570 is 180, but the max at DB585 is 220. Should managed speed therefore shoot for 220?FIXED: Issue when deleting HOLD as part of procedureFIXED: EFIS ND Mode Change Message not displayingFIXED: Floating arrowFIXED: MFD PERF: QNH inHG entry format errorFIXED: GO Around logic issuesFIXED: VLS conf full and conf3 are the sameFIXED: AFS Control Panel functionality incorrectFIXED: Takeoff trim out of limits when lightFIXED: Issue with glowing brakesFIXED: Pressing FIRE pb should turn the FADEC offFIXED: Engine oil capacityFIXED: OIL quantity indication oscillates during cruiseFIXED: Engine failure after V1 feedbackFIXED: XPDR behaviour from STBY to AutoFIXED: RMP 3 logicFIXED: Text overlap on fuel pageFIXED: RNAV SLS incorrect NAVAIDS tuningFIXED: SURV: can click through the confirmation boxFIXED: FADEC not powering off 15min after ENG shutdownFIXED: MAGVAR issue for display on AFS, PFD, NDFIXED: Brake cooling mid-airFIXED: Spoiler behaviour reversesFIXED: VNAV VSD de-synced from sequenced waypoint after inserting holdFIXED: RWY (armed) shows when flap lever is set to 0FIXED: Sim Pause triggering on user AP disconnection with protection onFIXED: ENG ECAMFIXED: FMS goes blank when selecting FMS1FIXED: Spoilers don't extend when overspeedFIXED: No zero on barometric altitude when below 100 feet MSLFIXED: Engine thrust doesn't follow cursor when set to idle reverseFIXED: No TAWS messages on NDFIXED: A. LOCK doesn't workFIXED: WIND UPLINK issuesFIXED: Cost Index vs cruise speed too low at normal cruise levelsFIXED: Battery draining during pauseFIXED: TCAS amber with NAV PRIMARY LOSTFIXED: ETP FMC calculationsFIXED: D-ATIS arrival request shows departure ATISFIXED: CMS formatting on NDFIXED: SEC Index page logicFIXED: PRED TO function not working as expected for typed FLFIXED: PRED CLB ECON not showing as referenceFIXED: PERF CRZ FL391 input reverts to ---FIXED: SPD to MACH reversion shows incorrect SPD window valueFIXED: Level-Off Arrow symbol rendering bugsFIXED: Constraint logic not functioning as intendedFIXED: AP disconnection due to low FPSFIXED: Mode reversion to heading mode in high windsFIXED: EFIS CP baro reference issueFIXED: C/L sensed items not staying green after takeoffFIXED: Suggested optimum step fieldFIXED: Nose drops automatically on touchdownFIXED: Auto sideslip control issues and side slip indicator behaviorFIXED: FO OIS brightness buttons affecting contrast barFIXED: No level off arrow in CRZ phaseFIXED: WPs missing from CMS/Step AltsFIXED: Roll feedback in FBW systemFIXED: TMPY inputs not resetting after FMC resetFIXED: FMS ALTN F-PLN scroll/view mismatch with NDFIXED: Wind data at cruiseFIXED: ND drawing of cross track errorFIXED: CP logic at power upFIXED: VSD not showing level-off altitudeFIXED: PFD LS distance info displayFIXED: GLS approach loading issueFIXED: SURV page misbehavior when IR unalignedFIXED: Aircraft takes off stick-free at low FLEX/TOGAFIXED: VAPP jumping erratically in strong windsFIXED: Cannot deselect FLS on LDA approachesFIXED: Step altitude logic revisions implementedFIXED: Level-Off Arrow Symbol rendering issues in multiple scenariosFIXED: WIND DES page and ALTERNATE entries in FMS not functioning correctlyFIXED: SELECTED FOR NAV tab not calculating RADIO NAV MODE and RADIO POSITIONFIXED: With engine out, automatic CLB phase no longer engages incorrectlyFIXED: Transponder functionality reversedFIXED: Window wipers function with no power (cold and dark, BATs off)FIXED: Pressing FIRE pb did not shut down FADECFIXED: ND did not indicate next waypoint correctlyFIXED: Issue with VHHH LIMES waypoint not rendering properlyFIXED: ALTN flight plan shows dashed line not matching ND routeFIXED: WIND DATA synchronization in FMS not workingFIXED: AFS CP logic failure with empty FMSFIXED: MFD crash when switching to SEC-FPLN (WASM issue)FIXED: ANF/EFIS crash scenario addressedUPDATED: Elevator trim blending logic proposal for smoother rotation handling when transitioning from ground to air OISFIXED: ROP warnings not workingFIXED: Activating ALTN doesn't clear original DEST dataFIXED: BRK MED disarming during go aroundFIXED: CMS issueFIXED: Navaid auto tuning feedbackFIXED: PRED TO function not working in any phaseFIXED: No FMA change box in engine out when selecting THR MCTFIXED: MAP waypoints in PLAN should be blue not greenFIXED: MAP constraints shouldn't have prediction circlesFIXED: BRK MED not workingFIXED: Missed approach showing 0nm to waypointsFIXED: ND display of departure airportFIXED: BTV not workingFIXED: T.O. THS out of range on spawnFIXED: ND LS-Mode with FLSFIXED: ND NAV mode, level-off arrow behind aircraft in selected HDG+VSFIXED: Brake cooling mid-airFIXED: Engine failure after V1 feedbackFIXED: LDG inhibit disappears too earlyFIXED: Auto callout RETARD issueFIXED: GSX passenger load count &gt; max capacityFIXED: GSX unable to disconnect GPUFIXED: Updating return information for TOPerf to FMGSFIXED: Fuel jettison shows ON and OPEN instead of ON and faultFIXED: ENG 1/2 MASTER ECAM logic with BLUE faultFIXED: Gear failed on left side not showing red down lockFIXED: SPD LIM TMPY input disappearing when editedFIXED: Engine out: ATHR off FMA keeps flashing LVR MCTFIXED: ISIS option and menu behaviorFIXED: MFD F-PLN selection should scroll to the topFIXED: ECAM WXR &amp; TCAS faults shown when IRS is offFIXED: SPD Brakes visually appear but have no flight model effectFIXED: SURV panel spelling issueFIXED: Display type &amp; status not synced on spawnFIXED: Track line missing when on HDGFIXED: VD bracket on ND should disappear when in HDG/TRKFIXED: Spawning mid-flight triggers AUTO EMER DES as cabin alt of 15kFIXED: Autoland at EDDLFIXED: Waypoints missing from CMS/Step AltsFIXED: Managed speed quick fluctuationsFIXED: SUGT optimum step fieldFIXED: Engine failure after V1, stuck in TO phaseFIXED: BRK MED: box around it on FMA when active present againFIXED: Incorrect order of memos on ECAMFIXED: PRIM1+2+3 fault, FD listed as INOP but still worksFIXED: "M" in PFD LS "NM" is hidden behind target bearingFIXED: REFUEL IN PROGRESS memo stuckFIXED: NW STEER DISC memo stuck EFB/OIS🖥️FIXED: GSX loading in the wrong orderFIXED: OIS Loadsheet page fields not updating correctly during/after GSX progressive boarding/refuellingFIXED: OIS charts issue and readabilityFIXED: No option to set departure time on the OIS FLT PLN Simbrief pageFIXED: OIS OFP page large fps drop when mouse within OIS bordersFIXED: OIS Screen brightness bar missing (CPT/FO)FIXED: SYNC FMS not workingFIXED: Cabin Language livery config takes priority over OIS setting – warning addedFIXED: Add load configuration button (Doors/Cargo)FIXED: Toggling fuel panel on MX page opens L1 doorFIXED: Typo: Dual Engine Failure SituationFIXED: Avionics Bay and Cargo Bay lights turning on simultaneously via EFBFIXED: Oil overflow indication on maintenance pageFIXED: OIS OFP text size not persistingFIXED: Enroute map route drawing error on trans-pacific flightsFIXED: Fuel weight calculation issueFIXED: GSX remote stand boarding not opening L2FIXED: GSX boarding does not continue automatically if fuel is upliftedFIXED: Region-based GPS jamming impact areas addedFIXED: New ZFWCG calculations integratedFIXED: Cannot print mailbox messages via MSG RECORD pageFIXED: Printer D-ATIS / MAILBOX page feedbackFIXED: Printer FPLN INIT page feedbackFIXED: Some ECAMs should be restricted to 2020/2024 onlyFIXED: OIS ENR SUGT – do not draw MAP (missed approach)FIXED: EHAM to EGBB chart crash in LIDO repositoryFIXED: Printer -T.O DATA- Page FeedbackUPDATED: EFB API enhancementsADDED: Preferred PF seat selection to options page,ADDED: Geo referencing for LIDO charts ART🎨FIXED: Condensation animation only shows on left wingFIXED: JA03XJ - Sustainability Goals decal should be removedFIXED: ETH 1000 liveries missing tail flashFIXED: Edelweiss -900 missing wing reg and decalsFIXED: OH-LWK export failureFIXED: Lufthansa winglets alignmentFIXED: JAL aircraft not rendering in simFIXED: Fuel ventilation overpressure discFIXED: DLH D-AIVA tailplane white texture instead of blueADDED: Hot brakes emissive SOUNDS🔊FIXED: No sound on belly door releaseFIXED: Missing gear door opening sounds on groundFIXED: No touchdown soundsFIXED: EXT APU sound too loudFIXED: Parking brake handle has no soundFIXED: Park brake sound plays once then not againFIXED: Brake fans missing spool up/down soundFIXED: Add varied flap motor noisesFIXED: External sound added to landing gear doorsFIXED: External hydraulic sounds no longer overly filteredFIXED: Adjusted hydraulic sound distancing from cockpit perspectiveFIXED: Missing system noise in walkaround viewFIXED: Reduced dip in engine volume after startupFIXED: Added variety to flap soundsFIXED: TCAS sound events not playingFIXED: Brake fan spooling sound missingFIXED: Exterior avionics volume increasedFIXED: FS20 exterior sound distancing muted at certain anglesFIXED: FS20 sunshades audio mix increasedFIXED: APU levels adjusted near the nose areaFIXED: Dropped intensity of maximum low-frequency gainFIXED: Delay on gear thump sound after rotationFIXED: FS20 touchdown sound inconsistencyFIXED: Retard callout louder than other GPWSFIXED: Hydraulic pump stopping sound plays after ENG shutdownFIXED: Post engine start sounds too quietFIXED: D-ATIS Auto Update not functionalFIXED: HYD pump sound when recharging accumulator should not be audible from cockpitFIXED: Taxi roll sound too loud and sounds oddFIXED: No belly door release soundFIXED: Wing to center tank xfer pb has double click soundFIXED: ELEC pushbuttons play double click when toggled ON &gt; OFFFIXED: PARK BRAKE sound plays once then stopsADDED: Printer sounds added ‍ The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dus101</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Düsseldorf Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dus101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683e5ce6048ae267d61f671f_dusup1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently issued an update to their newly released rendition of Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024, addressing issues, improving the level of detail, and more. Update 1.0.1 – released just a few days after the product’s release – brings a hefty changelog consisting of many improvements around the terminal, bug fixes, LOD tweaks, and more. The changelog follows below: The scenery is available on Contrail for roughly $20.56, requiring at least 4.38 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmwsss</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Singapore Changi Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmwsss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683f90219060370618258298_changi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels recently released their rendition of Singapore Changi Airport (WSSS) for X-Plane 12. It is one of the world's busiest airports, with a yearly average of 58 million passengers. It was inaugurated 42 years ago when the Singaporean government was forced to build a new airport to cope with the region's ever-growing demand for air travel.  At first, their original plan was to expand Paya Lebar, the former main airport in Singapore, but the 1973 Oil crisis changed everything. By 1975, they had already decided to build a brand new airport at the eastern tip of the main island of Changi, at the Changi Air Base. After its first year of operation, the airport had already handled an average of 12.1 million passengers, which led to the construction of a second passenger terminal in the 1990s. Terminal 3 soon followed in 2008, and then Terminal 4 in 2017. Terminal 5, which is planned to be larger than all four combined, is expected to open in 2030. It's a FedEx Express, Jetstar Asia, Scoot, and Singapore Airlines hub. AirAsia, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air India, Air New Zealand, All Nippon Airways, Cathay Pacific, China Southern Airlines, EVA Air, Garuda Indonesia, Hainan Airlines, IndiGo, KLM, Lufthansa, Qantas, Swiss, United Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made PBR ground textures, high-detail models, SAM jetways, performance-friendly optimization, weather textures (X-Plane 12), and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $26.48, requiring at least 1.86 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samqin</id>
    <title>SamScene3D Releases Qingdao Jiaodong International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samqin"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/683f94b63bf970eb359418b6_qing1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SamScene3D has recently released their rendition of Qingdao Jiaodong International Airport (ZSQD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Qingdao with a yearly average of 21.4 million passengers. It was built to replace Qingdao’s former main airport, Qingdao Liuting International (same ICAO). The project was approved in 2013, and construction started in 2017. By 2020, the terminal building had already passed completion acceptance, greenlighting it for a 2021 inauguration. It features a single 478,000-square-meter terminal built to handle up to 35 million passengers a year, designed in a starfish shape with five concourses, and two 3,600-meter-long runways able to handle up to an A380. It’s a hub for Qingdao Airlines and Shandong Airlines and a focus city for Beijing Capital Airlines and China Eastern Airlines. 9 Air, Air Busan, Air China, Air Macau, All Nippon Airways, Cathay Pacific, China United, Donghai Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Jeju Air, Korean Air, Scoot, Shanghai Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tibet Airlines, West Air, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed terminals, detailed ground markings, custom jetways, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.09, requiring at least 3.90 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl302</id>
    <title>FSLabs Releases A321ceo Update Including MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl302"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de3df1ae2d10ada9d7bc_labsup2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently released a new update to its A321ceo product line, available via its Public and Experimental branches on the FSL Control Center. The update adds initial compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, many system enhancements, sound upgrades, and more. Update v11.0.1.302 is their first update to feature initial compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It makes several changes under the hood to support the new environment while also retaining compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The new update also brings system-level improvements, including bug fixes, performance optimizations, and refinements to raise the realism bar and reliability. They were driven by extensive internal QA and feedback from their community of pilots and testers. ‍ The sounds were also upgraded, substantially improving the soundscape around the cockpit and engines. ‍ Furthermore, FSLabs has also added the ROPS (Runway Overrun Prevention System)—not to be mistaken with the thing missing from some RTX 5080s and 5090s—an advanced safety feature designed by Airbus to help mitigate the risk of runway excursions during landing. It integrates two core functions: ROW (Runway Overrun Warning) and ROP (Runway Overrun Protection). The Runway Overrun Warning provides proactive in-flight alerts by continuously computing the aircraft’s predicted stopping distances on dry and wet runways, considering real-time factors such as weight, speed, configuration, wind conditions, and runway slope. If it determines the available runway length is not enough for a safe landing, it automatically issues visual and aural alerts: ‍ The visual alert has the PFD display “runway too short,” the navigation display indicates the predicted stopping points extending beyond the runway’s end. The aural alert, on the other hand, triggers below 200 feet, with a repetitive “runway too short” audio warning. ‍ The alerts are in place to prompt the crew to start a go-around procedure, as a landing attempt beyond that point is deemed completely unsafe. ‍ The ROP system takes over upon touchdown and continuously assesses the aircraft’s deceleration capability against the remaining runway length, providing immediate guidance may it detect insufficient stopping distance: ‍ A visual alert – similar to the ROW one –displaying a “runway too short” warning, and aural alerts issuing commands such as “brake max braking,” “set max reverse,” and “keep max reverse” depending on the situation at hand, ensuring maximum deceleration efforts. ‍ The feature was faithfully recreated to replicate Airbus logic, ensuring realism and immersion for the virtual pilot. ‍ The Flight Performance Model has also been tweaked, changing how it responds in roll. By closely analyzing the roll momentum and inertia characteristics of the real A321 and incorporating feedback from current Airbus-rated pilots, they have fine-tuned the control laws within the ELAC (Elevator and Aileron Computer). It involved reworking gain schedules and dynamic response parameters to replicate the plane’s roll behavior more accurately across different flight phases and load conditions.  ‍ Furthermore, the update now makes livery-specific EFB Backgrounds a possibility, no longer relying on Airline packs for that. ‍ The complete changelog for the update follows below: Simulator Platform Air Con APU ATSU/AOC CPC Effects EFIS/FCU Engines FAC Flaps FMGC Flight Guidance/ELAC/FM LGCIU/BSCU Fault logic fixed ROPS Sounds Techlog XPDR Others ‍ FSLabs has also briefly teased their upcoming A321neo with a single screenshot of an easyJet livery. The FSLabs A321ceo is available in their store for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
