<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-10-25T18:32:16.314998+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/at346p</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Further Preview A340-600 Pro for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/at346p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f268109616642482fbc026_A340-600_13.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has shared a batch of A340 previews on their Discord, complete with a development brief from community manager Raphael.  Furthermore, the long-haul aircraft is now set to release ahead of Aerosoft’s A330 NEO, which was previously said to release in the Fall of 2025. The previews shared focus on cockpit and cabin progress, with Aerosoft stressing that these are still in an unfinished state, shared for transparency’s sake. Among the highlights is the team’s so-called “sleeping sidestick”, hopefully a bug to be fixed. Colours, wear, and detailing are still being tuned, but the core systems shown are functioning, according to Rafi. Expect more angles in upcoming Friday updates, including exterior modelling. A full showcase is expected closer to launch. For the full update, visit Aerosoft's Discord server. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/idfteft</id>
    <title>IndiaFoxtEcho Details Release of Eurofighter Typhoon for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/idfteft"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f279d78d5d3e162d75db10_560558151_1383010860495397_8443586208946758006_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IndiaFoxtEcho has finally resurfaced with new details on its long-awaited Eurofighter Typhoon for Microsoft Flight Simulator, and this time, there’s a potential release window. In a new post, celebrating the studio’s 10th anniversary, the team confirmed they are now deep into debugging the Typhoon, and “hopefully” preparing it for release in November. The update comes after several months of radio silence, which the team addressed directly, apologising for the lack of news, while reassuring fans that progress has not stalled. According to IndiaFoxtEcho, the Eurofighter is currently being tested by a mix of internal staff and real-world Typhoon pilots. Alongside the Typhoon, IndiaFoxtEcho shared news on a few other projects. Their F-16A, developed in collaboration with Heatblur Simulations, is progressing steadily on the art side and is now targeted for a Q1 2026 release.  The TA-4J remains on hold until the Typhoon is wrapped, while DCS fans can look forward to ongoing work on the G.91 and a maintenance realignment for the MB.339. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/irsa24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Svalbard Longyear Airport for MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/irsa24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f2a81db94686308ced53b0_FlightSimulator2024_qrclJTs70K.png.76d989c52904082979ec1f0bc339d20e.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their newest scenery creation for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, this time heading to the arctic airport of Svalbard Longyearbyen (ENSB). Located at 78 degrees north of the equator, the airport is the northernmost with scheduled passenger service. The first airport on Svalbard was constructed during World War II by the Luftwaffe. After the war, it was taken over by the Norwegian Air Force, who started occasional postal flights. However, operations were tricky due to harsh conditions, and could only operate a few months out of the year. In the 1970s, it was decided that a new airport was needed, so a site was selected near Hotellneset, and construction began in 1973. Svalbard Airport was officially opened on September 2, 1975 with its first flight being operated by SAS. Over the years, the airport has undergone various renovations, with the most recent being an upgrade to the passenger terminal in 2007. Today, the airport serves as a vital link to mainland Norway, with flights to Oslo and Tromso being operated by both SAS and Norwegian. Additionally, there are charter flights to Moscow and Murmansk operated by Arktikugol, a Russian mining company, to serve the mining town of Barentsburg, which has a population primarily consisting of Russian nationals. iniBuilds’ rendition features high-quality textures, detailed building interiors and parallax, recreation of landside areas including the Svalbard Global Seed Vault, custom night lighting, custom static aircraft, and more. Svalbard Airport is available for purchase on the iniBuilds Store for approximately $13.35, requiring at least 2.29GB of disk space. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spehse</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Breda International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spehse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f370f78ef000260bed60bc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimPixel has recently launched its version of Breda International Airport (EHSE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This general aviation aerodrome is located in North Brabant, Netherlands, and features a runway that is 2,723 feet long. Opened in 1949 as a glider field, the airfield was originally named Seppe Airfield. Powered aircraft began flying at the airport in 1969. In 2002, the original grass runway was replaced with an asphalt runway. The airfield does not accommodate aircraft with jet engines. In 2015, the airfield was rebranded from Seppe Airfield to Breda International Airport, following an announcement made in 2014. The ICAO code EHSE remained unchanged. In addition to general aviation traffic, the airfield is home to the Vliegend Museum Seppe, which showcases various aircraft on display. The aviation training company Aviation Performance Solutions is also located at the airfield. The scenery is rich with features like high-resolution textures, custom 3D models, dynamic lighting, detailed interiors, static aircraft, ground vehicles, and much more. The newly released Breda International Airport by SimPixel is now available from iniBuilds for approximately $9.39. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skar24</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases El Edén International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skar24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f3b5179c6322fd2a935041_01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. V Pilot Designs has recently released a rendition of El Edén International Airport (SKAR) for MSFS 2024, building on the new sim’s new lighting, materials, and terrain tech.  Set in Colombia’s coffee region near Armenia, Quindío, the package delivers a custom terminal and tower, accurate runway and taxiway layout, full PBR textures, realistic night lighting, and optimised models with LODs, for smooth performance. The MSFS 2024 edition is a free upgrade for existing MSFS 2020 owners, and it is available now on the in-sim Marketplace. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw771</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Updates PMDG 777 Sound Set for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw771"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f4fc54484fa9e7b6d14ec7_maxresdefault%20(3).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works has recently pushed V1.1.0 of his PMDG 777 Sound Set for MSFS 2020 and 2024.  Included is a complete rework of the GE90-94B buzz on the 777-200ER, improved PW4000 drop-spool behaviour, a fix for missing Rolls-Royce Trent engine idle, refined hydraulic and fan attenuation, a louder APU on the exterior, and added flap, slat, and slat-turbulence effects.  A PDF manual is now also included on the Orbx product page. Here’s the full changelog: ‍ Changelog:  ‍Added a PDF Manual - Refer to manual on product page via ORBX Direct or Central - PLEASE take a look at the recommended settings, try it with those, and adjust to your liking. There are quite a few settings that can totally wreck the sounds ‍ Boris' 777 Sound Set is available via Orbx Direct, retailing for $18.54. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vrspcl</id>
    <title>VeroRoutes Releases Pilot-Controlled Lighting for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vrspcl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f506c41df07feba3065fac_c18f78213210f22cd7973d3b5c92c9d3c4cdba91.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. VeroRoutes has released their Pilot-Controlled Lighting addon for MSFS 2024, a first for the sim, letting you key the mic to control the runway lights.  You do this by tuning the published PCL frequency, clicking your push-to-talk three, five, or seven times within five seconds, and the lights will then spring on for 15 minutes, with low, medium, or high intensity. Coverage is broad, too. The add-on simulates pilot-activated lighting at roughly 4,500 airfields and heliports worldwide, with runway edge, centreline, threshold, and approach systems all modelled.  By default, the field stays dark, and the package can even be driven remotely via SimConnect. You can try it with a free trial, then pick it up from the VeroRoutes website for $23.20, as well as simMarket. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oby1tf</id>
    <title>OBY1 Releases EuroFly Twinfox for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oby1tf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f5129d02f41e1a95877ded_1146d4313cccea75d92c47d9359fb68e71832f3c.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. OBY1 has recently released the EuroFly Twinfox for MSFS 2020 and 2024, bringing one of Italy’s most distinctive ultralights into the simulator. Developed in close cooperation with Eurofly, and tested by real-world pilots, the Twinfox delivers an authentic, short-field flying experience. The cockpit environment has been carefully modelled, and it also includes authentic checklists. You can swap between a glass cockpit and steam gauges on the fly, and the aeroplane also supports VR out of the box.  Bundled with the release is a companion activity pack, too, giving plenty of things to do with the new plane. As always, here is a key feature list: ‍ Aircraft key features: You can get it on the MSFS Marketplace for both MSFS 2020 and 2024. For a handbook and more information on the aircraft, visit the official download page, on OBY1's website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ldeyvi</id>
    <title>Lisium Design Releases Vilnius International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ldeyvi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f682dcb49b25b0048ed07b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Lisium Design has launched its latest scenery package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, featuring Vilnius International Airport, which serves the capital of Lithuania. The airport is located just under four miles from the city center and connects Vilnius to numerous destinations across Europe. Opened in 1932, the airport initially operated only a few commercial flights to various cities. This continued until the outbreak of the Second World War when the airport served as a military airfield until 1944. After the war, a new terminal was constructed, which was completed in 1954. To accommodate an increase in air traffic, a new departure terminal was built in 1993. Another terminal followed in 2007, and yet another was completed this year. Today, the airport is a hub for airBaltic and serves as a focus city for GetJet Airlines, Ryanair, and Wizzair, among others. The airport handles nearly 5 million passengers annually, connecting them to destinations all over Europe. The scenery comes packed with features such as a true-to-life terminal, true-to-life apron layout, detailed custom ground textures, custom lighting, and more. The newly released Vilnius International Airport by Lisium Design is now available on Contrail for $20.19. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/confa50</id>
    <title>Contrail Publishes FA50 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/confa50"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f8b7c1b62b3ca0205fcf2f_fa50-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Contrail has recently shared the development progress on their upcoming FA50 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showcasing their ongoing work on the cabin door, new flight deck textures, and much more. The cabin door is now fully complete, with authentic animations and interior detailing. Furthermore, Contrail has also completed the cockpit texture overhaul. It now features the rather distinctive rough-painted metal finish found in many real FA50s, significantly reducing glare and bringing it one notch closer to reality. Their work in the systems department is going well, thanks to feedback provided by real pilots and mechanics, who helped them capture the aircraft’s true essence, quirks and all. They have also provided a first look at the hydraulics system, demonstrating how the elevator drops to a full nose-down position when hydraulic pressure is lost, making the yoke move fully forward. In contrast, the ailerons only sag ever so slightly and remain that way even when pressure is wholly restored. Once the plane is airborne, of course, the airflow over the wings brings them to a neutral position—or slightly above center—as per real-life behavior. ‍ Contrail says, “more updates are on the way” as their product continues to take shape for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f282310</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s Fokker F28 Professional V2.2 Launches Tomorrow</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f282310"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324a8883ddb907aea4d80_fuk3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight’s long-awaited full revamp and port to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 of their Fokker F28 is set to land soon—tomorrow—entirely free of charge for V1 owners and with a 20% discount for new buyers. While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. ‍ They will also include MSFS 2024’s pre-flight walkaround mode and a new EFB tablet model with a window-mount option. The complete 2.2 changelog will be made available at release time tomorrow. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpa28x12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Piper PA-28-181 Archer III for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpa28x12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f8be44d4d77c506d11a7d8_archer31.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight and Thranda Design have recently released their rendition of the Piper PA-28-181 Archer III for X-Plane 12, following on from their Warrior II as part of their new general aviation aircraft lineup for Laminar Research’s latest simulator. The add-on features a highly accurate rendition of the Piper PA-28-181 Archer III, following comprehensive hands-on research on a real unit - G-CIFY - based at Turweston Airfield in the United Kingdom. It’s a four-seater piston-engine airplane with a four-cylinder 180-horsepower plant, a fixed tricycle landing gear, and a fixed-pitch propeller. It’s one of the most recent PA28 variants to be built, easily seen through its relatively modern and streamlined flight deck design, especially on the overhead. It cruises at 118 knots with a range of nearly 500 miles, making it perfect for touring and flight training. Furthermore, the cockpit features a rich avionics suite with a Garmin GNS 530 GPS unit, a GNC 255 radio, a S-TEC autopilot, HSI, and ADF instruments.  The add-on accompanies six liveries from the USA, Australia, Switzerland, Spain, Germany, and the United Kingdom. Thanks to the dynamic livery EFB app, a near-infinite variety of paint schemes can be created within the simulator. The aircraft sports full PBR texturing in 8K with real-time environment reflections. Additionally, there’s an Electronic Flight Bag tablet with many settings such as aircraft configuration options, panel states, interactive checklists, and more. It’s available on the Just Flight website for $42.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf282255</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates Fokker F28 Professional for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf282255"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324880615470b16ee888a_fuk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently released the long-awaited 2.2 update for their Fokker F28 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and now 2024. The update brings cabin updates, native MSFS 2024 compatibility with pre-flight walkaround support, SimBrief flight plan uplink, and more. ‍ While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. ‍ The MSFS 2024 version also includes the pre-flight walkaround system, making it a native 2024 aircraft.  ‍ The EFB tablet model was revamped, offering a new mounting position (window-mounted), and the airplane now supports SimBrief flight plan uplinks, making the flight planning experience more seamless. The complete changelog follows below: v2.2 - Upgraded to a MSFS 2024 native package (MSFS 2024 only). - Added additional model LODs for improved performance (MSFS 2020/2024) and MSFS 2024 compatibility. - Added Preflight Walkaround support (MSFS 2024 only):     - Chocks/Cones     - GPU     - Passenger and service doors (including airstairs handle, automatic/manual extension and jetway mode)     - Cargo doors     - Enter/exit aircraft - Added SimBrief OFP import functionality to UNS-1 FMS. - Added custom cabin textures to passenger liveries - Added new, modern EFB tablet model (tablet can now be moved between two positions by clicking the top/bottom bezels). - Added Jetway External Power logic - Default and GSX jetways, and GSX GPU, can now supply external power.Buttons on the EFB aircraft app allow for the selection of GPU or jetway power once available, or the overhead panel switch can be used as before. - Added 'AUTO CABIN MUSIC' option to the EFB, allowing you to control whether the cabin crew switch the cabin music on/off. - Added galley hot water handle animation. - Added support for third-party liveries to include livery configuration files. - Fixed EFB Charts and Map apps flickering (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed duplicated pilots appearing on exterior (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed missing copilot (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed copilot not animating with seat - Cockpit seat positions are now locked in MSFS 2024 due to simulator limitation that prevents the pilot characters from moving with them. - Fixed EFB OFP page formatting (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed user aircraft being detected by TCAS when using time compression. - Fixed MSFS 2024 payload initialisation issues when starting C&amp;D (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed RMI dot/cross annunciator logic. - Fixed cockpit window seal flickering. - Fixed autopilot mode selector lighting brightness (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed preflight walkaround collision boxes – It’s no longer possible to walk through parts of the aircraft when in preflight walkaround mode (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed forward galley collision boxes – It’s no longer possible to click through from cockpit to cabin and vice versa, preventing inadvertent selections, e.g. toggling a cockpit switch when trying to toggle a galley switch. - Fixed navigation light effects disappearing at distance (MSFS 2024) - Improved ASI bug logic - dragging of bugs is now possible, bugs interact with each other, and are more accurately set by speeds flipchart. - Improved EFB pushback functionality. - Improved cabin crew callouts triggers during taxi – “Cabin Is Secured” callout will now automatically trigger 5-8 minutes after the doors are closed, simulating the time it takes for a safety briefing and seat belt check. “Cabin Crew Seats For Take-off” logic remains the same, either triggered via the “CABIN CALL” button on the overhead panel when the aircraft is in a take-off state, or automatically during the take-off run. - Improved Audio Selector Panel logic - Reworked for greater accuracy. - Improved Door 1L logic and animation - door up/down buttons are now functional, door can be pushed for manual extension, smoother airstairs animation, improved door/handle animation logic when triggered via EFB. - Moved ‘navdata’ folder externally to the package to comply with MSFS 2024 SDK (Navigraph Hub has been updated to support the new location). - Updated Operations Manual - Updated EFB Manual - Updated UNS-1 Operations Manual ‍ The add-on is available on their store for $55.99 (a temporary 20% discount due to the new update). The original retail price is $69.99. It requires at least 5.3 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sextan</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Tanegashima Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sextan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fca63bfad42ae4c270e28a_shima1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Tanegashima Airport (RJFG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the town of Nakatane on Tanegashima Island in Japan and has a yearly average of 74,633 passengers. It was built roughly 19 years ago to replace the original Tanegashima Airport, which was deemed unsuitable for jet aircraft and geographically impossible to expand from its original length (1500 meters). The Tanegashima Airport was built around 8km from the original, with modern infrastructure and a slightly longer runway (2000 meters). It’s served by J-Air and Japan Air Commuter, with flights to Osaka-Itami, Fukuoka, and Kagoshima. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed terminal, a fully modeled boarding area, custom ground textures, custom runway textures, and more. It’s available in the Marketplace for roughly $12.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gtfa32rl</id>
    <title>GotFriends Releases Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gtfa32rl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fcae8b742352c55c02c91d_vix1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. GotFriends recently released their rendition of the Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen, a Ukrainian two-seat ultralight aircraft first flown in 2014, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The A-32 is built upon the A-22 Foxbat, bringing several improvements and with one significant difference: unlike its “father”, which could be purchased in kit form or fully assembled, it is only available as a kit in the United Kingdom, whereas you can get a factory-built version in 31 other nations. It’s powered by a 100hp Rotax 912ULS engine, allowing it to cruise at 213 km/h with around 4.5 hours of total endurance, carrying only one person. The first prototype was completed in January 2014, and the first production aircraft was showcased in April 2015. The A-32 is still in production today. The add-on features an accurate rendition of the aircraft, featuring a high-detail 3D model, a comprehensive EFB, two flight deck configurations (standard six-pack, glass), and much more. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $25, requiring at least 2.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aes340du2410</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes A340-600 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aes340du2410"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fcb6a013416d3ae2ccbd4a_toe1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has published another A340-600  development update in conjunction with ToLiss Simulation Software, which handles the intricate systems of the long-awaited aircraft. This week’s update goes in depth about the aircraft’s fuel and electric systems and how they differ from the rest of the A320 family due to the extra two engines and the many challenges that come with it, such as the necessity for a fuel transfer system that gets in action during take-off and landing to ensure the center of gravity is within a safe zone. While the fuel transfer isn’t visually demonstrated, it is described by Torsten - ToLiSS founder and CEO -, where it kicks in at different times throughout the flight, especially during the take-off roll and landing to ensure the center of gravity is balanced correctly, and ensuring it also accompanies its respective ECAM message, both for when it starts and for when it’s done transferring. After the halfway mark, they also cover part of the electrics and how they differ from the rest of the family, like the A340 having four generators rather than two—as it is one per engine—offering extra redundancy, and how the APU got its very own battery, just like the A330, so that it doesn’t drain the other batteries when handling the APU startup. There is no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
