<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-08-12T18:28:33.122252+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/berxp11</id>
    <title>Tailstrike Designs and Windsock Simulations Release Airport Bergamo V2 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/berxp11" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62be82382d4ce9926440c797_298773_lime-xp_24.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="307675"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Tailstrike Designs and Windsock Simulations have recently released Airport Bergamo v2 for X-Plane 11. The airport, a leap forward compared to its original version, brings updated terminals, animated jet bridges, and redesigned surrounding details. According to the scenery’s store page, Airport Bergamo v2 will reflect the latest layout of its real life counterpart in 2021, including the new north apron. It will feature high quality PBR textures, custom made signage, and full surrounding details instead of blurry satellite images. 	Additionally, the developers have indicated that scenery will have minimal impact on the performance of the simulators, ensuring that users can have a smooth flying experience. It is recommended that users have at least 4GB of free disk space in order to successfully install the product. 	Currently, the product can be purchased on simMarket or Aerosoft’s webstore for EUR 20.13 or USD 20.91. Owners of Airport Bergamo V1 for X-Plane can purchase the new version for a reduced price of EUR 10.07. Credits to Lazerzen from the Threshold Discord for the news scoop. For more X-Plane news, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jftgr1</id>
    <title>Just Flight Teases Tornado GR1 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jftgr1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62c27b1f3dba37e4dfeccaeb_TOR%203.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="112172"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Last week, Just Flight announced their newest project for Microsoft Flight Simulator - the Tornado GR1. The Tornado GR1, a step up from the developer’s Hawk T1, will bring the perfect experience for pilots looking for the thrill of high speed, low altitude flying. According to the developers, the Tornado GR1 will feature 8k textures and study-level systems. Judging by the pictures provided, the exterior and cockpit of the jet have been completely modeled and textured, including moving parts such as spoilers and reverse thrust buckets. At this stage, no feature list or any additional details have been provided, though the team promised to keep the community updated on the aircraft’s progress.  Tornado GR1, a collaboration between the UK, West Germany, and Italy, is designed to be a multirole military aircraft capable of carrying out a variety of anti-ground, intercepting, and air defense suppression missions. First produced in 1979, different variants of the Tornado saw action in the Gulf War of 1991, “Bosnian War, Kosovo War, Iraq War, in Libya during the 2011 Libyan civil war, as well as smaller roles in Afghanistan, Yemen, and Syria”. Currently, the developers are yet to announce the release date and pricing of the jet aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/togamu</id>
    <title>TOGA Simulations Mitsubishi MU-2 for X-Plane Releasing Friday</title>
    <updated>2022-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/togamu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62cb51008b9d36a2a0dabd84_MU2_2_Release.jpg.827eb705b75f8863126f4fdc7d74a5c6.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="72371"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. A familiar face with an unfamiliar name will be launching the reincarnation of the Mitsubishi MU-2 for X-Plane this week, with Tom Kyler -- most notably of IXEG -- completely overhauling the now 14 year old product. The product's release will coincide with the gazetting of a new name: X-Scenery is no more and will be replaced with TOGA Simulations to better align with the products the brand makes. The Mitsubishi MU-2 has been a prominent fixture on the X-Aviation store since its creation in 2008. In fact, it was the first product ever sold on the platform according to Cameron Son, the store's owner. Speaking on the X-Pilot forum, Son made the following announcement.  "Today, we're officially announcing Friday, July 15, 2022 as the release date for v2 of this great aircraft! This isn't just an update to the existing aircraft! It's an entirely new code base, 3D model and FMOD sound simulation. It is truly a new product." A specific release time was not given, though the American-based company said they're aiming for 'the afternoon on Friday'. Further information is expected in the coming days. There's been no word of a price yet either. This will be unveiled once the product page goes live later this week. Previous customers of the MU-2 can expect a $20 discount on v2, though these coupons will only be available for 60 days.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swkodi</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Details Kodiak Improvements</title>
    <updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swkodi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62cca56fadaf9474154325e2_293382350_4845411982231640_3219375507246419653_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="360957"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Software house SimWorks Studios have come forward today with more information on a large-scale update to their Quest Kodiak 100 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The details were shared via Facebook, with today's update focusing primarily on the handling characteristics of the aircraft. "Here is an update on the Kodiak packages. A big flight model update was delivered to us this past week, which will improve the response of the aircraft," the team wrote on social media. "Many people complained that the plane was very sensitive to pitch input, something we attributed to the short travel that most desktop yokes have." "After a long time of tweaking and balancing, the next update will improve this aspect of the Kodiak's handling." The new flight model also rectifies the Kodiak's performance, giving a more accurate reflection of the American aircraft after Sim Update 8 left the high-wing somewhat underpowered. The amphibian edition of the Kodiak is also seeing some nice progress according to the developer, even given "MSFS' flight model limitations" in this area. Before release, the aircraft will see some last fine tuning and get a sign off from Quest's parent company Daher. Speaking of a release window, SimWorks have said that both the wheeled Kodiak update and new Amphibian variant should be coming out after Sim Update 10 launches in mid- to late-August. This is to take advantage of new features coming in that update. See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff7640</id>
    <title>FlightFactor 767-400ER Available in Public Beta</title>
    <updated>2022-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff7640" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62cf2a393106e73d388c9423_FXJcDpeXwAAI9pU.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="602496"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The most recently released real-world variant of the Boeing 767 is now available for X-Plane courtesy of FlightFactor.  First launched in 2000, the -400ER shares a common type rating with other 767 models as well as 757 variants, though in cockpit form is much closer to Boeing's 777 with six displays arranged in the same way as the larger widebody. Today's beta release coincided with a number of other improvements for the 767 series as a whole. These include: FlightFactor are retailing the 767-400ER at $79.00 USD with a $69.00 USD launch price for the time being, whereas owners of other 767 variants can upgrade for $30.00 USD.  The developer recently released this chart to show the upgrade options available for the 767. It's important to note that even though the -400ER is able to be purchased, the developers makes it clear that this is a public beta and issues are to be expected. Purchase the standalone 767-400ER from the X-Plane.org Store here, or upgrade at this link here.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mktene</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Tenerife Airports Package</title>
    <updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mktene" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62d07c3acce12651ea70bfb0_Microsoft-Flight-Simulator-2022-06-16-10_14_13-PM-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="395337"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Polish scenery creator MK Studios has launched two new airports today, with both North and South Tenerife Airports (GCXO and GCTS respectively) combined into one scenery package. For previous simulator platforms, such as Prepar3D version 5, the developer opted to sell the airports separately. "Welcome to Tenerife, the largest and most populous island of the Canary Islands," reads the product description. "The island of Tenerife has two airports: the Tenerife North Airport (or Los Rodeos) and Tenerife South Airport (or Reina Sofia). The south airport is situated in a tourist area, and therefore is the busiest, having hundreds of connections to different parts of the world. Tenerife North Airport operates mostly domestic flights between the islands of the archipelago." "In this package, we recreated these two airports, GCTS and GCXO, and added a few POIs with custom satellite images and mesh." The aerodrome pair package includes the following features: You can purchase MK Studios' Tenerife for EUR 15.99 from simMarket or $23.95 AUD (approx. US$16.19 | €16,14 | £13.68) from OrbxDirect.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf75du</id>
    <title>JustFlight Releases 757 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf75du" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62e089371f1b929e4177e29d_757_1_eGcsHo811.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="117254"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. On 22th of July 2022, they announced they had advanced the work on the VC animations, the FMS, and the flight dynamics. As for the external model, they work mainly on the landing gear. There were no other changes on the textures, as other exterior details are still to be finalized. The flight model has also been developed, but it is unknown to what extent. The developers simply say that there is still a lot of work to be done on this aspect. This update primarily adresses the modelling of the FMS and the programming of its various components. As per the update, the developer states that the VC animations 90% complete, although the devs then state that many switches still need to be integrated. Readdressing the FMS, the devs strongly emphasize the priority the FMS has in development. Once the FMS is complete, other systems will be worked on and addressed. If you are interested in reading the full update for yourself, you may view it on JustFlight's website. The work is still in progress, and no release date has been announced yet. Threshold will keep you updated on any futher updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wxrff</id>
    <title>When X-Plane Fights Real Forest Fires </title>
    <updated>2022-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wxrff" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62e5e773660fbc7c7fb8e87f_screenshot-2022-07-18-183624.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="689898"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Bridger Aerospace, a real-life firefighting company, is now using VR simulation to train its pilots to fly in complex conditions, like flying low to put out a forest fire. The simulator they will be using? X-Plane. During real life training, it is impossible to accurately reproduce the conditions of wildfires pilots will be expected to put out. Only simulation and virtual reality can realistically recreate such extreme conditions. On top of this, pilots can even train in the same virtual aircraft using the “shared cockpit” model from completely different locations - drastically increasing training efficiency and reducing overall cost.  Pretoria Engineering, a real life group of engineers from the University of Astoria, are designing the plug-in for X-Plane 12. When completed, it will integrate Bridger’s aircraft with the ability to fly ultra realistic aerial firefighting missions. Such an integration of X-Plane into pilot training programs is proof that flight simulation is so much more than a video game - it is capable of not only fulfilling the dream of aviation enthusiasts but also playing a critical role in the training of pilots for an array of possible scenarios they may encounter in real life. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/isksat</id>
    <title>iniScene Releases San Antonio International Airport (KSAT) for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/isksat" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62e8aafd01b8ef5c147880c3_27_7688d03f-f9ff-4d27-af38-5e6967700133.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="156716"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Last week, developer iniScene released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator - San Antonio International Airport (KSAT). The airport, crafted with “with unparalleled attention to details”, will feature everything from custom ground decals to 30cm/px satellite imagery that utilizes the latest MSFS SDK. According to developers, KSAT will feature hand-made ground polyones for every surface from runways to aprons, custom made signages, vegetation, and car models, PBR textures, and terminal interiors.  ‍ Additionally, the airport will be integrated with dynamic ground handling vehicles. The product will first come with a custom pushback tug with more vehicles being added in future updates. To view the entire feature list, visit the developer’s website. Currently, the scenery can be purchased on the iniScene webstore for $20.06 USD. To successfully install the product, the developers recommend users to have at least 6.61GB of free space on their hard drive. For more MSFS news, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc12ca</id>
    <title>Carenado Publishes PC-12 Screenshots</title>
    <updated>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc12ca" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62e8ae7cfa7f39830db544f5_292071041_5216927795050659_1988621114253456010_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="66362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has recently showcased various screenshots of their upcoming visual rendition of the Pilatus PC-12 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This comes after a period of tight-lipped silence from the developers. Carenado did express an apologetic state, as they have experienced unexpected delays in the release of this aircraft to the public. They do hope to surpass these setbacks and move forward with the release aircraft. In the screenshots posted to their Facebook page, they showcased working GTNXi by TDS, and the in-house EX600 Suite. With these operational, Carenado hopes to move forward with development and an eventual release. Be sure to follow Threshold for more updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t208gc</id>
    <title>Thranda Releases Free Expansion Pack for C208 Grand Caravan</title>
    <updated>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t208gc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62eb32157b64ff81adee4fa2_unknown.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="277119"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Last week, developer Thranda announced via the X-Plane forum the release of a new expansion pack for its C208 and C208B Grand Caravan. The best part: this pack is completely free and can be downloaded from the X-Plane.org store! The feedback on the forum is very positive. Users seem to be delighted with this free and well-developed initiative. But what exactly does this pack contain? First of all a seaplane version of the Grand Caravan equipped with floats. ‍ For the landplane version, the pack offers tundra tires and mud flaps, enabling operations in rough terrains. The package also offers changes to the interior of the aircraft such as an integrated G1000. The seats will also be removable via presets, allowing the aircraft to serve either as a passenger or cargo plane. These features will be available for both the amphibious and landplane models. Currently, users who already purchased the plane can download the expansion pack together with the new version. Those who are looking to pick up the aircraft can purchase it on the X-Plane.org store for $44.95, ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jff28u</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker F28 Fellowship Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jff28u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ec9b05681fa0dbd328e67a_1000_Air_France_srxkHMBHR.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="89426"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer Just Flight published a brief update for its upcoming Fokker F28 Fellowship for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The short blog focused on the work being done on the aircraft’s interior modeling/texturing and cockpit lighting. Announced just over a year ago, Just Flight’s Fokker F28 has seen extensive work being done on it over the past few months. Since the last update, the developers have been making “extensive upgrades to the cockpit”. Due to the great variations in cockpit design that exist between the F28 variants operated by different airlines, the team chose to base their design on the real F28 they visited in Fokker Technical College. With the layout finalized, the developers are working to improve the visual fidelity of the cockpit while testers, including  “F28 flight, engineering, and training crew”, are checking and rechecking every detail. Apart from cockpit modeling, progress has also been made in cockpit lighting. Just Flight has included a few pictures in the update to showcase the night lighting of the Fokker’s instruments, annunciator, and warning lights. Currently, Just Flight is yet to announce the release date and pricing of the aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Shout out to Joe from the official Threshold Discord server for the news scoop. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniadu</id>
    <title>iniScene Publishes August Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniadu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f09df44826b824a9cb2609_Screen%20Shot%202022-08-08%20at%201.23.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2821738"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer iniScene published its development update for the month of August. The brief blog touched upon the team’s plan for the coming weeks and unveiled two new sceneries - Ibiza Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator (LEIB) and Buffalo Airport (KBUF) for X-Plane. 	Starting off the update, the developer announced Ibiza Airport for MSFS and confirmed that the scenery will be available for purchase later this month. Though the team is yet to release further details on the airport, it can be seen from the trailer that it will feature everything from terminal interiors and PBR textures to animated vegetation and custom night lighting. ‍ 	Apart from Ibiza, the developer also announced Buffalo Airport for X-Plane. The scenery will feature hand-made ground polygons, realistic ground equipment, and dynamic lighting, and high quality textures. iniScene confirmed that the airport will be fully compatible with upcoming X-Plane 12 and teased that a few more X-Plane scenarios will be released later this year.  Currently, the developers are yet to announce a firm release date for either Ibiza or Buffalo airport. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. Shout out to MJ from the official Threshold Discord for the news scoop.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfosfd</id>
    <title>ShortFinal Design Releases KSFO Definitive for XP11</title>
    <updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfosfd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f09d0e1ca43f55577d226d_a350_xp11%20-%202022-08-04%2013.25.45.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="238302"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Known developer for X-Plane 11, ShortFinal Design (aka MisterX6) has released his long-awaited KSFO Definitive Project for X-Plane 11. With many updates from the previous rendition, this visual rendition of San Francisco International impresses one and all, with new techniques used by the developer. MisterX6 released his first and only freeware rendition of KSFO back in 2015, and it underwent updates till he moved to payware projects. Since then, the San Francisco area received no love from developers, till SFD announced he was revisiting the area and had started from scratch on the project. This rendition has a vast inclusion list that has been provided. Starting off, the usage of SAM for jetways and airport operations has been used to add realism and life to the airport. The airport layout shipped is the current layout of KSFO as of 2022. Various animations of airport vehicles, workers, and passengers have also been included. The usage of PBR textures is present throughout the scenery package. For the complete feature list, you can view it on the X-Plane.Org Store This rendition of KSFO is now available on the .Org Store and sells for $26.95. If you are interested in other packages developed by ShortFinal Design, you can view his payware catalog on the .Org Store as well. If you are interested in his freeware catalog, you can have a look over on his forum page.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc12ca2</id>
    <title>Carenado Finishes PC12 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc12ca2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f68cc569f22508515e2486_298795014_5315779201832184_7004121334989087429_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="303487"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has announced that development work and testing are complete on their upcoming PC12, meaning that it is now ready to fly under the command of virtual pilots! The aircraft has been a long-awaited addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator and from what we can see visually in the teasers, it looks stunning.  In a recent press release on their Facebook page, the developers said: “dear friends, we are very happy to inform you that the PC12 project was finished and handed over to Microsoft to be uploaded to the simulator marketplace, Microsoft recently told us that this will happen in the first days of September, we appreciate all the shows of support and understanding setbacks in the development of this project, thank you all very much and we hope you have fun with this wonderful plane!” Judging by the post, it looks like fans of Carenado and the PC12 can expect to take off for the first time in the Pilatus early in September.  Though the developers are yet to announce a precise release date for the PC12, it is certain that we only have a few more weeks to wait! Threshold will keep you updated on any news regarding the aircraft. For now, check out a previous article on the PC12  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inikbuf</id>
    <title>iniScene release Buffalo Niagara KBUF scenery for X-Plane 11 </title>
    <updated>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inikbuf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62f68e8e7904d06ceed85d21_22_24069982-7921-4e4f-b57a-28f78a2b1b40.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="555864"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has released its anticipated Buffalo Niagara scenery for X-plane 11. KBUF is located in Buffalo New York, the airport serves Buffalo and the surrounding area, as well as the southern golden horseshoe region of Ontario Canada. Interestingly KBUF is the third busiest airport in New York. It serves as a hub for; United Airlines, American Airlines, Delta, Jet Blue, and various other airlines on top of being a relatively large hub for FedEx Express and UPS.  The developers have teased that the scenery boasts  You can find the full feature list for KBUF here Currently, Buffalo Niagara Airport is available for the reasonable price of £16.99 on the iniScene Store. The developers recommend users to have at least 2.94GB of free space on their hard drives to successfully install the product. Be sure to follow Threshold for more updates on the latest scenery and aircraft for MSFS and X-plane 11.</summary>
    <published>2022-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
