<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-05-12T18:20:57.047473+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navcha</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates SimBrief with Charts Integration</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navcha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6453e8611180cdeb8b3e374c_navi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="151885"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Navigraph has recently added a brand new feature to their SimBrief flight planner: Navigraph Charts are now available within their flight planner with four different map layers.   Navigraph Ultimate users can toggle their charts within SimBrief, with four options: High IFR, Low IFR, VFR, and World Map. To do so, click on the Navigraph icon in the top right corner of the map (displayed on New/Edit Flight and View Flight Plan page), and then a dropdown list will appear with the aforementioned options.   Users without the Ultimate subscription will only get the default style map. The Ultimate plan is available on Navigraph’s website for $9.92/mo or $89.98/yr.   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rotm80</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-80 Pro for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rotm80" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6453f1ceec32760b1d3f19d9_rotate1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="110433"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate recently released their rendition of the McDonnell Douglas MD-80 for X-Plane 12 under a beta program.  The MD-80 Pro for X-Plane 12 aims to deliver a precise flight model and fine-tuned engine performance, developed with advice and counseling from real MD-80 pilots.  The features include a custom flight management system with SIDs and STARs, custom LNAV and VNAV, take-off and approach speed management, custom navigation display, complete HOLD functionality with entry pattern calculation and present POS, a detailed simulation of systems with WX/TCAS, an accurate PW-JT8D-219 model with its intricacies, advanced electrical and hydraulics systems, and realistic visuals with PBR texturing, accurate animations, rain and ice windshield effects, VR compatibility, and custom sounds.  The MD-80 is a twin-engine, medium-range jet airliner designed and manufactured by McDonnell Douglas. It was first introduced in 1980 and quickly became a popular choice for airlines worldwide due to its fuel efficiency and reliability. It was a shortened version of the earlier DC-9 airliner, which had been in production since the 1960s. McDonnell Douglas updated the design of the DC-9, incorporating more modern technology, such as advanced avionics and more efficient engines, to create the MD-80.  Despite its popularity, its production eventually ended in 1999 when Boeing acquired McDonnell Douglas. However, many MD-80s are still in service today, particularly in countries with developing aviation industries.  It’s available on X-Plane.Org for $59.95. Owners of the X-Plane 11 version are entitled to a discounted upgrade ($24.95).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/agsbur</id>
    <title>AG Sim Releases Burgas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/agsbur" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64550a051ed2d0d98d301b13_burgas1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="727378"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AG Sim has recently released their rendition of Burgas Airport (LBBG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 2nd busiest airport in Bulgaria with a yearly average of 2,885,000 passengers. The first landing strip was built in 1912 by the Bulgarian Army during the Balkan War. This airfield was used for military purposes during World War I and II. After the war ended, it was also used for civilian purposes. ‍ In the 1960s, a new modern airport was built on the old airfield site, officially opened in 1970. The airport had a single runway and a small terminal building at the time. It served as an essential transportation hub for Bulgaria's Black Sea coast, and it played a significant role in the country's tourism industry. During the 1980s and 1990s, the airport underwent significant renovations and expansions, including the construction of a new terminal building, a second runway, and improved navigation and air traffic control systems. These upgrades allowed the airport to accommodate larger aircraft and more passengers, becoming a major gateway to the country for tourists from all over Europe. In the 2000s, the airport continued to expand and modernize. In 2013, a new terminal building was opened, increasing the airport's capacity to more than 2.7 million passengers annually.  The airport's traffic is primarily seasonal, with many airlines coming over to visit during the summer: Aer Lingus, airBaltic, BH Air, Bluebird Airways, Bulgaria Air, Buzz, Corendon Dutch Airlines, easyJet, Enter Air, European Air Charter, Eurowings, Freebird Airlines Europe, GetJet Airlines, Jet Time, Jet2.com, LOT Polish Airlines, Luxair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, SkyUp, SmartLynx Airlines, Smartwings, Sunclass Airlines, Sundair, TUI Airways, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Netherlands, TUI fly Nordic, Windrose Airlines, and Wizzair (the only one with a year-long route to London Luton). The scenery accurately represents the airport's terminal, runway, taxiways, and surroundings, with custom ground textures, PBR materials, dynamic apron objects, and realistic night lighting.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $15.49, requiring at least 1.60GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sdeflo</id>
    <title>S-Design Releases Florø Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sdeflo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645512a778f7b09cd6542422_flo1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3440809"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. S-Design has recently released their rendition of Florø Airport (ENFL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the town of Florø in Vestland, Norway. The yearly average sits at around 200,000 passengers as of 2014.  The airport opened in 1971 with three other regional airports in Norway. Back then, it was served by Wideroe with de Havilland Canada Twin Otters until 1994, when Coast Air took over. Danish Air Transport took over briefly between 2003 and 2012 when Wideroe made their glorious return.   Avinor, the airport owner, has plans to eventually expand the airport, which still uses its first terminal from 1971, considered small by today’s standards. They also consider a potential runway extension from 1,700m to 2,000 meters, allowing bigger aircraft to operate at the airport. The major implication, though, would be the cost: 200 million kroner, and the amount of work it would imply, as it would require lots of flattening and landfilling.   It is served by three airlines: Bristow Helicopters (Deepsea Stavanger, Gjøa, Snorre A and B, Visund), DAT (Oslo), and Widerøe (Bergen).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-definition hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, 20cm aerial imagery, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, and 4K PBR texturing.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.17, requiring at least 621.32MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!     ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/netgue</id>
    <title>NetDesign Releases In Guezzam Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/netgue" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6456a359d537e89d2831bfc9_datg1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1697928"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NetDesign has recently released their rendition of In Guezzam Airport (DATG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a regional civilian and military airport in Algeria, right on the border with Niger.   Guezzam Airport was built in the early 1970s, primarily as a military airport. However, it has also been developed to serve commercial air traffic in the years since. Today, the airport mainly serves domestic flights within Algeria but also has international connections to other African countries, such as Niger and Mali.  The airport has a single runway that measures 2,200 meters in length and is equipped with modern navigational aids. The passenger terminal building is relatively small but provides all the essential services travelers require, including check-in counters, baggage handling facilities, and a small selection of shops and restaurants.  Due to its location in the Sahara Desert, Guezzam Airport can experience extreme weather conditions, including sandstorms and high temperatures. As such, travelers need to check weather conditions and plan their trips accordingly.  In addition to its role as a transportation hub, Guezzam Airport is also strategically important for military purposes. The airport is located near Algeria's borders with Niger and Mali, which have experienced security challenges in recent years due to the presence of armed extremist groups.   The scenery aims to faithfully recreate the airport based on the few available photos and satellite imagery, with a basic terminal, control tower, and an Algerian military base. It features 4K PBR textures, a VOR approach with the official airport chart included, detailed sandy sidewalks, realistic night lighting, and performance-friendly optimization.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.00, requiring at least 242.62 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnancy</id>
    <title>France VFR Releases Metz-Nancy-Lorraine Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnancy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6456b0500ecf7b713408630a_nan1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="264175"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. France VFR has recently released their rendition of Metz-Nancy-Lorraine (LFJL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Lorraine region of France with a yearly average of 250,000 passengers. The airport opened in October 1991, replacing Nancy-Essey and Metz-Frescaty, sporting modern infrastructure and supporting the region’s economic growth and development. In 2006, the airport underwent upgrades, with the runway being lengthened to 3,050 meters, along with refurbishing work on the terminal, built in the 90s. It’s 7500 square meters large, with 14 check-in desks, two gates, and two luggage claim belts.  It’s served by Air Algerie (Algiers, Constantine, Oran), TUI fly Belgium (seasonally), and Twin Jet (Marseille, Toulouse).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, photo-realistic 3D buildings, realistic night lighting, multiple charts provided, and custom vegetation. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.09, requiring at least 280.75 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mx6bos</id>
    <title>MisterX6 Updates Boston Logan International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mx6bos" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6459ce0b4e1a000ede9da7b1_bosx1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1376413"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. MisterX6 has recently updated their rendition of General Edward Lawrence Logan International Airport (KBOS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the busiest airport in the Northeastern United States outside the New York Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 42 million passengers as of 2019.  Opened almost a hundred years ago in September 1923, it was mainly used by the Air National Guard of Massachusetts and the United States Army Air Corps. Scheduled passenger service started in 1927 with Colonial Air Transport, flying people between Boston and New York City.  The airport had its first expansion during the 1940s and 1950s when the rise in demand for air travel forced the operator to increase its area size through landfills in Boston Harbor. In that same decade, the terminals were expanded, with Terminals B and C being constructed in 1949, still in use in 2023.   Shortly after WW2, Boston became a transatlantic gateway. American Overseas Airlines offered a weekly Boston-Shannon-London service in the late 40s, Pan Am’s direct flight to Shannon and Santa Maria Island in the Azores, then to London and Lisbon. In the early 50s, BOAC started nonstop operations from Glasgow, and Air France made a multi-stop link from Paris-Orly to Boston. By 1957, there were 49 weekday departures on average.  In the 70s, with the advent of jet aircraft, the routes multiplied: Pan Am started a daily service to London Heathrow with the legendary 747-400, and the daily traffic average skyrocketed. Such a boom forced the airport to grow even further, with the newly built Terminal E (1974) becoming the second-largest international arrivals facility in the United States.   Nowadays, Boston Logan International Airport has four terminals with 102 gate positions in total and six runways.   It’s a hub for Cape Air and Delta Air Lines, the latter holding 19% of the market share, with JetBlue taking the lead at 30.08%, and American Airlines is third with 18.54%, followed by United (10.42%) and Southwest (4.65%). Washington, DC, is the busiest national destination with 769,000 passengers, followed by Chicago-O’Hare (717,000) and Orlando (678,000). The international top three comprises London Heathrow (664,886), Dublin (346,232), and Paris Charles de Gaulle (326,184).   The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with animated airport vehicles and ship traffic, animated marshallers and jetways, custom ground textures for taxiways and runways, photoscenery for the airport and surrounding area, lots of Boston landmarks, and now compatible with X-Plane 12.  It’s free on X-Plane.org, requiring at least 495 MB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to agonyair for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jarcop</id>
    <title>JarDesign Teases CoPilot Addon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jarcop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a8e87642f0702c8abdedc_linda1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2315905"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. J. A. Romanov, JARDesign's owner/developer, has recently published a short video on his YouTube channel teasing his upcoming CoPilot Addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which aims to add a realistic First Officer model in the cabin that can execute multiple tasks. According to the developer, it consists of an animated copilot object and a WASM module, combining speech simulation, speech recognition, a systems engine based on visual avionics, and more.  The video demonstrates the copilot's behavior on multiple aircraft, executing different cabin flows, chatting with the developer, and following checklists. Due to its config file dependent nature, it should theoretically work with any aircraft as long as someone sets it up properly. They claim to be still working on it, with no information regarding pricing or availability yet.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lamx12</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Publishes Short Term Roadmap for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lamx12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a93759cd41b66f42251dd_xp1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="1906242"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has recently published a new short-term roadmap for X-Plane 12, delineating the next steps for versions 12.05 and 12.06.   With every 12.0X release, they aim to stabilize the product, complete or tune planned features, and improve performance. Since the early access release in late 2022, they have been working on maximizing X-Plane 12’s potential and overall experience with many bug fixes, improved AMD card performance, NOAA weather processing, and more.  For version 12.05, which is currently in Release Candidate, they plan to improve the A330 flight experience with a fully custom MCDU, autopilot, and flight systems. Based on real pilot feedback, the simulator’s flight model was also improved, better matching the real world.   In the near future, 12.06 will deliver the result of three months worth of rendering engine improvements, according to their claim, with new cirrus clouds, lower VRAM use, improved cloud rendering in general, and OpenXR integration for VR folks.  It will also bring several ATC/AI improvements, with AI aircraft behaving more realistically, better conveying the experience of flying close to other aircraft.   Even further ahead, they have already made plans for 12.07, which should focus on improving lighting, water mixed render targets, networking fixes, atmospheric scattering, turbine engine improvements, and more.  There’s no release date for the updates yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbw380</id>
    <title>FlyByWire Simulations Teases A380X’s Wing Flex </title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbw380" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a9a77a5d90f86407e360f_wing1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1193830"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyByWire Simulations recently published a YouTube video showcasing the wing flex physics of their upcoming Airbus A380 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With each wing weighing around 50 tons and up to 150 tons when loaded with fuel, it’s far from the average wing out there, meaning the developers had to develop an entirely new wing flex system from scratch, correctly simulating the bending of the wing along its entire length, with varying resonance. They also state how each fuel tank has its mass and position in the wing, affecting the physics and increasing the complexity of such simulation. The work is still in progress, and the developers aim to bring a result as close to the real thing as possible. The A380 is a double-deck, widebody commercial airliner produced by Airbus. It’s the largest passenger airliner in the world, with a seating capacity of up to 853 passengers in a single-class configuration or 544 passengers with a typical three-class layout. It was designed to address the increasing demand for air travel while providing a fuel-efficient and eco-friendly option for long-haul journeys powered by four engines (either a Rolls-Royce Trent 900 or the General Electric GP7200), with a range of up to 8000 nm. Despite its impressive features, the A380 faced several challenges in the commercial market. Its high price tag, maintenance costs, and the increasing popularity of smaller, more fuel-efficient aircraft led to lower demand for the A380. In February 2019, Airbus announced that it would stop producing the A380 after delivering its final orders in 2021. There’s no information regarding a potential release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asoat4</id>
    <title>Asobo Studio Updates ATR 42-600/72-600 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asoat4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645aa804ff8b15fa42c6acc2_genista1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3363772"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Asobo Studio has recently released an update to their Expert Series I: ATR 42-600/72-600 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing multiple fixes and improvements. Update 1.0.8 is the first update for the ATR lineup, smoothing VNAV flight path calculation, fixing multiple CTDs, EWD Alerts Overflow behavior improvements, slight flight model tweaks, and much more. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ The ATR 42-600 is a twin-engine, high-wing turboprop seating up to fifty passengers, introduced in late 2012. It’s an updated ATR 42, the initial combined effort between Airbus and Leonardo in the 1980s. The “42” came from the original seat count.  The ATR 72-600 is a relatively stretched version of the ATR 42-600 with a seating configuration ranging from 70 to 78 seats, with a range of 850 miles, and cruising at 320 miles per hour. The ATR Bundle is available on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $19.99, with a 30% discount for deluxe/premium deluxe owners. Images are courtesy of adam and genista. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbsth</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases St Helens Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbsth" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645aad6209fbf947772f465a_sth1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3233889"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of St Helens Airport (YSTH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a small regional airport serving the town of St Helens on the northeast coast of Tasmania, Australia.   In 1933, a local pilot named Bill Knight began using a small airstrip in St Helens for his flying activities. This airstrip was located on private land and was only suitable for small aircraft. However, it became popular with local pilots, who began using it for recreational flying.  Nowadays, it’s primarily used for transporting fresh seafood - one of St Helens’ economic fortes - to the Australian mainland. Scenic flights also take place in St Helens occasionally, showcasing the wonders of the Tasmanian east coast to everyone interested.  The scenery is developed by Ken Hall, featuring photorealistic textures, custom vegetation, and custom edge lights.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $5.41, requiring at least 744.70 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcrejet</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcrejet" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645c091641f287c65c43e439_E-JETS_FAMILY_BY_X-CRAFTS_E175_006.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="128662"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts have released their updated E-Jets Family for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. This release follows their older E-Jets and ERJ products. This new version of the E-Jets family covers the E170, E175, E190, and E195 models. The aircraft is a complete rebuild of its original E-Jets family featuring a new authentic FMS and all-new systems.  The E-Jets family is a collection of regional jets from the Brazilian aircraft manufacturer Embraer. The E170/175 has become wildly popular on short routes in the 70-seat American regional market. The E170/175 Features a range of around 2100 NM while the larger E190/195 jet features a range of 2300 NM. The larger E190/195 has become popular with many larger airlines to serve routes with medium demand.  The X-Crafts E-Jets family has a large feature list including an authentic FMS, systems that closely simulate the real aircraft, a custom EFB, and custom FMOD sounds. The aircraft comes compatible with both X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12 and utilizes SkunkCrafts Auto Updater. Other features include: Systems &amp; Autopilot Avionics Flight Model FMS Electronic Flight Bag ‍ The aircraft is available from the X-Plane Store with many options to choose from, users can purchase each model individually or as a complete package with all four models. Customers of the X-Crafts E-Jets 2.5 are eligible for a 15% discount on the full family package only. As always stay tuned to Threshold for more news. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/100btu</id>
    <title>OneHundred Simulations Releases Tucuruí Regional Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/100btu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645d4c0da28b72251e7164bf_sbtu1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="883648"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. OneHundred Simulations has recently released their rendition of Tucuruí Regional Airport (SBTU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Tucuruí in Pará, Brazil.  Recently renovated, the airport got the green light to operate commercial flights in 2021 after a decade of inactivity. It was closed in 2015 because its infrastructure was deemed improper for any commercial operations, creating a significant hassle for the locals who depended heavily on the airport.   A hydroelectric plant nearby (Usina Hidroelétrica de Tucuruí) also weighed a lot on the decision to reactivate the airport, given they would have no way to get aerial rescue without an operating landing strip. On top of that, when the city’s hospital had to transfer patients to a bigger city, they had to drive for over 8 hours. It was judicially reopened in November 2021.  The airport is relatively modest, with a 2,000-meter runway and a single passenger terminal, albeit with all the required bits for commercial operation.  It’s served by Azul Conecta, with daily C208 flights to Val de Cans International Airport (SBBE).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Tucuruí Regional, with custom 3D objects, high-detailed textures, realistic ground layout, PBR texturing, and custom ground textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $8.75, requiring at least 45.79 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spcapa</id>
    <title>SDProjectsCO Releases Apartadó Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spcapa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645d538e87d941955234366e_apa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="757137"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SDProjectsCO has recently released their rendition of Antonio Roldán Betancur Airport (SKLC), serving the town of Apartadó in Antioquia, Colombia, with a yearly average of 210,000 passengers.  The airport was named after Antonio Roldán Betancur, a Colombian politician who served as Governor of Antioquia in the late 1980s. The airport was built in the late 1960s to early 1970s, primarily to serve the needs of the local population and to facilitate the transportation of goods and people in and out of the region.  The airport had a single dirt runway and elementary facilities in the early years. Over time, the runway was paved, and a small terminal building was constructed. However, the airport remained relatively small and basic, serving mainly as a regional airport with limited flights to other cities in Colombia.  In recent years, the airport has seen some improvements and expansions. In 2014, the runway was extended to accommodate larger aircraft and the terminal building was renovated and expanded to improve passenger comfort and service. The airport now has a modern terminal building with check-in counters, waiting areas, and other amenities.  EasyFly serves it with a route to Medellín - Olaya Herrera, and SATENA with two routes: Bogotá and Medellín - Olaya Herrera.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail 3D model of the main terminal, PBR texturing, custom night lighting, custom ground textures, a true-to-life airport layout, and custom ground clutter.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.95, requiring at least 123.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aau2be</id>
    <title>Working Title Releases Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 2 Beta for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aau2be" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645de8a72d16b421bb8457b4_scot1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3587664"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Working Title has recently released the first beta patch of the Aircraft &amp; Avionics Update 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing issues with the Garmins (G3000, G5000, GNS430W, and GNS530W), bringing a complete overhaul of the avionics on the Boeing 787-10 and 747-8i, and more.   The highlight of the update is the overhaul on the default Boeings, bringing accurate fonts, look, functionality, and feel, with advanced flight plan support, integrated checklists on the MFD, performance-based VNAV with idle descent capabilities, RNP/ANP indications, functional GPS and IRS navigation systems, fully featured autopilot with autoland, flare, and rollout modes, a fully featured autothrottle system with correct AT modes, and much more.  The 787-10 also gets a revised soundscape, a HUD overhaul with nearly all real-world symbology, and a brand new fly-by-wire system accurately replicating the real-life counterpart.   They have also made sure to list some limitations, including the lack of an EFB on the 787 for performance calculations, the pedestal CDU on the 747 mirrors the left CDU for performance reasons, and issues with the electrical and fuel system on the 747. The complete list of known issues accompanies the changelog below:  Garmin G3000 / G5000 Garmin GNS430W / GNS530W ‍ WT21 ‍ ‍ Boeing 787-10 / Boeing 747-8i ‍ Cessna Citation Longitude ‍ Daher TBM 930 ‍ If you want to learn how to install the beta branch, please refer to the official guide here. Images are courtesy of SCOTSGOD. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
