<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-03-25T18:23:06.673580+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhr310</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates London Heathrow Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhr310"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fc81989f110d42f89564c5_lhr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing ground service equipment positions, fixing issues, and improving overall performance. Version 3.1.0 divides terminal 3 into three smaller sections to improve performance, reduces GSE textures, brings positional fixes for ground service equipment, fixes jetway clipping issues, and more. The complete changelog follows below: - T3 model divided into smaller sections to reduction per-mesh tri count (fix for model not showing on xbox) - Some tweaking of GSE positions - Reduced GSE textures - Incorrectly scale stairs removed - Various jetway/wing clipping issues - Missing taxiline on 27L - C1 checkpoint labelled as D1 on taxi sign - Wrong/missing Taxiway signs - Floating geo Stand 311 - GSE building clipping - Various jetways not dropping low enough to meet a/c door - Layout modified to prevent departing traffic from joining 09L via AB12 and backtracking. AB12 is now no longer available to AI aircraft. - Adjusting some markings intensity - Replaced all frequencies with custom (via chart). Default (non-NG) has tower and ground on the same freq. - Helipad Lights missing - Jetways disconnected from terminal - various locations - Misplaced buildings overlapping parking - Added lighting to cargo area - Added spawn parking and full taxi paths to remote parking/maintenance areas - Added custom lighting to fuel depot near cargo area The scenery is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.27 (on sale), requiring at least 5.67 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/entx12</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Tromsø Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/entx12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fc86444d31b71ab24c45c9_tromso1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of Tromsø Airport (ENTC) for X-Plane 12, serving the municipality of Tromsø with a yearly average of 2 million passengers. It opened in 1964, replacing a water aerodrome that used to be Tromsø’s “airport.” It quickly became Widerøe’s primary hub for their regional flights to Finnmark and an important domestic destination for SAS, Braathens SAFE, and Norwegian Air Shuttle. Within a decade of its inauguration, the original terminal was already suffering from overcapacity, leading to the construction of a new passenger terminal in 1977. It still exists as terminal B and was renovated for the first time in the late 1980s. Terminal A opened in 1997 with three jet bridges and was built exclusively for jets, “relegating” the old terminal to regional and international services. Aegean Airlines, Air France, Austrian Airlines, DAT, Edelweiss Air, Eurowings, Finnair, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Transavia, Widerøe, and Wizz Air serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with revised lighting (it was ported from X-Plane 11), custom ground textures, PBR textures, weather effects for wet, snow, and ice, reworked autogen, custom vegetation placement, a fully XP12 compliant mesh, and more. ‍ It’s available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $16.38, requiring at least 1.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/edxx12</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Helgoland Airfield for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/edxx12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fc8c2ba97aeb1f1deaabe2_helgo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of Helgoland Airfield (EDXH) for X-Plane 12, serving the small archipelago of Heligoland in Schleswig-Holstein, Germany.  It was originally constructed as a military airfield during World War 2 and entirely rebuilt in 1962. The layout has remained the same to this day. With its longest runway being less than 500 meters long, it’s only licensed for aircraft up to 5,700 kilograms, limiting the variety of potential visitors. The length and the often harsh weather (winds) imply special preparation from the pilots, and pilot training is mandatory for commercial service. It’s served by OFD, flying passengers to Heide-Büsum, Nordholz-Spieka, and Uetersen. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airfield, with revised lighting (it was ported from X-Plane 11), custom ground textures, adjusted PBR reflections, weather effects for wet, snow, and ice, full support for native XP12 seasons, a full XP12 compliant mesh, and more. It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $20, requiring at least 4.7 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdbzib</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Releases Bratislava Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdbzib"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fc93de3ae7277b5bc2c870_bratis1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Chudoba Design has recently released their rendition of Bratislava Airport (LZIB) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, serving Bratislava, in Slovakia, and Vienna, in Austria, with a yearly average of 1.8 million passengers. Construction work started in 1948, and the airport was inaugurated in 1951. It replaced the old Bratislava Airport in Vajnory, which is 3 kilometers away and no longer exists. With the fall of the Soviet Union in 1991, Bratislava Airport lost most of its traffic to the nearby Vienna International Airport due to lower prices and higher flight availability, but the advent and popularization of low-cost carriers led to Bratislava becoming an important LCC hub for Ryanair and Wizz Air. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, performance-friendly optimization, custom buildings and objects, and full X-Plane 12 compatibility. It’s available on Chudoba’s website for roughly $12.83. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x12mdt</id>
    <title>Xometry Design Previews Harrisburg International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x12mdt"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fc9694d31599ee8b562fe8_kmdt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry Design has recently announced and previewed their upcoming rendition of Harrisburg International Airport (KMDT) for X-Plane 12, serving Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, with a yearly average of 1.1 million passengers. The airport dates back to 1898, when the Signal Corps of the US Army was stationed there, building what would become Olmsted Field and having its first planes landing in 1918. It was used almost exclusively for military purposes up until 1969 when the Middletown Air Depot closed, and airline flights moved from the nearby Capital City Airport to Olmstead State Airport, renamed Harrisburg International Airport in 1973, which was also when the passenger terminal reached full completion, designed by architect William Pereira. Thirty-one years after the passenger terminal’s inauguration, a new 360,000 square-foot terminal was built, costing around $120 million and designed by the Sheward Partnership. Allegiant, American, American Eagle, Delta, Delta Connection, Frontier, United, and United Express serve it, connecting the city to their most prominent hubs. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed, up-to-date buildings, high-resolution ground textures, PBR normal maps, realistically drawn wear and tear and dirt, SAM jetways, custom night lighting, and more. There’s no information on the pricing and release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oten12</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases True Earth GB North for XP12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oten12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fd1b44c3e6c688ee8edcd7_434074982_407847091893285_6361718592333214804_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx have just posted previews for another TrueEarth product for X-Plane 12. In an announcement, they posted a few teaser screenshots of their current project: TrueEarth Great Britain North for X-Plane 12. Orbx has developed numerous sceneries for all sorts of simulators, ranging from X-Plane 11/12, Prepar3D, Microsoft Flight Simulator, to lesser known sims, such as Aerofly and Tower! Simulator 3. This is their eighth product in the “True Earth” series for X-Plane, and is the first for X-Plane 12. This is also a continuation of their Great Britain True Earth products, being very popular in X-Plane 11. According to Orbx, the region will contain Scottish Highlands, the beautiful Lochs, the Outer Hebrides, the Shetland Islands, and the Isle of Man.  ‍ There is no fixed release date, however Orbx have said that “it’s around the corner”, but whenever they do announce a release date, Threshold will keep you informed, so stay tuned for more information!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777223</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777223"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fd58aa23906046ffbef014_Screenshot_2024-03-22_at_4.05.03_pm.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has published the first development update since the variant reveal of their upcoming 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with information on 737 updates for the marketplace version and a brand new 777 preview image (which is the cover of this article). Their 737 lineup is finally version matched across all platforms, all on 3.00.0091, the update which brings many memory improvements that significantly impact the product’s overall stability. That also means the Xbox version finally features the Ultimate Flight Tablet, albeit with some limitations: the data entry requires a keyboard to function, as the on-screen keyboard does not transmit data into the simulator in a way that the keystrokes could be captured by the add-on, which makes filling out the fields an impossibility.  They will be working on implementing a functional on-screen keyboard, but the turn-around time for beta builds on console is prolonged, which makes the experimenting take a lot longer than it would on PC. For now, having a keyboard attached to the console is the only way to interact with the tablet appropriately. As they have been busy with the 777 development, the 737 updates have halted, but they will pick it back up once the 777 is released. Updates will come if SU15 introduces any change that could break the 737 family. The 777-300ER is going through the final stage of development, where they ensure everything is polished and working accordingly. Randazzo even says they could theoretically launch the plane as it is right now, and people would be overwhelmingly happy with it. Still, they want to ensure everything is perfect before pushing the button.  They are working on getting the modern navdata conversion into beta testing, along with the lateral path guidance improvements made possible by Navigraph’s current format.  The 737 family can be found on their website or in the MSFS Marketplace, and the price ranges from $34.99 to $69.99, depending on the variant. The pricing for the upcoming 777-300ER has not yet been revealed.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwpbi</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release Palm Beach International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwpbi"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fdcd0c168135245b29c196_palm1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld &amp; AmSim have recently released their rendition of Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Miami metropolitan area with a yearly average of 7.7 million passengers. It opened in 1936 as Morrison Field, eventually becoming an important training airfield during World War 2 and operating as a staging base for the Allied invasion of France in 1944, with aircraft departing Palm Beach towards England in preparation for D-Day.  After a brief return to being a civil airport, the airport was once again utilized for military purposes in the early 1950s as Palm Beach Air Force Base, training nearly 23,000 airmen during the Korean War. The Air Force Base was closed in 1962, and Palm Beach was back to being just a civilian airport.  Currently, the airport has 32 gates and three concourses. Concourse A houses Bahamasair and Silver Airways; B houses Air Canada, American Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines; C, on the other hand, holds Delta, Frontier, JetBlue, and Spirit. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution custom ground textures, custom ground markings, parallax windows, animated jetways, and fully modeled buildings and objects. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.09, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniltn</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases New Mystery Airport</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniltn"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fe325ce0ae1a7c32c0a08a_433095249_18042843742709728_5876284696907720379_n.jpg.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds have posted a preview of their new work in progress scenery on their Instagram today. The picture shows a garage followed by a sign saying “Terminal Car Park 2”. Threshold did some digging and found that this render resembles the Car Park next to London Luton Airport. This garage suffered a fire in 2023 and since then has been closed to the public. Situated north of London, and considered to be one of London’s 5 major airports, London Luton Airport (EGGW) is one of the biggest hubs for low-cost airlines, used mostly by Ryanair and EasyJet, and during the day, this airport sees over 170 movements. In 2022, Luton reached a record number of over 13.3 million passengers, which is more than 9 million passengers compared to a year earlier.  ‍ iniBuilds has not announced a release date, pricing, or even confirmed that it is indeed London Luton yet, so stay tuned for more information - Threshold will keep you informed! </summary>
    <published>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftrcvg</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Cincinnati International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftrcvg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65fe35cf3549dba860aa34f5_26.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky International Airport (KCVG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Cincinnati is a global cargo hub for DHL Aviation, Kalitta Air, Atlas Air, ABX Air, and Amazon Air, placing it 6th for the busiest cargo hub in the USA, and 12th in the world. Opened in 1944 as a training airport during WWII, the airport got its first passenger terminal two years later, with the first arrival being an American Airlines DC-3 from Cleveland. In mid-1980, CVG became one of Delta’s hubs, increasing yearly airport operations by 200.000, and doubling passenger volumes by to 20 million passengers handled per year. During its peak in 2005, CVG handled more than 600 flights a day. The airport consists of four runways (three parallel and one perpendicular), a single terminal and two concourses, Concourse A - that has 23 gates, and Concourse B -with 28 gates. CVG also serves as a third biggest world hub for DHL (The other two being Leipzig-Halle and Hong Kong) and as a main shipping hub for Amazon Air operating with more than 50 767-300/200F. FeelThere’s rendition of Cincinnati International Airport includes the following features: This scenery is available on SimMarket for $19.50USD and takes only 1.03GB of space on disk. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news, reviews, and editorials!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x12tro</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Saint-Tropez Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x12tro"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ff4f235ff9337f7fefc9d2_tropez1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of The Airport of the Golfe of Saint Tropez (LFTZ), serving the commune of Saint-Tropez, France, with a yearly average of 7,000 to 10,000 passengers. It was built in 1964 by Count François Gazeau and Marc Den Bosch as a strip of land stretching between the then national road and the river. The land belonged to Charles Boyer de Fonscolombe, who agreed to rent it out to François and Marc in memory of Saint-Exupéry, who happened to be one of his close cousins. In the early 1980s, Charles Boyer entrusted the airport’s operation to a management company, which further developed the airport in the 1990s to provide the region with an adequately structured airport. In that same decade, the runway was made public after an agreement with the state, remaining open 365 days a year for daylight operations only. A new passenger terminal was built in 1995, significantly increasing the passenger handling capabilities and adding a bar.   It’s mostly a general aviation airport, which accounts for most of its yearly aircraft movements. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with revised lighting, PBR reflections, custom ortophoto, custom vegetation, weather effects for wet, snow, and ice, revised autogen, reworked static aircraft (togglable), and more. It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $13.64, requiring at least 1.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/otegbn</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases TrueEarth Great Britain North for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/otegbn"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009029280503a7ed21365c_65de834726853.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has released their first TrueEarth scenery for X-Plane 12, Great Britain North. TrueEarth consists of high-quality, color-edited photoreal imagery, using specially made autogen technology for X-Plane. This addon covers 40,415 square miles of hand-corrected imagery covering the entire central region, as shown below in the coverage map. Scenery consists of: the Scottish Highlands, the beautiful Lochs, the Outer Hebrides, and the Shetland Islands. It includes many VFR landmarks, such as castles, monuments, bridges, and ancient ruins. Apart from the “ancient” landmarks, GB North also has urban cities - Glasgow and Edinburgh. Key features of TrueEarth Great Britain North are: This scenery can be bought from the Orbx Store for roughly $29.30, requiring at least 118.93 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned for more flight sim news on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winwng</id>
    <title>WINWING Reveals Pre-Order Date for A320 FCU</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winwng"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660091f91a2014d31b525b1d_FCU_PC_homepage_fff.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. WINWING, a well-known hardware producer in the mil-sim community has recently expanded into the civil flight sim community with their newest product - a full-size A320 FCU. Known for their hardware, they have established themselves as a high-quality producer of HOTAS, MIP (Main Instrument Panel), rudder pedals, and Joystick grips for various fighter jets. ‍ Showcased a couple of days ago on their YouTube channel, WINWING unveiled the launch of the Full-size FCU for A320. In the trailer, along with the Flight Control Unit, we could notice that EFIS and glare wing are also present in the trailer. Along with the video, the price was also revealed: ‍ On their Facebook page, they have unveiled the pre-order date: March 27 at 02:00UTC. They have also disclosed an expected shipping date - which is supposed to be in early May. ‍ The trailer shows that the FCU backlighting can be adjusted, and WINWING claims that it is auto-synced with the plane. All the knobs have the recognizable Airbus push-pull mechanism and the look of the knobs is very similar, if not the same, as in real Airbus.  ‍ The screen panel features two orange integrated LCDs, with realistic segment code.  ‍ One thing that caught my eye, the EXPED button (button under the ALT knob) seems to be missing. It turns out that WINWING decided to make the button unmarked, but still functional. The user can change its functions to their choice (FD, LS, and CSTR buttons are just some of the countless options the user can adjust to their liking). ‍ The third button in the row below, it is a solid color surface. On the WW FCU, it is still a functional button, just styled in this way. Because in reality, the original 320 button is also like this, and the rapid climb and descent function is basically prohibited by airlines for normal use. ‍ It seems that there are more Airbus products in development, in addition to the FCU. Later on in the trailer, EFIS panels and glare-wings are unveiled. Although it is unknown when will these two be released, or what their price will be, we can be sure to expect them in the A320 product lineup. Interestingly enough, this isn’t WINWING’s first Airbus product, as a quick look at their store shows that they also offer A3XX sidestick, which explains why the sidesticks are also colored, along with the glareshield. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news, reviews, and editorials! ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtama</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Rick Husband Amarillo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtama"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009942e58895107b3796aa_Banner-Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam just released their rendition of Rick Husband Amarillo International Airport (KAMA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Amarillo, Texas, with a yearly average of 670,000 passengers. It has been named after local astronaut Rick Husband, whose statue can be found inside the airport ( and accurately represented in the scenery). The airport serves many popular destinations with a total of four different commercial airlines. Allegiant, American, Southwest, and United are the ones flying out of Amarillo. They fly to the likes of Dallas/Fort Worth, Austin, Las Vegas, and Denver, to mention a few. Yearly just around 800,000 passengers travel through the airport of Amarillo. ‍ The scenery has lots of features like PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, custom pavement, custom jetways and many more custom objects, like passengers and terminal interiors. The scenery is now available on SimMarket for roughly $16.50USD and takes up around 1.03 GB of space on disk. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctlapa</id>
    <title>VATSIM Confirms The Airports for Cross the Land: Asia Pacific</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctlapa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009a41e36708a2da90408f_APAC.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. VATSIM just announced airports for Cross The Land: Asia Pacific Westbound edition in April on their Twitter account. This event involves the Australian and South Eastern Asian airports. ‍ Cross The Land is one of the biggest events on VATSIM, and just recently it got an expansion. Along with the Europe-MEA edition, CTL now has the Americas edition, where pilots fly from Northern American airports to South America, and the Asia Pacific edition, which brings the Australia-SE Asia connection.  ‍ The airport list for this year’s CTL: Asia Pacific is smaller than expected, only 6 airports were chosen, three in Australia and three in Asia: ‍ As of the posting of this article, no information about slot booking has been disclosed. Any new information will be posted on the Cross the Land Discord server and Twitter, as well as on Threshold! If you are interested in learning more about VATSIM, you can visit their website here. ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdplhr</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases London Heathrow Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdplhr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009dfee9eefa0b6ca2a6dd_deathrow1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently released their freeware and open-source rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, serving Greater London with a yearly average of 80 million passengers. London Heathrow is the eight-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprehending international travel, and the remaining 6% is strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it. The scenery features custom orthoimagery, custom ground textures, 3D grass, SAM jetways, VDGS, custom buildings, realistic dirt and grunge, and more. Its open-source nature warrants constant improvement, and ZDP has already shared a list of future futures, including more custom buildings, a Concorde static model, improved clutter, improved ground markings, improved vegetation, and more. ‍ It’s available for free on the Threshold Forum. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
