<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-06-16T18:25:15.807524+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/letlxp</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Teruel for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/letlxp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6661fe19d3bc4fa0a3ed247e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FSDG has released their rendition of Teruel Airport (LETL) for X-Plane 12. Officially known as Plataforma Aeroportuaria-Teruel (PLATA), this airport serves as an aircraft storage and maintenance facility for Tarmac Aerosave - a company specialising in aircraft maintenance and storage. After being used as an airfield during the Spanish Civil War in 1936-1939, the location of Teruel Airport was a firing range for the Spanish Air Force for a long time, before plans for a new commercial airport were made. Construction work began in 2009 and after 4 years, Teruel Airport was officially opened in February 2013, after receiving certification from AESA (Spanish Aviation Safety and Security Agency) for public use. Throughout the years, many more platforms for long-storage were made, increasing the number of available stands from 24 to 84. In 2016, Teruel Airport was one of the few airports that were used in testing of the A400M. During the same year, a flight school opened with a base at Teruel. The latest expansion included the construction of a new parking area. Meteorological conditions, location and low density of traffic made Teruel a perfect place for long-term storage facilities. Aside from Tarmac Aerosave, the Spanish space launch agency, PLD Space, also uses this airport to test launch vehicle technology. FSDG’s rendition of Teruel Airport features an authentic light environment, static aircraft, dynamic lighting, reflective textures, and optimisation for great performance and visual results. This scenery is made for X-Plane 12 but is compatible with X-Plane 11.30+ as well. It is available for purchase on SimMarket for roughly $11.85. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csh130</id>
    <title>Cowan Simulation Releases EC130 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csh130"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6662008f6ebec53829397595_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cowan Simulation has just released their Eurocopter EC130 (also named Airbus H130) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Eurocopter EC130 is a single-engine light helicopter developed after the Eurocopter AS350. It was launched and produced by the Eurocopter Group, which would later be rebranded as Airbus Helicopters.  During the early 1990s, the development of a new helicopter, based on the Eurocopter AS350, began. The main difference was the adoption of Fenestron instead of a conventional tail rotor.  On 24th June 1999, the first prototype of EC130 performed its first flight. Apart from the Fenestron, the EC130 also featured a dual-hydraulic system and a wider fuselage. It was introduced in 2001 by Blue Hawaiian Helicopters, who were the launch operator. Powered by a single Turbomeca Ariel 2D Turboshaft engine, EC130 can fly at altitudes of 23,000ft for 4 hours, with a range of 327nm with a Vne of 155kts. Cowan Simulation’s rendition of EC130 features a detailed manual, paint kit, realistic systems, MEDEVAC version, 3 cockpit variants (G530/430/GTN/GX3 Touch/Analog), PMS or TDS GTN/GTNXi 650 and 750 integration (PC only), floats version, 50 liveries, functional spot/search lights, animated Cineflex camera, 4K PBR textures, detailed night lighting and accurate 3D modelling. This add-on can be purchased on the CowanSim store for $29.99 and will require at least 3.67GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msgsx3</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Updates GSX Pro for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msgsx3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6663271a821ff5243a62951c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDreamTeam has recently updated its GSX Pro add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator to version V3.0. The update includes new features and fixes, with the addition of seated passengers and a new crew system being the major highlights. With the new update, users can now see passengers seated within their plane. Initially, only the Fenix A320 has compatibility for seated passengers. The new feature aims to make the cabin environment more realistic. Another new feature is a new crew system, which includes 16 different characters with 227 airline uniform variations. In addition to the new features, the update also includes various fixes. The full changelog can be found below. Version 3.0.0 The updated GSX Pro is available on the FSDreamTeam website for approximately $37.49. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inprjk</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Jomo Kenyatta International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inprjk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6663355a70731e175cba9262_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has given a sneak peek of its upcoming scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new scenery package features Jomo Kenyatta International Airport (HKJK) in Nairobi, Kenya. As the country's largest airport, it accommodates a wide range of destinations and approximately 11 million passengers annually. The scenery package will include various features such as hand-crafted ground textures, realistic airport surroundings, dynamic lighting, detailed airport buildings, an official GSX profile, LOD optimisation, iniManager compatibility, and more. While iniBuilds has expressed the intention to release the scenery soon, no specific launch date has been announced yet. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmamxp</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmamxp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6665ae018a2022b3fc28a323_Banner%20Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released its version of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Milan metropolitan area and is the second busiest airport in Italy. With just over 26 million yearly passengers, it offers a variety of destinations worldwide. Milan Malpensa Airport began commercial operations in 1948 after previously being used for both general and military aviation. Over the years, the airport underwent various expansions and continuous development. In 1998, the Italian airline Alitalia relocated its main hub from Rome Fiumicino Airport to Milan Malpensa. Presently, the airport accommodates over 26 million passengers annually, with approximately 187.000 aircraft movements. It serves airlines such as easyJet, Neos, Ryanair, and others, offering destinations including New York, London, and Amsterdam. The recently released scenery package provides Microsoft Flight Simulator users with a variety of features for the Italian hub. The add-on requires 1.34 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $17.66. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msf4t2</id>
    <title>Microsoft Publishes New MSFS 2024 Trailer</title>
    <updated>2024-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msf4t2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6666210d0e9353b502720da2_newfs1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently unveiled the second trailer for the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which shows new aircraft, features, stunning visuals, and the long-awaited release date: November 19th! The new trailer was part of Microsoft's yearly Xbox Game Showcase, where Microsoft announces new IPs and/or teases stuff that was already announced beforehand. ‍ Similarly, the second trailer also shows many activities that will be possible within the new simulator, including air ambulance, aerial advertising, agricultural aviation, air rescue, cargo operations, ballooning, VIP passenger transport, and much more. It also hints at a new airliner: the Airbus A330, supposedly developed by iniBuilds for Microsoft, and a new photo mode. The pricing has yet to be available, but Microsoft Flight Simulator will be available on the Microsoft Store, Game Pass, and Steam on November 18th. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bacgam</id>
    <title>Backwood Studios Releases Glenswinton Aerodrome for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bacgam"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6668c353dc2e01a9e558e49c_glen1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Backwood Studios has recently released their rendition of Glenswinton Aerodrome (GB-0201) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a private aerodrome near Castle Douglas in Scotland.  Glenswinton's origins trace back to the early 1900s, a period marked by pioneering feats in aviation. The exact date of its establishment is unclear, but historical records suggest it served as a military airfield during the Great War. During this turbulent time, the aerodrome likely housed fighter aircraft tasked with patrolling the skies and safeguarding British airspace. With a 430-meter gravel runway, it's mainly suitable for smaller general aviation aircraft and STOL-capable airplanes.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the aerodrome, with custom-modeled buildings, animated people and farm life, hand-built dirt roads, a custom forest to reflect current satellite imagery, a custom runway slope, custom night lighting, and more. It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $4.95, requiring at least 1.01 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tbrjoy</id>
    <title>TechnoBrain Releases Yao Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tbrjoy"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6669f7df0f1e2bd9aaad2f48_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TechnoBrain has recently released its version of Yao Airport (RJOY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Yao Airport is a small airport in the city of Yao, located in the Osaka Prefecture, Japan. The airport serves general aviation and is also an airbase for the JGSDF, the Japan Ground Self-Defense Force. It is situated approximately 8.1 nautical miles from the centre of Osaka and does not have any scheduled airline services. In 1938, the airport started as Hanshin Aviation School. In 1940, the airport was renamed and seized by the army, becoming known as Taishō Airfield. The army also expanded the airport. After World War II, occupation forces named the airport Hansin Airfield. Later, the airport was returned to the Japanese. Today, the airport accommodates general aviation traffic and also offers charter flights and sightseeing flights. It has cross-runways and is located not far from the centre of Osaka. The newly released version of Yao Airport comes with a variety of features, including custom taxiway signs and ground markings, dynamic lighting, PBR materials, and much more. The add-on requires 285.27 MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $21.64. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teipas</id>
    <title>Teikof Studio Releases Antonio Nariño Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teipas"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666b77cfe18293bdcfc677e7_pas1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Teikof Studio recently released their rendition of Antonio Nariño Airport (SKPS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Pasto, Colombia, and has a yearly average of 333,600 passengers. The exact date of the airport's construction remains unclear, but its development was driven by the need for improved connectivity in a region known for its mountainous terrain. Building an airport on flat land proved difficult, so engineers opted for a daring solution: constructing a runway on a plateau 50 meters above the surrounding area. This distinctive feature has earned the airport the nickname "aircraft carrier" among pilots, referencing its resemblance to a flat-topped ship on a sea of land. One of its most notable aspects is its runway: due to the high elevation and surrounding terrain, it is relatively short, posing a challenge for larger aircraft. However, significant improvements have been made over the years. Since 2007, the addition of an instrument landing system (ILS) has allowed for safer operations during low visibility and nighttime conditions. ‍Crosswinds also pose another significant challenge, especially during the summer months. Pilots must possess a high degree of skill and experience to navigate these conditions safely. ‍ Pasto Airport's dependence on good visibility conditions and tame winds will eventually lead to its replacement, as it won't be able to keep up with the projected passenger traffic demand.  Avianca (Bogotá, Cali), Clic (Cali), and LATAM Colombia (Bogotá) serve it.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal, custom ground textures, custom terraforming, and more. It's available on the MSFS Marketplace for $9.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhrzdp</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Updates London Heathrow Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhrzdp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666b7d9752124d1e83c7c236_zd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently updated their freeware and open-source rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, adding a custom model for Terminal 5B and fixing issues with lights and pre-existing models. London Heathrow is the eighth-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprising international travel and the remaining 6% strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it.  Update 0.4.0, the first since its public open beta release brings a custom model for Terminal 5B, T5C improvements, lighting updates, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ It’s available for free on the Threshold Forum. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mseddf</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Releases Freeware Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mseddf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666c511c8b470c555156b1f4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Simulation Software has recently released its first airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new version of Frankfurt Airport (EDDF) is now available for free, following its previous release for X-Plane. Frankfurt Airport is the busiest airport in Germany, servicing numerous regional and international destinations. The newly released Frankfurt Airport features handcrafted airport buildings, custom ground support equipment (GSE), custom animated jetways, a custom GSX profile, realistic ground textures and layout, custom terminal interiors, points of interest (POIs), and more. The scenery can now be downloaded for free from Orbx.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taff62</id>
    <title>TAF Studio Previews Hayfork Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taff62"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666cb618a2958c860bd16999_6632f0c686be6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TAF Studio has teased their newest scenery for MSFS - Hayfork Airport (F62). Located in a mountain valley in Northern California, Hayfork Airport is a small airfield with a long runway (4100 ft) for its size. This scenery will feature some interesting additions, such as a modelled race track made for offroad vehicles and roads with signs leading up to Hayfork’s Bally lookout!  Aside from the automotive part of the scenery, two bush spots with three runways are also featured in Hayfork scenery. With an elevation of 6250ft and a length of only 295ft, serious STOL skills are required to land successfully. Another bush spot, located a couple of miles to the east of Hayfork’s Bally, has an even more challenging runway! Only 250ft of the runway on an uphill cliff, without an option for a go-around. Key features of Hayfork California are F62 Hayfork Airport, 2 bush spots with 3 runways, functional hangar doors at Hayfork Airport, custom charts for Hayfork Airport and Hayfork Bally Bushstrip, tiedown points at Hayfork Airport, Mountain Valley Raceway, Custom 3D buildings, and custom trees and vegetation. ‍ The release date and price of this scenery haven’t been announced as of the time of writing, however, as always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdlsgg</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdlsgg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666cc1cfa73b93c4b2454e8e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently released its version of Geneva Airport (LSGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Swiss city of Geneva and is located approximately 2.5 miles from the city centre. As the second biggest and busiest airport in Switzerland, it welcomes around 16.5 million passengers annually. Geneva Airport opened in 1919 as a simple airfield. The first concrete runway was constructed in 1937 to accommodate the increasing number of planes flying to Geneva. During World War II, all flights from Switzerland were prohibited, but after the war, passenger traffic at the airport steadily increased. Subsequently, more airlines began operating at the airport, leading to numerous developments and upgrades over the years. Today, airlines such as easyJet and Swiss International Air Lines ensure that the airport connects to a wide variety of destinations worldwide, resulting in approximately 165,000 aircraft movements annually. The newly released Geneva Airport from RDPresets comes with a variety of features, including completely custom modeling and texturing with PBR textures, 3D interior, custom ground textures, accurate night lighting, and much more. The add-on requires 3.13 GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for approximately $19.15. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aa60</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Announces Aerostar 600 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aa60"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666df4c4c46e8cd22c52d76e_aerostar.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently announced the development of a new Accu-Sim airplane for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the Piper Aerostar 600, a twin-engined propeller aircraft designed and built by Ted Smith Aircraft Company in the late 1960s.  Ted Smith, then an already experienced aircraft designer, envisioned a fast twin-engined airplane with no compromises, sleek lines, powerful engines, and speed as the main priority. By the late 1960s, the first prototype was already breaking records, making it the fastest twin-piston general aviation aircraft at the time, thanks to its light construction, low drag, and sheer power.  ‍ The Aerostar 600 had two Lycoming IO-540-K engines, producing 290 horsepower each. These allowed it to cruise at 408 km/h, with a service ceiling of 25,000ft and 1,500 miles of total range on a single tank of fuel.  ‍ Like their Comanche 250 (released mid-2023), the upcoming airplane will be built on Accu-Sim 2.0 technology. This technology features an advanced aerodynamics system that tries to accurately represent how an aircraft flies through the air, realistic wear and tear on the airframe and engine, in-depth electrical simulation, and much more.  ‍ They have owned and operated a real Aerostar 600 for several years, and it was assumed for the longest time that it would be their first product for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  Not much has been revealed yet, but they mention it’s an entirely different experience from flying the Comanche, with their Accu-Sim 2.0 technology accurately recreating the feel of flying a piston twin. It’s expected to be released “later in 2024.” ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxdc</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Detroit City for XP12 and MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxdc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666df7f3fd5f4e53f95ddf19_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has released another addition to their “Landmarks” product series, this time being a rendition of Detroit City for both X-Plane 12 and MSFS.  Being the biggest city on the USA-Canada border, as well as the most populous city in the state of Michigan, it is known for its contributions to art, music architecture, and its great automotive history. Orbx’s Detroit City scenery features over 52 custom-made buildings (the Renaissance Center, the Spirit of Detroit Sculpture, Comerica Park, the Guardian Building, Michigan Central Station, Ford Field, Little Caesars Arena, and the Aretha Franklin Amphitheatre), and a detailed representation of the waterfront and industrial areas along the Detroit River. Also included is a large amount of highly detailed models replacing the city’s photogrammetry data, including models for cranes, chimneys, vehicles, structures, animated Detroit People Mover on the raised tracks through the city’s downtown, and emissive textures on all buildings for nighttime flying across the city. The product can be bought on OrbxDirect for $9.88 for the MSFS version, while the X-Plane version costs $13.20. The XP version will require at least 1.92GB of free disk space, whereas the MSFS version requires 1.02 GB. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tcj525</id>
    <title>TorqueSim CitationJet 525 Enters Beta Testing</title>
    <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tcj525"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666ea7ec53965f75781f7919_CJ-2024-06-12-0023-825x510.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Cessna CitationJet is a series of light business jets, and are a part of the Citation family. Launched in 1989, the CJ 525 had its first flight in October 1991. Using the Citation II’s fuselage, the CJ 525 has a different wing box and T-tail design. After the original CJ proved to be a success, the 525 received an upgrade in avionics and engines and was marketed as CJ1, CJ1+, and M2, depending on the equipment the aircraft had.  Aside from the original 525 model, Cessna also produced prolonged versions: 525A, 525B and 525C. All of these versions later received avionics and engine upgrades and were marketed as CJ2, CJ3 and CJ4, respectively. During the testing phase, various aspects of TorqueSim’s CJ525 will be tested and examined, such as flight dynamics, systems accuracy, visual fidelity, and performance testing.  As of the publishing of this article, no information about the release date or pricing of this addon has been released, however, make sure to keep an eye out as Threshold will keep you updated with the progress of TorqueSim’s CitationJet 525! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
