<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-12-09T18:33:24.425036+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asmxpr</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asmxpr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67484e8088b8fa00e0945b51_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Aerosoft has recently launched its version of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. As the second busiest airport in Italy and the largest in northern Italy, it serves the city of Milan. The airport welcomes approximately 26.1 million passengers each year. Aviation activities have been taking place in the area of the current airport since 1910. In the early years, the airfield served both general and military aviation. It was not until 1948 that Milan Malpensa Airport began commercial operations. Over the years, the airport has undergone various expansions and continues to develop. In 1998, the Italian airline Alitalia relocated its main hub from the country's largest airport, Rome Fiumicino, to Milan Malpensa. Today, the airport welcomes over 26 million passengers annually, handling approximately 187.000 aircraft movements. It serves as a base for airlines such as easyJet, Neos, and Ryanair, while also accommodating a variety of other airlines that offer destinations around the world, including Rome, Amsterdam, and Singapore. David Rosenfeld has developed the newly released version of Milan Malpensa Airport, featuring an accurate and up-to-date representation of the airport, detailed terminal buildings, high-quality custom objects, realistic night lighting, and more. The add-on requires 3.4 GB of storage space and is available on Aerosoft for approximately $24.21. It's worth noticing that MSFS 2024 compatibility will be available for free in the coming weeks. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdpdud</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Posts Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdpdud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6748571a4fc14894e2191251_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently provided an update on their Discord regarding their current products and future plans. The team announced that they have entered the sustaining phase of their lifecycle, which means they will continue to support their existing projects. However, their capacity to start new projects is limited. The focus will be on v2 updates for their current projects. If they do take on any new projects, these will likely be smaller airports, similar in size to Gold Coast Airport. Next year will be dedicated to these v2 updates, although it is possible for a new project to emerge, none are currently planned. The team has provided updates on their current projects. EGLL is making steady progress, with a significant update expected in the first half of 2025, likely to include T5A.  ‍ The ZDP Library v1.2 update is nearly complete and is scheduled for release before the end of the year. ‍ RKSI will receive a v2 update featuring an updated taxiway layout, a new runway, new aprons, new buildings, and new ground textures.  ‍ MDPC is also set for a v2 update, which will include new ground textures, new vegetation, updated ortho, an updated taxiway layout, an updated apron layout, and completely redone buildings. ‍ The team intends to provide RJAA with a v2 update featuring new ground textures, ortho, vegetation, and more. However, this is a substantial task, and no timeline has been established for its completion. ‍ As for KSDF, PANC, EGNR, KCLL, and YBCG, no updates are currently planned.  ‍ Lastly, the EDHI project is unfortunately no longer active due to a lack of cooperation from iniBuilds concerning the Beluga Halle. Additionally, the source files were lost due to a hard drive failure. Consequently, the team has determined that reviving this project is not feasible at this time. The team has stated that they are monitoring the development of X-Plane 12 and the release of next-generation scenery. If any compatibility issues arise from these developments or releases, they will pause their current projects to focus on updates. As a result, the team's plans may be affected and are subject to change. ‍ We will keep you informed as soon as the team shares more information or releases any updates. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx532</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx532"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad36ef2cdccb6b9a18c44_sharklets12.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update to their A320 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, focusing on stability and code infrastructure. Update 2.3.0.532 fixes an issue where the aircraft's systems would not load or unload correctly, a bug with the CAB ALT gauge not showing the correct value and a few crash fixes. The model was also improved for MSFS 2024, with a cockpit blend mask fix across ambient occlusion, metalness, and roughness.  Their installer was also updated, and it now automatically cleans up old log files when installing a new product. MS Store is preferred over Steam if both are installed, as well as additional data logging and more. The full changelog follows below: The complete lineup (A319, A320, A321) is available on their website for roughly $114. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inibbn</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Brisbane Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inibbn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6748ed0df5b2a6430f3c2c5f_bris1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently announced the development and imminent release of Brisbane Airport (YBBN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Brisbane Airport is the largest airport in Australia by land area and the third busiest in passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 23.2 million passengers. The airport’s construction started in 1980. Built by Leighton Contractors, it cost 400 million dollars and opened eight years later. It initially had a domestic terminal and two runways. Nearly a decade later, in September 1995, the international terminal was inaugurated, bringing in further passenger traffic. In 2007, the government approved the construction of a new parallel runway, which was expected to take eight years to build on swamp land 2 kilometers west of the terminal area. The unexpectedly long construction time was due to the settling period of the 13,000,000 cubic meters of sand gathered from Moreton Bay to cover the swamp. Work was completed in 2020, costing $1 billion and taking precisely eight years from start to finish. It’s a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia. Air Canada, Air Niugini, Alliance Airlines, American Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, EVA Air, Fiji Airways, FlyPelican, Jetstar, Korean Air, Link Airways, National Jet Express, Nauru Airlines, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Skytrans Airlines, Solomon Airlines, United Airlines, VietJet Air, and Virgin Australia also serve it. ‍ There’s no information regarding pricing or features yet, but Threshold will keep you informed.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777612</id>
    <title>PMDG’s Boeing 777F Release Date Confirmed, 737 Lineup Update, and More</title>
    <updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777612"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6748f61a71e1eca5334fa74f_777f1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG has published yet another development update, bringing further information on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 add-on compatibility, the release date of their upcoming 777F, and a micro-update for their 737 Lineup, bringing it to full parity with the marketplace version. The 737NG lineup has been updated to version 3.00.0108, matching the marketplace version to be made available in early December (according to Randazzo's predictions). It's mostly a micro-update, removing "some cruft that was determined to be unneeded in the release build of the product" at the request of the Marketplace's intake team. In their previous development update, they mentioned that the 777F would get a release date once they had issued a few cleanup builds to their beta testers. This has happened, and now they have a date in mind: next Friday (06/12), during the evening, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Pricing will be announced at release. The add-on will feature accurately modeled supernumary controls and functions, main deck lighting systems, manual or automatic operation of the main deck cargo door, safety guards, and more. They have also increased the GSX compatibility by allowing FSDT's plugin to control the doors, loading process, etc. Their take on MSFS 2024, compatibility-wise, is still the same as that of the previous development updates: they have not yet been able to fully gauge the amount of work required because the new simulator does not yet provide the required tooling. Randazzo shared PMDG's thoughts on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024: "My answer remains optimistic. I have been exploring the new sim while flying the PMDG DC-6 which is not yet fully compatible, but overlooking the dim displays and some font issues, gives a very good representation of what it will be like once we get the fleet compatible with the new platform". "MSFS24 is to my eye more convincing visually than any simulation platform we have ever seen [...] It offers more opportunity to engage in interesting flying, varied degrees of flying, community participation and engaged learning than any simulation platform we have had access to in the short 40+ years I've called myself a simmer", he concluded. PMDG's aircraft lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fslweb</id>
    <title>FSLabs Launches New Website with Further A321ceo Details Included</title>
    <updated>2024-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fslweb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674a405ea755e614a14d347b_labs1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Flight Sim Labs recently launched their new website design, featuring a landing page for their upcoming A321ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and a selection of screenshots, details, pricing information, and more. The company rose to fame in 2016 after releasing the first high-fidelity Airbus A320 add-on. This add-on allowed Microsoft Flight Simulator X and Prepar3d users to experience the day-to-day operation of one of the most popular airliners, one that had not yet been developed to such standards (which quickly changed within five years). Described as “the most advanced Airbus A321ceo simulation for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020”, FSLabs’ upcoming bird is said to bring a combination of cutting-edge technology with unrivaled attention to detail, featuring immersive cabin operations, custom MEL (minimum equipment list) systems, next-generation visuals, enhanced systems, dynamic effects, realistic operational hazards, and real-world navigation obstacles such as GPS jamming, based on real-world data.  The add-on will retail for $69.99 and feature two engine options (CFM56 and IAE V2500), wingtip fences and/or sharklets, totaling up to four variants included in the package. They have also announced the development of an A321neo next, which is still being worked on but is said to “follow shortly behind” the release of the current engine option variant. Owners of the ceo between its release and the Neo’s release will be eligible for a discount. Refer to their website for further information on the upcoming product(s). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tmzbad</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Beijing Daxing International Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tmzbad"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674c4bddb5e54ac15b98b97d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Taimodels has recently launched its rendition of Beijing Daxing International Airport (ZBAD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This airport, which serves the capital of China alongside Beijing Capital International Airport, opened just five years ago. It accommodates nearly 40 million passengers each year. After years of proposals, the construction of the new airport was officially approved in 2014. Following five years of construction, the airport opened its doors on September 25, 2019, with its first commercial flight occurring the next day. The airport serves as a hub for six airlines: Air China, Beijing Capital Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, China United Airlines, and XiamenAir. Additionally, it is a focus city for Hebei Airlines. However, the airport is not limited to these carriers; it accommodates numerous airlines from around the globe, offering flights to various destinations, including Hong Kong, Amsterdam, Doha, and many more. The newly released version of Beijing Daxing International Airport includes realistic terminals, airport buildings, PBR ground markings, realistic lighting, custom jetways, and other features. The scenery requires 4.54 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for about $23.44. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jacxpl</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Jackson-Medgar Wiley Evers International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jacxpl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674f6e84f0807b34805888e7_jackson1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Fly2High recently released their rendition of Jackson-Medgar Wiley Evers International Airport (KJAN) for X-Plane 11 and 12. The airport serves the Jackson metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 1 million passengers. The airport opened in 1963, replacing Hawkins Field, Jackson’s former main airport since 1928. Construction took around three years and cost 6 million USD (equivalent to 56,000,000 USD in 2023).  It’s named after Medgar Evers (since 2005), a Mississippi Field Secretary for the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), who was assassinated in June 1963.    The airport is served by American Eagle (Charlotte, Dallas-Fort Worth, Washington-National), Delta Air Lines (Atlanta), Southwest Airlines (Atlanta, Baltimore, Houston-Hobby, Orlando), and United Express (Houston-Intercontinental). In addition to passenger flights, the airport handles cargo shipments, with UPS flying to Louisville. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-placed night lighting, 3D vegetation, weather effects (X-Plane 12 only), high-quality PBR texturing, custom terminal interior, and more. It’s available on X-Plane.Org’s Store for $17.99, requiring at least 1.6 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/224110</id>
    <title>Microsoft Launches New MSFS 2024 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/224110"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674f726a66e24230f8910eb8_msfs24-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft recently issued a new update to their newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing a series of stability, performance fixes, and minor SDK tweaks. Update 1.1.10.0 – the second update since release so far – fixes a crash when navigating fast between the challenges, mitigates an issue with adjusting Tobii Eye Tracker settings in the menu, and addresses various crashes that were reported by the users. Furthermore, the update fixes the floating jetway issue that has plagued the simulator since its release. It also corrects the unloading and reloading of WASM gauges upon restarting a flight. ‍ The complete changelog for the update follows below: Stability &amp; Performance ‍ General Bug Fixes ‍ SDK JS API ‍ Aircraft ‍ Aircraft tech ‍ Model behavior ‍ Flow/Progression ‍ MyLibrary ‍ The update is available right now on Steam and Microsoft Store.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inibne</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Brisbane Airport for MSFS 2024 </title>
    <updated>2024-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inibne"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6750c883263c47b2d10e1674_bri1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Brisbane Airport (YBBN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Brisbane Airport is the largest airport in Australia by land area and the third busiest in passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 23.2 million passengers. The airport’s construction started in 1980. Built by Leighton Contractors, it cost 400 million dollars and opened eight years later. It initially had a domestic terminal and two runways. Nearly a decade later, in September 1995, the international terminal was inaugurated, bringing in further passenger traffic. In 2007, the government approved the construction of a new parallel runway, which was expected to take eight years to build on swamp land 2 kilometers west of the terminal area. The unexpectedly long construction time was due to the settling period of the 13,000,000 cubic meters of sand gathered from Moreton Bay to cover the swamp. Work was completed in 2020, costing $1 billion and taking precisely eight years from start to finish. It’s a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia. Air Canada, Air Niugini, Alliance Airlines, American Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, EVA Air, Fiji Airways, FlyPelican, Jetstar, Korean Air, Link Airways, National Jet Express, Nauru Airlines, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Skytrans Airlines, Solomon Airlines, United Airlines, VietJet Air, and Virgin Australia also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom dynamic lighting, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, and an up-to-date layout.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $22.72, requiring at least 8.32 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx541</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx541"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad38675d6fc222fc4587a_sharklets9.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has recently issued another update – the third in the span of a few weeks – to their A320 lineup (A319/A320/A321) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, adding Quality of Life improvements and warranting further stability on both platforms. Update 2.3.0.541, very much like the previous update, primarily focuses on improving the stability and usability of the add-on in both platforms, addressing issues that would lead to CTDs, improving the robustness of displays, fixing pause at the top of descent, further improving the loading and unloading of the product in MSFS 2024, and wholly mitigating a clickspot issue in the EFB, also a 2024-only issue. The complete changelog follows below: Avionics and Systems EFB Their product lineup is available on their website for roughly $114 (at the time of writing). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lj35ac</id>
    <title>Flysimware Releases Learjet 35A Cargo Expansion</title>
    <updated>2024-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lj35ac"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6751c9d7364aab7d9f5528cf_flysimware-learjet-35a-cargo-expansion-pack-msfs2020%20(2).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Flysimware has released an expansion pack for their Learjet 35A for MSFS. The expansion pack contains three versions of Learjet 35A Cargo - LJ35A equipped with GNS530, GTN750 and GTN750Xi (the latter two require PMS50 GTN750 and GTN750Xi respectively). Based on one of the most popular business jets - the Learjet 35A, the cargo version is capable of carrying up to 900kg, and with the power from two TFE731-2-2B of payload to distances up to 3000km (~1620nmi). The cargo version features a modelled cargo hold, 4K PBR textures and 8 liveries. The expansion pack is available for purchase at Flysimware’s store for $14.99.  For more information about the product, check out the Flysimware Discord. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md8024</id>
    <title>Leonardo Announces Upcoming Maddog X Compatibility for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md8024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67520b59256ee91652e619eb_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Leonardo recently shared information on their forum regarding compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 for their Maddog X. The team noted the learning curve presented by the new simulator but emphasized their commitment to addressing the various issues it has introduced. The team has announced that the Maddog X will soon be available for MSFS 2024 as a native upgrade. This upgrade will be free for customers who own the aircraft for MSFS 2020. Additionally, the team is working on an optional expansion to further enhance the add-on, ensuring it meets what they refer to as “FS2020 standards” in terms of modelling, texturing, and sound. There is currently no ETA for this expansion. We will keep you updated as soon as the Maddog X is available for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmr77f</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Boeing 777F for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmr77f"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536cf0ffa8a38bf570aa36_frei1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently released their long-awaited Boeing 777F for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. This is one of the world’s most popular cargo haulers still in production, famous for its fuel efficiency and range. Developed by Boeing to meet the ever-growing demand for highly efficient air cargo transport, it has been hugely successful since its introduction in 2009. Ever since, it has been carrying massive payloads across the globe for many different operators.  Powered by two GE90-110B1 engines, which generate enough thrust to lift over 100,000 kilograms of cargo within 550 cubic meters, easily carrying oversized – and heavy – cargo to virtually any destination with a long enough runway. The add-on features an advanced simulation of all avionics and system management operations of the 777 flight deck, an accurately simulated display drawing process, a full electronic checklist, the PMDG Universal Flight Tablet, a full simulation of the 777’s autoflight director and autopilot systems, and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ PMDG 777F features Avionics &amp; Flight Deck: Air Conditioning System: Auto-flight System: Brakes and Tires: Cargo Main Deck: Datalink (Currently limited to Hopie Network for ATC services, but more coming!): Doors: Electrical System: Engines: Failures: Flight Controls and Flight Surfaces: Fly By Wire System: Fuel System: Ground Service Vehicles: Hydraulic System: Landing Gear: Lighting Systems: Navigation Data: Physics-based Flexing: Pneumatic System: Simulator Features: As mentioned in their last development update, the 777F is not yet compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 due to issues with the new SDK. The airplane is available at PMDG.com for $54.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rj2024</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates RJ Professional Bringing MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rj2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6754a4fc8eb5cbcaf2f90904_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has updated its RJ Professional add-on to version 1.2. The most notable change is the added compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Additionally, the aircraft has undergone various fixes and improvements. The new update includes several fixes and improvements. The EFB has received various updates, and the previous issue with the GSX fuel truck not disconnecting after refueling has also been resolved. Additionally, several manuals have been updated. The changelog for the update is provided below: ‍ v1.2 (0.1.2) ‍ - Added MSFS 2024 compatibility - Fixed GSX fuel truck not disconnecting after refuelling complete - Fixed overlapping text on EFB Aircraft &gt; Configuration menu - Fixed cabin GND PWR AVAIL light logic – Now remains illuminated whenever external power is available - Added ‘fade in’ / ‘fade out’ effects to exterior lighting to simulated incandescent bulbs - Fixed unable to change speeds flipchart after toggle EFB option on/off - Improved EFB page transition between WASM and JS/HTML pages - Improved navigation light electrical source – One Nav light on each wing tip is powered by ESS DC, the other by the Ground Service Bus. - Updated RJ Professional Operations manual - Updated RJ Professional EFB manual - Updated GNLU-910A FMS Operations manual The updated RJ Professional is now available for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The aircraft can be purchased directly from Just Flight for $69.99. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ardfse</id>
    <title>FSA Announces FSExpo 2025 Registration Opening December 14</title>
    <updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ardfse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6754b7fc2343ec8a89e6e6e6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The Flight Simulation Association (FSA) announced in a recent press release that registration for FlightSimExpo 2025 will open on December 14th. Starting next Saturday at 12 PM Eastern Time, you can sign up for the upcoming FlightSimExpo, which will be held in Providence, Rhode Island. For non-members, access from Friday to Sunday is priced at $80. For FSA First Officers, the cost is $72. If you are an FSA Captain, you will pay $64. However, if you are among the first 250 FSA Captains to register, your price will be just $50.  ‍ All pricing options include access to seminars and exhibit halls from Friday to Sunday. Participants will also receive access to post-event seminar recordings, a welcome drink during Friday’s reception, and coffee and tea provided on Saturday and Sunday mornings.  ‍ If you are unable to attend FlightSimExpo in person, you can register for live and recorded seminar access for $15. FSA Captains can access this content for free. If you or your team would like to sponsor, exhibit, or speak at the Expo, FlightSimExpo invites developers to register using the following link. Regarding travel and accommodation, discounted rates are currently available. According to co-founder Evan Reiter, one-third of the available rooms have already been booked. The discounted hotel rates represent some of the lowest group rates for a 4-star hotel in downtown Providence during a summer event. You can find more details about accommodation and travel at the following link. FlightSimExpo 2025 will be held in Providence from June 27 to June 29. Registration will open next week on December 14, so set your alarms if you plan to attend next year's FlightSimExpo. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
