<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-08-04T18:25:00.800715+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniddu</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Dubrovnik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniddu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a010f4e94078d32d9948e9_dub1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Dubrovnik Ruđer Bošković Airport (LDDU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Dubrovnik-Neretva County with a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers. The airport opened in 1962 and quickly became Yugoslavia’s busiest. By 1987, it had already served nearly a million passengers.  In the 2000s, a new passenger terminal was built to replace the original from 1962, costing the administration 70 million euros. It’s the most modern terminal in the country so far.  It’s a hub for Croatia Airlines and many other European carriers, including Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Volotea, Vueling, and Wizz Air, serve it on a seasonal basis. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, an up-to-date layout, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.36, requiring at least 3.94 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350724</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases Airbus A350 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350724"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a1789bec8bb4bc29f9939d_a3501.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently uploaded a teaser video and an in-depth development update of their upcoming Airbus A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, one of the most awaited addons for the platform so far. The short teaser video reveals some of the 3D art-focused details, along with a glimpse of the systems and sounds. Like their A300-600R, the A350 will feature fully modeled engine interiors, openable cowlings, and more. Users will be able to manage all possible maintenance options via EFB. The wear and tear system, also seen on the A300 to some extent, will be heavily improved. It will feature dynamic weathering of the aircraft, with paint peeling off the rivets, oil, and dirt streaks around potential leakage areas, dirt and grime on flaps, and more. It is said to build up as you fly the aircraft.  The cockpit features the same attention to detail, with PBR materials, high-resolution textures, and heavy optimization work to reduce VRAM usage without compromising visual quality.  Concerning the realism of the aircraft due to the apparent lack of data available, iniBuilds has said that—contrary to popular belief—there’s “quite a bit” of data around for core systems and overall functionality. To fill all the gaps, the missing spots were covered by renting a full-motion A350 simulator for multiple hours. They have also gathered twelve dedicated A350 experts to serve as a complimentary source of information. iniBuilds claims it will be not only visually stunning but will also far exceed anything else they have produced.  They have also made a FAQ section with many frequently asked questions regarding their upcoming aircraft and its features.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/300724</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes A300B4 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/300724"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a17f6e3df02ac1d8e38e9a_a3006.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a new development update on their upcoming A300B4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, covering their latest visual work on the cockpit. ‍ Their lead artist has been working hard for the past four months on recreating the remaining sections of the A300B4’s cockpit, taking into account every individual gauge, screw, knob, and panel, all with custom weathering and discoloration as per their reference aircraft. With the work now complete, Just Flight will be teasing new bits of the cockpit through the remaining development updates, starting with the center pedestal. ‍ They have authentically recreated the Carousel IV Inertial Navigation System (INS) Control Display Unit (CDU) on both sides. For those wishing for a more modern offering, the UNS-1 FMS will be an option. ‍ The following bits to be showcased are the stabilizer trim wheels, the speed brake lever, a flap/slat lever, the throttle levers, fuel cut-off switches, the parking brake handle, and some buttons. Lastly, the communications suite has 2 VHF control units, a transponder unit, two audio selector panels, weather radar controls, ADF navigation radios, and lighting controls.  The next development update will focus on the forward panel and autopilot.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/init33</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces T-33 Jet Trainer for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/init33"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a1853986721289168989ad_t331.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds, working alongside SimWorks Studios &amp; AceMaker aviation, has announced the development of a T-33 Jet Trainer for Microsoft Flight Simulator, part of their new “Premier” product line. Their Premier aircraft team comprises exceptional, high-quality 3D artists and programmers, as well as experts (pilots and engineers) who excel in crafting general aviation aircraft. The new project aims to further push the boundaries with extensive flight dynamic testing, greater system fidelity, and highly detailed visuals.  The T-33 is a turbojet training aircraft used by over 20 different air forces around the globe. Since its introduction, it has served a variety of roles, from an initial jet training platform to drone director, and even saw combat action during the Korean War! ‍ The upcoming add-on will feature highly detailed textures, an in-depth systems simulation, true-to-life handling characteristics, and a fully functional cockpit where every switch is operable. It will be available in two cockpit configurations: classic and modern, with a matching avionics suite. The complete feature list follows below: Exterior Art Features list:  Interior Art Features list: The expected release window is sometime around mid-August, and media partners will be allowed to showcase it a few days earlier. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777725</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777725"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a2c531c13d76899b69652f_update2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG recently issued a new update to their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing more stability improvements and mitigating another freeze-inducing code issue. Update 2.00.0041 is another micro update, focusing solely on stability improvements and error mitigation, as they are now switching their focus to wrapping up the upcoming 77F for beta testing. The changelog follows below: ‍ The 777-300ER is still under approval for the marketplace rollout. A testing build will become available early next week, and if things go well enough, it could be released in early August.  Last week’s 737 lineup update will become available for marketplace customers later today, bringing it up to par with the PMDG.com version. The same applies to the DC-6 texture update. Regarding implementing the new feature set from the 777 into the 737, the work is set to take place after the 77F is released. They plan to bring over the new navdata format and the new EFB functionality, which will take place through a series of updates as the work gradually passes through their testing process. Other 777 features, such as the new cabin lighting, openable cockpit windows, etc., still need to be evaluated and might or might not be carried over. ‍ The 777-300ER is available on PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/male25</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Velana International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/male25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a2d0bcd2991b5b9e31315f_male1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Velana International Airport (VRMM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Malé in the Maldives with a yearly average of 4 million passengers as of 2019. The airport started as a small strip of land on the island of Hulhulé in the early 1960s, with a runway made of slotted steel sheets. Four years later, the government and the residents started a joint effort to build a new asphalt runway, with four districts competing for a money prize for the fastest. Over 100 volunteers enlisted, and the runway was officially opened two years later. A decade later, the tourism boom in the Maldives led to the need for an international standard airport, and they figured it would be easier to upgrade the former Hulhulé Airport rather than build an entirely new one from scratch. With help from the International Airports Authority of India, the new airport was completed in 1981. Expansion work was carried out for the first time in 2018, with the construction of a new runway to serve longer aircraft. Although initially only used as a taxiway, it eventually got to serve its truthful purpose with the demolition of the old Trans Maldivian Airways seaplane terminal, which was in close proximity and not within international standards, therefore blocking the runway from being utilized. The demolition and eventual greenlight for usage only happened four years after completion. A new seaplane terminal was inaugurated in 2022 to replace the demolished one. It can accommodate more than 100 planes and handle up to 300 flights per day.  A new passenger terminal is also under construction and set to be completed in 2025. It will be over 78,000 square meters and handle up to 7.3 million passengers a year. It’s a hub for BeOnd, Maldivian, and Trans Maldivian Airways. Aeroflot, AirAsia, Air Astana, Air India, Air Seychelles, Austrian Airlines, Bangkok Airways, Batik Air Malaysia, Beijing Capital Airlines, British Airways, China Eastern Airlines, Condor, Discover Airlines, Edelweiss Air, Emirates, Etihad Airways, FitsAir, flydubai, flyme, Gulf Air, Hong Kong Airlines, IndiGo, ITA, Kuwait Airways, LOT, Malaysia Airlines, Manta Air, Neos, Oman Air, Qatar Airways, Royal Jordanian, Saudia, Shirak Avia, Sichuan Airlines, Singapore Airlines, SriLankan Airlines, Thai AirAsia, Turkish Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, Vistara, WizzAir, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed seaplane base, the new terminal (still under construction in real life), interior modeling, custom night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on their website for roughly $21.68, requiring at least 1.20 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/320232</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates Airbus A320 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/320232"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a41da33330d51949727e3e_installer3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update to their rendition of the Airbus A320 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes bug fixes, improvements, and a new installer. A brand new installer has been developed to speed up their release and update process. It breaks files into smaller parts and only fetches the parts that have been altered, significantly speeding up the whole process. They have gathered comparison data, and the difference is astounding: from 2 minutes and 14 seconds total (download and installation) to 35 seconds (fastest result). They also reiterate that the figures may vary depending on hardware specs and storage speed. The sounds have also seen a rework, with binaural microphone recordings straight from a captain’s headset during a full flight, with cross-referenced ADS-B data to ensure the audio matches the correct phases of the flight. The result, balanced and adjusted accordingly, is much closer to the real thing. They have also improved the over- and behind-wing experience with new N1 bearing recordings, airflow, N2, and behind-intake buzzsaw on the CFM56s. They also have done further sound balancing on IAEs, with new airflow recordings, buzzsaw improvements, and a new window vibration/rattle on both at high power settings. The atmospheric sound model also received its fair share of refinement. Different ambient conditions influence the engine sounds, as demonstrated in the video below, which showcases the difference between a takeoff in the cold and dry versus hot and humid. Last but not least, still regarding sound improvements, Fenix added two hydraulic pump options: Vickers and Parker, as per the real thing (it can be fitted with either), and their subtly different sounds. The systems and flight model were not massively improved due to their strong focus on the upcoming expansion (A319 and A321). Still, they have improved the ADIRU wind simulation, so the airplane gathers wind data through its sensors rather than fetching it through the simulator. The fly-by-wire was made slightly smoother in pitch while retaining precision, and the ground-to-air blend was made creamier. The full changelog follows below: ‍ The Fenix A320 is available on their website for roughly $64.33. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fss727</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Announces Release Date for Boeing 727-200F Add-on</title>
    <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fss727"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a6b1d07204103b480e16cc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio recently shared new information on its Discord about the upcoming Boeing 727-200F add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The developer revealed details about the release date and price of the aircraft. The new 727 by FSS is now set to be released to the public on August 6th at around 08:00 UTC. Originally, the release was planned for the end of July, but the team has decided to delay it slightly to ensure that the aircraft includes all the necessary last-minute updates before the release. Moreover, the team has announced that various content creators, both big and small, will have access to the aircraft on August 1st at 00:00 UTC. This will allow everyone to have a proper look at the upcoming 727 before its public release. It's important to note that the GNS-XLS, initially scheduled for the first release, will be delayed to allow for improvements to the INS system. The GNS-XLS will still be added to the aircraft, but it is expected to be included 1-2 months after the initial release. Lastly, the team has announced that the long-awaited Boeing 727-200F will be priced at $42. The upcoming aircraft will be available in just 8 days, and Threshold will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orgthd</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases MSFS Global Trees HD for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orgthd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a755c101aeca5c1a18e946_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released its newest add-on, MSFS Global Trees HD, for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This add-on, created by developer Dmytro Krykunov, aims to enhance realism by replacing all standard vegetation with high-quality specimens. The add-on allows users to customize and shape the landscape in Microsoft Flight Simulator according to their preferences. It offers features such as the ability to manage project data, change vegetation seasons, and replace the default grass. Dmytro designed the add-on to ensure that the biome and its vegetation are vibrant, diverse, and of high quality. MSFS Global Trees HD comes with various features, including high-quality replacement of default vegetation, the option to change vegetation seasons, the ability to replace default grass with six new types of grass, reworked biomes, and a software tool to adjust vegetation seasons and grass types. This add-on requires 2.78 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx for approximately $13.90. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/heca12</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Cairo International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/heca12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a7b13265af9e261ed19cb7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released the X-Plane 12 version of Cairo International Airport (HECA). Following the release of its MSFS version, the team has now launched their rendition for X-Plane 12. Cairo International Airport serves the capital of Egypt, Cairo, and is situated approximately eight nautical miles from the city's central business district. The airport handles an average of 14 million passengers annually. The airport originally opened as John Payne Field Air Force Base during the Second World War. After the war, the airport was taken over by the Civil Aviation Authority, marking the start of its use for civil aviation. It eventually replaced the former Heliopolis Airport. Today, the airport has three terminals and serves as the hub for the airlines EgyptAir, Nile Air, Air Cairo, and Air Arabia Egypt. Additionally, a variety of other airlines operate to and from the airport, providing connections to destinations worldwide. The newly released Cairo International Airport for X-Plane 12 comes with a variety of features, including highly detailed models, SAM animated jetways, high-quality PBR textures on objects and ground, complete autogen around the airport, ground traffic, weather textures, and more. The scenery requires 1.87 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for about $25.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fxsjer</id>
    <title>Fly X Simulations Releases Jersey Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fxsjer"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a7e55a7fe96da13811c771_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly X Simulations has just released its version of Jersey Airport (EGJJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It is located in Saint Peter, Jersey, and connects the largest of the Channel Islands with both domestic and international destinations. Jersey Airport was opened in 1937 when the States of Jersey decided to construct an airport with four grass runways. During the Second World War, the airport was taken over by the Admiralty and used as a Naval Air Station. The Luftwaffe occupied the airport and added concrete taxiways and hangars. In 1952, a tarmac runway was installed which led to the closure of the grass runway. Over the years, the runway has been extended and reached a length of 5.560 feet in 1976, which remains the same to this day. The airport is now a hub for the airline Blue Islands and serves various other airlines including British Airways, Eastern Airways, and easyJet. Annually, the airport welcomes around 1.3 million passengers and handles approximately 17.000 aircraft movements. The scenery package is feature-packed with accurate and highly detailed airport buildings, an extensive and detailed terminal interior, high-resolution custom PBR textures, custom ground markings, and more. The newly released Jersey Airport requires 1.62 GB of storage space, and it is available on iniBuilds for approximately $15.44. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdsvix</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Previews Vitória Airport &amp; City for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdsvix"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a9231acfd405410bb2e675_background72.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently previewed their rendition of Vitória - Eurico de Aguiar Salles International Airport (SBVT) and its surroundings for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Vitória in Espírito Santo, Brazil, with a yearly average of 3.2 million passengers. Originally built in the 1930s, it was not until a decade later that it would get its first passenger terminal and a paved runway. Heavy renovation work, including a new passenger terminal and runway, was carried out in 2005. Although scheduled to be completed in 2007, a series of scandals led to a "temporary" halt for nearly a decade. Construction work only resumed in 2015 and concluded three years later, in 2018, sixteen years after the original planning.  A few years before the resumption of the expansion works, the airport's operator, Infraero, deemed it the country's worst airport. Operated by Zurich Airports AG since 2019, the new airport finally meets international standards and swiftly leaves its dark past behind. Azul (Belo Horizonte, Campinas, Recife), Gol (Brasília, Porto Seguro, Rio de Janeiro, Salvador, São Paulo), Latam (Brasília, Rio de Janeiro, São Paulo), and Voepass (Porto Seguro) serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a highly detailed terminal, city POIs, custom ground clutter, and more.  There's no information on pricing and release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737730</id>
    <title>iFly Shares New 737 Max Previews for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737730"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a9774c93f217c7f163769e_max1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iFly has recently shared another set of images from their upcoming Boeing 737 Max 8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing its flight deck, cabin, and externals. The development state is said to be far along to the point it can already complete a full flight, but it’s not yet in official beta. Other than that, the developers did not share any further information. They have also set up a Discord server to facilitate communication with current and future customers regarding their new product. Furthermore, they uploaded a cabin walkthrough video, from rear to front, into the flight deck. There’s still no information regarding pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/darmal</id>
    <title>David Rosenfeld Previews Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/darmal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a97bf1ae35da8173e5f8c5_mal1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. David Rosenfeld recently previewed the interior work on his rendition of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Milan metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 26.1 million passengers. The site where the airport was built has more than a century of aviation history, with records dating back to 1910 when the Caproni brothers flew their Cal biplane. It became a popular prototype testing site in Italy, eventually leading to its upgrade to an actual airfield.  During that same period, the Caproni brothers decided to build a factory there, and Giovanni Augusta followed suit. It became the largest aircraft production center in the country. The airfield hosted two Royal Italian Air Force squadrons in the following decades.  In September 1943, the German Luftwaffe captured the airfield, building its first concrete runway, which didn't last long: the airfield was heavily bombed during WW2.  With the retreat of the German forces from Italy and the eventual end of the war, the runway was rebuilt and extended to 1,800 meters. A small terminal was built to shelter passengers and cargo from adverse weather conditions. Its official inauguration was in 1948 as Aeroporto Città di Busto Arsizio, and Sabena and TWA were among the first international carriers to serve it. In 1952, now under the control of the municipality of Milan, it was decided that Malpensa would become Milan's international airport, and Linate (Milan's other airport) would handle domestic services.  Milan's main airport needed a respectable terminal, which was built between 1958 and 1962. The runways were also extended and were the longest in Europe at the time.  Even though their original intent was to make Linate domestic-only, major European carriers preferred it over Malpensa because it was closer to the city center, transforming it into a secondary airport for over 20 years.  Things only changed in the 1980s when Linate was forcibly downgraded to domestic, and Malpensa underwent heavy upgrade work. Construction started in 1990, and it only reopened eight years later. ‍It's an operating base for AlbaStar, easyJet Europe, Malta Air, Neos, Ryanair, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air France, Air India, AirBaltic, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad Airways, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. The developer has said that work on the interior is moving forward at full speed, and the goal is to finish it within a few weeks. Then, he is going to focus on the apron. A release date was not shared at the time, but he's aiming for late fall/early winter. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom jetways, custom terminal interiors, custom ground textures, and more. There's no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/maastr</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Maastricht Aachen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/maastr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ac06874de014b56e05e7cc_aachen1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently released their rendition of Maastricht Aachen Airport (EHBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Maastricht in the Netherlands and Aachen in Germany. As of 2022, it was the second busiest cargo airport in the Country, handling 108,000 tonnes of cargo. Plans to build an airport in southern Limburg (near Maastricht) started in 1919, but it didn't come to fruition until much later due to debates with various municipalities over its location and funding. It wasn't until 20 years later that an agreement was reached to back the project financially, but the start of World War 2 put the plans back in the drawer. In early 1945, the USAAF Ninth Air Force decided to build a temporary airfield in the area, using rubble from an unintentionally bombed city to level the area. Its first runway was around 1,700 meters long and reinforced with pierced steel planks. The whole construction work took an impressive two months to complete. Due to its completion closely matching the war's end, there wasn't any combat to speak of being operated out of there. It was rapidly transferred to the Dutch government in early August 1945 and named Beek Airfield. The first terminal was built in 1947, and the main runway was paved two years later, followed by a second runway in 1950. The Dutch Air Force offered help in 1951 to further expand the main runway and add night lighting (which only happened nine years later). Commercial operations greatly expanded in the late 50s/early 1960s, bringing operators such as KLM, Airnautical,Skytours, Euravia, Tradair, and Transair.  In the early 1970s, the airport was expanded again to accommodate larger aircraft. The runway was lengthened to 2,500 meters, taxiways were widened, and the aprons were made bigger.  The 1980s brought a new passenger terminal and ATC tower. The same terminal is still in use today, albeit significantly expanded since. Corendon, Pegasus, Ryanair, and Tarom serve it. Cargo-wise, it's often visited by Emirates SkyCargo, MASkargo, Qatar Airways Cargo, Royal Jordanian Cargo, Rom Cargo Airlines, Saudia Cargo, Turkish Cargo, and Zimex Aviation. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom-modeled terminal, custom aerial imagery, custom static aircraft, custom night lighting, custom taxiway signs, custom ground vehicles, PBR textures, and an up-to-date ground layout as of 2024. ‍ It's available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $13.56, requiring at least 3 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carpvp</id>
    <title>CloudSurf Asia Releases Puerto Princesa International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carpvp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66adfb7c4f131c862f06e6ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CloudSurf Asia has recently released its version of Puerto Princesa International Airport (RPVP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the province of Palawan, Philippines, the airport serves the area of Puerto Princesa. The airport welcomes just over 1.1 million passengers annually. Built by American prisoners of war during the Second World War, the airport was under construction from 1942 to 1944. After completion, the airport was used by Japanese transport aircraft alongside a former grass airstrip located near today's NCCC Mall Palawan. After the liberation of Palawan in 1945, various units from the US Army Air Forces were stationed at the airport. It wasn't until 1947 that Puerto Princesa opened and started with air travel. Since then, the airport has seen a variety of airlines and aircraft, and has also undergone several expansions and improvements due to the increasing demand for air transportation. Today, the airport is an operating base for Air Juan and serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific, Philippine Airlines, and Philippines Air Asia, with nearly 9000 aircraft movements and around 1.1 million passengers yearly. The newly released Puerto Princesa International Airport for MSFS includes a variety of features such as up-to-date airport data, a fully modeled terminal with an interior, full custom objects around the airport, custom ground markings, full PBR textures, and more.  The add-on requires a total of 0.99 GB of storage space and is now available on Orbx, SimMarket, and iniBuilds for approximately $15.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
