<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-11-20T18:37:15.075841+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simnaples</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Naples Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simnaples"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69148bc9792bec67bae9a6fb_naples1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimPixel has recently released their rendition of Naples International Airport (LIRN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Metropolitan City of Naples, Campania region, with a yearly average of 12.6 million passengers, making it the fourth busiest airport in Italy. The airport started its life in the early 1900s as “Campo di Marte”, a little airfield for general aviation, occasionally hosting flight exhibitions. World War 1 had the airport become a military airport to defend the town against the Austro-Hungarians and Germans. Then it saw heavy usage again during World War 2, this time by the United States Army Air Forces and the Royal Air Force, and later became a major transshipment hub for cargo. The commercial debut occurred in 1950, marking the official opening of “Naples Airport”. It serves as an operating base for easyJet, Ryanair, Volotea, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Arabia, Air Cairo, Air Canada, Air France, American Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Eurowings, Finnair, flydubai, FlyOne, Iberia Express, Israir Airlines, ITA Airways, Jet2, KLM, Lufthansa, Luxair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Smartwings, Swiss International Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, TUI, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution PBR textures, highly detailed terminals and hangars, dynamic night lighting, custom ground layout, static aircraft and ground equipment services, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $22.34, requiring at least 5.71 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dflrhode</id>
    <title>Dreamflight Studios Teases Rhode Island T. F. Green International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dflrhode"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69149283cd8f81afb4f9405d_rhode1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Dreamflight Studios has recently teased their rendition of Rhode Island T. F. Green International Airport (KPVD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Providence, Rhode Island, with a yearly average of 4 million passengers.​ It was dedicated in 1931 as Hillsgrove State Airport, and its first passenger terminal was built in 1933. Its original layout consisted of three 910-meter-long concrete runways. ‍ It was used for flight training by the United States Army Air Force during 1942 and 1945, hosting the 435th Army Air Force Base. ​ The World War II occupation period led to several upgrades, including runway extensions (300 meters each) and slightly improved infrastructure. In the 1960s, a new terminal was constructed, as the old one was insufficient to handle a metropolitan area with over a million people.  ​ It wasn’t until 1996 that it would see another upgrade, entirely replaced by a new passenger terminal with 18 gates. Four extra gates were added in 1997. ​ It’s a hub for Wiggins Airways and an operating base for Breeze Airways. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, BermudAir, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express serve it. ​ There’s no pricing information available yet, but it is expected to be released sometime this week. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/car390rel</id>
    <title>Carenado Releases B390 1A for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/car390rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6902655801dc90c1d37b973b_beec.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has recently released their rendition of the Beechcraft B-390 Premier 1A for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a light business jet first conceived in the mid-1990s.  The Beechcraft B-390 Premier 1A was an updated version of the Premier 1, which was designed in the mid-90s, first flown in 1998, and certified in 2001. The IA was almost like a real-life patch to fix some lingering issues with the project, such as the subpar brakes, the noisy cabin, and the cockpit, which was deemed below par by many. The aforementioned upgrade rolled out in 2006, and over 163 new Premiers were built in five years. The little jet is powered by two Williams FJ44-2A Turbofan engines. It cruises at 841 km/h, has a range of 950 miles, a service ceiling of 41,000 feet, and, depending on the configuration, can carry 6 to 7 passengers. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $24.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/deckardisreal</id>
    <title>Valve Announces New Standalone VR Headset</title>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/deckardisreal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6914de99bfc475b5609e04e0_frame.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Valve Software has recently announced their new hardware lineup for early 2026, including a Standalone Virtual Reality headset running Steam OS and capable of functioning as a PCVR headset via streaming.  Originally codenamed Valve Deckard, the Steam Frame is Valve’s first entry into the standalone headset market, following its pioneering role in mainstream PCVR headsets with the launch of the Valve Index in 2019, which is still widely used in 2025 and is considered one of the best headsets ever made. With 16 GB of unified LPDDR5X RAM, a 4nm Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, UFS storage options ranging from 256 GB to 1 TB, dual LCD panels featuring a 2160x2160 resolution each, and pancake lenses, it rivals the best offerings from Meta and Pico.  Furthermore, the Steam Frame comes with its own 6 GHz dongle for PCVR streaming, and the addition of foveated streaming (possible thanks to the presence of eye tracking) will allegedly improve the streaming efficiency tenfold, as they can dynamically increase the pixels where your eyes are focusing on and lower the pixels where it’s not needed, making the image streaming as efficient as possible. ​ The controllers work on one AA battery each, and the analog sticks are magnetic, preventing the dreadful “stick drift”, a known enemy to most virtual reality players.  As previously mentioned, the new headset will run on SteamOS, and Valve will implement a “Steam Frame Verified” system (similar to what they did with the Steam Deck), allowing players to check whether the game they want to buy is compatible with their headset. Alternatively, streaming flat-screen titles from your PC will also be an option. ​ There is no release date or pricing information available yet, but Valve has mentioned that it will ship in early 2026. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inimansoon</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Upcoming Manchester International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inimansoon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69175431a4ba6fed33289f51_iniman1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently shared new previews from their upcoming Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, developed in cooperation with the airport authorities. Their next addition to the British lineup is nearing completion, built with extreme attention to detail using thousands of reference photos and textures. They also gained insight into their daily operations, future expansion plans, and design updates, which helped them further increase overall accuracy. Furthermore, they have also gained access to Terminal 2, which is still under construction, photographing every detail to ensure the scenery is as close to the real deal as possible. iniBuilds also thanked the community for their help, as it was a community-driven effort, with ramp staff, engineers, and even real-world pilots contributing as much as they could with reference imagery and feedback. The scenery will feature hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life landside recreation, dynamic airport lighting, custom jetways, over 180 hand-crafted models, a full HD ground poly, an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. ​ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but iniBuilds says it’s “coming soon” and streamers will be getting their hands on it shortly. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkshelv2rel</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Helsinki-Vantaa Airport V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkshelv2rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691759cf8e315639349f692b_hel1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently released their updated rendition of Helsinki-Vantaa Airport (EFHK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Helsinki metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in Finland. The airport was built in the early 1950s to replace Helsinki’s former main airport, Malmi, which was considered too small and unable to handle the ever-increasing passenger figures.  For its first four years of existence, Helsinki-Vantaa was a single-runway airport. The second runway was only built in 1956, together with the first airplane hangar. Regular jet operations started three years later, in 1959. A new terminal opened in 1969, followed by the first transatlantic service to New York later in that same year. In 1993, an exclusively domestic terminal was built, and the international terminal was expanded and merged with the domestic terminal in 1996. Three years later, the international terminal underwent further expansion, accompanied by the creation of an arrival and departure lobby. Yet another runway was inaugurated in 2002, and the international terminal underwent its third expansion in 2004. In 2009, Terminal 2 was expanded with a total floor area of 43,908 square meters. Later that same year, the administration decided to remove the terminal-specific division between domestic and international flights, replacing it with a division based on airline. ​ In the early 2010s, the airport’s passenger figures skyrocketed, prompting further expansion work, which started shortly after. By 2012, a new terminal expansion had already been completed, and Terminal 1 and 2 were combined in 2022. It’s a hub for Finnair, Norra, and Norwegian. Aegean Airlines, Air France, airBaltic, Eurowings, Icelandair, Japan Airlines, Juneyao Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Luxair, Pegasus Airlines, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Sunclass Airlines, SunExpress, TUI Airways, TUI fly Nordic, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality terminal models, custom jetways, an up-to-date ground layout, real-world elevation data, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.91, requiring at least 4.10 GB of free hard disk space to install. V1 owners get a 30% discount. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/n707nv</id>
    <title>Nimbus Shares New Preview of Boeing 707 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/n707nv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69179dd49e6d293daa358bd7_707-2024-08-2313_43_51%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has released a new work-in-progress video, showcasing its upcoming Boeing 707 for X-Plane 12, with a focus on the JT3D powerplants. The footage highlights the characteristic fan roar and exhaust scream that defined early jet travel, giving a first taste of the audio experience the team is aiming for. According to Nimbus, the 707 is being built as a high-fidelity recreation of the classic three-crew jet. The aircraft features carefully modelled and textured visuals, with wing and engine vibrations, rattles and shakes, driven by physical forces, to provide visual cues about what is happening outside the cockpit.  Additional animations will depict the movement and complexity of mechanisms in the wings, tail, and landing gear. On the systems side, Nimbus plans to simulate all major systems, based on original manuals and available references. Meanwhile, the flight model is being tuned using performance charts and pilot testimonies to capture the hands-on feel of the era.  A virtual crew is also planned to assist with flow and system management, helping to reduce the workload for one simmer operating the aircraft alone. Nimbus has not yet announced a release date for the Boeing 707, but development updates will continue to be shared via its forum and Discord. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dffwindsor</id>
    <title>Dfflyer Releases Windsor International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dffwindsor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6917ad305ddc49e2ef2abbdb_windsor1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Dfflyer - a new scenery developer in the scene - has just released their first scenery: a rendition of Windsor International Airport (CYQG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Detroit-Windsor region with a yearly average of 330,000 passengers. It opened in 1928 as Walker Airport, after Hiram Walker, a Canadian whiskey distiller and distributor. It joined Canada’s national portfolio of airports in 1967, when it was recognized for its regional importance as a hub for Southwestern Ontario.  Since early 2007, the airport has been managed by an ad hoc group on behalf of the City of Windsor. This arrangement followed the request by the last operator, Serco Services Inc., for early termination of their airport management contract in 2006, as the airport was losing 40k USD monthly. The new administration had a better fate, managing to post a small profit instead, and has since been granted an indefinite contract. It’s served by Air Canada Express, Air Transat (to start in late 2025), Cameron Air Service, Porter Airlines, and WestJet. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom taxiway and runway lights, custom ground service equipment, custom cars, a high-quality rendition of the main terminal and all hangars, and more. It’s available in their store for roughly $12.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcsbal</id>
    <title>OnReTech Announces DCS: Balkans Map for 2026</title>
    <updated>2025-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcsbal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691a5dc6fd17d3b64286d8cc_In_Dev_07.11.2025.6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. OnReTech, the team behind DCS: Sinai, has announced its next terrain for DCS World, DCS: Balkans, developed in partnership with Eagle Dynamics,  and currently planned for a 2026 release. The map is designed to recreate NATO air operations over the former Yugoslavia between 1991 and 2001, with players able to fly as either NATO or Serbian forces.  It will cover large parts of the Balkans, the Adriatic Sea, and sections of Italy, combining varied coastlines, numerous islands, and several major mountain ranges, including the Dinaric Alps, Apennines, and Dolomites. OnReTech plans to include a broad mix of urban centres such as Venice, Dubrovnik, Belgrade, Zagreb, Trieste, Bari, and Rijeka, connected by highways and rail networks.  Alongside this, a range of military airbases and civilian airports will be located across Italy, Serbia, Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Kosovo.  The newsletter specifically highlights Aviano Air Base, home to the United States Air Force 31st Fighter Wing, and Venice Marco Polo Airport. The map is designed as a suitable theatre for aircraft such as the F-16C and MiG-29A, and will be accompanied by further additions to the popular Currenthill asset pack, including a Grisha-class corvette for coastal and anti-submarine operations, and an AI-only EC-665 Tiger UHT attack helicopter. You can check out the full newsletter here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff777fnw</id>
    <title>Flight Factor’s 777 Freighter Expansion to Launch This Week</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff777fnw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691b4f0bc917354639e486ce_freight1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Factor has recently teased their upcoming 777 Freighter Expansion for X-Plane 11 and 12, scheduled to launch this week. The long-awaited freighter expansion for Flight Factor’s 777-200ER V2 Ultimate is a week away from the virtual shelves, and selected streamers have already received preview keys from Flight Factor to showcase the product.  In similar fashion as of the 772, Flight Factor’s 777F will feature a deep systems simulation, a proprietary flight model within 2-5% of standard certification tests, true-to-life dimensions, authentic systems, a new weather radar, a custom sound system with 3D stereo engine sounds, a failure and maintenance system with over 1,000 simulated failures, an advanced EFB with SimBrief integration, and much more. ​ There’s no pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf146v242024</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s 146 Professional v2.4 Releasing by the End of the Month</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf146v242024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691b50f142dd4063fed49569_bingo1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently provided a brief development update on their 146 Professional v2.4 update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing full compatibility with the latter and introducing brand-new features yet to be revealed. The development process is nearing completion, and the team aims to release it by the end of the month for both platforms. As usual for Just Flight, this will be a free update for existing owners, and new buyers will benefit from a temporary discount upon launch. ​ They claim it’s the most substantial upgrade yet to the 146, bringing it up to pair with the RJ Professional in terms of features and realism. They will soon be sharing more photos, videos, and the “massive” changelog. ​ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssoct</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Studios Shares E-Jets Progress for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssoct"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691b9a91a7bb9844e03f0331_Another-ejets-header.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flight Sim Studios (FSS) has released a development update on its awaited E-Jets overhaul for MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, highlighting progress on the custom FMS, improved navigation behaviour, and the final pieces still in the works. The new version has been in testing for several months, and according to FSS, with over 88 testers, logging more than 2,000 recorded sessions, identifying 64 issues, and prompting over 350 code changes. The aircraft, the studio says, is now fully flyable in normal operation. Major FMS pages are implemented, LNAV tracks reliably, and VNAV is already functional. Integrating Navigraph navdata proved to be one of the biggest hurdles, forcing a rebuild of the entire ILS system, but the team reports that it is now “rock solid”. Significant fixes have also been made to SIDs, STARs, and unusual procedure types, along with a much-improved Direct-To function. Before the wider community can try it, the remaining blocker is the suite of vertical autopilot modes, which are still being refined to ensure stable behaviour. With LNAV now fully rebuilt for the new CFMS, the vertical logic is the last major component that can still misbehave, particularly during RNAV approaches. Sound logic and the EFB’s performance calculator also remain unfinished, as both require systems to be migrated from older frameworks. FSS plans to invite another 100 testers shortly. If progress on the autopilot continues at its current pace, the team aims to release an experimental, public build in December. This version will ship with a few known gaps, including missing sounds, such as the TO CONFIG check, and the temporary removal of the performance calculator. However, it is already described as being far more enjoyable to fly than the existing E-Jets release. Regarding a full v1.0, the developer is not yet ready to set a release date. Instead, they emphasise delivering the significantly improved version as soon as possible, regardless of what the eventual update is called. Read the full update here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mplbud</id>
    <title>MicroProse Updates B-17G Flying Fortress to v0.9.2 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mplbud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691ba7a575592fdcf3ae01bc_579314912_1273604118139836_1757491807982642047_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse and Just Flight have released the second Early Access update for the B-17G Flying Fortress in MSFS 2024, titled the “Long Beach” update (v0.9.2). The new build continues to refine the heavy bomber, focusing on cockpit detail, performance, and a few long-requested quality-of-life tweaks.  On the visual side, the developers have overhauled internal texture ambient occlusion baking, refined the internal 3D mesh, and resolved several internal LOD issues. Externally, various texture fixes and updates have been applied, and a new empty bare-metal livery has been added. Under the skin, the update adjusts the centre of gravity, applies further flight model and aerodynamic improvements, and corrects both the manifold pressure and vertical speed gauges, so that they now use the proper units. Spawning on the runway now loads the aircraft with all four boost pumps enabled by default, which should make quick-start operations in MSFS 2024 a little smoother.  The “Long Beach” patch follows October’s “Seattle” update, which addressed LODs, mesh, and texture issues, as well as aircraft weights and dimensions. It also significantly reworked the fuel, engine, and system setup, laying much of the groundwork for the current round of refinements.  Existing owners of the Early Access B-17G Flying Fortress can download version 0.9.2 from the “Your Orders” section of their Just Flight account; new buyers will receive the latest version by default. You can get it here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atanov</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Publish Third A340-600 Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atanov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691c75750c7856e803322d60_videoframe_8778%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft and ToLiss have recently released the third development update for their Airbus A340-600 Pro series in Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update continues the deep dive into aircraft systems, with ToLiss head Torsten explaining the intricacies behind hydraulics, air, and avionics, hosted by Aerosoft's Rafi. Indeed, the Hydraulic systems were a key focus, with Torsten detailing how the four engines feed into three hydraulic circuits, including redundancy measures and the limited capacity of the ram air turbine. He noted that the user would see slower flap movement or gear extension under low-pressure scenarios, reflecting real-world limitations. The air and bleed systems were also discussed, illustrating how four engines distribute air into two systems, which in turn impacts fuel flow and engine behaviour. Each engine is simulated with unique tolerances, meaning oil pressure, temperature, and acceleration rates vary. Attention then shifted to avionics, including the three MCDUs, which mirror the real aircraft’s functionality. Only two can connect to the flight management system at a time, while the third, situated further back on the console, supports ATSU functions and acts as a backup. Display reconfigurations and redundancy were also covered, ensuring failures behave as they would in reality. The electronic flight bag (EFB) was also discussed, which appears to integrate the same principles as ToLiss’s previous EFB system for X-Plane. Here, you can control loading, ground services, performance calculations, Navigraph charts, and SimBrief connectivity. Situation and auto-saving are also included in the EFB. Finally, the team showcased their implementation of a taxi camera. While limited by MSFS technology, Aerosoft and ToLiss have adapted satellite imagery overlays to provide taxi guidance, calibrated to the aircraft’s position.  This marks the conclusion of the current interview series, with Aerosoft confirming future showcases, including a livestream featuring a real A340-600 pilot.  The product was also showcased over the weekend, at Aerosoft’s FS conference in Paderborn. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fel742f</id>
    <title>Felis Releases Boeing 747-200F for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fel742f"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691cca02c9fde2f6172b8175_369346_X-Plane_58fBpGHBM2_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Felis has just released the highly anticipated Boeing 747-200F for X-Plane 12 The Boeing 747 needs no introduction. It is one of the most iconic aircraft ever built, and the -200 variant is the second most sold variant, following the -400. The Boeing 747-200F is the freighter version of the -200. Most of the remaining Boeing 747-200s are freighters, with the exceptions being two Iranian aircraft - one for the air force - and six that operate for the U.S. Air Force, two of which serve as Air Force One. The Felis Boeing 747-200 has been one of the most popular high-quality aircraft add-ons for X-Plane for years. The new freighter variant includes a fully modelled main cargo deck, side cargo doors, and the iconic nose cargo door. Additionally, the cockpit has been updated for freighter operations.  Felis states that the freighter variant is constructed with the same level of detail as the passenger variant, featuring a few new system variants, including the optional tape-style instruments. The Felis 747-200F is available now on the x-plane.org store for $70. Owners of the passenger variants are eligible for a $30 upgrade price. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blsend</id>
    <title>Boundless Simulations Officially Shut Down</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blsend"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691cf7b7de61e51621520b29_image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Boundless Simulations has now closed its online store, bringing an end to the studio’s five-year run as one of X-Plane’s most prolific scenery developers.  The shutdown follows a July message from founder Lew, who explained that real life had taken over, and that the studio would shut its doors, with the store staying open until November. That deadline has now passed, and the storefront has quietly disappeared, leaving only the Discord server, which remains open for now. Boundless began in 2020 as a bedroom project, and went on to produce an enormous catalogue for X-Plane, covering everything from tiny Irish helipads to major airports, including Dublin, Stansted, Inverness, Faro, and Bournemouth.  Along the way, Lew used the income to fund his flight training, eventually securing a place on the A320 flight deck, something he openly credits to the community that supported the studio. A handful of Boundless products seemingly remain available through the iniBuilds store, though only select titles, and not always in their latest versions.  With the storefront now gone, we see quite an influential developer finally leave the scene. With a remarkable number of airfields built over the years, the legacy of Boundless will certainly be remembered for a long time. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
