<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-12-29T18:21:16.277219+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfcuv</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases City Update V</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfcuv"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65820d3883b577c78dbc2d7e_cuv.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator has recently released a new update with a curated selection of renowned European cities, developed in conjunction with Bing Maps and Vexcel. City Update V: European Cities 1 includes five urban regions throughout Europe: The Hague (Netherlands), Brussels (Belgium), Košice (Slovakia), Zagreb (Croatia), and Cádiz (Spain), developed with the latest geographic information and triangulated irregular network surface modeling.  The update is free to all owners of Microsoft Flight Simulator on all platforms. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfces</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases Cessna T207A Stationair</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfces"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65821348c28a5038b6c0724c_station.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator has recently released the new iteration of their Famous Flyer lineup: the Cessna T207A Stationair, a legendary light civil utility model with over 600 airframes built over 15 years of production (1969-1984). The Cessna 207 is the eight-seat variant of the Cessna 205/206, which was essentially a Cessna 210 with fixed landing gear and changes to the crew and passenger door arrangement. With a slightly longer fuselage (114 cm) and a nose section extension, it could fit more seats and more luggage, transforming it into the ideal flying wagon. Its real-world usage case varies from air taxi applications to skydiving, aerial photography, and private use. The airplane is powered by a Continental TSIO-520-M, producing up to 310 horsepower, a range of 671 miles, a cruise speed of 185 miles per hour, and a service ceiling of 26,000 ft ASL. The add-on features three variations: cargo, standard, and skydiving, with 20 liveries in total.  It’s available on the Marketplace for $14.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avifre</id>
    <title>Aviotek Software’s Frankfurt International Airport for MSFS Releasing for Free in 2024</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avifre"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6582186983be7bde6b7f6cdf_aviotek1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Software has published a development update where they thank the community for providing feedback, testing, and reference images and offer a rendition of Frankfurt International Airport (EDDF) as a “thank you” gift to be released in the near future.   They have been working on optimizing the user experience, increasing the level of detail, improving texturing, models, and some of it was shared with the community, which are the pics that illustrate this article.   Aviotek asks the community to “bear with them for another month” while they add the final touches (jetways, etc.) before an eventual release. They also invite people to apply to beta-test the scenery before its release (testing is set to begin in January 2024).   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737087</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737087"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65822614fd49bb24eeafab0b_1250410_20231218213033_1.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Update 3.00.0087 is now available for PMDG.com customers, bringing a list of fixes to their Ultimate Flight Tablet for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  PMDG’s last product update for this year is mostly minor, aiming to “squash a few items that we felt were disruptive,” according to Randazzo’s own words. The next update will be available in a few weeks, focusing on adding more functionality and features, as previously promised. The changelog follows below:   12817: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Navigraph map-type choice (IFR low/high/etc.) should be persistent (rmurdoch) 12610: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Save users pref of aircraft symbol in settings (rmurdoch) 12832: [EFB - Performance and Computational] New menu data for 777 (cbpowell) 12635: [EFB - General] Day/Night should default to most applicable and allow over selection please (rmurdoch) 12831: [EFB - General] Make signal bar reflect currency of airplane pings (rmurdoch) 12569: [EFB - General] Utilize MSFS built-in airport data for OPT (rmurdoch)  PMDG had mentioned in their last development update that the update would be submitted to the marketplace as soon as it was made available for PMDG.com customers. Still, its intake process might take longer than usual because of the end-of-the-year holidays.  PMDG’s aircraft lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $64.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ppbs</id>
    <title>PixelPlanes and Aerosoft Release Breezer Sport</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ppbs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6582ad4c0e257519f9956a22_05.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PixelPlanes and Aerosoft have released their newest project, the two-seat ultralight Breezer Sport. The release comes just days after the initial product announcement.  The Breezer Sport as mentioned above is a 2-seater ultralight aircraft and features a full aluminum construction with a Rotax 915 iS/iSC power plant. The German-manufactured Breezer has a cruising speed of 145 knots and a maximum range of 755 nm. The aircraft also features a retractable landing gear. ‍ Pixel Planes and Aerosoft's rendition of the Breezer Sport features an authentic interior and cockpit, modeled after the original specifications from Breezer Aircraft. The aircraft features several animations and ground objects, this includes the opening/closing of the canopy as well as a removable safety pin and pitot cover. The cockpit features a full glass panel with integrated AS3 touch systems and a simplified RSFlight EMU for displaying engine information. The Breezer Sport can be purchased from the Aerosoft website for $22 USD.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for all your flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/justfl</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes End of Year Update</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/justfl"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65831c8acc65189f9829ca6b_A330%20DETAIL2.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has taken to their website and Facebook to provide a comprehensive update on all projects expected for release next year. The news bulletin covers all projects, indicating that Just Flight has almost every corner of the aviation market covered for the coming year. From general aviation to heavy airliners, it is evident that next year will be a busy one for Just Flight. The team has outlined a list of aircraft in production, all slated for release in the upcoming year. Starting with the highly-anticipated release of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, Just Flight vows to commit to ensuring product compatibility and development for Asobo's upcoming simulator. Airliner projects were thoroughly covered with updates and new previews, such as the A300B4 Professional, which was revealed at FS Expo last year. The team is diligently working on finishing the extensive texturing of the flight deck and exterior model, paying attention to every imaginable detail, including a reworked modeling of the nose section of the aircraft. System coding has made significant progress, with the completion of the electrical, air bleed, air conditioning, pressurization, APU, and fuel systems. These systems, like their real-life counterparts, will respond to environmental factors. Progress is ongoing, with the team aiming to provide every detail, down to individual weathered texturing for screw heads. Updates don't stop with the A300, as the RJ Professional is next in line to be released. Just Flight reports significant progress in coding and systems completion, highlighting new systems matching differences between the older 146 and the more modern RJ. Visually, the RJ will feature a high-density 3+3 layout with a full range of animations and sounds. A preview of the cabin is provided below.  The F70/100 Professional is also making progress, with a current focus on reworked texturing from new reference photographs, ensuring an unprecedented level of detail. Various details, such as certain switches and knobs, have been remodeled. The progress continues with animations, lighting, and systems integration.  Finally, an update to the 146 Professional is expected early next year, including the UNS-1 FMS and a reworked detailed cabin from the RJ Professional. This update is currently under beta testing, with more information expected closer to release. Furthermore, the Blue Bird Simulations' 757 is still scheduled for next year, with Just Flight stating that the team is "also incredibly busy" working on the "flying pencil." Just Flight covered general aviation projects, starting with the Piston and Turbine Duke by Black Square, nearing completion. Thandra Designs will collaborate with Just Flight to update their X-Plane 11 fleet to X-Plane 12 standards, utilizing all available features of the simulator. The Duchess, being the first on XP12 list, will feature 8k textures and modern texturing effects inside out. Animations will also be reworked, with reactive animations responding to G-forces and air resistance. Additionally, Just Flight’s new EFB will make it to the X-Plane 12 model, providing controls over airframe features. This update aims to breathe new life into the X-Plane version of the Duchess. Not all projects are progressing as well as hoped, with the Tomahawk project facing setbacks. Just Flight stated that the Tomahawk project stalled but is now at the center of their attention, bringing it in line for their next GA aircraft release for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The in-house team is working on upgrading the interior and exterior modeling and texturing, as well as systems. Expect fully functional avionics stacks, including the GMA340, SL20, SL40, the GX28 transponder, as well as GPS options. On the military side, Just Flight’s Tornado GR1 for MSFS is also making progress. The "Tonka" is being worked on by the same team that brought us the incredibly detailed Avro Vulcan. The same level of detail and passion is being applied to the Tornado. The team has remodeled many parts of the aircraft to bring higher detail and accuracy, with texturing receiving highly detailed 8k treatment as well. Coding is next on the team's list. The Tornado team will be tasked with transferring the Hi-Fi code from the Prepar3D Tornado to MSFS. During the transfer, new features and improvements will be added to bring as much operational accuracy to the real aircraft as possible. Also, Expect 24 paint schemes to be released with the Tornado. Just Flight is wrapping up and preparing for a busy 2024 for the flight sim community, with releases covering all spans of aviation. They express gratitude to the community for its support throughout 2023 and wish everyone a "Very Merry Christmas and health and happiness in the New Year." To see the full update page see follow this link. As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/omduin</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Skydive Dubai Airport &amp; Landmarks for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/omduin"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65832780830573b451c6c96f_skyline.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has just released the OMDU Skydive Dubai &amp; Landmarks package for MSFS, marking day three of their Winter Wonderland Event and winter sales. This package covers the Skydive Dubai airport and prominent landmarks across Dubai's skyline with high-resolution detailing. Notable features encompass 23 Marina Tower, Address Beach Resort, Atlantis the Palm, the Burj Khalifa, and more. Additionally, custom ground vehicles and sea vessels have are also included. The primary aim of this package is to provide users with an immersive experience of flying as a skydive drop pilot within the Dubai area. Key features of the package include the intricately modeled OMDU Dubai Skydive Airport by Fykky, a fully modeled JBR Beach area, and a range of iniBuilds assets such as the Yacht, Jet Ski, vehicles, and iconic police cars. The inclusion of brand-new lighting technology further enhances the visuals of prominent structures like the Coca-Cola Arena, Five Hotel, Ain Dubai Observation Wheel, Blue Water Island, AI Habtoor City, Burj AI Arab, Burj Khalifa, and more. The buildings included in the package are, 23 Marina Tower, Address Beach Resort, Address Boulevard, Address Sky View, Atlantis The Palm, Atlantis The Royal, Cayan Tower, D1 Tower at Jaddaf Waterfront, Dubai Frame, Dubai Mall, Elite Residence, Index Tower, Jumeirah Emirates Towers, Marina 101, Marina Gate, Museum of the Future, Ocean Heights, One Za'abeel Tower, Princess Tower, and The Palm Tower. The iniBuilds OMDU Skydive Dubai &amp; Landmarks package is available for FREE download via the iniBuilds store. Stay tuned to Threshold for more news on iniBuilds' Winter Wonderland Event!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidub</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Dubai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidub"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658467223da901a657da2f7a_dubai.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Dubai International Airport (OMDB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in the world with a yearly average of 88 million passengers. ‍ It was opened in 1960 after one year of construction work, with a 1,800-meter runway made of compacted sand, which was enough for most airplanes. Three years later, they began constructing an asphalt runway with 2,800 meters of total extension, followed by the construction of hangars, installation of navigational aids, and passenger terminal improvements.  To prepare for the wide bodies in the 1970s, a new terminal was built with an enclosed floor area of 13,400 square meters. Then, the existing asphalt runway was lengthened to 3,810 meters, along with some upgrades to allow the operation of Boeing 747s and Concordes. The second runway opened in April 1984.  Terminal 2 opened in 1998 as part of the 1997 development master plan. The second stage, Terminal 3, began in 2004 and reached completion four years later, with a two-year delay and a cost of 4.55 billion USD.   The arrival of the Airbus A380 led to a $230 million investment in adapting some of the stands for the aircraft. Concourse 3 followed soon after, increasing the passenger handling capabilities to 79 million a year.  It’s a hub for Air India Express, Emirates, FedEx Express, flydubai, and IndiGo. The visitors’ list includes Aegean Airlines, Aeroflot, Air Canada, Air France, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Cebu Pacific, China Eastern, China Southern, Cyprus Airways, Eurowings, Finnair, Iran Air, KLM, Korean Air, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Smartwings, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and Wizz Air.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a hand-crafted ground poly, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, correct taxi signage, an up-to-date layout, custom low-poly static aircraft, LOD optimization for optimal performance, custom GSX profile, and configuration options.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $25.30, requiring at least 4.44 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nav023</id>
    <title>Navigraph Publishes Community Survey 2023 Results</title>
    <updated>2023-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nav023"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65860f70516bf40cc54356e3_survey2023.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has recently published the results of their yearly Community Survey, with answers from 23,376 participants worldwide. From the most played flight simulator to the most popular graphics card among flight simmers, they got all our questions covered.  Microsoft Flight Simulator leads the 2023 popularity chart with 70.8% of the respondents using it as their primary flight simulator, followed by X-Plane in second with 13.1%, and Prepar3d in 3rd with 4.6%. The gap has widened compared to 2022, where Microsoft Flight Simulator already had a comfortable lead, but X-Plane 11 had 23% of the respondents playing it frequently, and 12 around 15%. While Navigraph has taken a slightly different approach to quantifying the most popular platform this time, it’s visible that X-Plane has lost a chunk of its relevance in 2023.  Regarding features most valued in an add-on aircraft, 38% of the respondents said aircraft system complexity, followed by realism and authenticity with 26.6%, and flight model accuracy with 17.4%.  The GPU results for this year were relatively surprising, with the RTX 4090 topping the charts at 14.5%, closely followed by the RTX 3080 at 11.5% and the 3080Ti at 10.3%. The only AMD card from the list is labeled “AMD Radeon,” with 4.5% of the respondents owning a GPU from the red team. Nvidia shows clear dominance in the flight sim realm, reflecting their overall lead in the global GPU market.   According to the respondents, the best flight simulation release of the year is the PMDG 737 with 11.2%, even though it was not released in 2023, followed by the Fenix A320 with 9.7%, which also was not released this year. A2A Simulations’ Comanche 250, released in 2023, is third with 8.8%.   The most anticipated products for 2024 are the PMDG 777 (29.2%), Fenix A319/20/21 (12.3%), and the FlyByWire A380 (11.3%). Surprisingly, MSFS 2024 sits at 6.6%. On that Flight Sim 2024 note, respondents were asked about their expectations for the upcoming simulator, and 27.9% said performance optimization, 20.2% said improved graphics and realism, and 16.8% wanted weather engine improvements.   To check out the full results, please visit this page.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcej</id>
    <title>X-Crafts E-Jets Family Updated to Version 1.0.4</title>
    <updated>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcej"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6587404303d2dc32a4c7cd53_E-JETS_FAMILY_BY_X-CRAFTS_EXTERIOR_0002.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts, well-known for their lineup of Embraer aircraft for X-plane, have released an update for their E-Jet series. The update focuses mainly on improvements to the autopilot and FMS but also includes many updates to other parts of the planes.  In a post on the X-Plane forums X-Crafts have outlined the new update that has focused on “minor but annoying issues.” The post also teased a large feature update coming in 2024. The full update list contains almost 100 overall changes, you can find the full list here but we’ll be focusing on what X-Crafts have listed as the main changes. It seems as though the main focus of this update has been the flight management and autopilot systems and adding functionality that exists in real-world aircraft including things like FLCH now being limited to +2° up while climbing and -7° in descent, updated approaches that include x and y designations allowing for users to be able to follow approaches more accurately. An effort has also been made to help the aircraft run more smoothly overall by changing how often the fuel predictions on the FMS progress page updates, before the update it would do the calculation every frame, it has now been changed to every 5 seconds allowing for an easier CPU load. The FMS updates also include some quality-of-life fixes with features like the localiser and ground speed selectors staying active after disconnecting the autopilot. X-crafts have also made changes to the aircraft systems in preparation for the planned steep approach mode, this includes changes such as improved speed brake indications on the EICAS.  X-Crafts are also offering a time-limited discount for those who have purchased either of the V2.5 E-jets. This offer is only valid through  May 10th, 2024 and grants a 15% discount towards the purchase of the full E-Jets collection, pricing for the different purchase options can be found on the X-Crafts website. Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for the flight simulation news that matters to you!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gkfa</id>
    <title>Golden Key Studio Releases F-111 Ardvark For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gkfa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65874afa4e4124d02bf27138_chrome_MD6qQXfE8R.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Golden Key Studio (also known as GKS) have released their rendition of the F-111E Ardvark for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The release comes just days after the most recent update on the project’s development.  Originally developed by General Dynamics in the early 60s the F-111E, nicknamed the Ardvark, was a pioneer for the development of features that would become a staple of modern combat aircraft. The Ardvark was the first production aircraft to feature variable-sweep wings. The platform also played a pivotal role in the design of modern after-burning engines. The Ardvark first entered service with the USAF in 1967 with the Australian government later purchasing the E variant of the F-111. While the RAAF only ever deployed their F-111s as a deterrent the USAF flew over 4000 combat missions in both the Vietnam and Gulf wars. The USAF retired their F-111s in 1996 while the RAAF had theirs in active service until 2010.  ‍GKS promises users of the F-111 will experience an authentic flight model with impressive graphics and a highly detailed cockpit featuring accurate aircraft systems. GKS has kept the development of the Ardvark pretty quiet overall, and while there isn’t a ton of information available on their latest offering it is expected that it will be up to the same standard as their MiG-21.  For more flight simulation updates be sure to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini350</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini350"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6587af32a96680102a68f5a8_Screenshot%202023-12-23%20at%2011.10.21%20PM.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer iniBuilds has announced their next major project — A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The unveiling, released as part of iniBuild’s 2024 roadmap, comes as a surprise for the community and adds to the developer’s lineup of upcoming aircrafts that includes the A380 and the A300-600R. ‍ According to iniBuilds, the team has already been working hard on the A350 over the past few months and, as shown in the WIP previews provided, has completed a great part of the plane’s exterior modeling. The finished product is expected to feature both the -900 (2 winglet options) and the -1000 variants.  In addition, iniBuilds is currently looking for individuals such as pilots and engineers who have experience working with the A350 in effort to improve the realism of the final product. ‍ Currently, the iniBuilds is forecasting a release date sometime in 2024, though a specific date is yet to be announced. Threshold will keep you updated on the progress of the A350, including its features, pricing, etc. </summary>
    <published>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfmt</id>
    <title>Got Friends Releases Freeware Mozzie Mk III</title>
    <updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfmt"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6587b774045c2647b0ef9bc8_MOZZIE_2_1800x1800.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Got Friends, who you’ll know from their F4F Wildcat and Double Ender project, have released a new freeware helicopter for Microsoft Flight Simulator with a purpose.  Got Friends has developed the Mozzie Mk III as a way to help fundraise to help the father of one of their developers who needed emergency brain surgery to save his vision, you can read more about the situation on the family’s gofundme page. As of writing the freeware project has raised over $350 through the gotfriends website with others donating directly to the gofundme.  The Mozzie Mk III is a single-seat ultralight helicopter with an open cockpit. Powered by a V-twin motorcycle engine the Mozzie is designed as a conventional tail rotor helicopter and as such is capable of autorotations. Overall the Mozzie is a very easy helicopter to fly and the perfect introduction for anyone wanting to learn how to fly them in the sim. You can download the Mozzie and donate directly to the gofundme through the Got Friends website.  On behalf of the writers and staff at Threshold, I’d like to wish Scott a quick and easy recovery, our thoughts are with the entire Yaeger family this holiday season.  </summary>
    <published>2023-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmp777</id>
    <title>PMDG Previews Upcoming 777 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmp777"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658a0b264e4124d02b1cff0e_t7.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published another development update with further information on their upcoming Boeing 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with four new screenshots showcasing its external model.  Randazzo strongly emphasizes the modeling work placed on the triple seven, with accurate color distortions according to the viewing angle, visible and detailed rivets, and surface irregularities around the joints of the radome and the forward gear doors.  ‍  The tail area also brings great detail, with visibly different looks between the surfaces made of carbon fiber and aluminum.  ‍  They also report their upcoming product performs almost the same as their 737 lineup, meaning it won’t be particularly demanding despite the alleged 3D model improvements.   The fly-by-wire simulation, with its control laws and inherent oddities, is said to be accurately represented. Failures will be a possibility, too.  It’s still undergoing beta testing, with more than 200 reports so far during the first phase of testing, half of which were already fixed, according to Randazzo.   More previews will be shared with the community in the days and weeks ahead, and they seem “happy with the pace and character of the testing they have been doing thus far.”  There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fswl35</id>
    <title>Flysimware Learjet 35A for MSFS releases for Early Acess</title>
    <updated>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fswl35"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658d98d750a91e0a7c257086_sV2UWfE.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flysimware has released their Learjet 35A into early access. The learjet 35A, which was previously available in P3D, has been updated to take use of new features found in MSFS. According to Flysimware users of the older FSX/P3D version will notice this product to be more accurate with a steep learning curve to understand the compex systems of the aircraft.  The Learjet 35 first flew in 1971 ands started production in 1973, with the upgraded Learjet 35A starting production in 1975. The learjet 35 is a light business jet that can carry about 8 passengers. The learjet 35A is an upgraded version of the airplane with more powerful TFE731-2-2B engines and upgraded avionics. The 35A also supported wing-tip fuel tanks that extended the range of the aircraft to around 2,700 Nm.  The Flysimware Learjet 35A is currently in early access, with no manuals or tutorials included at this time. Flysimware stated that the product is flight worthy, however a discord is available to discuss systems and aircraft bugs, updates will be available to address bugs before the final release. The FSW Learjet 35A currently supports the Asobo Garmin 530 as well as both the PMS/TDS GTN 750.  To join this early access period for the Flysimware Learjet 35A, head over to the Flysimware Store. The cost to join the early access is $39.99 USD and will include an update to the final release when available. For more information about the product, see the Flysimware Discord.  </summary>
    <published>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniuae</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniuae"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658e3c811516bf3a35353721_inia300.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of the Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the modern and longer version of the classic A300, certified in 1984 and still operating today for many cargo airlines and a few passenger airlines.  The Airbus A300-600 is an extended version of the A300B2 and B4, with two additional rows of seats, powered by two General Electric CF6-80C2 engines, and making use of the A310 cockpit, with no need for a flight engineer like the older A300s. 313 A300-600s were sold between its inception and 2007, when production stopped.  The add-on features authentic systems, a custom FMS, custom VNAV and LNAV, custom hydraulic, pressurization, electric, and fuel systems, a maintenance system with cautions and warnings triggered by ignoring it, realistic RNAV, and autoland capability. The flight model is tuned to represent the aircraft’s behavior and intricacies accurately.  The textures are PBR and up to 8K quality, with lower texture packs available for lower-end systems. The cockpit and external models for the passenger and cargo variants were entirely reworked.  The sound environment is fully tridimensional, using real recordings of the engine and cabin switches.   Additional features include an Electronic Flight Bag, a basic ground handling set, and pre-set cargo loads with visual models.  It’s important to note that the PW engine variant and CPDLC/ACARS will be available later.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.55, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
