<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-04-22T18:27:55.943821+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crj948</id>
    <title>ADSimulations Announces CRJ900 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crj948" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/624fe3a082d9c95c7c6151b8_01.thumb.jpg.c53c14e8709c8c846aa98f93835a283c.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="55747"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer ADSimulations has announced their next project for X-Plane 11, the Mitsubishi CRJ-900! The larger CRJ follows the developers growing line of aircraft, following their original CRJ-700 release.  The Mitsubishi CRJ-900 is an extended variant of the CRJ-700 base model in the Bombardier Aerospaces' regional jet product line. It features 1,553NM of range, can accommodate up to 90 passengers, and cruises at Mach 0.82. The plane is used in various environments worldwide, though it can be found in excess with American, Delta, Lufthansa Cityline, and SAS. Unfortunately, ADsimulations hasn't shared any additional information with us except that they'll release the product within the next few weeks, and complimenting the release will be an update to their CRJ-700.  Stay tuned with Threshold, as we'll keep you updated with the latest and greatest from ADsimulations.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kontxp</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Ontario International Airport for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kontxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62521870f27b8619508ec77a_Screenshot_13-1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1002348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, developer Verticalsim released Ontario International Airport (KONT) for X-Plane 11. The scenery, featuring PBR textures, HDR lighting, and custom ground traffic, will serve as a fantastic gateway for pilots who are planning to visit the beautiful state of California or looking for a major cargo hub to fly their new MD-11 or A300. According to the product’s store page, Verticalism’s rendition of Ontario Airport will be based on the latest layout of the airport, including the recently added Fedex ramp. The scenery will feature SAM jetways, highly detailed models, custom lighting, and “usage of LOD’s for optimization”. For a complete list of features, check out the developer’s website. Ontario Airport, located in San Bernardino County, California, is a public airport that serves as both a passenger and cargo hub for the region, as well as the alternative landing site for LAX. It is home to airlines such as American and Delta and cargo carriers such as UPS and Fedex. In 2018, KONT saw some 5 million passengers and an average of 65 flights per day. Currently, Ontario International Airport for X-Plane 11 can be purchased on Verticalsim’s webstore for $24.99 USD, excluding any sales tax that may incur. To successfully install the product, users must download the SAM plugin and have at least 3.51GB of free space on their hard drive.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg41</id>
    <title>PMDG 737 for MSFS Enters the "Home Stretch"</title>
    <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg41" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6253da417c450e0a47cc1efe_image_15778.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437320"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo at PMDG Simulations has taken to the developer's forums to give more insight into the 737 for MSFS development progress. The team is nearing the end of the initial testing phase of the 737-700 and will hold a meeting next week to finalize the release date. (the above photos are sourced from PMDG's March 15th 737 update) Contextual Information PMDG intends on including the MAX product line to complement the Next Generation products. The initial release product will be the PMDG 737-700, which will consist of the passenger, cargo, and BBJ variants of the aircraft, featuring a multitude of winglet styles, configurable options, and PMDG's classic realism. The team will release an additional variant of the 737 product line in approximately six-week intervals, including 737-600, 737-800, and 737-900 for MSFS.  "Customer Driven Ideas" Every 737 variant will be sold separately to allow customers more flexibility to acquire the models they desire instead of purchasing variants in a large package. Another idea touted by customers was that the team intends to treat the release phase of the 737 as if it was early access. Most features will initially be available in the aircraft, but a few features won't be possible to delegate to the product line until the product releases. These product updates will be available in two-week intervals during the initial 24 week release period.  Features That'll Be Added After Release or Excluded Altogether. The aforementioned updates will be available to users at no cost via updates to the products.  What's Included in the 737 Products? Essentially, the aircraft will contain numerous features, with customized performance data, accurate flight modeling, complete flight management, realistic autopilot, and functioning LNAV, VNAV. "How is the performance?" Performance "remains quite good" the 737 should run fine if your setup can already handle other third-party aircraft. Randazzo's rig, featuring an early i9 and 2080Ti, can run the 737 well at default airports. He provided Drzewiecki Design's RNT as an example, which offers 40-45fps with the 737 in-sim, and default airports such as FMEE provide mid-to-low 50s.   Discounts Users should not expect any discount/trade-in or upgrade programs for the 737 product line, except for one scenario. If you purchased the 737 NGXu for P3D when the team offered a transition program for those who desired to buy the MSFS 737 at release, you would receive a $99.99 credit towards purchasing the 737 MSFS product line. This credit offer only applies to those who purchased the NGXu before December 31st, 2019.  Product Pricing is TBA at the Moment Final Thoughts Robert has shifted his focus to recording some videos to showcase the aircraft's depth and features (PMDGs YouTube channel). He mentions that this series will not be a tutorial but rather "serve as small bites of information that will allow you to quickly see the depth of features available to you as a PMDG 737 product line user." Beta testers will be able to share information and media about the upcoming aircraft beginning of next week.  As we all await the forthcoming news from PMDG in the coming weeks, stay tuned with Threshold as we report on all the news originating from the simulator world. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rkch41</id>
    <title>ACO Design Studios Releases RCKH for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rkch41" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6253dee6de4061db98b6db4a_293472_KHH_01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="362497"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer ACO Design Studio has released their second scenery for the new simulator, Taiwan Kaohsiung International Airport! The airport appears to take full advantage of MSFS' landscape, with custom terminals and surrounding environment. Kaohsiung International Airport (RCKH) is the second busiest airport in Taiwan, following Taoyuan. In 2018, it served nearly seven million passengers, with service from air carriers such as EVA, China Airlines, Japan Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines. The airport also serves as a hub for China Airlines, EVA, Uni Air, Mandarin Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan. RCKH contains one runway, at 3,150m or 10,335ft.  You can purchase ACO Design Studios Kaohsiung International Airport on SimMarket for 19.50EUR/21.18USD/16.25GPB. It will also be available on the MSFS Marketplace in May, as Microsoft is still processing the scenery. </summary>
    <published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rv14fs</id>
    <title>SimWorksStudios Releases RV-14 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rv14fs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62550ca89aaaf9df3572d8a5_RV14-01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="175010"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorksStudios have officially released their rendition of the RV-14 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With a variety of features accessible to users, this aircraft is a keen addition to MSFS's General Aviation market.   Touted as an aircraft with many pristine features, Van's RV-14 features a wide variety of features for real-world pilots to experience. The aircraft ships in two variants, the RV-14, and the RV-14A. Visually the difference is the main variant is a taildragger, whilst the A variant is not. With a high fuel economy, fast speed, and a comfortable flight deck, this aircraft offers much of a pilot's dream.  SimWorksStudios have provided a feature list upon release. Starting, all variants of the RV-14 have been included with 3 different liveries. The 3D model and animations all replicate the real-world aircraft, plus the flight dynamics of the aircraft have been tested by real-world pilots. All MSFS icing and rain effects are compatible with the aircraft. Alongside this, GTNS750 compatibility with both PMS50 and TDS is available. If you'd like the full feature list, you can check it out on the aircraft's product page.  If you are interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can purchase it over at the SimWorksStudios Website, selling for €14.99. If you are interested in other products by the same development team, you can check out their website to view their catalog of products.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/macafs</id>
    <title>Macco Simulations Release Cancun International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/macafs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6256e4f3e5996a22e6d51ed5_MMUN.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1025424"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The team over at Macco Simulations have released their visual rendition of Cancun International Airport (MMUN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. With MSFS' beauty, this package enhances the area and the airport for all virtual visitors worldwide. Opening in 1974, the Cancun International Airport has two parallel runways and serves as a hub for Latin America carrier MAYAir, and is a focus city for Volaris and VivaAerobus, offering routes to over 20 Mexican airports, and serves other routes to over 30 countries. The airport is Mexico's second busiest airport after Mexico City, and is Latin America's third busiest airport, with serving over 22 million passengers in 2021. Upon release, the team has provided a feature list of what is included in this package. Firstly, PBR materials have been used throughout the model, with utilizing 4k textures. A basic terminal interior has been modeled, alongside custom lighting and static vehicles across the airport, with the inclusion of fully custom jetways. If you are interested in the full feature list, you can view it below: If you are interested in picking this scenery package for yourself, you can find it over on the Macco Simulations Website and sells for $15.99. If you are also interested in other packages by the team, you can check their product catalog on their website as well.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bl75u1</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Posts 757 Developmental Update</title>
    <updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bl75u1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62591260ee673a6005c89915_Screen%20Shot%202022-04-15%20at%201.33.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="868480"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, BlueBird Simulations posted the first development blog on its upcoming 757-200/300 series aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The short update brings the latest on the team’s progress, new previews of the aircraft, and a quick glimpse of the developer’s plans down the line. The development update, released 2 months after the aircraft was first announced, revealed that “exterior model (including textures) is around 50-60% complete”. In addition, the developers reported that work on the 757’s systems and flight dynamics are progressing as planned, though they will not be ready to share details on them for another few months. Finally, Bluebird Simulations teased that a new development update will be released every 4 to 6 weeks. BlueBird Simulations’s 757 will feature two variants of the aircraft: the -200 with RR/PW engines and the -300 with RR/PW engines. According to the developer’s website, the aircraft will be equipped with everything from custom-coded systems to 4k PBR textures. Check out a previous Threshold article to learn more about the product. Currently, the developers are yet to announce a firm release date or pricing for the aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmtrfs</id>
    <title>M'M Simulations Releases Tromsø Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmtrfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62599ab136b78adabc54ea22_TromsoCover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="809180"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. M'M Simulations have released their visual rendition of Tromsø Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Touching down in the Scandinavia region, the team has brought their skills to the airport and its surrounding area. Being established in the 1930s, the airport was first operated by Norwegian Air. As the European Theater of WW2 began, the airport began servicing the Junkers Ju-52 for the German Luftwaffe and they began the expansion of the aerodrome. After the war, the Norwegian Air Force took over operations and began adding expansions to the airport. Years later, the Norwegian Parliament approved construction for public passenger services, with the airport opening to the public on the 14th of September, 1964. The team has included a small, but down to the point feature list. Starting, the team has accurately modeled the surrounding area and the airport grounds, alongside accurate terraforming and CGL data. PBR textures have been added, and a modeled interior for added user experience. Ambient animated objects and an upcoming terminal have been all included.  If you are interested in picking this scenery package up for yourself, you can find it over on the simMarket Store and sells for €19.00. If you are interested in any other renditions by the team, you can view their catalog on their website.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bruclo</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Inches Closer to Release With Brussels for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bruclo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625d44557c579403c3ea7e55_bro.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3582917"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has returned with another major airport, soon to be released for Microsoft Flight Simulator, hopping over to Brussels with a detailed rendition of the namesake airport, the team has released a trailer for the product, signalling a close-to-release stage of the development. The project has been through an extended development period since the earlier days of MSFS, and the recent developments and news on the forums has portrayed a project status that's closer to the end of the tunnel. In typical Aerosoft fashion, their development house has brought a vividly detailed recreation of the airport, featuring a well-rounded replica of the terminal complex and its interior. It will also boast some unique features such as assisted docking. It has not been confirmed that the system will work for all aircraft types, but further details regarding the feature may be confirmed as we approach the release of the airport. Brussels Airport, which has the ICAO code EBBR, served almost twenty-five million passengers in Europe in 2019 making it Europe’s 24th busiest airport. The main airline to serve the airportis the country’s flag carrier, Brussels Airlines, which operates an all Airbus fleet including the A319, A320, and A330. Aerosoft has not disclosed a price however they confirmed that they will be selling in their store very soon.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737rel</id>
    <title>PMDG On Approach to Release for 737-700; Remains Tight-Lipped On Release Date</title>
    <updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737rel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625d54e2d60a955d6adc601f_ayo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="906428"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG is reaching the end of the tunnel in the development of their hotly-awaited 737-700NG3. On their forums, Robert Randazzo detailed that the team remains bullish for a timely release, but is still reserved on setting a concrete release date due to several factors adding “ambiguity” to the project’s completion, and the upcoming Sim Update 9 from Asobo additionally brings more uncertainty to the add-on’s stability with potential issues that is unforeseeable. Randazzo explained that a lot of logistics are involved in preparation for enabling the team to adapt to SU9, one of which is ensuring a stable testing environment to avoid a “negative initial user experience”. A lot of details are yet to be finalised, including the release date which not even the team has a concrete answer internally, there is an “entire evaluative process” taking place to pinpoint a date. That said, RSR reassured that the product’s launch will not be a surprise drop in store, a release date with possibly an approximate time of day will be announced prior to the release. As the team approaches the final leg of the 737-700’s development, Randazzo optimistically said that things will become much more exciting between now and the product’s release. The embargo will be lifted so testers of the add-on can share and provide additional new insights into the product, streamers who got ahold of the aircraft will have their embargo lifted as the plane is released.  To kickstart the beginning of the hype building, the team is currently releasing a series of walkthrough videos on the 737-700 on their YouTube channel, with an introductory video published already (embedded on top). A few hours ago, another video is published detailing the Tow Out and plans after the release of the aircraft: More videos will steadily be published in the coming days and weeks. Moving on, Randazzo has shifted to discussing the sounds that are developed for the add-on. Armen, who is principally behind the soundset, has been developing a “sound-scape” to match the visuals and systems fidelity of the rest of the aircraft. Stressing that the sound engine that MSFS used is “unlike anything they have every[sic] had the opportunity to work with”, to which Armen has used the engine to its full potential. Randazzo wraps up the update by assuring that this will be a monumental release, both for the team and the flight sim community; the talent behind Vin and Jason to develop the most visually, and technically faithful 737 for MSFS combined with the delightful sonic experience from Armen that brings the bird to life. To read the original update, visit their forums.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrfam</id>
    <title>Pyreegue &amp; Family is Safe and Well; Development Still Going Strong</title>
    <updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrfam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625ec87a2e2ad36e5e3e0292_owo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1616642"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Ukrainian developer Pyreegue has dropped an update providing a short raincheck on his whereabouts and his family in light of the Russian Invasion of Ukraine. The war brought much disruptions to the developer's (and many others) way of life, fortunately, the developer confirmed that he and his family are safe. As things are beginning to settle down for Pyreegue - he is now back to work on his current projects for MSFS. The developer assured that he has not fallen behind in his commitment to his projects regardless of the happenings around the flight sim community in that extended period of time. For this update, the developer is previewing some of the new modeling for current scenery projects and a reworked set of static aircraft: Wrapping up the weather update, Pyreegue thanks everyone for their support, including Orbx, who has put effort to support Ukrainian developers hosting their products on their store.  “Once again, I can’t thank you enough for being there in my time of need, for what you guys and the team at Orbx did to help me overcome this misery, I wouldn’t be where I am today without people like you. Thank you.” For the original update with more pictures, visit the forum thread comment.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bnddub</id>
    <title>Boundless Simulations Confirms Release Date for Dublin</title>
    <updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bnddub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625ecb12fd7f46025a6de66b_uwu.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="285355"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless Simulations has confirmed the date that they will be releasing their “most ambitious project yet” which is Dublin Airport. According to the scenery developer, they are “well on track” and are aiming to bring the scenery to their store on Friday, May 13th. Boundless has ramped up their effort to increase product quality by implementing more detail than ever before, in line with most modern scenery releases of today, the scenery will be laid with up to date satellite imagery sourced near the end of last year along with a detailed terminal model containing interior modelling for added depth. Boundless now employs the popular SAM plugin to animate its custom jetways. Finally, the rest of the landscape is decorated with custom vegetation. Here is the full feature list: This release date is provisional but one that Boundless “intend to stick to”. The developer has also confirmed that the product will cost £19.99 which is “cheaper than any other alternative payware Dublin scenery”. There has been no word on whether they will be selling it on any other broker's website other than their own just yet. Nonetheless, we’ll keep you in the loop on further developments to this project. Stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sbwapl</id>
    <title>SimBitWorld Teases A Pilots Life V2 Screenshots</title>
    <updated>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sbwapl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625ee30eeb0310b9de2a5e55_APL01.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="202953"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimBitWorld, developers of "A Pilots Life" have posted a new showcase on their Facebook page regarding the next generation of the plugin. With a complete overhaul of features and new additions coming in the near future. The company CEO, Ovidiu has teased various features of APL v2 for the past few months, showcasing various UI overhauls along with features making a reappearance in the new version, alongside new features that will be making an appearance. The team is expecting a release sometime in spring or summer of this year. A Pilots Life provides users an immersive experience into the world of a commercial airline pilot. Whether it be in regards to passenger or cargo operations, the plugin provides and tailors to the user. You make your way up through the airlines, completing routes, with various aircraft. As you gain experience, you have the option to move to more major carriers, and have the option to earn more virtual money. No complete feature list has been provided at this time. The project is currently in its beta stage of development, and Ovidiu is planning on making his deadline for release, which he has yet to disclose.  You can purchase A Pilots Life over on the simMarket for a limited discount price of €8.38, after which the product sells for €16.75</summary>
    <published>2022-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p737ea</id>
    <title>PMDG Outlines Early Adopter Model for MSFS 737</title>
    <updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p737ea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/625fa99cc9935bf720cf1049_Screen%20Shot%202022-04-20%20at%201.34.51%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="865174"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, PMDG published a lengthy blog, detailing its plans for the release of its much anticipated 737NG series for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Through the blog, the developers explained in detail the Early Adopter model they will utilize for their upcoming products and outlined a general release plan for its 737s. According to PMDG, the Early Adopter model will be implemented for the first time to give the developers additional time to fully master the new technologies brought by MSFS, allowing them to gradually implement features that they couldn’t provide in the past. In the Early Adopter Period that starts with the initial release of the -700, “new features, bug fixes, model and texture improvements, performance optimizations, and increasing MSFS integration will be rolled out in update intervals spaced approximately two weeks apart”. During this time, the -600, -800, and -900 will also be released, with new updates being made available to all four variants simultaneously. In total, the developers expect this period to run a total of 24 weeks, ending around 6 weeks after the release of the -900, though it may be extended if needed. The developers stressed that the airplanes will be fully functional during this time and this period will enable them to “expand it beyond the initial capabilities delivered”. Additionally, PMDG will be providing a list of features that it will add/optimize, including ones that are currently unachievable due to SDK limitations. The list will be kept up-to-date with the roll out of each new version.  After the Early Adopter Phase, the aircraft will enter the continued maintenance phase where PMDG will shift focus away from developing new features and instead provide regular compatibility/stability updates, turning to the development of its next product - the 777 series for MSFS. Currently, PMDG has not yet announced a firm release date or pricing for the 737NG series. However the developers stressed that the Early Adopter phase will not affect the price of the aircraft. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fxhjgh</id>
    <title>FlightFX and Marwan Gharib Reach Publishing Agreement; Sets Release Price</title>
    <updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fxhjgh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/626031e594fa2d45d22fec2c_HJetCoverCompressed.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="848056"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After 3 years of development, Marwan Gharib has reached an agreement with FlightFX to publish his rendition of the Honda Jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with also coming to a decision on a set release price. In a document provided by Nick Sdoucos from FlightFX, he expressed his optimism for the future of the product: The document further explains changes that will further be happening. The HJet Discord will migrating over to the FlightFX discord , and will be giving the option to users to obtain roles and follow the project further as updates and release. Nick then explains that: The announced price of the Honda Jet is to be $24.99. As of today's announcement, no release date has been officially announced, however the official release date will be coming within the next 1-2 weeks. You can check out the FlightFX Discord for further developments on the Honda Jet. Threshold will keep you updated on any further developments out of FlightFX.</summary>
    <published>2022-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerbru</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Brussels Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerbru" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/626237e8e33d771b107df3ec_ebbr-msfs_07.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="115258"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Bringing attention to detail, Aerosoft has released its highly awaited visual rendition of Brussels International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release adds to the ever-increasing catalog of major airports that Aerosoft has pushed out. Dating back to the early days of the German Luftwaffe occupied the area and operated the area as a backup airfield. After the war in the 1960s, the airport received multiple hangers with then receiving cargo ramps in 1976 and passenger terminals in 1994. Brussels received about 23 million passengers in about 2019 pre-COVID-19. With an all-inclusive feature list, Aerosoft has provided content that all users will enjoy. Starting off, a complete layout of Brussels Airport with detailed modeling has been provided alongside, custom jetways and correct terminal variations included. Next, accurate lighting along the airport grounds and ground textures have all been modeled and included. You may view the full feature list on Aerosoft’s website. If you are interested in picking this scenery package up for yourself, you can pick it up over on Aerosoft’s website and sells for €20.97. If you are interested in Aerosoft’s catalog of other sceneries, you can visit their website and take a look. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
