<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-06-10T18:20:07.943641+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inix12</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases A300 &amp; Beluga ST Open Beta for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inix12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647559958fd4882944d76e3f_beluga1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2633471"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniBuilds has recently made their A300-600R(F) and Beluga ST compatible with X-Plane 12 under an open beta program, allowing anyone with a copy of both products to experience their classic Airbuses on the new platform.   The A300 and Beluga, previously available on X-Plane 11 only, bring accurate flight dynamics, failures, a custom FMS, an extensively tuned flight model, PBR texturing, high-resolution cockpit displays, an electronic flight bag, interactive loading, and more. The X-Plane 12 open beta brings the following changes: ‍ It’s available for roughly $12.36 (temporarily) on the iniBuilds Store, requiring at least 3.5 GB of free disk space (each) to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wsslia</id>
    <title>WorldSky Studios Releases Lombok International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wsslia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64761dbb084f780d20984453_lombok1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="676163"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WorldSky Studios has recently released their rendition of Lombok International Airport (WADL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Lombok in Indonesia with a yearly average of 4 million passengers.  Opened in 2011 to replace Selaparang Airport, the only airport serving the island, Lombok International allowed the island to receive widebody traffic, which used to be nearly impossible with the former airport and its 2,100m long runway. Lombok’s runway is 1,200 meters longer, accommodating airplanes such as the Boeing 777 and the Airbus A330.  With a total area of 551.8 hectares, it is the second largest airport in the country after Soekarno-Hatta International, serving the metropolitan area of Jakarta.  There are expansion plans in mind for the near future (by 2028), increasing the terminal area to 28,750 square meters and adding 700 meters of runway length, along with an apron extension (from the current 63,294 square meters to 74,514).  It’s served by Batik Air, Citilink, Garuda Indonesia, Indonesia AirAsia, Lion Air, Scoot, Super Air Jet, and WingsAir.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, custom ground textures, PBR texturing, custom aerial imagery, a terminal interior, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.75, requiring at least 735 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/setcdi</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Cataratas del Iguazú Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/setcdi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647640b21df3a0f53f0f2302_igua1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1565828"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulacíon Extrema has recently released their rendition of Cataratas del Iguazú International Airport (SARI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Puerto Iguazú in Argentina with a yearly average of 1,000,000 passengers.  Inaugurated in 1943 as “Puerto Iguazú Airport,” it originally featured a small terminal with a short runway catering to the transportation needs of the local population and businesses in the region.   With the popularity growth of the Iguazu Falls, a nearby landmark, the passenger figures have risen considerably, which led to many infrastructure improvements and expansions.  In 1996, they inaugurated a brand new passenger terminal, increasing the airport’s capacity by a significant amount and allowing it to handle more traffic.  It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Córdoba, Rosario, Salta, San Salvador de Jujuy, Tucumán), Flybondi (Buenos Aires-Aeroparque), and JetSmart Argentina (Buenos Aires–Aeroparque, Buenos Aires–Ezeiza).   The scenery shows how the airport will look after completing the new improvement plan. It has high-quality custom jetways, custom ground textures, and a fully detailed control tower with its interior.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.93, requiring at least 633.45 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simesq</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Esquel Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simesq" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6476536a407647937a27e3af_esquel1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1155072"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Esquel Airport (SAVE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Esquel in Argentine Patagonia with a yearly average of 40,000 passengers.  Dating back to the early 20s, when the Argentine military recognized the strategic importance of establishing airfields in remote areas of the country, leading to the construction of a landing strip in Esquel in 1928.  With the increased air travel demand in the 1950s, the landing strip was finally expanded, along with the construction of a terminal building and its subsequent inauguration as a civilian airport.  Many upgrades followed throughout the next decades, culminating in its international status in 2001, opening up opportunities for tourism and business. It quickly became the gateway to Argentinian Patagonia.  To this day, it’s still an important economic driver for the city and its region, taking people to stunning national parks like the Los Alerces National Park.  It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas with a flight to Buenos Aires - Aeroparque.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport after the construction work is finished, with high-quality PBR texturing, custom jetways, custom ground textures, and a fully modeled terminal interior.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.86, requiring at least 614 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t2gorl</id>
    <title>Taxi2Gate Releases Orlando International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t2gorl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647749b784a7d531f0620a1f_mco1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3708726"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Taxi2Gate has recently released their second scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator: a rendition of Orlando International Airport (KMCO), the busiest airport in Florida and seventh in the United States with a yearly average of 50 million passengers.  Orlando International started its life as Orlando Army Air Field #2 in 1942, an auxiliary field to the Orlando Army Air Base, now known as Orlando Executive Airport. Although very briefly, it was used for aircraft testing right after the war.   The Korean War saw its return as a strategic air command facility, housing B-47 Stratojets and KC-97 Stratofreighters. Then, during the Cuban Missile Crisis in 1962, it became a temporary FOB for fighter bombers and reconnaissance aircraft flying over Cuba.   Between 1974 and 1975, control of the airport was given to the FAA, where it finally became a civil-only airport. Previously, it was a joint civil-military airport, which was back then a model for other civil joint-military airports in operation (some are still operating today). After that agreement, in 1961, many airlines shifted their operation from the old Herndon Airport to Orlando International.   The opening of the Magic Kingdom at Walt Disney World in 1971 transformed Orlando into a major tourist destination, attracting traffic from all over, be it nationwide, South America, Asia, and Europe.   In 1978, they started constructing the current Landside terminal and two airside on the west side of the terminal, which reached completion in 1981. The original international concourse opened in 1984, and Airside 4 was finished in 1990 with a new International concourse. Arside 2, completing the North Terminal complex, reached its completion in 2000.  The airport has 93 gates, divided between three terminals: A, B, and C, with two airside each on A and B.   It’s a hub for Silver Airways and a focus city for Avelo Airlines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, and Spirit. Southwest leads the passenger market share with 23.54% of the yearly figures, followed by Spirit, Delta, and Frontier with 15.85%, 14.05%, and 13.06%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom photoscenery, a detailed custom mesh, full-detail buildings, numerous static objects, fencing, an up-to-date AFCAD, dynamic night lighting, PBR texturing, and more. The developers recommend turning off photogrammetry to avoid terraforming issues on bridges.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $25.77, requiring at least 2.35 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thbn2a</id>
    <title>Thranda Design Releases BN-2A Islander for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thbn2a" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646f7513212245607aea3254_thr5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="84531"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Design has recently added a new airplane to their Dynamic Generation Series lineup: the Britten-Norman BN-2A Islander, a British light utility aircraft released in 1969. ‍  The BN-2A is an evolution of the Britten-Norman BN2, which took off for the first time in 1965. With aerodynamic and flight equipment improvements, along with a slightly more powerful engine, the BN-2A turned good into better. The engines and its robust construction allow the aircraft to operate from unprepared airstrips, making it a popular choice for remote and inaccessible locations where traditional runways may be limited or absent. It soon became the airplane of choice for humanitarian missions, surveillance, aerial survey, and commercial island hops.  Seating up to nine passengers and featuring an easy way to reconfigure for cargo transportation, medical evacuation, or any task at hand, the BN-2A is versatile.  Powered by two piston engines, the Lycoming 0-540 or the Textron Lycoming TIO-540, it cruises at 140 knots, with a total range of 800 nautical miles. The combination of fuel efficiency and low operating costs has made it popular worldwide. As of late 2019, 800 islanders were still flying out of the 1,280 built.  The add-on features a fully configurable 3D instrument panel, full VR compatibility, over 50 instruments to choose from, 3D lighting, a dynamic livery editor, 8K high-resolution PBR textures, individual functional circuit breakers, detailed and accurate flight dynamics, an advanced FMOD-based sound system, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:  Special features: Feature-rich elegant fly-out menu with the following features: Flight dynamics and systems: Advanced FMOD-based sound system:  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $34.95, requiring at least 2.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Poptart for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nibn2b</id>
    <title>Nimbus Studio Updates BN-2B Islander for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nibn2b" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647a02737eb61e12abb9a49a_islander1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="150668"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Studio has recently updated their Britten-Norman BN-2B Islander, adding compatibility with X-Plane 12.    The Britten-Norman BN-2 was developed in 1963, with its creators aiming to create a reliable, cheap, and fuel-efficient aircraft. They wanted a plane that would sacrifice cruise speed or range for a higher payload, lifting more weight than the competition ever could. With 1,280 built and over 700 in use, it’s easy to say they have succeeded.  The BN-2B Islander is an improved version of the BN-2 with better soundproofing, increased takeoff, and landing weight, and minor improvements, making it more suitable for passenger transport.   The BN-2 family is known for its versatility, with an easily configurable interior that can carry passengers (up to nine), cargo, or even work as a medevac airplane. On top of all that, it’s also STOL capable, allowing it to operate anywhere in the world. It’s a British jack-of-all-trades.  The add-on features X-Plane 12 compatibility, a highly detailed 3D model, 4K textures, PBR texturing, a custom sound system, accurate handling and flight characteristics, real performance based on performance charts, and VR compatibility.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $34.95, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Highbrow for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simkho</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Khon Kaen International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simkho" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647b9946d155a5032ada4284_vtuk1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1131756"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Khon Kaen International Airport (VTUK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Mueang Khon Kaen in Thailand with a yearly average of 1,568,000 passengers.  Built by the Japanese Army during World War 2, the then airfield featured a 1,300-meter-long runway with no navigational aids, which was eventually expanded when the war ended, and the airport was converted into a civilian facility.   In 1962, the Civil Aviation Authority of Thailand revamped the airport's infrastructure for the first time, building parking lots, hangars, garages, and basic buildings to handle passenger traffic. A year later, Thai Airways started flying to Khon Kaen with a DC-3 from Bangkok to Ubon Ratchathani, carrying passengers, cargo, and mail.   A new passenger terminal was approved in 2017, expanding the airport's size to 45,500 square meters. The construction work started a year later. The finished project should raise the passenger handling capabilities to 5.5 million passengers a year and support wide-body aircraft like the Airbus A330 and the Boeing 777.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D terminal and its interior, an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, custom jetways, and custom night lighting.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $18.07, requiring at least 344.83 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiwil</id>
    <title>TaiModels Releases Newport News/Williamsburg International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiwil" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647e3db31b50ab42c7439d60_kphf9-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2585522"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TaiModels has recently released their rendition of Newport News/Williamsburg International Airport (KPHF) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Virginia Peninsula in the United States with a yearly average of 430,000 passengers.  The airport was originally part of a military base from World War 2, Camp Patrick Henry. They got 924 areas of that land, where they built a 1,100-meter-long runway. Scheduled service started shortly after in November 1949 with Piedmont Airlines and Capital Airlines.   In 1951, the terminal was heavily damaged by a fire, prompting them to rebuild it and upgrade the airport while at it with an upgraded traffic control tower and a longer runway (400 meters longer). The new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1955.  Williamsburg Airport, then Patrick Henry Airport, was granted international status in 1975, with four airlines serving the airport nonstop: Allegheny, National, Piedmont, and United. The airport could finally handle international traffic (airline and corporate) with a brand-new customs facility.  With the airline deregulation in 1978, the airport lost most of its jet service: National in 1978, Piedmont and Allegheny in 1979, and United in 1981.   In 1984, with the airport falling deeper and deeper into a massive crisis, they hired a new executive director, who brought a new plan to the table: implementing a business park within the airport to attract air carriers. A year later, it was America’s fastest-growing airport, the success of which was also repeated in 1986. The jets were back.  In September 1990, the airport got its current name: Newport News/Williamsburg International Airport.   In the early 2000s, they launched another expansion effort, adding new parking lots, opening new passenger concourses, and bringing more airlines.   For the past decade, the airport has entered a fast decline. It all started with AirTran Airways stopping their operations after its merger with Southwest Airlines, hitting the passenger count significantly. Then, in 2020, Delta suspended their service to Atlanta. In July 2022, there was a glimmer of hope with Avelo Airlines, but they suspended their operations a year later.  The airport is only served by American Eagle (Charlotte) and Netjets (Birmingham, Columbus, Knoxville, Minneapolis, Raleigh-Durham, and Teterboro).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models, SAM jetways, high-quality PBR textures, performance-friendly optimization, custom autogen around the airport, ground traffic plugins, and weather textures (X-Plane 12 only).  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.91, requiring at least 1.22 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fdsjia</id>
    <title>FSDesigns Releases Jacksonville International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fdsjia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647e469e24cfc50e48a50e01_jia1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1592241"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FSDesigns has recently released their rendition of Jacksonville International Airport (KJAX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Jacksonville Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 6,500,000 passengers.  Jacksonville International was conceived as a replacement for Imeson Field, which has served Jacksonville since 1927. It was simply not big enough to handle the increased demand for air travel, and the runways could not be expanded due to terrain limitations.   Inaugurated in 1968, its growth could have been faster, with only two million passengers a year by 1982 (way below expectation). However, the 90s saw a massive increase, with the average hitting the 5 million mark. In 2000, they approved an expansion plan to rebuild the landside terminal, central square, main concessions area, and a parking area expansion.  In 2006, they rolled out the second phase of the expansion program, rebuilding concourses A and C, designed by Reynolds, Smith &amp; Hills. The crisis of 2009 stopped any other ongoing expansion work, with the old Concourse B being demolished and only considered for rebuilding ten years later when the traffic figures were healthy again. The pandemic, though, halted that project, which should begin by the summer of 2023.  It’s served by Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Silver Airways, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. American, Delta, and Southwest hold most of the market share, with 20% each.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality 3D models, custom ground textures, an optimized terminal interior, an up-to-date airport layout, SAM jetways, 3D vegetation, dynamic night lighting, and custom wear and tear using the latest technology.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $19.99, requiring at least 1.26 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthstl</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases St. Louis International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthstl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647e4e5716e5af35c913c3a9_stl1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1466068"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of St. Louis Lambert International Airport (KSTL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving metropolitan St. Louis with a yearly average of 13 million passengers.  Opened 100 years ago, St. Louis started its life as an airfield with the addition of hangars and a passenger terminal two years later, in 1925. In that same decade, it became one of the first airports to have an air traffic control system, although via flags instead of radio communication.  In 1928, it became one of the first municipally owned airports in the United States after the city paid 2 million dollars to Albert Bond Lambert, its owners, and one of the most famous precursors of aviation in St. Louis, being the first licensed pilot in the city and part of the leadership of the Missouri Aeronautical Society.  During World War 2, it became a manufacturing facility for McDonnell Aircraft Corporation and Curtiss-Wright.  In the 1950s, the airport got a new passenger terminal to handle the increased air travel demand, costing 7.2 million dollars and bringing an innovative dome design that preceded JFK (New York) and CDG (Paris). By 1957, they had 44 weekday TWA departures, 24 from American Airlines, 16 from Delta, 14 from Ozark Airlines, 13 from Eastern Air Lines, six from Braniff, and two from Central.   In the 1970s, Missouri residents rejected a proposal to build a new airport in suburban Illinois. Later in that decade, the airport underwent a massive expansion project that expanded the runways, increased the number of gates to 81, and boosted its overall capacity.   Following the airline deregulation in 1978, the dominant forces at St. Louis were TWA with 36 routes and Ozark with 25, followed by American and Eastern with 17 and 12, respectively.   As a direct consequence of the deregulation, airlines adopted a hub model. St. Louis became one of TWA's hubs, flying people all over America and even across the ocean to London, Paris, and Frankfurt.   With the aviation crisis that followed 9/11, TWA ceased operations and got bought out by American, which couldn't afford to keep St. Louis as one of their hubs. Southwest preyed on that by boosting their daily departures and overall participation. Currently, they hold 61.40% of the passenger market share, followed by American Airlines (12%) and Delta Air Lines (7.70%).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with over 60 custom buildings, custom animated jetways, custom night lighting, custom ground clutter, realistic terrain elevation, and high-resolution ground textures.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $15.07, requiring at least 685.08 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflf2s</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews Fokker F28’s Sounds for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflf2s" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62ec9b05681fa0dbd328e67a_1000_Air_France_srxkHMBHR.png.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="89426"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently uploaded a 14-minute video showcasing the sounds of their upcoming Fokker F28 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a short-range jet airliner from the late 1960s. The video covers various sound examples, ranging from knobs to the engine’s scream on the take-off roll—minutes upon minutes of each and every sound an F28 produces. First flown in May 1967, the Fokker F28 was developed to compete with turboprop airliners, carrying the same amount of passengers but cruising faster and offering more straightforward operation based on American design methodologies.  Its development was aided by feedback from many of their F27 operators, mainly North Americans, hence the “Americanisation” of the F28 to make it sell even better on American soil. With 241 units built in total, Fokker made six variants of the F28 with different carrying capacities and lengths.  There’s still no information on pricing or a potential release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slhkit</id>
    <title>SLH Sim Designs Releases Robert L. Bradshaw Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slhkit" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64810027c9130ef80c716c8a_kitt1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1665218"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SLH Sim Designs has recently released their rendition of Robert L. Bradshaw Airport (TKPK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of St. Kitts with a yearly average of 400,000 passengers.  Built in the 1940s as a Royal Air Force airfield, it was turned over to the local government right after the dust had settled, becoming a civilian airport. It underwent several upgrades, including a major renovation between 2004-2006.  It’s served by ten airlines: Air Canada Rouge, Air Sunshine, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, InterCaribbean Airways, Silver Airways, Sky High, Trans Anguilla Airways, and United Airlines.   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled passenger terminal, dynamic night lighting, custom 3D taxi signage, static sea traffic, and custom ground textures.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.63, requiring at least 1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmont</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Ontario International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmont" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64824b7befd4c5dc1277f45e_kont1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="759429"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Ontario International Airport (KONT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of San Bernardino, Riverside, and Greater Los Angeles with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1941 as an Army Air Corps aircraft training and operation base. After the war, it became a large storage, sale, and scrapping center for Army Air Forces aircraft.   Shortly after, in 1946, the airport was renamed from “Ontario Municipal Airport” to “Ontario International Airport” because of outgoing trans-pacific cargo flights. The first international passenger flight happened that same year, a Pacific Overseas Airlines flight from Shanghai to Ontario, inaugurating round-trip air passenger service between the United States and the Orient. Western Airlines began operating at the airport three years later, followed by Bonanza Air Lines in 1955.  A new terminal was opened in 1998, discontinuing the old terminals, which now function as the administration and the USO. There are 26 gates total, with 12 on T2 and 14 on T4. Terminal 2 hosts Alaska Airlines, Avianca El Salvador, China Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, United Airlines, and Volaris. Terminal 4 hosts American Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, and Southwest.  It’s a FedEx and UPS Airlines cargo hub, transporting cargo all over North America and Asia (UPS). Amazon Air, Ameriflight, Amerijet International, Asia Pacific Airlines, and Kalitta Air also serve it. Ontario International is the ninth-largest cargo airport in the United States.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom taxi signs, parallax, LOD optimization, realistic night lighting, custom jetways with gate numbers, and more.  It’s available on Verticalsim’s Shop for $19.99, requiring at least 2.16 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Soarandskor for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aes330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews A330’s Flight Deck for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aes330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6482588861a07f020c939cc5_cove-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3820180"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft’s Product Manager, has recently made a new forum post with a set of 4K screenshots from their upcoming Airbus A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showing the electronic flight bag and some of its features, some of the cockpit and more.  ‍ Mathijs also makes sure to reinstate that the images don’t represent the final product just yet, as they worked with five separate development paths that will eventually come together once it’s nearing release.   The first image shows the Operational Flight Plan on the EFB, along with the METARs for the destination, arrival, and alternate airport:  The second image shows the loadsheet manager in its full glory, along with the take-off performance calculator tool:  The following images show the integrated charts and the moving map, which help taxiing around complex airport layouts:  Kok then showcases the web-based interactive manual, built to help newcomers with the cockpit flows:  The subsequent imagery shows more of the cockpit and the overall texture work around it:  There’s still no release date or pricing information, but Threshold will keep you informed! Shout out to Geeky for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssda20</id>
    <title>SimSolutions' DA20 nearing completion</title>
    <updated>2023-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssda20" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64837745e1be006af07b40de_banner.JPG" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="538225"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimSolutions' latest creation, A Diamond DA20 for MSFS 2020 is now nearing its final stages of development. The developers behind the project have disclosed to Threshold that there are only a number of small functions remaining to be added, along with the finalisation of the sound profile for the aircraft.  The aircraft is based on a popular training aircraft and as such will contain a true to life avionics package, one would come to expect from a training aircraft. It will boast a GNS430 Navigation unit along with a standard transponder, the cockpit and exterior have been recreated in excruciating detail. Particular attention has also been paid to lighting both inside and outside the aircraft. Instrument panels will be accurately illuminated along with accurate flood lighting.  A release date and price is still yet to be confirmed by SimSolutions, but once it is we will be sure to keep you updated!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
