<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-10-28T18:37:41.583935+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ldeyvi</id>
    <title>Lisium Design Releases Vilnius International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ldeyvi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f682dcb49b25b0048ed07b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Lisium Design has launched its latest scenery package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, featuring Vilnius International Airport, which serves the capital of Lithuania. The airport is located just under four miles from the city center and connects Vilnius to numerous destinations across Europe. Opened in 1932, the airport initially operated only a few commercial flights to various cities. This continued until the outbreak of the Second World War when the airport served as a military airfield until 1944. After the war, a new terminal was constructed, which was completed in 1954. To accommodate an increase in air traffic, a new departure terminal was built in 1993. Another terminal followed in 2007, and yet another was completed this year. Today, the airport is a hub for airBaltic and serves as a focus city for GetJet Airlines, Ryanair, and Wizzair, among others. The airport handles nearly 5 million passengers annually, connecting them to destinations all over Europe. The scenery comes packed with features such as a true-to-life terminal, true-to-life apron layout, detailed custom ground textures, custom lighting, and more. The newly released Vilnius International Airport by Lisium Design is now available on Contrail for $20.19. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/confa50</id>
    <title>Contrail Publishes FA50 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/confa50"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f8b7c1b62b3ca0205fcf2f_fa50-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Contrail has recently shared the development progress on their upcoming FA50 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showcasing their ongoing work on the cabin door, new flight deck textures, and much more. The cabin door is now fully complete, with authentic animations and interior detailing. Furthermore, Contrail has also completed the cockpit texture overhaul. It now features the rather distinctive rough-painted metal finish found in many real FA50s, significantly reducing glare and bringing it one notch closer to reality. Their work in the systems department is going well, thanks to feedback provided by real pilots and mechanics, who helped them capture the aircraft’s true essence, quirks and all. They have also provided a first look at the hydraulics system, demonstrating how the elevator drops to a full nose-down position when hydraulic pressure is lost, making the yoke move fully forward. In contrast, the ailerons only sag ever so slightly and remain that way even when pressure is wholly restored. Once the plane is airborne, of course, the airflow over the wings brings them to a neutral position—or slightly above center—as per real-life behavior. ‍ Contrail says, “more updates are on the way” as their product continues to take shape for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f282310</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s Fokker F28 Professional V2.2 Launches Tomorrow</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f282310"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324a8883ddb907aea4d80_fuk3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight’s long-awaited full revamp and port to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 of their Fokker F28 is set to land soon—tomorrow—entirely free of charge for V1 owners and with a 20% discount for new buyers. While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. ‍ They will also include MSFS 2024’s pre-flight walkaround mode and a new EFB tablet model with a window-mount option. The complete 2.2 changelog will be made available at release time tomorrow. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpa28x12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Piper PA-28-181 Archer III for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpa28x12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f8be44d4d77c506d11a7d8_archer31.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight and Thranda Design have recently released their rendition of the Piper PA-28-181 Archer III for X-Plane 12, following on from their Warrior II as part of their new general aviation aircraft lineup for Laminar Research’s latest simulator. The add-on features a highly accurate rendition of the Piper PA-28-181 Archer III, following comprehensive hands-on research on a real unit - G-CIFY - based at Turweston Airfield in the United Kingdom. It’s a four-seater piston-engine airplane with a four-cylinder 180-horsepower plant, a fixed tricycle landing gear, and a fixed-pitch propeller. It’s one of the most recent PA28 variants to be built, easily seen through its relatively modern and streamlined flight deck design, especially on the overhead. It cruises at 118 knots with a range of nearly 500 miles, making it perfect for touring and flight training. Furthermore, the cockpit features a rich avionics suite with a Garmin GNS 530 GPS unit, a GNC 255 radio, a S-TEC autopilot, HSI, and ADF instruments.  The add-on accompanies six liveries from the USA, Australia, Switzerland, Spain, Germany, and the United Kingdom. Thanks to the dynamic livery EFB app, a near-infinite variety of paint schemes can be created within the simulator. The aircraft sports full PBR texturing in 8K with real-time environment reflections. Additionally, there’s an Electronic Flight Bag tablet with many settings such as aircraft configuration options, panel states, interactive checklists, and more. It’s available on the Just Flight website for $42.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf282255</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates Fokker F28 Professional for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf282255"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324880615470b16ee888a_fuk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently released the long-awaited 2.2 update for their Fokker F28 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and now 2024. The update brings cabin updates, native MSFS 2024 compatibility with pre-flight walkaround support, SimBrief flight plan uplink, and more. ‍ While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. ‍ The MSFS 2024 version also includes the pre-flight walkaround system, making it a native 2024 aircraft.  ‍ The EFB tablet model was revamped, offering a new mounting position (window-mounted), and the airplane now supports SimBrief flight plan uplinks, making the flight planning experience more seamless. The complete changelog follows below: v2.2 - Upgraded to a MSFS 2024 native package (MSFS 2024 only). - Added additional model LODs for improved performance (MSFS 2020/2024) and MSFS 2024 compatibility. - Added Preflight Walkaround support (MSFS 2024 only):     - Chocks/Cones     - GPU     - Passenger and service doors (including airstairs handle, automatic/manual extension and jetway mode)     - Cargo doors     - Enter/exit aircraft - Added SimBrief OFP import functionality to UNS-1 FMS. - Added custom cabin textures to passenger liveries - Added new, modern EFB tablet model (tablet can now be moved between two positions by clicking the top/bottom bezels). - Added Jetway External Power logic - Default and GSX jetways, and GSX GPU, can now supply external power.Buttons on the EFB aircraft app allow for the selection of GPU or jetway power once available, or the overhead panel switch can be used as before. - Added 'AUTO CABIN MUSIC' option to the EFB, allowing you to control whether the cabin crew switch the cabin music on/off. - Added galley hot water handle animation. - Added support for third-party liveries to include livery configuration files. - Fixed EFB Charts and Map apps flickering (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed duplicated pilots appearing on exterior (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed missing copilot (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed copilot not animating with seat - Cockpit seat positions are now locked in MSFS 2024 due to simulator limitation that prevents the pilot characters from moving with them. - Fixed EFB OFP page formatting (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed user aircraft being detected by TCAS when using time compression. - Fixed MSFS 2024 payload initialisation issues when starting C&amp;D (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed RMI dot/cross annunciator logic. - Fixed cockpit window seal flickering. - Fixed autopilot mode selector lighting brightness (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed preflight walkaround collision boxes – It’s no longer possible to walk through parts of the aircraft when in preflight walkaround mode (MSFS 2024 only). - Fixed forward galley collision boxes – It’s no longer possible to click through from cockpit to cabin and vice versa, preventing inadvertent selections, e.g. toggling a cockpit switch when trying to toggle a galley switch. - Fixed navigation light effects disappearing at distance (MSFS 2024) - Improved ASI bug logic - dragging of bugs is now possible, bugs interact with each other, and are more accurately set by speeds flipchart. - Improved EFB pushback functionality. - Improved cabin crew callouts triggers during taxi – “Cabin Is Secured” callout will now automatically trigger 5-8 minutes after the doors are closed, simulating the time it takes for a safety briefing and seat belt check. “Cabin Crew Seats For Take-off” logic remains the same, either triggered via the “CABIN CALL” button on the overhead panel when the aircraft is in a take-off state, or automatically during the take-off run. - Improved Audio Selector Panel logic - Reworked for greater accuracy. - Improved Door 1L logic and animation - door up/down buttons are now functional, door can be pushed for manual extension, smoother airstairs animation, improved door/handle animation logic when triggered via EFB. - Moved ‘navdata’ folder externally to the package to comply with MSFS 2024 SDK (Navigraph Hub has been updated to support the new location). - Updated Operations Manual - Updated EFB Manual - Updated UNS-1 Operations Manual ‍ The add-on is available on their store for $55.99 (a temporary 20% discount due to the new update). The original retail price is $69.99. It requires at least 5.3 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sextan</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Tanegashima Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sextan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fca63bfad42ae4c270e28a_shima1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Tanegashima Airport (RJFG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the town of Nakatane on Tanegashima Island in Japan and has a yearly average of 74,633 passengers. It was built roughly 19 years ago to replace the original Tanegashima Airport, which was deemed unsuitable for jet aircraft and geographically impossible to expand from its original length (1500 meters). The Tanegashima Airport was built around 8km from the original, with modern infrastructure and a slightly longer runway (2000 meters). It’s served by J-Air and Japan Air Commuter, with flights to Osaka-Itami, Fukuoka, and Kagoshima. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed terminal, a fully modeled boarding area, custom ground textures, custom runway textures, and more. It’s available in the Marketplace for roughly $12.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gtfa32rl</id>
    <title>GotFriends Releases Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gtfa32rl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fcae8b742352c55c02c91d_vix1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. GotFriends recently released their rendition of the Aeroprakt A-32 Vixxen, a Ukrainian two-seat ultralight aircraft first flown in 2014, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The A-32 is built upon the A-22 Foxbat, bringing several improvements and with one significant difference: unlike its “father”, which could be purchased in kit form or fully assembled, it is only available as a kit in the United Kingdom, whereas you can get a factory-built version in 31 other nations. It’s powered by a 100hp Rotax 912ULS engine, allowing it to cruise at 213 km/h with around 4.5 hours of total endurance, carrying only one person. The first prototype was completed in January 2014, and the first production aircraft was showcased in April 2015. The A-32 is still in production today. The add-on features an accurate rendition of the aircraft, featuring a high-detail 3D model, a comprehensive EFB, two flight deck configurations (standard six-pack, glass), and much more. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $25, requiring at least 2.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aes340du2410</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes A340-600 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aes340du2410"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fcb6a013416d3ae2ccbd4a_toe1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has published another A340-600  development update in conjunction with ToLiss Simulation Software, which handles the intricate systems of the long-awaited aircraft. This week’s update goes in depth about the aircraft’s fuel and electric systems and how they differ from the rest of the A320 family due to the extra two engines and the many challenges that come with it, such as the necessity for a fuel transfer system that gets in action during take-off and landing to ensure the center of gravity is within a safe zone. While the fuel transfer isn’t visually demonstrated, it is described by Torsten - ToLiSS founder and CEO -, where it kicks in at different times throughout the flight, especially during the take-off roll and landing to ensure the center of gravity is balanced correctly, and ensuring it also accompanies its respective ECAM message, both for when it starts and for when it’s done transferring. After the halfway mark, they also cover part of the electrics and how they differ from the rest of the family, like the A340 having four generators rather than two—as it is one per engine—offering extra redundancy, and how the APU got its very own battery, just like the A330, so that it doesn’t drain the other batteries when handling the APU startup. There is no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/afl73o</id>
    <title>Airfoillabs Shares 737 MAX Dev Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/afl73o"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68fec31302b75d1a73bcd671_5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airfoillabs has recently shared yet another development update on their Boeing 737 MAX for X-Plane 12, with a new look at the aircraft’s ongoing systems and flight model work.  On the systems side, the engine model continues to evolve, with work now going into RPM behaviour, acceleration and deceleration logic, and EEC, all validated by feedback from real-world pilots. Every thrust mode has also been replicated.  Meanwhile, the flight model has been retuned across all regimes to better capture the aircraft’s aerodynamic subtleties, including spoiler and flap dynamics, during takeoff and approach. Elsewhere, Airfoillabs has worked on the 3D and texture front, such as cockpit windows, fuselage textures, and lighting effects. FMS and VNAV are also progressing steadily, with altitude and speed constraints, climb profiles, and vertical path logic all in active development.  You can also watch a YouTube video from the update here: While there’s still a way to go before release, Airfoillabs 737 MAX looks to be shaping up to be something special. You can read the full update here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lu737s</id>
    <title>LevelUp Teases 737NG V2 Sound Overhaul for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lu737s"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ff9b8b55c949303e36af9b_maxresdefault%20(3).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. LevelUp has recently previewed its new FMOD 2.0 soundscape for the upcoming 737NG V2 in X-Plane 12, sharing an eleven-minute video on YouTube, giving more insight into the upcoming rework.  Now included are separate, standalone interior and exterior soundsets, refreshed cabin ambience, and fixed avionics and wind noise. Highlights include an all-new interior engine suite, recorded from the real aircraft, a buzzsaw cone that shifts with power setting, and other tweaks and updates, such as stick shaker on battery engagement and HUD control sounds. Thanks to the new interior set, overall loudness on the take-off roll also now drops naturally, as ground reflections fall away. The new sounds will be included in the upcoming 737NG V2, which you can read more about here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/facbyo</id>
    <title>FlyingArt Updates Cabby AI Plugin for MSFS and X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/facbyo"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffad9aa454e0bdd40d4e55_maxresdefault%20(3).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FlyingArt has rolled out an update for their Cabby, AI Cabin Crew software, adding a dynamic Passenger Satisfaction Simulation, networked boarding screens, and 3D spatial audio.  Every flight now generates a unique manifest with individual profiles and fear-of-flying levels, so smooth landings and fewer delays keep your virtual cabin happy, while rough rides do not. The new Boarding Screen feature mirrors a real gate setup on a TV, tablet, or second monitor, with four layouts and simple network access.  3D spatial audio is also implemented, with announcements in realistic positions around the cabin, working with headphones, 5.1, or 7.1 setups, for a more convincing soundstage. Rounding things off are AI flight summaries, landing feedback, and a flight history map.  You can read more about Cabby and try it out on the FlyingArt website. Prices range from $12.00 to $22.00, with several plans available. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfbrso</id>
    <title>SoFly Teases Bristol Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfbrso"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffb2624e3410f359972f65_571115643_1411194024345331_391040262126603842_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly has shared a fresh update of its upcoming Bristol Airport (EGGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, confirming that the scenery has now entered beta testing.  The team previously stated their focus is on detail and authenticity, with a carefully modelled terminal interior, inspired by real reference material. While not every area will be perfectly true to life, SoFly promises a close and convincing recreation, capturing the atmosphere of one of the UK’s busiest regional airports. The first beta testing round is nearly complete, with a second build already underway, meaning release could be just around the corner. We’ll keep you updated. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brsaa1</id>
    <title>BRSimDesigns Releases AA-5B Tiger G1000 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brsaa1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffbb0985c5542599d0b4ce_557530637_1404745094986421_9076242823794646352_n%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. BRSimDesigns has recently rolled out a refreshed version of its AA-5B Tiger for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, now including a full Garmin G1000 suite. The package includes a dual-screen WT-G1000 with autopilot, custom flight dynamics, an authentic Wwise sound set, and an EFB for payload, panel, and ground options.  Furthermore, the aircraft features high-quality 3D modelling, a mix of 4K and 8K textures, full PBR materials, dynamic registration, and MSFS volumetric lighting.  You also get eight liveries, an openable canopy, and a castor nose wheel, among others. FEATURES The Tiger is available at simMarket for $29.08. Owners of the original AA-5B Tiger can upgrade for $13.99, excluding sales tax. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dc2921</id>
    <title>Eagle Dynamics Updates DCS World, Including Heatblur F14A Early </title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dc2921"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffc89dd87ce2caceda3463_G38OHk8WcAAiwX0.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Eagle Dynamics has recently released DCS World 2.9.21.16362, a substantial update that, among others, brings the long-requested F-14A-135-GR (Early).  This new variant captures the original fleet-defence interceptor era, powered by the quite notorious Pratt &amp; Whitney TF30-P-414A engines, and fitted with the AN/ALR-45/50 radar warning receiver, complete with its distinctive strobe display.  The RIO cockpit features new RWR panels and indicator lights, plus updated TACAN and volume panels. There is also a VF-101 Grim Reapers livery from 1978 included. Beyond the Tomcat, this update touches nearly every corner of DCS. The F-4E Phantom II, for example, has also seen an update from Heatblur, including an EFB, and the AN/APX-80A “Combat Tree” IFF interrogator.  TV-guided weapon logic has been refined, new Zuni rockets have been added, and the Jester AI now has some new IFF options and a faster interface. Moving along, Eagle Dynamics’ own aircraft have seen meaningful improvements, too. The MiG-29A has had its autopilot behaviour updated, the F-16C Viper and F/A-18C Hornet have gotten first-person visor effects and an expanded NCTR database, while the AH-64D Apache’s George AI copilot has been updated with smarter flight logic, new control modes, and expanded commands. Furthermore, Ugra Media’s Normandy 2.0 has been updated with a new winter season, additional airfields across the Channel Islands, and dozens of fresh landmarks. Some new Swedish and Norwegian airfields have been added to Orbx’s Kola map, plus environmental refinements across the region. There are numerous other changes, summed up in the full changelog below: AI (Ground, Air, Sea) ‍Dedicated Server Weapons User Interface Mission Editor Graphics / Effects 3D Models Features Launcher Currenthill Asset Pack Known Issue: Switching George AI Pilot’s altitude reference between radar and barometric when hovering at an altitude of 20 feet or less over the surface can cause a conversion error that will force George to land and may not be able to switch back to radar altitude. This has been fixed internally. DCS: A-10C II Outpost Campaign by Stone Sky DCS: AH-64D Outpost Campaign by Stone Sky DCS: F/A-18C Operation Green Line Campaign by Badger 633 DCS: F/A-18C: The Rampagers Campaign by Baltic Dragon  DCS: F/A-18C Operation Mountain Breeze Campaign by Sandman Simulations DCS P-51D Blue Nose Bastards of Bodney Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS Spitfire IX The Big Show Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS P-51D Debden Eagles Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS Bf-109K-4 Jagdflieger Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS P-47D Wolfpack II Overlord Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS Mosquito FB.VI V for Victory Campaign by Reflected Simulations DCS: F/A-18C Operation Cerberus North Campaign by Ground Pounder Sims DCS: F-16C Dragon's Fury Campaign by SorelRo DCS: UH-1H The Huey Last Show Campaign by SorelRo The full changelog for DCS World 2.9.21.16362 is also available here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mtsoct</id>
    <title>Miltech Simulations Shares October Progress Update </title>
    <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mtsoct"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ffd0ad544caa222d4927f3_532517991_777431868129951_528965529907888171_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Miltech Simulations has recently published its October development blog, outlining progress across several of its big projects, including updates for the MH-60, Mission Hub, and Skyraider. New details on the U-2 Spyplane and CH-53 have also been shared. Miltech confirmed plans to gradually phase out MSFS 2020 development by 2026, citing the majority of users having already moved to MSFS 2024.  The MH-60, developed in partnership with Blackbird Simulations, remains one of Miltech’s flagship aircraft, and recently joined the Marketplace’s Top-Rated Aircraft Sale.  A major v1.0.3 update is on the way, featuring an overhaul of  APU logic, improved flight model and SAS behaviour, and AFCS refinements.  The patch also introduces optional realistic INS alignment, new keybind support, and pop-out gauge functionality for multi-monitor setups.  In addition, the first Livery Pack is nearly complete, adding a nice selection of military and rescue variants from the US Navy, 160th SOAR, and other international operators. Meanwhile, the Miltech Mission Hub is preparing for its long-awaited Xbox release, with both MSFS 2020 and 2024 versions in final testing. The update introduces sling load enhancements, a distance measuring tool, new SAR scenarios, and expanded SimObjects including vehicles, ships, and rescue assets.  A Mission Builder App is also in development, allowing players to upload and share missions directly from the cloud. The upcoming Skyraider, also developed with Blackbird Simulations, has entered beta testing and is described as feature-complete for MSFS 2020, with a full conversion to the modular MSFS 2024 framework.  Miltech said that the project will include multiple variants, including the A-1H, AD-3W, AEW.1, and AD-4W, each tied to specific liveries. Pricing is expected to land in the mid-$20 USD range, covering all variants, and the aircraft will support both PC and Xbox platforms at launch. Also in active development is the U-2, a passion project that originally began in early 2023. Miltech is building both S (digital) and R (analogue) variants, with complex avionics systems, new ground equipment, and fully modelled chase cars.  The aircraft will come with five detailed airbases,  including Groom Lake (Area 51), Fairford, and Akrotiri, and will feature dynamic missions built for Mission Hub.  While no release window has been given, the developer notes that additional resources have been dedicated to bringing the project up to modern standards. Rounding out the lengthy blog, Miltech provided a brief look at the CH-53, showcasing its intricate rotor hub and configurable cabin layouts.  Both the CH-53E and MH-53E variants are in progress, leveraging MSFS 2024’s modular framework for high detail and performance efficiency.  You can read the full blog here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdsolar</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases United Kingdom &amp; Ireland Solar Farms for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdsolar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6900c3f259f9eea8304143d0_solar2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Burning Blue Design has recently released a comprehensive pack of solar farms across the United Kingdom and Ireland, allowing VFR pilots to navigate more accurately during their virtual journeys. Over 1700 distinct solar farms total 210 square kilometers of custom scenery area (larger than the city of Dublin), featuring a variety of sizes and layouts, from tiny solar farms to massive behemoths spanning over 3 square kilometers of area. The product is made with full PBR texturing to ensure it will shimmer and reflect realistically regardless of the weather conditions. Furthermore, the developers have ensured that every little detail is captured: custom-modelled solar panels, inverters, and substations, with performance-friendliness in mind (multiple levels of detail). They also ensure that it blends seamlessly with the terrain. It’s available on their website for roughly $15. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
