<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-02-06T18:24:09.704036+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzacst</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Previews Christchurch International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzacst" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd14328ae1d41e285cd27d_christ1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="458971"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NZA Simulations has recently previewed their progress on Christchurch International Airport (NZCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in New Zealand with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Located in Harewood, a northwestern suburb of Christchurch, it officially opened in May 1940, as RNZAF Station Harewood. Six years later, it already had a small terminal building, and basic infrastructure for passenger traffic, which eventually led to its clearance to operate internationally, granted in 1950. It was New Zealand’s first international airport.  The current runway layout was conceived in 1953, with runway 2/20 being around 2,000m and 11/29 at nearly 1,800m. The length was just enough for TEAL’s DC-6 aircraft to operate on their trans-Tasman service in 1954. The sudden surge in passenger figures led to the construction of a new terminal, designed by Paul Pascoe, and inaugurated in 1960. Runways were extended in the mid-60s to conform to Boeing 707 standards, used by Qantas on the route to Sydney. The main runway underwent further extension work in 1984 to the current total of 3,287 meters. The airport is served by 12 airlines, with direct flights to 18 domestic and 11 international destinations, with 1057 weekly flights (as of 2015). It’s a hub for Air New Zealand, with a network of domestic legs and four international destinations in Australia. The developers claim it has entered final testing, with external testers and partners receiving their release candidate versions. The release date is still unknown, but they aim to line it up with the upcoming New Zealand World Update XII.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbpbi</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Palm Beach International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbpbi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd24bae20d7a21df41d37e_pbi1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1636688"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the primary airport of Palm Beach County, serving Wellington, Delray Beach, Boynton Beach, Jupiter, and Palm Beach Gardens. It’s the third busiest airport in the Miami Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 7 million passengers.  Its origins date back to 1936 when it opened as Morrison Field, named after Grace Morrison, a key planner of the airfield. The first flight to ever depart from it was an Eastern Air Lines DC-2 heading to New York that same year. Not soon after, in 1937, it was expanded beyond an airstrip, with the construction of hangars, and its first terminal: the Eastern Air Lines Terminal. It took a major role during WW2 as a training base (and staging, later on) for the Allied invasion of France, with an en masse departure towards the United Kingdom to join the D-Day invasion of Normandy. It was later returned to Palm Beach County, with its current name being officially adopted in 1948, although not for long, as it was once again transformed into an Air Force Base in 1951, training airmen for the Korean War.  In 1962, the Air Force decided to close the AFB, and it once again became Palm Beach International Airport. Delta Air Lines began their scheduled flights a couple of years prior, followed by Capital Airlines. After local voters rejected a proposal to relocate the airport in detriment of an expansion, PBI got an eight-gate main terminal on the northeastern side of the airport in 1966, with Delta eventually moving into its own terminal in 1974, with six-gates and featuring the airport’s first jetways. Fourteen years later, the airport got another terminal, with 25 gates. It was named after David McCampbell, a WW2 ace. It was considered to be among the finest in the United States by the readers of the Conde Nast Traveller Magazine. Further expansion work followed in 2006, with the construction of a seven-story parking garage and three gates in concourse c.   As of 2018, the airport has 32 gates, with Concourse A housing Bahamasair and Silver Airways, Concourse B housing Air Canada, American Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines, and Concourse C hosting Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, and Spirit Airlines. JetBlue is responsible for 25.37% of the market share, with 1,362,000 passengers, followed by Delta and American, with 21.65% and 21.09%, respectively.  The scenery features detailed 3D models of the airport, terminal, and surrounding buildings, with high-quality PBR textures, realistic night lighting, custom ground service equipment, custom animated SAM jetways, animated radar systems, and an updated layout matching 2022 standards, along with integration with TrueEarth Florida (X-Plane 11 only).  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.41, requiring at least 3.27 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simsin</id>
    <title>SimNord Releases Sindal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simsin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd2dee204c42793267baa9_sindal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1775730"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimNord has recently released their rendition of Sindal Airport (EKSN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the northernmost airport in Denmark. It’s a municipal airport, first established in 1977 and home to the Sindal Flying Club.  With a 1,199-meter-long paved runway, Sindal is the ideal playground for general aviation aircraft and small business jets. It functions as a conventional airport during working hours, and as a self-service airport when closed (with prior permission required). It’s ready for IMC conditions with ILS on runway 26 and NDB on runway 08.  On a curious note, the airport hosts the “Car of the Year in Europe” test, also referred to as the Tannis test, where vehicles get tested in evasive maneuvers and safety systems. It’s held every year in September. Sindal Airport also hosts street racing (occasionally, under rental) on a 402-meter-long circuit.  The scenery features an accurate representation of the airport as it currently stands, with its main terminal, SUN-AIR Technic hangars, accurate marking and signage, custom ground textures, and realistic clutter.  It’s exclusively available on the MSFS Marketplace for PC and Xbox for $9.99, requiring at least 679 MB of free disk space to install.Shout out to PopFizzels for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfufst</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates FS Traffic for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfufst" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd506fd7590b0cbedc19e1_fst1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="268587"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently issued an update to FS Traffic for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing a CTD-inducing compatibility issue, improving the FS Traffic module, and other minor fixes.   FS Traffic is Just Flight’s newly released AI traffic plugin that injects traffic based on real-world data with matching models, liveries, and accurate scheduling. It features tens of thousands of real-world flight plans from different periods, sourced from the same supplier used by real-world websites and applications. New flight plans can be added through their Traffic Control Center application, where it’s also possible to add new liveries and third-party AI aircraft models.  The 1.0.2 update fixes a compatibility issue with the FS Traffic in-game menu that would conflict with other third-party in-game panels and lead to a CTD, adds an alternate way to set your destination airport in the Traffic Control Center for VR users, mitigates a crash when changing aircraft and/or livery in the MSFS menu, which would consequently prevent aircraft from generating at the departure and arrival airports, fixes an issue where the FS Traffic module data would not be correctly reset between flights if the user was quick in navigating through various MSFS menus, multiple changes to default settings in an attempt to reduce the likelihood of traffic generating invisible at the departure airport, and the correction of an unhandled exception error in the Traffic Control Center when trying to add a pre-existing route.  It’s available on Just Flight’s Store for $39.99, requiring at least 8.6 GB of free disk space to install. Shout out to spkevin81 on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boudub</id>
    <title>Boundless Previews Dublin Airport Upgrade for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boudub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd5b0d7eb54d8ac59e566f_bou1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="402963"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently previewed the progress on their Dublin Airport (EIDW) upgrade for X-Plane 11 and 12, which adds the new runway (10L/28R), new fencing models, improved ground textures, and more.  Dublin Airport is the 12th busiest airport in Europe, and the 1st in Ireland, with a yearly average of 30 million passengers. It hosts their flag carrier Aer Lingus, the low-cost carrier beast Ryanair, and TUI Airways, with a significant route network that encompasses most of Europe and some key cities in North America.   According to Boundless’ development report from late January, the update will bring full X-Plane 12 compatibility, new overhauled lighting (based on real-life reference imagery from 2023), the integration of the new runway, light tone updates on the Ryanair pier and Terminal 1, road traffic (XP12 only), airside traffic (XP12 only), new fence models, new ground textures, partial photorealistic textures based on 2023 imagery, FPS improvements, ortho updates to match the current state of the airport, general bug fixes, added barriers/fencing, new ground service equipment vehicles with 2023 liveries, road network improvements, better ortho and road network blending with default landclass, and the addition of road details. The developers even visited the airport to take reference pictures for the update, to warrant maximum acuity with the real-life counterpart.  There’s no information on a potential release date yet, but they claim it should be out in a few days. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsr10</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Releases Van’s RV-10 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsr10" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd62dedc62aa58733755cc_rv1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="277686"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimWorks Studios has recently released their rendition of the Van’s RV-10 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engine, low-wing homebuilt airplane sold in kit form by Van’s Aircraft.   The RV-10 was designed to satisfy a demand for a four-seat version of the RV series, focusing on greater stability and payload. With engines ranging from 210 to 260 hp, 825 miles of range, and 197 miles per hour of cruise speed, the aluminum-bodied RV-10 has been completed over 1,010 times as of November 2022 (it’s sold in a kit form, meaning the owner has to build it, the process of which can take up to 2,000 hours for beginner builders).  SWS’s rendition was made under license by the manufacturer, featuring an accurate 3D model with animations, five custom liveries, a custom interior by Aerosports Products, a realistic flight model tested by RV-10 pilots, flutter animations from propwash, weight-based visibility of copilot and baggage in the cockpit, opening exits, animated air conditioning vents, realistic backlighting and floodlighting, realistic exterior lighting, Sky4Sim NG Tablet compatibility, and with the inclusion of MSFS rain &amp; icing effects.  It’s available on the SimWorks Studios Store for roughly $16.20, requiring at least 1.03 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/denfbm</id>
    <title>FLIGHTBEAM Studios Issues KDEN Progress update</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/denfbm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd73fa17f3e6ce5b1dd58f_eba5cc_ac84e2d81e0f4a50a7a00eea8a86bc12_mv2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="356569"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSFS scenery developers FLIGHTBEAM Studios have recently issued a progress update on their upcoming expansions for the KDEN scenery. The updates will be focused on matching the continuing improvement/ expansion work at the real Denver international airport.  The team at FLIGHTBEAM have gone on to say: “I've (FLIGHTBEAM) been extremely fortunate to have some amazing customers who work at the airport, send me a slew of previous photos of the massive expansions happening at the airport. It's become apparent that this is by far one of the biggest real-world expansions at an airport I've seen in some time” As a result of the sheer scale of the work happening at Denver airport, FLIGHTBEAM has decided to issue their updates in 2 to 3 parts which will each focus on progressing the scenery along. They have disclosed that not only will the airport expansions be the focus of the scenery updates, but they will also be updating each terminal already in the scenery to a new and even higher standard. This includes - New 4k textures and updated PBR, exterior modelling upgrades, an entirely new interior, completely re-made from scratch and brand new Flightbeam Gen-5 Jetways at each gate to name just a few new features.  Although a date has not been revealed for the first part of this update, FLIGHTBEAM have ensured their customers that it will be soon. We will keep you updated as this develops here at Threshold.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd900</id>
    <title>PMDG Reveals Planned Release Date for 737-900</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd900" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd8b017ba9eafe2f261ccc_900-1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1973767"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG made a forum announcement with further information on the upcoming 737-900 package for Microsoft Flight Simulator, set to feature both the 737-900 and the 737-900ER with blended winglets and split scimitar winglets.  They have recently sent a beta build to their testers (which they hope to be the last one before release), with plans to release it next Tuesday (07/02) unless a major issue is found. Regarding pricing, it’s expected to be somewhere between the 600 and the 700/800.   The entire 737 lineup is set to get an update once the -900 rolls out, keeping all of them in sync and smoothing out some “annoyances”, fixing bugs, and improving the airplane handling (as an example, they mention the elimination of the notchiness with nearly-centered ground steering).  Regarding the Electronic Flight Tablet, it’s still being worked on. They have figured out an alternate way around the C++/WASM limitation, using a much simpler script-based language that can ‘talk to the outside world’, but PMDG found issues while trying to get the tablet and the airplane to communicate. While reinstating the lack of a release date for the EFT, they ensure it’s being extensively tested to provide the best experience possible once it’s out.   They finish off with a quick note on the modernized navdata implementation, which will replace their navdata system on the 737 once it’s ready to roll, allowing for greater accuracy in RNP procedures, and further improvements to the stability of lateral navigation. There’s no ETA for the said update.  The 900 is not available yet, but you can find the rest of the lineup on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Images are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! (All pictures shown are for illustration purposes only and may not be an exact representation of the product)</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffwv27</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Updates 757 v2 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffwv27" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd9733dbfc9cf71dbe57f6_blu1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1076162"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently issued an update to their Boeing 757 v2 Professional for X-Plane 11 and 12, with a range of XP12-related fixes going from livery improvements to tire friction coefficient alterations.   The 757 Professional v2 brings the Boeing 757 experience to the X-Plane world, featuring an accurate flight model, dynamic center of gravity, VR compatibility, a fully functional FMS and EFIS system, interactive checklists, custom systems and failure model, special effects, 3D sounds, and seven default liveries.  The update brings the 757 up to version 2.6.7 and includes an assortment of fixes: the FF house livery has been fully fixed, the gears are no longer floating or underground on the 757-RF, the landing altitude display brightness was addressed, and the X-Plane 12 rain was removed from the cabin windows, improving performance on some systems, along with a reduction on the tire friction coefficient for some models. The complete changelog follows down below:  The add-on is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $79.00, requiring at least 4 GB of free disk space, and is compatible with both X-Plane 11 and 12. Images are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffw767</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Updates 767 Professional for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffw767" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dd9c19c5fb2a718e74cc8c_azul1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1125774"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently issued an update to their 767-300 ER Professional for X-Plane 11 and 12, with a couple of XP12-related fixes concerning performance, the tire friction coefficient, and more.  The 767-300 ER Professional brings the 767 experience to the X-Plane world, featuring an accurate flight model tested by real-world pilots, a pop-out EFB with checklists, options, menus, PA announcements, and more, VR support, in-flight Navigraph charts, an electronic interactive checklist with an automatic helper, a fully functional FMS and EFIS system, custom systems and failure model, accurate 3D models with real dimensions based on external drawings provided by Boeing, high-resolution textures, spatial rain simulation, detailed passenger cabin, wingflex, and more.   The update brings the aircraft to version 1.6.7, bringing a similar changelog as of the latest 757 update, with tweaks on the landing alt display brightness, removal of the X-Plane 12 rain from the cabin windows (which increases performance), and a slight reduction on the tire friction coefficient. The complete changelog follows down below:   The add-on is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $79.00, requiring at least 4 GB of disk space to install, and is compatible with both X-Plane 11 and 12. Images are courtesy of AllNaturalBlue. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukrora</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Aurora Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukrora" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dda1a62a273947874b8bc6_auro1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="222047"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Chicago Aurora Municipal Airport (KARR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a public airport serving the city of Aurora, in Illinois. It’s sometimes used as a reliever airport for O’Hare and Midway, due to its proximity to Chicago (80 kilometers west).   It houses the Air Classics Museum of Aviation, which includes a collection of aircraft, vehicles, uniforms, and other aviation memorabilia from the 30s to the current day. The aircraft collection includes a Republic P-47D Thunderbolt replica, a Bayerische Flugwerke Messerschmitt BF-109 replica, a North American Aviation RF-86F Sabre, a McDonnell Douglas TA-4J Skyhawk, a Republic Aviation F-105D Thunderchief, a North American T-39 Sabreliner, a McDonnell Douglas F-4B Phantom II, a Ling-Temco-Vought A-7E Corsair II, a Bell UH-1H Iroquois, a Curtiss P-40 WarHawk replica, and a North American Aviation P-51D Mustang Replica.  As a curious fact, the Aurora Municipal Airport is one of the few airports in the United States where the FAA and IATA identifiers are not the same, because ARR was taken on the IATA by an airport in Argentina. Thus, it uses AUZ as its IATA code.   The traffic figures sit at 76,650 aircraft operations between April 2021 and April 2022, averaging 210 per day, with 98% corresponding to general aviation, 2% to air taxi, and 1% to military and commercial, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with full-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, high-detail airport vehicles, full set of signs, fencing, vegetation, PBR materials, interior details and parallax internals, and optional static aircraft.  It’s available on UK2000’s Store and SimMarket for roughly $15.65 and $14.15, respectively. At least 24 MB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wilgaf</id>
    <title>Got-Friends Release Wilga Series For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wilgaf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63de9a55853037f1b60c34ef_Marketplace_Background_PNG_PNG_PNG_1800x1800.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="202350"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Wilga is a Polish short-takeoff-and-landing (STOL) aircraft and originally it was manufactured by PZL Warszawa-Okęcie but and later by European Aeronautic Defence and Space Company (EADS), who acquired the original manufacturer in 2001. Microsoft flight sim addon developers Got-Friends have released their own version of the Wilga series aircraft which is now available on the MSFS Marketplace or through the Got-Friends website for $35.00  The aircraft comes with both Polish and English variants, it includes a modern avionics package and even comes with a scenery package - Forwood Farm which was hand-crafted by Emerald Scenery design in Partnership with Got-Friends. Overall there are 4 variants of the aircraft included in the package, each comes with its own unique features. </summary>
    <published>2023-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cow500</id>
    <title>Cowan Simulation Updates 500E for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cow500" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63dee87a3f35cc403e1816e9_co1-min.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="609798"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cowan Simulation has recently issued the very first update to their rendition of the MD 500E, fixing issues with the flight model, adjusting the 3D model, and more.  The MD Helicopters MD 500E is part of a family of light utility civilian and military helicopters, introduced in 1967 with the Hughes 500 (which was a civilian version of the OH-6A Cayuse/Loach), and developed over time into what it is now after Hughes was acquired in the 1980s by McDonnell Douglas Helicopters.   The 500E variant is an executive version of the 500D with a recontoured nose, certified in 1982. It’s powered by a Rolls-Royce Model 250-C20B turboshaft engine rated at 420 hp, with a maximum cruise speed of 135 knots and a range of 235 nautical miles at sea level, according to a 2022 chart.  The update brings many improvements to the flight model based on customer feedback. The developer mentions it still flies with a slight low left skid, and they plan to work more with the flight model in the future. The trim ball was also improved, yet they say it's not quite optimized for helicopters when using the correct code. Adjustments were made to the air intake tube in the nose, along with other small details in the 3d model. The remainder of the changelog follows down below:  The red emergency fuel cutoff valve code was fixed. There was a bug with wrong values. Now that should work properly. Pushed in is open and pulled out is closed. The ignition key needs to be on to run the starter now. Hopefully this does not trip anyone up.  The two cabin light switches and the lighting attached was changed. Now one is red and one is white and they are not so bright so you can use them at night. All the other lighting was gone through and optimized. Added some ambient light from the green panel lights. Fixed the skid nav lights with flex. Added some occluders to the skids and new bear paws so the grass lays/smashes down when off pavement. The two buttons above the cabin light toggles are now tied to rotor wash and engine heat blur effects. Pushing them will disable either respectively. 15 new liveries were added to the package to make a total of 63 available. Thank you Chrigel Linder for your contribution to this project. ‍ ‍ The 500E is available on Cowan Sim’s Store and SimMarket for $32.99 and roughly $33.33, respectively. At least 2.30 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simpps</id>
    <title>Simport Team Releases Porto Santo Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simpps" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e0126fba8407e1029446fb_sim1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3285822"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simport Team has recently released their rendition of Porto Santo Airport (LPPS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the oldest and first airport in the Madeira Islands, inaugurated in 1959.   With a yearly average of 180,000 passengers, most of the scheduled flights operate on a seasonal basis, with offerings from AlbaStar, Binter Canarias, easyJet, Eurowings Discover, TAP Air Portugal, and TUI Airways. Porto Santo has a single 3,000-meter-long runway, long enough for most airliners, and a modern terminal completed in 1995. The airport is shared with the Portuguese Air Force, with permanent detachments of Squadrons 502 and 751, whose main focus is search and rescue operations.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it stands, with 8K baked textures, custom 3d models, custom lights, accurate terrain elevation and runway profiles, realistic night lighting, custom ground textures, detailed markings, and custom satellite imagery. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.67, requiring at least 205 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spiint</id>
    <title>Spinoza Releases Interlaken Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spiint" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e022ca7571b7a5b060084b_inter1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1866816"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Spinoza has recently released their rendition of Interlaken Airport (LSMI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a former military airbase dating back to WW2.  Built by the Swiss Army Military in 1940, it originally had two runways, with the first one made of concrete and 600m of total length, made operational in 1942. The second one, 900 meters long, was completed a year later. After the war, it was converted into a Jet Maintenance Base for the De Havilland Vampire, with an eventual runway expansion to accommodate the fighter (the original runway was extended to 920 meters), along with the construction of a control tower. Further lengthening happened in the following decades, where it ended up at 1656 meters.  Commercial service took place for the first time in 1964, with Globe-Air flying from Interlaken to London thrice a week until 1967.  The base was closed in 2003, now hosting REGA 10, a Swiss Air-Rescue service responsible for more than 1100 mountain rescue operations annually.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the former airport as it stands, with the military hangars, a 3D model of the Jungfrau Park, and the REGA 10 - Wilderswil base.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.11, requiring at least 223 MB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avmsfs</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Avro Vulcan as Next MSFS Project</title>
    <updated>2023-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avmsfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63e0a35e2c0da73570befac2_328984399_653392803205798_2471093560067383555_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="346707"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer Just Flight has announced its latest project for MSFS - the Avro Vulcan. The team is working hard to bring this iconic British bomber to the community, utilizing the latest technologies the simulator has to offer. Just Flight has previously released a version of the bomber for X-Plane, P3D, and FSX, and is currently working to improve the plane and “bring it up to the very latest MSFS standards”. At this stage, however, it is unclear how much of the plane will be inherited from these older versions and how much of it will be built from the ground up. Alongside the announcement, a few preview photos of the plane have also been released to showcase its detailed modeling and texturing. According to the developers, the Vulcan’s basic flight model and systems are already complete and the plane is just entering an early testing phase. Though the team is quite optimistic about the bomber’s development, they stressed that their main focus is currently directed at other projects such as the F28 and RJ series. Currently, there is little information on the release date or pricing of the product. However, the developers did hint that the aircraft will also come to Xbox, provided that Microsoft fixes “the current WASM issues”. Threshold will keep you updated on the progress of the Vulcan. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
