<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-06-27T18:35:03.754308+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfse25</id>
    <title>Threshold at FlightSimExpo 2025: What to Expect</title>
    <updated>2025-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfse25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684eead05fdddd6bccb40fe2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FlightSimExpo returns this month, bringing one of the world’s largest flight simulation events to Providence, Rhode Island. With more than 3,000 attendees expected and over 70 exhibitors confirmed, FSExpo 2025 is shaping up to be one of the biggest gatherings yet for enthusiasts, developers, and aviation professionals alike. ‍ Threshold will once again be on-site to provide live coverage throughout the event. From June 27 to 29, our team will share real-time updates, breaking announcements, and hands-on insights from the show floor via our social media channels. Expect frequent posts across Bluesky, Instagram and Facebook, as well as video content directly from the exhibit hall. We will be streaming a special event on our YouTube channel, covering the biggest announcements and product reveals from #FSExpoFriday. As with last year, we will be speaking with major developers, creators, and exhibitors, bringing you exclusive video interviews and insights from the event. If you prefer to catch up at your own pace, don’t worry, we will publish daily roundup articles to summarise the key news and releases from each day. Attending in person? Feel free to say hello to Magnus and Drew on the show floor, they will be around all weekend and would love to meet you, whether you’re a long-time reader or just discovering Threshold! ‍ From product debuts to engaging conversations, we’re excited for what FSExpo 2025 has in store.  ‍ Be sure to follow Threshold for all the latest updates! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mslgsk</id>
    <title>Mango Studios Releases Skiathos International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mslgsk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/684f823e8a3d6ac3b711c010_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Mango Studios has recently released its version of Skiathos International Airport (LGSK) for X-Plane 12. Known for its challenging approach, this Greek airport welcomes over 550,000 passengers annually. Skiathos International Airport first opened its doors in 1972. In 1998, the airport added a passenger terminal and a new control tower. However, this terminal was closed due to a minor earthquake in 2001, and a new terminal was inaugurated just a year later, in 2002. Since 2019, the airport has operated with two terminals: one for international flights and another for domestic flights. Currently, the airport can accommodate aircraft as large as the Boeing 757-200. It serves a variety of airlines, including easyJet, Jet2.com, Olympic Air, Ryanair, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air, among others. These airlines help the airport handle over 550,000 passengers each year, supported by more than 5,000 annual aircraft movements. The scenery features 4K PBR terminals and airport buildings, a fully modelled car park and waterfront, custom runway textures, realistic GSE, a pre-made ortho tile, and much more. The newly released Skiathos International Airport is now available from the X-Plane.Org Software Store for $17.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/750css</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Releases Crossfill for GTN 750Xi/650Xi Units</title>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/750css"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68523601998401abc0b9a01c_gpslol.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. TDS Sim Software has updated their GTN 750Xi add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and X-Plane. The update adds crossfill between the two units, allowing them to talk to each other and exchange data. Contrary to popular belief, Garmin’s crossfill function does not only synchronize the active flight plan between two units; it also crosses over fourteen items, such as the flight plan catalog, user waypoints, user-defined frequencies, missed approach acknowledgment, nearest airport criteria, CDI scale, and more. Their crossfill implementation fully replicates the real unit’s behavior, using the same protocols as in real life, ensuring ultimate immersion and fidelity.  ‍ For crossfill to work, one must use an aircraft with two GTN units, be it two 750Xi, one 750Xi and a 650Xi, two 650Xis, and so on. It’s also possible to turn it off if the user wants individual flight plans on each. ‍ To get the functionality working, you should be on the Trainer’s V20.42 version or higher, 1.3.0.0 or higher of the TDN Pro for MSFS 2024, and 1.0.0.4 or higher for X-Plane. ‍ Furthermore, the GTN 750Xi/650Xi is now available in select default MSFS 2024 airplanes, as part of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s SimAttachments feature. Thanks to a mod created by one of their community members, their GPS unit canm now be part of the default Cessna 185 Skywagon, Cessna 404 Titan, and also on the Cessna 172 Skyhawk Classic. ‍ Work is underway to support even more default aircraft in the future: DA40, PC6 Gauge version, DV20, C152, Twin Otter, C207, V35B Bonanza, and H125. ‍ Please refer to their official website for further information. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ham618</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Hamburg Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ham618"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68536e1c6b7e0adbea6a1073_perle1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft recently released their rendition of Hamburg Airport (EDDH) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Hamburg metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 14.8 million passengers, making it the fifth-busiest airport in Germany. It opened in January 1911, making it the oldest International airport in operation in the world and the second oldest in Germany after Tempelhof, which is now closed. It was given its current name – Hamburg Airport – during the British occupation of Hamburg starting in 1945. Its importance was proven in 1948 when it was an essential part of the Berlin Airlift, where allies carried supplies to West Berlin after the Soviets had blockaded every land access, effectively cutting their supply lines. It was Lufthansa's hub in the mid-50s, although Frankfurt eventually replaced it due to growth constraints that couldn't be overcome. While this did not affect the airport's potential as a non-hub, it could not meet Lufthansa's expectations as a large hub.  It wasn't long until the government started discussing the construction of a new airport away from the city and thus not suffering from any potential growth constraints. While the idea seemed nice on paper, they quickly dismissed it due to how bad it was back in the 1960s to have your airport away from the city (transport infrastructure was far from efficient at the time). Thus, they settled with what they had, which could not grow much but was at least within the city's heart and easily accessible.  Furthermore, Lufthansa had already moved to Frankfurt, so the traffic demands were not justifiably high anymore. The 1990s saw extensive modernization work at the airport, including a pier extension, a new terminal, and an airport plaza between the terminals. It's a focus city for Condor, Eurowings, Ryanair, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air Cairo, Air France, Air Serbia, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, Croatia Airlines, Emirates, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, TAP, Tunisair, Turkish, Volotea, and Vueling also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, realistic 3D ground, custom aerial imagery, detailed airport buildings, seasons support, 3D vegetation, custom animated vehicles, custom animated jetways, and more. It's available on their shop for $19.99, requiring at least 2.6 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsa321n</id>
    <title>FSLabs Releases A321neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsa321n"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68540e8ed866ddc50457ee02_fslneo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs recently released their rendition of the Airbus A321neo, the largest and most capable member of the A320 family, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024.  Airbus introduced the A321neo in 2010 as the next generation of their very popular A321. It features newer—and more efficient—engines, aerodynamic enhancements, and higher passenger capacity, making it a solid choice for airlines wishing to transport passengers efficiently on high-density routes. FSLabs’ rendition attempts to capture the full range of technological and operational advancements that define the new generation of Airbus narrow-body aircraft. Engine behavior, extended range capabilities, and fuel management logic were all modeled to reflect the real counterpart as closely as possible.  The rollout will be done in two phases, with the first (current) focusing on the A321-251N and A321-251NX equipped with CFM LEAP-1A32 engines, the A321-252N and A321-252NX featuring the LEAP-1A30 variant, and the A321-253N and A321-253NX with the LEAP-1A33. The second phase will follow shortly and include the A321-271N and NX, powered by Pratt &amp; Whitney 1133G-JM engines, and the A321-272N and NX, powered by the 1130G-JM engine. They split the development phase to streamline development, testing, and delivery. The second phase will be provided at no extra cost. The complete feature set includes all the aforementioned variants with their respective performance profiles, startup behavior, thrust response, and fuel efficiency. It also accurately depicts the standard and ACF cabins with their peculiarities. The DRAIMS (Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System) is also included, featuring seamless integration with VHF radios, audio selectors, intercom functionality, and PA systems. The full feature list follows below: ‍ A321 NEO LR Support with Additional Centre Tanks (ACTs): ‍ DRAIMS – Digital Radio and Audio Integrating Management System: ‍ High-Fidelity Flight Performance Model: ‍ Custom Engine Sound set: ‍ Advanced ELAC L103 (Elevator Aileron Computer): ‍ ‍ Updated FADEC with engine cooling: ‍ Realistic ground handling: ‍ ROPS / ROW Integration (Runway Overrun Protection / Warning): ‍ GSX Pro Full Integration: ‍ Fully Integrated ATSU/AOC Functionality: ‍ A321ceo owners are eligible for a discount coupon, which needs to be redeemed here. The offer is only valid until September 15, 2025.  The add-on is available in their store for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsrsss</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Starship for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsrsss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68546092a5ad2bba524cd835_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has released the highly anticipated Starship for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This aircraft was developed in partnership with the owners of the real Starship to ensure the most realistic recreation possible. Development of the Starship began in 1979, and after ten years, in 1989, the first production model took to the skies. Although a total of 50 Starships were built, only six remain airworthy today. The aircraft was groundbreaking for several reasons: it was the first certified canard wing aircraft, the first all-composite structure business aircraft, the first certified twin pusher turboprop, and the first general aviation aircraft to feature an all-glass cockpit. Additionally, it is one of only three civilian turboprop aircraft with a service ceiling of 41,000 feet. The Starship was truly ahead of its time. The aircraft is equipped with numerous features, including an accurate recreation of the Collins avionics suite, a sophisticated pressurisation simulation, and an advanced cabin temperature simulation. It offers 230 potential failure scenarios, a new tablet interface, and much more. These various features contribute to its promotion as one of the most advanced aircraft simulations available for the simulator. The newly released Starship by Black Square is now available from Just Flight for $54.99.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bs757p</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Shares 757 Pricing and Beta Plans in Latest Video Update</title>
    <updated>2025-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bs757p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685829e71757547af85458c1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a new YouTube video, the owner and CEO of BlueBird Simulations, Shervin Ahooraei, has shared a June update on the team’s upcoming Boeing 757 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update confirms pricing details and outlines the aircraft’s multi-phase beta roadmap. While development progress is steady, Ahooraei emphasised that a release remains several months away. The passenger variant of the 757, including both the -200 and -300 models, and multiple engine options, will be priced at $80. The aircraft will be compatible with both MSFS 2020 and 2024. It will be available for PC through Just Flight and BlueBird’s website. The Xbox version is expected several months after the initial release. ‍ “Just because we're comfortable announcing a price doesn't mean we're close to release”, said Ahooraei in the video. “We're still months away from the next stage of testing”. Ahooraei also outlined a three-phase beta program, beginning with a small group of testers with extensive experience with the 757. Stage two, described as the most critical, depends on completing the flight management system (FMS), which Ahooraei acknowledged is still several months away due to its complexity. The final stage will open for broader testing, allowing access for all users. Recent development efforts have focused on a comprehensive rework of the pneumatic system, enabling a more authentic engine start process and failure simulation. BlueBird has implemented functional air-ground logic and the 757’s engine electronic control (EEC) computer, while completing significant work on flight controls, using custom code. Over 450 custom sound samples are now integrated into the cockpit, and although the virtual cabin is beta-ready, additional cabin features are not currently a priority. Looking ahead to FlightSimExpo 2025, BlueBird Simulations will exhibit for the first time, with a fully equipped 10x20 booth showcasing the 757. Attendees can try the aircraft hands-on using a dedicated hardware setup, featuring peripherals from Thrustmaster and WinWing.  ‍ Ahooraei reiterated the team’s long-term vision and commitment to quality: “The goal is to be a top-tier developer, and the 757 is just the beginning.” BlueBird also reaffirmed work on its Boeing 767, beginning with the -300ER variant. Handled by a separate team, the project doesn’t impact 757 development, but draws from shared resources and an established codebase, which is expected to speed up development. No release date has been announced, and Ahooraei was clear in managing expectations: “We’re here for the long haul. We’re not going anywhere.” FlightSimExpo 2025 begins on 27 June in Providence, Rhode Island.  ‍ For all the latest updates, be sure to follow Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mjcdsh</id>
    <title>Majestic Software Publishes In-Sim Renders of Upcoming Q400 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mjcdsh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6859e571a075141a4e1498af_dasher1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Majestic Software recently shared the first in-game previews of their upcoming Bombardier Dash 8 Q400 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which is being “aggressively worked on.” The developer clarified it is still an early work-in-progress preview, and the model being displayed is far from final and undergoing a rebuilding process. Further development updates will come as “they deem necessary,” and there is no information about pricing, features, or a potential release date. Majestic’s Q400 was one of the most detailed add-ons during the Microsoft Flight Simulator X/Prepar3d era. It featured a completely external flight model that could accurately replicate the behavior of a propeller engine and a deep system simulation across different versions. For a premium, the user could settle for either an A to B plane with no failures or a near-complete training suite.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xpl624</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases New X-Plane 12 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xpl624"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ef0ee9572b607093dd0c18_lgt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has released update 12.2.0 after a few months of beta testing. This update brings a major graphics overhaul to their latest flight simulator, with new clouds, new tone mapping for lighting, and much more. First launched on alpha in March 2025, update 12.2.0 was finally deemed mature enough to enter the release channel. It brings a wealth of improvements to the simulator’s visuals and overall performance and fixes long-standing issues, such as the dark cockpits, which are no longer a problem. Furthermore, the update also overhauls the cloud rendering system, making it more efficient and closer to reality. The changes to the sky don’t change there, with tonemapping tweaks and atmospheric rendering improvements that bring better sky colors and cloud shadows. The simulator’s stability has improved significantly, resulting in a more consistent experience. Airport ground textures have also been revamped, with crisper markings all around. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmlgsm</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Samos International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmlgsm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685b051ca2819fe5c5c30a23_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has just released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This time, the team focused on the Greek island of Samos, specifically Samos International Airport (LGSM). Annually, the airport welcomes nearly 500,000 passengers looking for the Greek sun. Opened nearly 50 years ago in 1976, the airport has a long history. The terminal underwent renovation in the late 1990s, which significantly increased its capacity to handle passengers. The airport is known for its challenging approach due to its surroundings and strong winds. Today, it is served by airlines such as Aegean Airlines, Jet2.com, Scandinavian Airlines, Sky Express, and TUI fly Nordic, providing flights to various destinations across Europe, including Athens, London, Copenhagen, Oslo, and Stockholm, among others. With nearly 6,000 aircraft movements each year, the airport accommodates just under 500,000 passengers annually. The scenery features an accurate 3D model of the terminal and control tower, realistic terrain with slope adaptation, custom vegetation, enhanced night lighting, high-resolution textures using PBR implementation, and much more. The newly released Samos International Airport, developed by MM Simulation, is now available from Orbx for approximately $18.60. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aeac</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Announces Early Access Program for Upcoming Accu-Sim Aerostar</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aeac"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has made a surprise announcement in their Discord community regarding the long-awaited Piper Aerostar, which will be released in early access this July, allowing the community to experience the aircraft as it undergoes its final polishing stages. ‍ They claim the development process has taken longer than expected due to a “combination of business demands and personal challenges.” Still, the result is “an exceptional aircraft that we are incredibly proud of.” ‍ The aircraft’s systems and features are said to be mostly complete at this point. It will enter its early access phase next month as a “late beta,” with only a few areas yet to be refined and polished. ‍ A roadmap detailing their post-release updates will follow shortly after release. ‍ There’s no pricing or a date for the release yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfk204</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s FS Traffic Now Compatible with MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfk204"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de9518d6a767358f14d12_traffik1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight recently updated FS Traffic to support Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, along with a temporary 20% discount, lowering its retail price from $39.99 to $31.99. FS Traffic is a traffic solution made from the ground up for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, with performant 3D models, high-definition liveries, night lighting textures, custom animations (engine fans, flaps, spoilers, and thrust reversers), custom visual effects (contrails, engine heat blur, exterior lighting, and touchdown smoke), compatibility with airports jetways and ground units, and realistic sounds crafted by Turbine Sounds Studios. Furthermore, the solution adds tens of thousands of real-life commercial flight plans from different time periods, covering the whole world. Their provider powers several popular flight-tracking websites and applications, making the data as accurate as it gets. You can choose the day of the week you want to fly, with varying traffic intensity depending on the day. Flight plans can be wholly customized with their Traffic Control Centre application, and there’s next to no impact on overall performance. It’s available in their store for roughly $31.99 (temporary discount), requiring at least 30 GB of free hard drive space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxjul</id>
    <title>FlightFX's C750 to Release in July for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxjul"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685def6f7d4378fb1e58c875_citation1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlightFX has finally set a release date for their upcoming C750 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. It will be available in people’s virtual hangars on July 10 as an MSFS Marketplace exclusive. “After countless late nights, endless reworks, a few are we there yet moments, and more caffeine than any doctor would recommend - the C750 is ready for takeoff on July 10”, they said at the start of their announcement post on Discord. “We know it has been a long road, and we sincerely appreciate the patience and support from this community. We’re excited to finally get it into your hands”. The Cessna 750 Citation X is a mid-size business jet produced by Cessna, announced in October 1990 and first flown in 1993, with its certification following 3 years later. It used an entirely new design compared to the previous Citations, with commonality only being maintained around some cockpit controls, the windshield, and the tail light bulb. It incorporated many innovative design features for the time, such as the large diameter of the engine intakes, reducing the noise, and improving fuel efficiency. The highly swept wing with a supercritical airfoil increased its top speed, making it faster than all the previous generations.  ‍ The design process also involved making it as aerodynamically efficient as possible, trying to minimize drag and, thus, improve its overall efficiency. The innovative wing design was part of that thought process during the development. ‍ It’s powered by two Rolls-Royce AE 3007Cs with either 6442 or 6764 lbs of thrust, allowing it to cruise at 972 km/h, covering up to 3,460 nautical miles of range, at up to 51,000ft.  ‍ FlightFX’s rendition features an accurate simulation of the Primus 2000 flight suite, full VNAV, a custom FADEC with an optional VNAV-coupled auto-throttle, two variants: winglet or no-winglet with their respective performance impact, a real-time EPB system for dynamic engine performance modeling, a deeply modeled pressurization, environmental, hydraulic, electrical, fuel, and ICE systems, full RTU and autopilot capability, realistic IRS, CAS, engine sync, and more. Their custom Electronic Flight Bag features Navigraph and OpenStreetMap integration, a SimBrief-linked load manager, active noise reduction, a ground services manager, and an options customizer (auto-throttle, LCD/CRT toggle, etc.). ‍ The airplane also features wing flex, enhanced lighting inside and out, realistic clutter and cabin details, and dynamic registration on the placard and covers. ‍ The audio was recorded on-site in California, with real APU, engine, mechanical, chime, and cabin interaction sounds. ‍ The add-on is releasing on July 10, exclusively at the Marketplace for $29.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl306</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo and A321neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl306"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685e7451454fab1b0a43e8b9_neow1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently issued an update to their A321ceo and newly released A321neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing system improvements, model updates, sound enhancements, and more. Update v11.0.1.306 improves logging and error reporting, brings several improvements to the systems, adds wingflex in interior views, removes rubber marks from the flap textures, brings a complete rework of the ground roll, landing, and take-off sounds, and much more. The full changelog follows below: AOC Service: Systems Improvements: Model Updates: Sound Enhancements: ATSU Updates: Furthermore, FSLabs has added a free hardware interface for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing seamless integration between their two products and selected high-end hardware, starting with full support for the Skalarki product line. From the mini overhead panel to the DCDU, the interface allows plug-and-play functionality, aiming to deliver an immersive and highly authentic experience. It can be seen live and in action at FlightSimExpo 2025 at Skalarki’s booth (stand 116). They conclude the blog post on the update with a brief progress update on the PWs, which is said to be coming soon, and they have been hard at work at properly integrating it, from its very unique “whale-like” sound to how it performs and flies, being more than just a different 3D model. The update is only available on their experimental channel for the time being. Users can switch to the experimental branch by heading over to the settings page of their Control Center (in right corner of the settings page).  ‍ Their A321ceo and neo are available for $69.95 each + VAT on their website. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozafe</id>
    <title>MOZA Releases New Flight Sim Equipment at the FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozafe"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ebc8bb89cd73a97bdc143_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. MOZA has recently launched a range of new products at FlightSimExpo 2025, further expanding its flight simulation ecosystem. Among these new products are a new force feedback flight base, a throttle quadrant, a pair of rudder pedals, and more. The first new release is the AB6 FFB Flight Base, accompanied by the MHG Flightstick. The AB6 Flight Base delivers 6 Nm of torque, providing realistic torque feedback due to its high-performance outrunner motor. It also includes dual throttle sliders. The MHG Flightstick, designed for high-performance control in conjunction with the AB6, is ergonomically crafted and features programmable buttons, hat switches, adjustable resistance, and more. Next, MOZA introduces the MTQ Throttle Quadrant. This new throttle quadrant is designed to be modular, ensuring compatibility for flying both commercial jets and fighter jets. It features swappable grips, allowing users to choose between fighter jet style levers, Airbus style levers, and Boeing style levers. The team has introduced a new pair of rudder pedals known as the MRP Rudder Pedals. These pedals are constructed entirely from metal and feature metal brake pedals as well. They come equipped with non-slip rubber pads for added stability. Designed for high performance, the pedals include a precision swing-arm design, customizable centering force, and an optional adjustable damper. The final release is the FMP18 Front Panel System. Inspired by legacy naval jet cockpits, this system offers a full-scale, cockpit-grade replica. It features authentic 7.1-inch square displays, universal VESA mount compatibility, and an angle adjustment clamp. This system is a must-have for anyone who enjoys these kinds of aircraft. MOZA has not yet announced pricing for its various products, but we will keep you updated once new information is available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ta320c</id>
    <title>ToLiss Announces Upcoming Airbus A320ceo for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ta320c"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ebc0a1567fd5f4a5401d1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ToLiss has announced they are developing the A320ceo for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Following the release of the A320neo in 2023, the team is now focusing on the predecessor of the newer A320neo. Although the team has not yet provided additional details, they have announced that the A320ceo will be released as an addon for the current A320neo. They also mentioned that the release of this addon is planned for before the end of 2025. ToLiss has not announced pricing yet or shared any previews, but the team mentioned that more news will be coming tomorrow. It is unclear whether this news is related to the upcoming A320ceo. We will keep you informed as more information becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
