<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-10-16T18:32:54.089987+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ife346</id>
    <title>IndiaFoxtEcho Visual Simulations releases M-346 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.</title>
    <updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ife346" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633c6167bbba790b88584aad_302726521_6020609041285840_6318830664896955025_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="755770"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IndiaFoxtEcho Visual Simulations has released their M-346 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Leonardo M-346 is a twin-engine fighter commonly used for training in armed forces, with primary users Israeli Air Force, Italian Airforce, and the Polish Airforce, to name a few. The M-346 was also a contender to replace the T-38 in the US Airforce, being succeeded by the Boeing T-7. India Fox Echo recreated procedures based on the actual M-346 flight manuals, with a focus also on the HUD, MFD, and UFCP. Modeling and texturing details are faithful to the actual aircraft, with ten liveries included.  ‍ ‍ IndiaFoxtecho will improve and add more features to the M-346 as time progresses. Currently available for PC with an XBox version coming soon. The M-346 is available on OrbixDirect and SimMarket. Check out the well-produced trailer by the Italian Virtual Airforce here!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/apaefm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews A330’s EFB for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/apaefm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633dee8c23c51ff5b6d65c70_as3.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="84857"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a short video, Mathijs Kok from Aerosoft has previewed some of the functionalities of their brand new Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) for the upcoming A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It covers relevant aspects such as Simbrief integration, NavDataPro/Navigraph compatibility, flight planning tools, live map, pushback, etc. There is no information about release date or pricing just yet, but you can follow the development updates on Aerosoft’s forum thread on the A330’s progress.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpgrha</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Releases Hot Air Balloon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpgrha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633fa905abe2687a20674e52_bal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="261776"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has released their Hot Air Balloon for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Usually known for developing helicopters such as the H135 freeware and the payware H145, they decided to try ballooning next. With a custom flight model, it’s - according to HPG - the first professionally developed hot air balloon for MSFS. The feature list follows down below: The add-on is available on HPG’s website for $15.00. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inivlb</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases its Free Venice Beach Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inivlb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634189cd5b23083a3a3c648a_VBC.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="583795"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ iniBuilds released its Venice Beach Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator today, featuring the well-known attractions Venice offers. iniBuilds recently released its KLAX scenery, making an ideal bundle for scenery covering the Southern California Area. The pack covers the Boardwalk while adding the expected lifeguard shacks, vehicles, and a fictional beach airstrip. Scenery focusing on non-airport environments could soon reshape flight sim scenery. iniScenes is on to something with this package. The KLAX Venice Beach Pack is Free for Microsoft Flight Simulator; on the iniBuilds store.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xenviro</id>
    <title>xEnviro 1.17 Released</title>
    <updated>2022-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xenviro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6341d241a7d2d7f0c45ac29b_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="348608"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After an extended development time due to real-world circumstances, The team behind xEnviro have finally released their latest version of the product, update 1.17. Containing loads of new features and updates to the weather add-on. ‍ ‍ The team at behind the project have worked really hard to get this new version of xEnviro to everyone, considering what happened with some of the developers in the aftermath of the invasion of Ukraine. This update is rather major compared to the recent version 1.16, and contains an overall new look and major changes to the already robust weather plugin. The team will also continue to update this plugin as long as they deem necessary and worthwhile for the people who still use X-Plane 11. ‍ From the extensive forum post project leader Magnus Lorvik made about the update, the post mentions the hurdles and limitations when it comes to bringing the plugin into the newly released X-Plane 12 Early Access, as well as the major updates 1.17 brings to the table. ‍ “X-Plane 12 Sadly, there is some bad news. Laminar Research have turned down the idea of bringing xEnviro into their newly released simulator X-Plane 12 due to reasoning that the team at Threshold cannot understand and find somewhat puzzling. There have been ongoing arguments and conflict issues with Laminar Research attempting to bring xEnviro to X-Plane 12, but as the Executive states “We’re tired of fighting and hopelessly defending long development cycles”. This is not just us that are having difficulties coming to terms with Laminar Research, Developers Enhanced Skyskapes, SkyMaxx and others are also experiencing the same issue.  ‍ VR Compatibility Threshold has made a main change to xEnviro in version 1.17 by basing it on a spherical buffer. This has allowed them to get a much better performance for lower end machines and higher screen resolutions. Higher end machines also benefit, but not as much. VR is only compatible currently with Vulkan. ‍ 1:1 Scale The team at Threshold have made a main objective to make a true to life representation of the environment as possible and thus we recreate the atmosphere in 1:1 scale. This differs to other clouds in MSFS and X-Plane 12 as xEnviro gives a true positioning awareness when relating to your surroundings in the sky. An example of this is when you fly between two layers of clouds that are close to each other. While in MSFS and X-Plane 12 you get claustrophobic in a 5000 feet gap, you will perceive this as a grand space in xEnviro. ‍ Some Known Issues The 1:1 scale has its demands on performance. The main compromising issue in 1.17 is obvious when you load into the sim. Movement shimmer. This is not a huge problem when you fly slow and are gone when standing still. The artefacts are especially noticeable around the edges of the clouds. We have added a quality slider to reduce that shimmer - but at the cost of performance. This will be a continuous target to refine and improve for us going forward.  ‍ ‍ 1.17 Changelog ‍ Added ‍ Changed ‍ Removed Known issues ‍ If you are a current owner of xEnviro, this update will be free to obtain by heading over to the X-Plane.org Store or the Threshold Store and downloading the latest version. If you are still an X-Plane 11 user and would like to purchase this addon, you can purchase it through both the X-Plane Store for $69.90 or the Threshold Store for $69.69. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/90t7ef</id>
    <title>PMDG Drops New Updates on Current Projects for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/90t7ef" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63436a636a3b91068879ba22_Screenshot_640%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="748136"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After an extended period of silence, Robert Randazzo has dropped a new update detailing the final piece that complete the 737 NG family in MSFS, We know that we can expect the final aircraft from the 737 fleet, the 737-900, at some point during November unless they find more obstacles along the way. It is approaching the beta testing phase which has been hindered due to the uncovering a few issues, causing PMDG to push the Beta test date back. As part of the update, we got to take a look at the newly developed EFB for all of the Boeing fleet that should hopefully be with us soon! This new addition could massively enhance users' experience within the Simulator to make a more realistic flight. The EFB will allow for better performance computations, analysis, weight/balance, etc. It will also enable the use of Navigraph and SimBrief inside of the aircraft. Unfortunately, as it is a quick preview, we’re still in the dark with any potential roll-out of the EFB feature to be here with us to be used in MSFS. The update has also touched-base with some new updates regarding the development for the Xbox side and things are looking rather promising. The team is currently awaiting further news from Asobo/MS as they are still working on compatibility for C++/WASM projects on the Xbox platform. Once this has been completed, then PMDG will release the DC-6 for Xbox first, to ensure everything works smoothly before making the 737 fleet available on the platform. As a final note from the update, Randazzo has dropped some new information regarding their next product to be ported to MSFS. We have been told that the development of the 777 has seen a massive amount of progress since the last update and they seem to be running more ahead than they thought! Their plan is to use a more worn, mid-aged 777 cockpit to replicate rather than a brand new one as the 737’s are. This should overall give a far better unique look to the 777 and enhance the visuals for the people who will fly this aircraft. Robert stated himself “Wait until you see it- it is spectacular!”. That’s all for the info-drop from PMDG, If you are interested in the other aircraft PMDG currently have released then head over to the PMDG website. For MSFS they currently have released the DC-6 and all the 737 aircraft apart from the -900 Variant.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rrgcba</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Girona-Costa Brava Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rrgcba" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6345b11d86c63a50448511d4_giro1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="432286"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has just released their rendition of Girona-Costa Brava Airport (LEGE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Catalonian connection to Costa Brava and the Pyrenees is visited by 2 million passengers yearly, served by airlines such as Ryanair, Jet2, Transavia, and Tui Airways. Built in 1965, the traffic figures used to be low up until the early 2000s, when Ryanair chose Girona as one of their European hubs, making the figure grow exponentially, from less than 200,000 yearly to over 5.5 million in 2008. Ryanair’s move to El Prat International (bigger airport) made the numbers drop by half in 2012, where it currently sits. ‍ The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ The scenery is available on FlightSim.to for $17.99 and on the RDPresets store for €19.99. At least 2.57GB of free disk space is required to install the product.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oraams</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Asturias Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oraams" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6349449a82ef363ece098174_asturias.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1934786"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has just released their rendition of Asturias Airport (LEAS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the only International Airport of the Principality of Asturias, in Spain. It’s a relevant domestic destination, visited by an average of 1.5 million passengers yearly and a focus city for Volotea and Vueling. Ryanair will operate international routes out of Asturias starting in early November, with destinations such as Charleroi, Dublin, London, Rome and Weeze.  Originally released for Prepar3d, the Microsoft Flight Simulator version got an enhancement on textures, new clutter, new custom animated jetways, airside traffic and optional static aircraft.  The complete feature list follows down below: The add-on is available on OrbxDirect for $15.49, requiring 1.70 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/osalhx</id>
    <title>Origami Studios Announces London Heathrow for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/osalhx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634a0f48a4b16a5c57451dd6_lhr1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1596674"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Origami Studios has recently announced their rendition of London Heathrow (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, the home of British Airways and Virgin Atlantic. It is the 7th busiest airport in the world, averaging 80 million passengers yearly, and has a route network that covers the whole globe. According to their product page, the scenery will feature an accurate rendition with custom buildings, a modeled Terminal 5 interior, moving jetways, landmarks, and points of interest, and modern X-Plane 12 features such as snow and rain effects, reflections and 3D forests. It is said to be coming soon to the iniBuilds store. There is no information regarding the release date or pricing yet, but we’ll keep you updated.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/usrsam</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Spaceport America for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/usrsam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634a3b20f3dfcb35d624a342_space1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2206963"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Spaceport America (9NM9) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an FAA-licensed spaceport in New Mexico (United States) for vertical and horizontal launch space vehicles, launched in 2011 and deemed ready for operations in 2019.  Owned and operated by the State of New Mexico, it is the first purpose-built commercial spaceport, focusing solely on commercial operations. It’s home to companies such as HAPSMobile and SpinLaunch, and a hub for Virgin Galactic, Up Aerospace, and Exos Aerospace.  Its concept was first introduced in 1990 by Dr. Burton Lee, a Stanford University engineering lecturer. Responsible for writing the initial business and strategy plans, he secured 1.4 million dollars in seed funding, aided by Senator Pete Domenici. In 1992, they formed the Southwest Space Task Force, focusing on advancing New Mexico’s space industry  infrastructure and activity-wise. After lots of research, they chose a 70 square kilometer plot of state-owned land, near Las Cruces, to build the spaceport. In 2003, the Economic Development Cabinet Secretary Rick Homans presented the idea to Governor Bill Richardson, which then reached an agreement with Sir Richard Branson from Virgin to make New Mexico the headquarters for Virgin Galactic and consequently facilitate it for the state laws to be enacted and authorize the construction of the airport.  The scenery was built with PBR textures, accurately replicating the real-life counterpart as it looks in 2022. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available for purchase on FlightSim.to for $7.49 or on UK2000’s website for £7.49, requiring at least 77 MB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffa320u</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases New Update for A320</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffa320u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634a5fd29bff5644bb3c7f2a_Screenshot%202022-10-15%20at%202.22.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3340893"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer FlightFactor has recently released a new update to its popular A320 aircraft for X-Plane. This update brings various bug fixes and quality of life improvements to the plane, as well as an array of other misc. features. The A320 made by FlightFactor was first released for X-Plane 10 in February 2018. It was further updated to be made compatible with X-Plane 11 a short time later. The team at FlightFactor has been making constant progress at  fixing any issues and adding new systems to the aircraft. However, there was a long period of no development to the A320 for X-Plane 11 and some users were experiencing performance issues. FlightFactor had reacted to this by releasing a major new update towards the end of 2021 which had fixed many issues users were experiencing. When X-Plane 12 was released, FlightFactor had worked hard on the constant updates with this aircraft and are still continuing to make the small little changes to enhance the users experience within the sim. The new version marks another solid step in the development of the Airbus A320, which is currently an open BETA phase for X-Plane 12. The update provides overall improvements to the flight deck such as font stylings and colors and other quality of life updates to the aircraft systems. Below, You will find the changelog for newly updated A320 v1.5.2 BETA. ‍ Improvements: Fixes: ‍ The update is free and now available to download for all current owners of the A320. You can do this by updating it through the X-Updater or heading over to the X-Plane.org Store. If you want to become an owner of this aircraft then you can purchase it on the X-Plane.org Store. In addition to the A320 beta, the team at Flight Factor has also been hard at work developing their upcoming 777 Professional v2. They have recently released a small development update in regards to the emergency batteries panel. Currently, no further updates have been provided in regards to the 787. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfrjpr</id>
    <title>JustFlight Release Update on RJ Professional Development</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfrjpr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634abbb3a52156542b692494_4_RJ100_BA_Colum_e7EKPrRyT.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="93190"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight have released a new development update on their upcoming RJ Professional series. Announced officially on the 15th of August 2022, the RJ professional line is set to be a more modern and streamlined version of their previous “146 Professional” addon. Differences include slightly larger and more powerful engines, but the most significant difference comes in the flight deck! The RJ professional line will boast an all-new EFIS system replacing the traditional analogue ADI, HSI and engine instruments.  In providing an update on the development process, JustFlight has said: “The interior and cockpit modelling and texturing has been undergoing extensive testing in recent weeks, with every rivet, screw and label being compared to its real-life counterpart, to ensure 100% accuracy. After spending many months developing the 146, it’s been interesting to see just how much was improved and upgraded in the later RJ, and how all come together to reduce pilot workload without losing the appeal of the aircraft.” JustFlight has informed us that throughout the cockpit the majority of instruments are now “alive” and being fine-tuned. The other significant bit of work to take place has been the development of over 30 different true-to-life liveries which will be released with the aircraft!  To read more from JustFlight's latest RJ development update click here! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwoneo</id>
    <title>X-Works Release A330-900NEO Mod for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwoneo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634ae17aa8b1bb7dfa7b4eb8_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="454110"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Works have released their A330-900neo mod for the Laminar Research A330-300 in X-Plane 12. They have worked hard as a team to bring this modification together for users to enjoy the newest variant of the A330. During the time this aircraft modification has been in development , the development team has given sneak peaks and modeling updates to show the progress of the A330-900neo. X-Works have also stated, “If you are on windows: DO NOT update to beta 7! Laminar broke the A330-300 and thus our mod too.” If you want to use this modification you will have to avoid the latest X-Plane 12 BETA update until a fix has been brought out to the Laminar Research. ‍ Features of the X-Works A330-900neo: ‍ To obtain this modification, you can head over to X-Plane.to to download it for Free. To install, you simply duplicate the default Laminar Research A330 folder and drag the new files in, overwrite when prompted to. ‍ If you would like to download liveries for this aircraft, then you can head over to their discord server where they have a selection of liveries. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/versir</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Release KSYR Syracuse for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/versir" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634c0db8014580b7685b6640_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="445532"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Syracuse Hancock International Airport (KSYR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a joint civil-military airport located in central New York that first opened in September 1949. ‍ The real airport is operated by the Syracuse Regional Airport Authority (SRAA) and encompasses approximately 2,000 acres of land in Onondaga County, about 6 miles northeast of the city of Syracuse. ‍ The airport serves as a major transportation centre in central New York, providing direct connections to 29 destinations which are served by a multitude of aircraft from General Aviation, cargo, scheduled commercial flying as well as military aircraft. The airport has a challenging cross-runway configuration as well as a beautiful approach overflying the Oneida and Onondaga Lakes. The original airfield was opened in 1927 as a node for handling airmail for Syracuse and the surrounding towns, the airport expanded into a training centre for the Army Air Forces 14 years later. A short while later in 1949, the airport was replaced with a new airfield that we know today as the original complex could not accommodate the rapidly increasing traffic and demand. Since then, the airport has received numerous enhancements and upgrades, the most recent being a $62 million renovation of the main terminal.  ‍ For Verticalsim’s rendition, the scenery comes with a standard set of features that we can expect from most airport sceneries on Microsoft Flight Simulator, built with high-definition PBR textures and models that accurately represent the airport in its current form. Verticalsim announced that the airport is the team’s most detailed airport to date. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ Verticalsims rendition of KSYR Syracuse airport for MSFS is available for purchase on Verticalsim's website for $17.99, requiring over 4 GB of free disk space to install. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbd757</id>
    <title>Blue Bird Simulations Releases New Previews for 757 in MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbd757" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634c0e74e521b66e3410709c_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="382977"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Blue Bird Simulations has recently released new previews of their upcoming Boeing 757 project for MSFS. The update, which was made on the Blue Bird Simulations Facebook page, provided new images of the nose gear area of the aircraft including textures imported into the sim for the first time. The release, which is planned for late summer/fall 2023 is set to include passenger versions of both the 200 and 300 variants of the Boeing 757. Each variant will include the Pratt &amp; Whitney as well as the Rolls Royce engine options along with winglet and non-winglet types. ‍ Launched back in February this year, the project has seen rapid a development pace, with multiple update drops: one in April and more recently a few months back in July.  The Boeing 757’s stunning performance makes it one of the most popular Boeing aircraft ever built. Its adaptable seating configurations, spacious cabin, and suitability for short, medium and long-range operations offer its users flexibility and its passengers the ultimate in comfort. The first prototype completed its maiden flight on February 19, 1982, and it was FAA certified on December 21st. Blue Bird have said that their rendition of the 757 will be a mid-level complexity aircraft which will be several layers more complex than the default airliners.  The team have a dedicated airline pilot who is putting in a lot of time and effort to make sure the flight model is as realistic as possible using real-world data. The product is a combined effort from developers with decades of experience in flight simulation development.  The Blue Bird Simulations Boeing 757 is set to release in mid to late 2023 and is likely to be available from the Just Flight store, till then, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsqkia</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases King Air Analogue Gauge Overhaul</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsqkia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634c2bb945464d5e2a272ea5_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="433191"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently released their steam gauge overhaul for the Asobo King Air 350i, the second add-on in Black Square’s overhaul series for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  The new study-level remake of the Beechcraft King Air 350i, which is provided as default with the simulator, provides a completely redesigned interior and panel for the mid-range turboprop aircraft. The overhaul features a fully custom and remodelled electrical system, full 3D cockpit lighting for each gauge and panel, improved flight and turbine dynamics, panel state-saving options, crew oxygen system, checklists, flight manuals and custom failures. Users will find an increased level of detail on the various instrument panels compared to the default level which is also replicated in the cabin.  The Beechcraft King Air 350i is one of the world's most popular business turboprop aircraft due to its versatility. The aircraft is an updated version of Beechcraft’s very sucessful and popular B300 series and features improvements in the cabin, better performance as well as a lower operating cost compared to other models. The aircraft's Pratt &amp; Witney PT6 turboprop engines produce over 1000 horsepower each allowing the aircraft to maintain a speed of 290 knots cruising at 35,000 feet.  Various radio navigation systems are available from several eras of the King Air’s history, so users can pick and choose how they would like to outfit their aircraft’s avionics suite. The Black Square 350i is equipable with a Bendix KNS-80 RNAV system or they can fly with the convenience of a fully digital Garmin GTN 750, giving the user true customisation over their aircraft. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ Model Cockpit Systems Flight Dynamics  The Black Square King Air 350i steam gauge overhaul for MSFS is available on the JustFlight store for £27.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
