<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-02-21T18:46:37.702468+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phomun24</id>
    <title>PhotoRico Releases Muñoz Marín International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phomun24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698ad8a28f11f50024789c8a_marin1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PhotoRico has recently released their rendition of Muñoz Marín International Airport (TJSJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving San Juan, Puerto Rico, with an average of 13.4 million passengers per year. Planning for the airport’s construction began in 1945, when the government recognized they’d need a newer, larger airport to keep up with the air traffic demands of the following decades, since the region's main airport had a very short runway and could not be expanded further.  The project received approval in 1946; work began in 1947, and by 1949, they had completed the first phase, which involved cleaning, filling, leveling, and draining the soil. By the latter half of that year, they were already paving the runways and taxiways. The inauguration only took place in 1955, six years later, with a six-story passenger terminal, a control tower, a 2,400-meter-long runway, and basic aeroportuary infrastructure. ​ The 1960s brought further expansion, including lengthening the runway for jets and the addition of a second runway (which was only completed in the 1970s).  ​ In the late 1980s, a $137 million investment was announced to expand the passenger terminal and make multiple improvements to the airport, which were carried out between the 90s and early 2000s.  ​ It was followed by another terminal expansion in the early 2000s, making Terminal B slightly larger and remodeling the hotel, among other minor things. In the 2010s, despite the significant drawbacks of the 2008 crisis (leading, for example, to American Airlines greatly reducing its presence), the airport underwent further work, including a new passenger terminal, new pavement, new lighting systems, press conference rooms, and more. ​ It’s a hub for M&amp;N Aviation and Tradewind Aviation, and a focus city for JetBlue. Air Canada Rouge, Air Transat, American Airlines, Arajet, Avelo Airlines, Avianca, Cape Air, Contour Airlines, Copa Airlines, Delta Airlines, Frontier Airlines, Iberia, Southwest Airlines, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and WestJet also serve it. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully detailed terminals, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom taxi lights, performance-friendly optimization, and custom weathering. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect (2020/2024) for roughly $22.38, requiring at least 1.60 GB of free hard disk space to install.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbnordranch</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Nordheimer Creek Ranch for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbnordranch"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698da14a41739045d96b5fdb_nord1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Nordheimer Creek Ranch (CA107) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a tricky airstrip tucked into a steep, narrow mountain valley in California.  Located in the Six Rivers National Forest (Orleans, California), the Nordheimer Ranch Airfield is one of the most challenging airstrips in the United States, with a punishingly short runway and difficult terrain, with no margin for error. The area is known for its high-altitude lakes, dense forests, and diverse wildlife, attracting tourists from all over. Furthermore, its rich past continues to attract attention to this day, be it the remnants of old mining operations and the ancient fruit trees left by homesteaders centuries ago. It’s also famously known for world-class kayaking and rafting, with the nearby Nordheimer Campground being a very popular base for rafters. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airstrip, with high-fidelity visuals, PBR texturing, advanced collision modeling for out-of-cockpit exploration, and much more. ​It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $8.53, requiring at least 485.70 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rloghdlg</id>
    <title>realops Simulations Releases Ground Handling Plugin for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rloghdlg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698da48ac1caa516f03291cd_real1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. realops Simulations has recently released their newly announced ground handling plugin for X-Plane 12, bringing GSX-like features to Laminar Research’s newest simulator.  realops aims to simulate ground handling operations like never seen before in X-Plane 12, with realistic boarding, refueling, baggage handling, catering, and more. While optimized for Type C aircraft (B738, A320, etc.), it works with any airplane thanks to custom presets. The developers claim their next-level animations will greatly enhance the ground handling experience in X-Plane 12, alongside accurately modeled 3D objects, physical aircraft loading (Zibo and LevelUP), many liveries for common ground handling and catering companies, full SimBrief integration, and much more. It’s available on their website for roughly $34.11, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmg73624</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases 737-600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmg73624"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698ef2d536c0578d03ac314d_1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released their rendition of the Boeing 737-600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the third member of the 737 lineup to step into the “future” envisioned by Microsoft and Asobo. It’s their third product built natively for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 (the 777 was mostly just a compatibility patch), with a lidar-scanned flight deck, improved textures and lighting, new sounds, upgraded systems, and more. ​ As did the 738 and 739, it leverages the simulator’s capabilities to lay the groundwork for a truly native product line that will follow after all the 737 lineup members are out (only the -700 and -600 are pending now). The complete changelog follows below: ...and much much more!     Important Notes: It’s available on PMDG.com for $34.99, and owners of the MSFS 2020 version are entitled to a 60% discount ($14 total). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inl1du1</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares Lockheed L-1011 Tristar Development Update for MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2026-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inl1du1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698f7158ca0ad091233c1ffa_10.png.c798230029133be7ddac883114b410be.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In their most recent post on their forums, iniBuilds has shared their latest development update for their upcoming rendition of the Lockheed L-1011 Tristar for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This development update focuses on core systems and flight model, as well as exterior and interior visuals. The team reports that extensive work has been done on the flight model, with a strong focus on the three Rolls Royce RB211-524 engines powering the Tristar. Within their engine model, they have built in authentic EPR logic, tuned engine spool, and inertia characteristics in order to faithfully represent the engine’s performance across all power levels and phases of flight. A distinct feature of the L-1011 - Direct Lift Control (DLC) - is fully simulated, assisting pilots in vertical adjustments along the glidepath without major changes in pitch. Core systems and automation in the L-1011, such as the Automatic Flight Control System are simulated, giving full CAT IIIB autoland capability with accurate flare logic, de-rotation behaviour, and rollout control. This extends to the navigation systems, auto-throttle, and lateral and vertical modes, accurately modeling the automations making the L-1011 so advanced for its time. Detailed electrical, pneumatic, hydraulic, fuel, and environmental control systems will also be included. The iniBuilds team plan on making a fully interactive Flight Engineer station, but will also have an automatic operation option. When it comes to navigation systems, iniBuilds say that they wanted to provide flexibility to “support everyone: from casual flyers [...] to the most dedicated purists”. To achieve that goal, they are giving users the multiple options, from a simple RADNAV-based system all the way up to a modern GPS-based one. This will all be selectable through their new “Paper Flight Bag”, a vintage alternative to the electronic flight bags. iniBuilds will also support importing flight plans from SimBrief or the simulator EFB directly into the INS. On the visual side, iniBuild’s rendition of the Tristar will feature detailed cockpit textures, accurate interior lighting for each panel, and realistic wear and tear on the materials. Much focus has been put on the mechanical accuracy, with realistic spoiler lift and flap movement. On release, iniBuilds will include a variety of “3D Decal” liveries of operators of the L-1011-500, such as Delta, British Airways, LTU, Air Transat, Pan Am, and United. iniBuilds has not announced a release date yet, but they say that development is now “entering the final stages”, and they will be releasing another development update prior to release. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for the latest in flight simulation! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lsdher</id>
    <title>Lisium Design Announces Heraklion International for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lsdher"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69921e9a2d6b3650c7cab988_622256277_122250391994087512_7539844117049188758_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Lisium Design has officially unveiled its next project: Heraklion International Airport “Nikos Kazantzakis” (LGIR), for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Located just 5 km east of Heraklion’s city centre, on the island of Crete, Heraklion is Greece’s second-busiest airport after Athens. It serves as the primary gateway to the island’s world-famous summer destinations, including Malia, Hersonissos, Agios Nikolaos, Elounda, and beyond.  Lisium Design describes the project as a detailed recreation of the busy island airport, complete with fully modelled interiors, including detailed Duty Free areas. According to the developer, these interior spaces are being implemented without compromising performance. Screenshots shared so far are marked as work-in-progress, with more information on the release window and pricing expected soon. LGIR is currently scheduled as a Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 release. Lisium has indicated that a 2020 version may be considered after the initial launch, though no confirmation has been given at this stage. More details are expected soon. See the full post here. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbisa24</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Mount Isa Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbisa24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6992d389d56bba60ab079bc5_isa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Mount Isa Airport (YBMA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Mount Isa, Queensland, Australia, with an average of 217,526 passengers per year. It was built in the 1950s, replacing the former Mount Isa aerodrome, which was built in the 1920s to provide an air link from Mount Isa to the important hubs across the country. In 1969, a new passenger terminal was built to accommodate the ever-growing demand for air traffic in the region. Further expansion work was carried out in the 1980s to allow the airport to handle bigger jets. In the early 2000s, the terminal underwent major refurbishment to improve the overall experience.  It’s served by Alliance Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Rex Airlines, and Virgin Australia. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom aerial imagery, a detailed terminal and hangar, custom ground service equipment, an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, custom windsocks, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect (2020/2024) for roughly $18.42, requiring at least 1.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aaerostar105</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aaerostar105"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently issued a hotfix update to their Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing it in line with the MSFS 2024-native version of the Comanche 250. Update v1.05 reworks the magnetos, addresses a few SimConnect issues, and fixes a tablet issue.  The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkskeyw</id>
    <title>MK Studios Announces Key West International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkskeyw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6992dec90c02bcf4a924f3d7_keyw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently announced the development and imminent release of Key West International Airport (KEYW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Key West, Florida, with an average of 1.5 million passengers per year. The airport’s history goes back over a century, when Augustin Parla flew to Cuba in 1913. Fifteen years later, Pan American Airways began flying scheduled routes from Key West. It was briefly taken over by the US Army during World War 2 after the Pearl Harbor attack, as an alternative to the Trumbo Point seaplane base and the main Naval Air Station for fixed-wing aircraft. ​ It was returned to the city after the war, leading to its application for FAA grants in 1953 and its designation as Key West International Airport. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery will feature custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground service equipment, custom terminal interiors, custom jetways, and more. ​ There’s no information on the release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2alegacy</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Announces Accu-Sim Legacy RG550 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2alegacy"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69958e398d7d4faff01220a1_legacy1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently announced the development of their third airplane for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024: the Legacy RG550, a high-performance experimental kit-built aircraft! It’s the first time A2A Simulations has developed a kit-built airplane, which poses a significant challenge because no two kit-built aircraft are identical. But they claim it’s “perfect” for their Accu-Sim lineup because that individuality is the essence of their digital ownership philosophy. ​ The reference unit at hand is based on a real airplane owned and flown by Scott Gentile (A2A’s founder) for a number of years, allowing them to intricately replicate its flight dynamics, behavior, and quirks, just like the Comanche 250 and the Aerostar 600 (which they also happen to own, although the Aerostar 600 is no longer under their ownership).  ​ The add-on will feature fully custom flight physics, a custom sound design, persistent wear and tear, multiple avionics configurations (including a full custom Garmin G5 simulation that will be retrofitted into the Comanche and Aerostar), laser-scanned and photogrammetry assisted 3D modeling, in-depth electrical simulation, fully simulated systems, and a highly detailed engine simulation model, down to individual sparks during combustion. ​ It’s scheduled for release in Q2 2026, and pricing is yet to be announced (though it will likely fall in the usual $49.99 ballpark). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsla21n326</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo/neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsla21n326"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/699708512d498f4de580084d_1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently issued an update to their A321ceo and neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, focusing on performance, stability, and overall refinement.  Update v11.0.1.326 is the first to be released since the Pratt &amp; Whitney update rolled out a few weeks ago, addressing the high VRAM usage issues reported by many users through a multi-phase optimization process, which started with an option to entirely disable the cabin seats, and now features a multi-stage cabin and model optimization which substantially reduces the memory and load footprint, delivering memory reductions without any compromises to the overall visual quality. Furthermore, they also worked on handling, refining the braking behavior with updated pedal curves, with a more accurate and progressive deceleration feel. Plans are in place to address slow-speed stopping behavior in future updates. They also resolved SRS and LOC capture issues that were plaguing the neos.  There were multiple system-level improvements across engines, FADEC, EIU, DMC, and supporting systems, based on customer feedback and internal validation efforts. The FMGC stability has also been improved, alongside a more robust logging system to help detect and diagnose edge-case issues. ​ The FSLabs A321ceo and neo are available on their website for $69.95 + VAT each. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/se5318</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases El Chaltén Aeroclub for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/se5318"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6997631ce38b3004a5c58283_slide0001-scaled%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Simulación Extrema has recently released El Chaltén Aeroclub (LAD 5138) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing a small but vital Patagonian airfield to the sim. Set beneath the towering Andes and the iconic Mount Fitz Roy, the gravel-and-dirt strip serves as a key link for tourism, medical flights, training, and firefighting operations in Argentina’s trekking capital. The scenery features hand-crafted 3D models of the aeroclub facilities, custom runway and apron textures, a detailed Mount Fitz Roy model, and static local wildlife, such as guanacos and rheas.  Four parking positions are included, with one near runway 27 set up to simulate firefighting water-loading operations, reflecting the field’s real-world role during forest fire season. Read more here. El Chaltén is available now on the MSFS Marketplace for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gacqdl</id>
    <title>Guilb’Air Teases Cannes Quai du Large Helistation for XP12</title>
    <updated>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gacqdl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69976f17f62a0f51a91d1cdf_1000035390%20(1).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. A new X-Plane 12 scenery has been teased, with developer Guilb’Air revealing an upcoming rendition of Cannes Quai du Large Helistation (FR-0200). Located along the waterfront in Cannes, in the Alpes-Maritimes region of southern France, Quai du Large is a compact but demanding heliport, positioned right beside the marina, and just minutes from the city centre.  You can watch a preview stream here. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/1240fr</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.4.0 </title>
    <updated>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/1240fr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/694b2a1a5c5001242ad2008a_CCheck_Update_Title_1-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has officially pushed X-Plane 12.4.0 out of beta, with the update now available to both LR Direct and Steam users. Following a lengthy public testing phase, 12.4.0 arrives as a substantial platform update, focusing on performance refinements, aircraft system improvements, and expanded hardware support.  One of the headline additions is the introduction of multi-threading for scenery loading. X-Plane can now distribute scenery preparation tasks across multiple CPU cores, reducing bottlenecks when operating in dense or complex environments. For those flying into detailed airports, large cities, or custom scenery-heavy regions, this change should help improve overall smoothness, particularly during approach, taxi, and initial loading phases. Modern multi-core systems, of course, stand to benefit the most from this update. The default Airbus A330-300 has received a significant round of updates. Electrical systems have been refined, avionics logic improved, and cockpit display behaviour adjusted for greater accuracy. ACARS functionality is now also accessible via the third MCDU. The Cirrus SR22, among others, sees avionics tweaks, improved autopilot logic, and clearer navigation display behaviour.  X-Plane 12.4.0 also introduces native Windows support for the Tobii Eye Tracker 5.  You can review the complete 12.4.0 release notes here. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmpbirel</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Palm Beach International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024 </title>
    <updated>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmpbirel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6997e68e4e998441e1359b76_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Palm Beach International Airport (KPBI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Miami and Port St. Lucie metropolitan areas, with an average of 6.6 million passengers per year.  It was opened in 1936 as Morrison Field, eventually becoming an important training airfield during World War 2 and operating as a staging base for the Allied invasion of France in 1944, with aircraft departing Palm Beach towards England in preparation for D-Day.  ‍After a brief return to civilian use, the airport was once again used for military purposes in the early 1950s as Palm Beach Air Force Base, training nearly 23,000 airmen during the Korean War. The Air Force Base was closed in 1962, and Palm Beach was back to being just a civilian airport.  Currently, the airport has 32 gates and three concourses. Concourse A houses Bahamasair and Silver Airways; B houses Air Canada, American Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines; C, on the other hand, holds Delta, Frontier, JetBlue, and Spirit. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, a highly detailed terminal with a fully modeled interior, performance-friendly optimization, custom taxiway signage, true-to-life landside, and much more. It’s available on their website for roughly $21.99, requiring at least 3.67 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inihkg24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Hong Kong International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inihkg24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69985d0687060ea4ff1f62c4_hong1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently announced the development of Hong Kong International Airport (VHHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the 8th busiest airport in the World, with an average of 71 million passengers per year. Hong Kong International was built to replace the old Kai Tak Airport, deemed too small to handle the traffic it was handling, and to address the insane number of complaints from airlines due to the delays, a direct consequence of the fact that it could not scale up to the demand. Planning studies started in 1974, with construction work only kicking in almost 20 years later, in 1991. Completion was achieved in early 1998. Built on a large artificial island, the total area of the airport (12.48 square kilometers) corresponds to nearly 1% of Hong Kong’s total area.  The airport is a hub for Cathay Pacific, Greater Bay Express, HK Express, and Hong Kong Airlines, and is visited by over 100 other airlines with more than 180 destinations. It’s also the World’s busiest cargo airport, hosting Air Hong Kong, Cathay Cargo, DHL Aviation, Hong Kong Airlines Cargo, Kalitta Air, Polar Air Cargo, and UPS Airlines.  The scenery will feature an up-to-date ground layout, true-to-life landside, handcrafted ground textures, custom jetways, highly detailed terminals, performance-optimized performance, custom night lighting, and a Point of Interest pack for Hong Kong landmarks. There’s no pricing or release date information just yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
