<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-12-06T18:25:12.916952+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oamvou</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Major Volanta Update</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oamvou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6388b90d207f340d2482fed9_vo2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="958100"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently made a forum post teasing some of the features of the upcoming Volanta 1.4 update, which includes a mobile app, a new - and updated - flight schedule source, and a stream overlay. There is no information regarding a release date yet, but it is said to be coming soon. The mobile app will allow premium users to track their flights remotely with statistics, route map, and the possibility to remotely pause the flight (P3D, X-Plane and FSX only). It acts as an extension of the Desktop application, and easening tasks such as taxiing, thanks to taxiway labels and gate information, specially for users with just one monitor.  It’s going to be available on the App Store and Google Play once 1.4 is out.   The new flight schedule source is FlightAware, increasing the quality and quantity of the data available, with reliability on the flight number, aircraft type, etc.  The stream overlay will provide a dynamically updated and customizable overlay for streamers, with information such as callsign, departure, arrival, ETA, ground speed and vertical speed.   The Discord Rich Presence is also getting a revamp, with more information shown, such as simulator in use, aircraft type, and a button that takes you straight to the flight on Volanta’s website. ‍  The built-in roster system, introduced on Volanta 1.2, has been improved, allowing users to schedule flights outside the real-world scheduling system, making it possible to plan out your entire daily schedule or maybe that long sought after world tour. They conclude the announcement with the information that there is more to come, currently being worked on.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssrji</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Juneau International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssrji" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6388ea7ba249e65c71d473c8_pajn1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1159915"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Northern Sky Studio has recently released their rendition of Juneau International Airport (PAJN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving a city with no direct road access to the outside world, making it extremely important for the townsfolk to get around. It’s a regional hub for all air travel, ranging from tiny carriers to big players such as Alaska Airlines. According to 2020 statistics, the yearly average is around 300,000 passengers. Alaska Airlines comprehends 87% of the yearly traffic figures, transporting people to six destinations (Anchorage, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Seattle-Tacoma, Sitka, and Yakutat). The other 13% are shared between minor regional airlines such as Alaska Seaplanes and Harris Air. The scenery features a detailed replica of the airport, with custom surroundings, PBR materials, shading and occlusion on all buildings, high-resolution textures, native gITF models, and custom ortophoto for the airport and surrounding areas. It’s available on SimMarket and OrbxDirect for roughly $17.95 and $18.11, respectively. At least 5.47 GB of free disk space is required to install the product.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdlmps</id>
    <title>TFDi Design Launches MD-11 Pre-Sale</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdlmps" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6388eef3cb3c453cdfc5029b_tfdi3.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="984334"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TFDi Design has recently announced the launch of a Collector’s Edition of their MD-11, with a limited run of 1000 copies priced at $80 each, granting early access to the aircraft once the beta is out, an extended range variant, and a special certificate for all the early customers. The complete feature list of the limited edition follows down below:  The developers plan to release the aircraft to the public in September 2023, with early supporters able to fly it earlier and provide direct feedback to the developers. They have also made a statement on the pricing plan for the product, with the base edition coming at $70 (passenger or freighter), $10 extra to have both variants, and $5 for the extended simulation package. The Collector’s Edition includes everything for $5 less.  The pre-order is available on their website for $80. There’s no information on system requirements as of now. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrcivf</id>
    <title>LuchoDev Releases Chacalluta International V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrcivf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6389011d96601a72c16e2352_arica1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="716909"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LuchoDev has just released the second version of their Chacalluta International Airport (SCAR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Arica in Chile. It’s visited by over 200,000 passengers yearly (according to Cointer), served by JetSmart, LATAM Chile, and Sky Airline, all domestically.  The scenery aims to represent the airport as it’s going to look after the current remodeling finishes, featuring an accurate representation of the upcoming terminal, a fire station, the control tower, and the DGAC sector buildings. Version 2 improves the terminal redesign while adding new areas, building upgrades on the DGAC sector, custom jetways, improved runway lights, PBR textures, more buildings, and several bug fixes.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.53, requiring at least 323 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gsrvim</id>
    <title>Gaya Simulations Releases Vienna International v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gsrvim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a286685446b76caa9111e_vie1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2043471"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Gaya Simulations has recently released the second version of their Vienna International Airport (LOWW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, overhauling the airport based on customer feedback, and adding custom ground service equipment.   VIE is the largest and busiest Austrian airport, with over 30 million passengers in 2019. It’s home to Austrian Airlines, with 48% of the annual figures (as of 2021), with many intra-european and intercontinental routes. Ryanair and WizzAir take another significant chunk, with 18% and 8%, respectively, and a wide network of intra-european routes to minor and major airports.   The updated scenery features the aforementioned overhaul, custom GSE, new true-to-life jetways, improved object placement across the airport, fixed AFCAD for AI traffic, fixed taxiway lights, static AI removal, better optimization, and more. The complete changelog/feature list follows down below:  • New true-to-life jetways models for all terminals with all new billboards and advertising. • New Gaya GSE: beautiful and fully custom Vienna-specific ground service equipment. • Overhauled object placement throughout the airport, improving visuals and accuracy. • Fixed AI traffic (FSLTL). • Fixed AFCAD for AI traffic. • Fixed taxiway lights, including the addition of orange and blue lights in the W area. • Static AI removed. • Fixed TIN/Imagery bug from World Update 6. • Added Solar Farm south of RWY11/29 • Added LODs to all objects. • Optimized normal map sizes for Xbox compatibility. • Fixed missing parking positions and improved spawn positions. • Fixed vegetation to fit new satellite imagery. • Fixed some terraforming issues. • Many quality of life fixes, such as fence placement, jetblast fences, taxi signs, etc. • Supporting an on release community-made GSX profile  The V2 upgrade is a free update to previous owners on Orbx Direct, with the Marketplace and Xbox version to release soon. It’s available on Orbx for $15.14 (48 hour v2 sale. Original price is roughly $21.65). At least 4.82 GB of free disk space is required to install the product. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fstefm</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Teases Embraer 175 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fstefm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a30c5c78b99b09e1b8d42_aviationlads01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1117508"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG has just released a teaser video in partnership with AviationLads teasing their upcoming Embraer 175 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a regional jet used by many airlines around the globe. There is no information other than external shots showcasing different liveries, model details, and sounds.   The video producer, AviationLads, made a post on Facebook indicating more content down the line (further showcasing the product), which is still in development.   The Embraer 175 is one of the four variants of the Embraer E-Jets, seating from 78 to 88 passengers in different class configurations, and with a range of 3334 kilometers on the standard variant (1800 nautical miles). It’s operated by 12 airlines around the World, with SkyWest being the largest operator (193 aircraft). Republic Airways is the second with 163, and Envoy Air takes the third place with 98.   There’s no information regarding pricing, release date, or system depth yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for further updates on the E175 and more! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drabim</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Austin-Bergstrom International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drabim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a3703e1c2984fff723fe0_kaus1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1582742"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam has just released their rendition of Austin-Bergstrom International (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Greater Austin metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16 million passengers. Built on what remained of what once used to be the Bergstrom Air Force Base, it is now the third busiest airport in Texas, with over 76 destinations (domestic and international) and approximately 510 arrivals and departures on a typical weekday as of 2018.  It is an important airport for Southwest Airlines, which takes 34% of the market share as of 2021, followed by American Airlines and Delta, with 22% and 13%, respectively. Destination-wise, Los Angeles is the most popular, with 543000 passengers. Dallas and Atlanta are second and third, with 530000 and 513000, respectively.   The scenery features PBR textures, dynamic lighting, true-to-life ground markings, custom hand-crafted pavement with imperfections and dirt, custom jetways, custom animated objects, passengers, and airport buses.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.85, requiring at least 870 MB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidtw</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Detroit Metropolitan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidtw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638a5e961f68a81acfcfe77a_detroit1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2062251"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has just released their rendition of Detroit Metropolitan Wayne County Airport (KDTW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Michigan’s busiest airport with a yearly average of 36 million passengers. It’s a Major hub for Delta Airlines, with a 39 state domestic route network and serving as their gateway to Asia from the East Coast.  DTW is categorized by the FAA’s National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems as a large hub primary commercial service facility, with six runways, two terminals, and one hundred twenty nine gates, and a maintenance structure large enough to service a 747-400.   Along with Delta (50%), Endeavor Air (12.95%) and Spirit Airlines (11.69%) take a significant chunk of the yearly passenger figure. Atlanta (696,000), Orlando (619,000), and Las Vegas (531,000) are the most popular destinations, operated by DAL, NKS and FFT.   The scenery features hand-made ground textures, true-to-life airport landside recreation, animated train in the McNamara terminal, hand-placed ground service equipment, static de-icing vehicles, LOD (Level of Detail) Optimization, and more. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $22.05, requiring at least 4.72 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msrafx</id>
    <title>Mountain Scenery Releases ALPS for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msrafx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638b741fd5db463992fb990b_alps1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="332734"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Frank Dainese and Fabio Bellini have recently released the ALPS UHD package for X-Plane 12, covering 8000 square kilometers of alpine area between Italy, France, and Switzerland. It includes four main packages: Eiger Park, Matterhorn Park, Aosta, and Mont Blanc, along with the main peaks of the Alps.  The aforementioned packages feature an accurate reconstruction with 3D models and photographic textures, with all the major cities and towns with their respective custom building placement (churches, stations, monuments, public buildings, etc.) and houses that match the local architecture. All major airports and airfields are included (5 main airports, 15 airfields, and 46 heliports), with their respective characteristics. The complete feature list follows down below: It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $49.95 with a 17% discount (default price is $59.95), requiring at least 3.3 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssdtbl</id>
    <title>SLH Sim Designs Releases Terrance B. Lettsome International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssdtbl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638cb795ece8b2670552ddc8_tupj1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="280212"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SLH Sim Designs has just released their rendition of Terrance B. Lettsome International Airport (TUPJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main airport serving the British Virgin Islands, and previously known as Beef Island Airport. It’s a gateway to other smaller islands in the archipelago and a bridge away from the main island (Tortola).   It underwent a Major renovation in 2004, which included a runway expansion to allow operation of larger airplanes. It also added a new 4300 square meter terminal building, an enlarged flight apron, a new control tower, and 150 extra parking stalls.   It’s served by many regional airlines such as Air Sunshine, Cape Air, LIAT, Silver Airways, VI Airlink, and Winair. American Eagle set to begin flying to Terrance B. Lettsome in June 2023 from Miami. Curiously, there is a $20 departure tax for anyone above the age of 5.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with modeled interiors for the terminal and tower, accurate terraforming and runway slope, dynamic night lighting, animated road traffic with functional toll gates, true-to-life airport landside recreation, custom taxiway and signage lighting, and 4K PBR textures.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.81, requiring at least 272 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxioth</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Doha Hamad International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxioth" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638df236bd27f82c6148bd15_doha5.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="371489"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has just released their rendition of Doha Hamad International Airport (OTHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Qatar with a yearly average of 36 million passengers. Opened in 2014, it replaces Doha International Airport as Qatar’s main airport, built on 22 square kilometers of land and able to handle 320,000 aircraft movements and 2 million tonnes of cargo per year. DOH is the first Middle Eastern airport to get the Skytrax's World Best Airport award (2021 and 2022), ending a nearly decade-long streak of Singapore’s Changi. ‍ It’s the hub for Qatar Airways, with a route network that covers most of the globe, from their next-door neighbors of Abu Dhabi to San Francisco. Such high coverage makes it so other carriers don’t have much of a financially logical reason to fly to Doha, but there are still a couple of them such as Air Canada, Air India, British Airways, Conviasa, Finnair, and Malaysia Airlines. The scenery features a high-detail recreation of the airport, with an updated ground layout, high-quality ground markings and buildings, PBR textures, custom clutter objects, a basic terminal interior with the World Cup theming, 3D passengers, animated passenger train inside the terminal building, custom jetways, Qatar Airways hangar with an animated door, animated RGB road masts and flags, and support for the Aerosoft VDGS system. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.07, requiring at least 1.4 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tadprg</id>
    <title>Tailstrike Designs Releases Prague Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tadprg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638dffdb883d9bfb0edf0be1_vaclav1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="196617"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Tailstrike Designs has just released their rendition of Václav Havel Airport Prague (LKPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the main gateway to Czechia with 85 years of history and over 15 million passengers yearly, home to Czech Airlines and Smartwings. Formerly Prague Ruzyně International Airport, it was renamed after the last president of Czechoslovakia and the first president of the Czech Republic (Václav Havel) in 2012.   With an intricate intra-European and international route network, PRG is regularly visited by Aer Lingus, Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Emirates, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and many other. Eurowings Europe and Ryanair have a base in Prague, with significant summer and winter networks.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models of the terminal, hangars, and buildings, along with true-to-life taxiways (as of 2022), tower and terminal interior, photorealistic PBR textures, custom animated jetways, realistic night dynamic lighting, and support for the Aerosoft VDGS module.  It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for $24.99, requiring at least 5 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflrfp</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Fokker F28 Video Preview </title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflrfp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638e0d5e3f4e8506d7265317_fokker1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="872414"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published another development update on their Fokker F28 Fellowship for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing the lighting (internally and externally) in a 3 minute long video around an Air Anglia F28-4000. According to the developers, there are 50 dynamic lights covering the exterior, cabin, and cockpit.   The Fokker F28 Fellowship is a twin-engined regional jet developed in the late 60s, with its first flight in 1967 and introduced in 1969, with 241 units built after a 20 year run (production ended in 1987). Multiple variants were developed, with the F28-1000 seating up to 70 passengers, the F28-2000 housing 79 people, and the later revision, the F28-4000, featuring quieter engines (Rolls-Royce Spey 555-15H), a redesigned cockpit and modified wings, and increased seating (up to 85 passengers). It was then superseded by the Fokker 70 and 100.   As of 2019, there are no current operators of the F28 around, with Fly-SAX being the last to operate it commercially. Garuda Indonesia was the largest former operator, with 62 of them. Other Major operators include the Ansett Group (13), AirQuarius Aviation (4), and Biman Bangladesh Airlines (4). The Ansett Group was also responsible for the longest nonstop F28 route in the world, between Perth and Kununurra, roughly 2300 km apart.   There’s no information on release date or pricing yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inip40</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases P-40F Warhawk for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inip40" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638e2c2e145661f624e2e103_p401.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1298377"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has just released their rendition of the Curtiss P-40F Warhawk for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engined classic fighter first flown in 1938. It was the third most produced American fighter in WW2, with 13,738 units by the end of the production cycle in late 1944, playing an important role during the war, used by most allied powers.   From the hot and dry Deserts of the Middle East to the dampness of Europe, the Warhawk has been everywhere in WW2, with over 200 allied fighter pilots becoming aces flying the P-40. It remained in active use well after the War, by Brazil, Egypt, Finland, and Turkey. The Brazilian Air Force was the last to retire their fleet, in 1954. The iniBuilds P-40F features the latest in CFD (Computational Fluid Dynamics) implementation from Microsoft, including the primary flight surfaces, control surfaces, and the propeller, with an authentically modeled Merlin engine which performs close to real-life figures (with feedback from type-rated pilots), a fully modeled fuel system, an electronic flight bag with maintenance page, moving map, radios, and weather information. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ The airplane is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.43, requiring at least 2.99 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kausmfs</id>
    <title>Dominic DesignTeam Releases Austin–Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kausmfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638ef23655f464fbf8202b53_Screenshot%202022-12-06%20at%201.41.38%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="4150568"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Dominic DesignTeam released their rendition of Austin–Bergstrom International Airport (KAUS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The product will bring the Texas airport to life with high quality models, customized objects such as signs and passengers, and detailed textures. 	According to the developers, the scenery will feature PBR textures, dynamic lighting, and custom jetways. Additionally, for added realism, all pavements have been “painstakingly hand-crafted” and ground markings have been modeled based on the real life airport. 	Austin–Bergstrom International Airport, located 5 miles from Austin downtown, is one of the main international airports serving the city. It provides flights to some 75 destinations around the world. Top operators at the airport include Southwest, Delta, and American Airlines. Currently, Dominic DesignTeam’s Austin Airport can be purchased on simMarket for $18.99 USD or EUR 20.10, excluding any sales taxes that may incur. The developers recommend at least 870M of free space in order to successfully install the product.</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksrvn</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Rovaniemi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksrvn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/638f7b34fdc31d1a20d021ba_efro1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1117127"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released an update to their rendition of Rovaniemi Airport (EFRO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Finland with 500,000 passengers per year. It’s visited by many airlines during the winter season, which includes Aer Lingus, Air France, easyJet, Eurowings, Ryanair, Transavia, and Turkish Airlines.   Built in 1940, featuring two grass runways, and used as a Luftwaffe air base and supply center during the Second Soviet-Finnish War between 1941 and 1944. Rebuilding work started in 1948, with regular traffic returning in the beginning of the second half of that year.   The current terminal building finished in 1992, with its first expansion happening in 2000 (and the inclusion of jetways). The runway underwent renovation work in 2016, with new pavement and LED lights, and 2019 marked the completion of the terminal’s third enlargement.  The scenery update added conditional visibility to the winter objects, smoke effects for cold weather, glass improvements, and general fixes. The complete feature list for the scenery follows down below: It’s available on Orbx Direct for $6.69 (on sale, 50% off), requiring at least 1.23 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
