<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-06-08T18:27:36.150169+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hjet31</id>
    <title>HJet for Microsoft Flight Simulator by Marwan Gharib Releasing May 31st </title>
    <updated>2022-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hjet31" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/628f062f99e95b60925375a2_62757e1417be36da0161cadd_11.1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2835360"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, FlightFX revealed that the HJet, developed by Marwan Gharib, will be released next Tuesday, May 31st. The jet, featuring custom coded systems, high quality textures, and detailed exterior models, will be a unique addition to the business jet lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator on both PC and XBOX. The HJet, developed entirely by Marwan over the past three years, will carry "an array of features, improvements, and personal touches that will make this aircraft impossible to step away from". The jet has been furnished with PBR textures, custom GPU, animated cabin/cargo doors, and hundreds of animated surfaces in both the cockpit and the cabin. Apart from the detailed modeling, the aircraft will also be equipped with a custom G3000 suite that includes the Touch Screen Controller, built- in checklists, and a custom PFD Crew Alert System. In addition, the HJet will come with custom fuel, electrical, and HVAC systems that mirror the handling and performance characteristics of the plane's real life counterpart. For a complete list of features for the HJet, visit FlightFX  The aircraft, according to the developer, will be priced at $24.99 USD and available for purchase on the Marketplace. For additional information on the HJet, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/es5232</id>
    <title>Biological Nanobot Updates Enhanced Skyscapes</title>
    <updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/es5232" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62905904db959da46a7d5d5b_ezgif-4-9ff0f646e8.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="66978"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Enhanced Skyscapes developer Biological Nanobot has published an update for the X-Plane 11 program. The "visual solution for X-Plane 11" replaces the default sky and clouds with realistic shader-based sky and fully volumetric clouds. It's fully compatible with weather injection add-ons, including but not limited to Active Sky XP and FS Global Real Weather. The update brings some hefty changes to the program, detailed below: Aspiring users of Enhanced Skyscapes can obtain the program on the Threshold store for 15.00USD. BioNanobot has provided prospective buyers a 20-minute demo to test the product before making their final purchase decision.</summary>
    <published>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf146u</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases v0.1.3 for 146 Professional</title>
    <updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf146u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62905c277a3259af7813237a_146-professional-microsoft-flight-simulator_14_ss_l_220429142651.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="566302"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer Just Flight released an extensive update for its popular 146 Professional. The new update, pushed to the community as version 0.1.3, brings a wide array of bug fixes and quality of life improvements that promises to enhance the user experience of the aircraft. According to the developer, the update fixed bugs in the plane’s autopilot, including VOR, DME, and LNAV/FMS tracking. Cockpit modeling and animations such as the cabin window rain effect are also added or revised. Furthermore, tutorial flight files have been added and tweaks to the VR experience have been implemented. These improvements are only a fraction of the ones Just Flight are bringing to the 146. For the complete list of changes, visit the developer’s website. Just Flight’s 146 Professional, released earlier this month, is a study-level recreation of the iconic BAE 146 regional jet, including realistic performance, a custom EFB, and all eight variants of the aircraft. For more information on the 146, checkout a previous Threshold article. Currently, the 146 Professional can be purchased on Just Flight’s webstore for $64.99 USD. Owners of the aircraft will be receiving the newest update for free.</summary>
    <published>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/storms</id>
    <title>SoFly Previews STORMS for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/storms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6295925b21533896c8e83519_STORM-by-SoFly-21.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="342369"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, add-on developer SoFly released a trailer for its upcoming STORMS for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The add-on, available for purchase starting May 31st, will bring an array of extreme weather presets to the MSFS, including accurately constructed hurricanes and terrifying super storms that will pose refreshing challenges for every pilot. According to the developers, the add-on will introduce to the simulator a wide range of weather presets. Users can choose from a wide selection of hurricanes (both historical and fictional), super storms, and global presets. Each of the presets will recreate the corresponding extreme weather in every detail from wind conditions to location. In addition to the weather presets, STORM will also bring a series of missions such as discovery flights that will enable users to admire the spectacle of extreme weather, educational flights that will provide the community with a brief historical background for each hurricane, and landing challenges that are designed to test even the most seasoned pilots. For a complete list of missions and presets, check out the product’s manual. Currently, the add-on is scheduled to be released on Tuesday, May 31st, though the pricing is yet to be revealed. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atr053</id>
    <title>MSFS2020 Upcoming ATR 42/72 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atr053" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6295ae94529bd97db2053d6d_atrasobo1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="311422"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSFS developers, Asobo Studios, have revealed more information about their upcoming ATR 42/72 for MSFS2020. The team hosted a Q&amp;A on their Twitch channel, which was later posted on YouTube for the community to recap. Asobo claims that they plan on the aircraft being available for both the PC and Xbox platforms.  The ATR 72 is a twin-engine turboprop airline produced by the French and Italian aircraft manufacturer ATR. "72" denotes that the aircraft presents a capacity of 72-78 passengers in a single class arrangement. The "72" is the larger variant of the ATR series, developed from the ATR 42. Currently, approximately 1,000 ATRs fly worldwide, primarily with IndiGo, Air New Zealand, Wings Air, and Azul Linhas Aereas.  Asobo has outlined the following details about the upcoming release: Hans believes it's still too early to comment on the aircraft's release date, but keep on the lookout for more news regarding the upcoming ATR series for MSFS2020!</summary>
    <published>2022-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fse223</id>
    <title>FSA Announces FlightSimExpo 2023 Dates and Location</title>
    <updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fse223" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/5b50f45f22ba1b84d4a3c4ad_Screen%20Shot%202018-07-19%20at%203.27.42%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="46563"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Sim Association has announced the dates and location of FlightSimExpo 2023! The event is one of the world's largest dedicated flight simulation conferences. Since 2018, over 3,500 attendees have attended Las Vegas, Orlando, and San Diego events. Similar to 2021, the event will be held in a hybrid online and in-person setting.  We are happy to announce that the venue and location for FSExpo 2023 is the Lone Star Flight Museum at Ellington Airport (EFD) in Houston, Texas! According to FSA, "the 130,000 square foot museum and learning center has ample space for more than 2,000 attendees across two air-conditioned hangars." Other facilities surrounding the area are the Texas Aviation Hall of Fame and learning exhibits that include Redbird flight training devices. FSExpo 2023 will be held from June 23rd to June 25th, with the 23rd being an "add-on series of group discussions" before the in-person conference on June 24th and 25th.  Ellington Airport is approximately 15 minutes drive away from Hobby Airport (HOU) and 35 minutes from Intercontinental (IAH). FSA's Evan Reiter writes that the venue is working with hotels, airlines, and rental car companies to secure discounted rates for attendees. They're also anticipating that attendees will be able to "add-on" experiences at NASA, ATC facilities, and more.  Registration for the event will begin in December. More information regarding hotels, attractions, and travel will be available later this year. Hopeful attendees of FSExpo can monitor their website to keep up to date with all new information regarding the upcoming event!</summary>
    <published>2022-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737uap</id>
    <title>PMDG 737-700 for MSFS Updated, -600 Previewed</title>
    <updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737uap" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629bdc88175235796b98e634_PMDG_600_screenshots4.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1454491"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The youngest siblings of the 737 family have seen some limelight on the PMDG Forum today with group chief executive Robert Randazzo announcing the release of the product’s first update post-launch. A subsequent post published shortly after gives further insight into the next entry in the series, the 737-600. Firstly though, the changes list for the -700. Randazzo describes the foremost changes: “[The update] comes with a number of changes and improvements, including updated models and associated textures, a significant update to the sound engine and dozens upon dozens of small tweaks, adjustments and improvements.” Version 3.00.0020 of the PMDG 737-700 brings the following 69 changes: Updating the product can be done via the PMDG Operations Center. Randazzo notes that some may experience some sound issues on the first post-update run of the 737. “We have traced this to the manner in which the sim caches sounds, and it can be easily corrected by simply running the airplane, then exiting back to the world menu and launching the aircraft a second time. For reasons we don't yet understand, the sim does not update the cache on the first run, but it does on the second launch and from then on you will be fine without further need to tinker.”  Turning to the -600 variant of the 737, the ‘thoroughbred’ Baby Boeing is running approximately seven to nine days behind the schedule dictated by PMDG in the lead up to the first variant’s release.  Robert Randazzo maintains that due to some ‘slop’ accounted for in the release schedule, the -600 ‘may still roll out on time’ later this month, and that any delay on the little brother will not have any effect on the 737-800, slated for early August. The post then launches into detailing a number of new advancements coming both for the -600 and 737 series as a whole. “For a few years now, we have been at work conducting a full rebuild on the lateral and vertical path modeling capability for the PMDG FMS used by all of our Boeing airliners.” “The good news is that we are preparing to insert it into testing within the PMDG 737 for MSFS, and it will then roll out to you in the forum of a free update. This modern path modeling has been something we have been building toward for some time and it will dramatically improve the accuracy of how PMDG airliners move through the sky in a 3D pathway “Concurrent with the Lateral/Vertical Path Module we have been working to build out a proper flight director roll and pitch module based upon input from some of the industry’s leading flight control logic engineers and our in house mathematical wizard. “This has been under initial iteration testing and will also roll out as a free update shortly.” On the topic of the Universal Flight Tablet, the team remains relatively tight-lipped on progress, with Randazzo suspecting that he may have given away too much information in last week’s update. Today, he offers a few words to the effect of “soon”. Other miscellaneous topics covered include another reminder to customers of the 737 NGXu who purchased in November and December 2019 that a $99.99 credit remains available for their use on the PMDG webstore and that another update for the 737 will be due ‘next week’. See the source posts for this article on the PMDG Forum.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oblmme</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Landmarks Melbourne for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oblmme" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629c27e343478aa71debd393_2-99a69df0352e53b3fa7c31060b20f1e6.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="776134"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Australian scenery-maker Orbx has today announced the forthcoming release of a landmarks pack based in their home city, Melbourne. The company’s head office is located at Essendon Fields Airport, which they have also recreated in-sim. “Welcome to the cultural and sports capital of Australia and the hometown of Orbx! With about a third of its current five million residents born outside of Australia, Melbourne’s skyline mirrors its inhabitants’ diversity, from Gold Rush and Victorian architecture to ultra-modern skyscrapers. Moreover, the city is home to Australia’s second busiest airport, Tullamarine (YMML) and its busiest seaport.” “While World Update 7 Australia added photogrammetry to Melbourne and about a dozen Orbx-made POIs, this new  Melbourne pack has another 200 custom-made buildings and structures, along with the many other enhancements and features our Landmarks series is known for.” The group have also added a number of animated features to the bustling city, including metro trains, hot air balloons and horses at two of Melbourne’s racecourses. The following feature list was provided: Check out World Update VII, which Orbx played a hand in creating, here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obkboi</id>
    <title>Orbx Boise for Microsoft Flight Simulator Available Now</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obkboi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629c90ec70a3b2347002e50c_2-209d23f7bf69ae55bfa70ea80a5c2f77.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="748742"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Idaho’s Boise Air Terminal has now seen an entry in Microsoft Flight Simulator courtesy of Orbx, who’ve made the city's Gowen Field their latest release for the platform.  The airport serves a dual civilian/military purpose and is also home to the state’s largest building — the control tower, which stands at a not-so-impressive 295ft or approximately 90 metres. Orbx’s rendition for the sim includes the following features: Boise is served by eight airlines in the current day, with a route network of 26 destinations. This is in stark contrast to its previous passenger-serving efforts, in which customers previously awaited their aircraft in what the developer describes as an ‘ageing Varney Airlines (now United) hangar’. The rather more modern, current terminal was opened in 2003. You can purchase Orbx Boise for $16.70 AUD (approx. US$12.04 | €11,23 | £9.64) from OrbxDirect.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inissa</id>
    <title>iniScene Development Update: KSAT Previewed, KBUF Coming to X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inissa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629d19e18cf55655316b0708_image.thumb.png.7e7cc59bccface0bcae0f3a1b0c22659.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="706950"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery-making subsidiary of development house iniBuilds, iniScene, has seen a busy last couple of months -- firstly with the release of Buffalo-Niagara (KBUF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator as well as the forthcoming release of San Antonio (KSAT) for the same platform. In a development update published today, the team have given some insight into the next steps moving forwards from three of their current projects. Ubaid Mussa, iniBuilds chief executive, addressed the group’s London Heathrow rendition first. “To start the year, in January we released our first mega-airport iniScene London Heathrow EGLL for Microsoft Flight Simulator.” “This was a fantastic project and we worked with some great people who engage with the airport daily to create a faithful rendition. Being our first mega-airport we learnt a lot, and as you can always expect from us, have reflected and are working on an update covering performance, night lighting and greater detail on road markings.” iniScene have opened a forum thread for users to share their wish-list for a free update to the product, which you can find here. Mussa confirms that iniScene London Heathrow will not be making its way to Prepar3D or X-Plane at this time. Turning their most recent release, Buffalo, the team express their thanks for great community reception to the product -- it is also now confirmed that work has started on the X-Plane 11 rendition of KBUF, which will see the light of day in further development updates. San Antonio is the final topic brought up in today's development update. Mussa acclaims iniScene's work as 'some of our best', and that KSAT will bring details 'not seen before in some of our other products'. "We plan to start release preparations for this airport very soon, and are working on the final details!" In addition to KSAT we are currently working on a few other projects which we will share more information on in the next couple of months along with a brand new product offering for you heli pilots. The CEO says a development update regarding iniBuilds' aircraft project will come in due course.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asa330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Showcases A330 Progress for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asa330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629d3bfab6eba1b253885528_A330_VC_001.jpg.7c42a2b930c392aedf55d403fdf5ca75.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="232195"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Airbus A330 will mark the third Microsoft Flight Simulator aircraft release for German developer Aerosoft, creators of one of the platforms' first complex products in the form of the CRJ series. Earlier this week, the development house provided new previews inside and out of Airbus' smallest widebody as well as some additional insight into various features. Aerosoft founder and spokesperson Mathijs Kok once again did the honours. He was careful to note that despite virtual cockpit 3D work being complete, the team is yet to add in decals and weathering -- essentially, these previews are not entirely representative of the final product. In a subsequent post on the same forum thread, Kok shares some new exterior previews too. When questioned by one community member about the apparent 'dumbing down' of Aerosoft's Twin Otter for the Xbox platform and whether this would be mirrored in the A330, Kok had this to say. "I do not know why you think that, the modelling and texturing were absolutely not dumbed down, was simple not needed. Nor will the A330 be. Both are optimized for Xbox use though, meaning they are fully done with MSFS technology. So not 8K textures but 2K with decals ending up with detail." A price has not been decided for Aerosoft's A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, nor a release date as yet.  You can find the original previews on the forum thread for the aircraft here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mynnfs</id>
    <title>Sierrasim Announces Nassau-Lynden Pindling for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mynnfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629d53fcacf98ec96a558cad_285190442_3484183708475644_8869966591637855385_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="181174"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Sierrasim Simulation has announced their latest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator: Nassau’s Lynden Pindling Airport (MYNN) in the Bahamas. The airport will be native to the platform, as the development group has not previously tackled Nassau for other simulators. The news was publicised via Facebook, in which is short post was shared. “Coming Soon - MYNN- Lynden Pindling International Airport MSFS PC/Xbox" Watch this space for further news. Check out the group's previous release, Olaya Herrera Airport (SKMD), in another article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdnapl</id>
    <title>RDPresets Debut Naples Airport in Latest Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdnapl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629db7d8db3dbefc6a0d23c8_wing-tra-737_orig.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1701430"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Creators of Rotterdam-The Hague for Microsoft Flight Simulator, RDPresets have announced that Naples’ airport will be their next pursuit for the platform.  With this news the developer doubles the number of projects they’ve got on the go, as work on Marseille continues concurrently. “[Marseille] has hit some major bumps in the road, some items failed our Quality Assurance and are requiring some remodelling, this will take time and has set Marseille back two release slots, meaning as it stands two other airports will come before it." The developer explains that the delay is necessary to ensure quality. "But this does allow me to announce you our first new airport which is in Italian [sic], “Aeroporto di Napoli”." "We’re incredibly proud of how this product is currently being developed and it’s going at an incredible pace. We’re using a new texture method ensuring a higher texture resolution, but at the same time using less texture sets. "It took us some time to perfect this and arguably we’re still learning it, but we feel it is really good already and worthy enough to put it above our current Rotterdam airport quality." RDPresets want to go 'the extra mile' in ground detailing with Naples, saying that the final product will 'truly give you an idea of arriving or departing [at an airport with proper weathering]. They have not offered a release date as yet, but maintain that the first in-sim images of Naples will debut shortly. It was also revealed in the development update that the brand is working on a hub software for their products. The software will be called RDHome. See the source post for this article on the RDPresets website.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mvpcce</id>
    <title>Milviz Discusses Updates for PC-6 Porter and Cessna 310R</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mvpcce" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629e70ea2b797332fd34fdff_286338871_5346744258703239_4442868559021534495_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="465253"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The tail-dragging turboprop PC-6 Porter from Milviz will shortly see an update according to developers, who are currently working on 'stage 2' of the Pilatus craft. The aircraft was first released for Microsoft Flight Simulator in September 2021 in a typical land-faring configuration. Milviz's stage 2 is set add floats and tundra tyres to the available set-ups. An option for an older steam gauge cockpit with 'multiple radio options' will also be available according to the developer. Speaking to the status of the update, the team had this to say -- "Development is ongoing, but we are a bit behind schedule. Hope to have some pics with the floats in the coming weeks." Stage 2 of Milviz's PC-6 Porter will see a price rise for new customers, but existing users will be able to upgrade for free. The developer says that your initial purchase will entitle you to any future updates for this products. In the same Facebook post, the team also made brief mention of their latest release, the Cessna 310R. The twin piston craft's service pack is "nearly finished!" See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42mex</id>
    <title>Parallel42 Announces New Airstrip; 'Scenes' to Sell Separately</title>
    <updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42mex" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629ef27127ce87013d8a92d5_0_bETJs4vXIrxSLDhT.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="289353"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Parallel42 continues their unique ‘scenes’ series with Mexican Mountain, a bush camping spot in Green River, Utah. The series is tailor-made for the group’s FreedomFox aircraft, which was released in December 2021. ‘Scenes’, small fictional airstrips dotted around Microsoft Flight Simulator’s backcountry, come free to customers of the FreedomFox and are stocked with plenty of room to park up on multiplayer adventures.  Edson Soriano, managing director at Parallel42 commented that the dioramas “continue bringing value to your time flying FF/F2.” The latest creation in the series, Mexican Mountain — which has been given the fictional ICAO ‘42MX’ — has been made in collaboration with several real-world pilots operating in the area. Green River makes for a dramatic backdrop for bush flying, with large elevation changes, ridges, cliffs and pinnacles but to name a few prominent features. “Mexican Mountain truly is…out there, the views are tremendous, &amp; you’ll have plenty of places to practice STOL landings nearby and you’re a short hop away from Moab.” Mexican Mountain will be available for free to owners of the FreedomFox Complete Package (incl. all Orbx customers) and will be available separately on the Microsoft Marketplace for $7.99 USD.  Starting with Mexican Mountain, previously released ‘scenes’ will also be migrated to the Marketplace so users without the FreedomFox Complete Package can use the strips too.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ownrel</id>
    <title>RWY26 Debuts in MSFS with Teaser &amp; Release of Owen Roberts Intl. Airport</title>
    <updated>2022-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ownrel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629ff2f20ddc54e420f6d68a_omg.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="528129"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A few hours ago, Runway 26 Simulations has officially made their debut on Microsoft Flight Simulator with the announcement of their first product on the platform, Owen Roberts International Airport (MWCR). Shortly after the news drop, the team got it released on SimMarket. The real airport is the main international gateway for the Cayman Islands. Consisting of a single 2,398 runway with a recently upgraded terminal, the airport is home to the nation’s flag carrier, Cayman Airways and sees over 1 million passengers traversing through the airport. The airport is a major facilitator to Cayman Islands’ reliance on imported goods, processing 1.5 million and a quarter of a million pounds of cargo and mail respectively. In a Facebook post briefly captioned “Behold... First scenery for MSFS2020…” The team also dropped a trailer on their YouTube channel, providing a quick walkthrough of the airport rendition. On the product page, there’s not much in the way of information, with the notable omission of a basic feature list. We do know that it comes at a rather light 175MB package. The developer is recognised for its scenery creations focused around Central America, and the push into MSFS with the West Carribean airport is something to be expected. If you’re up for some scenic flying, you could begin your journey by exploring George Town. The airport, priced at 15 Euros - is an accessible ask. Presumably, this will mark the beginning of more caribbean airports to come, particularly from Runway 26, stay tuned as we’ll keep you in the loop on future developments from the development team.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
