<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-07-28T18:40:50.522822+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl309</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo &amp; neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl309"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/687ac7f98fc52b4ce72b8314_309-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently issued a new experimental update to their A321ceo and ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, focusing on increasing stability, improving visual performance, and improving the handling, among other things. Update v11.0.1.309 aims to improve performance and lower VRAM usage, ensuring better headroom for users running very high resolutions or rocking cards with little VRAM to spare. Such extra headroom should warrant better stability in video memory-constrained environments, like approaching a demanding airport on top of a photogrammetric area. They have also mitigated certain CTDs that occasionally happen with very specific TCAS traffic situations and aircraft reloads. The steps taken to mitigate those should increase the overall robustness of their code, making it much more reliable. FSLabs has also worked on correcting an issue affecting the yaw behavior during the landing roll and retuning brake effectiveness based on measured stopping distances from real aircraft. These tweaks should bring more authenticity to the post-touchdown phase. ‍ Systems were also improved, with FMGC protections added, further improvements to the NEO engine logic, ROPS behavior, and many smaller fixes.  ‍ The complete changelog follows below: AOC Service:  ‍ ‍ APU: ‍ ‍ CIDS: ‍ ELAC: ‍ FMGC: ‍ ‍ FWC:  ‍ ‍ MCDU: ‍ ‍ Neo-specific: ‍ ‍ ROPS: ‍ ‍ Systems Improvements: ‍ ‍ Model Updates: ‍ ‍ The A321ceo and neo are available in their store for $69.95 each. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rexa24</id>
    <title>REX Simulations Announces REX Atmos CORE for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rexa24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/687ff9fa8aa5deb7df892707_atmos-core-logo.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. REX Simulations has announced REX Atmos CORE, a new utility meant to enhance the atmospheric environment in MSFS 2024. Building on the previously released REX Atmos 2020, Atmos CORE brings the popular enhancement utility to Microsoft’s new simulator. Atmos CORE enables real-time adjustments of weather, atmospheric rendering, and environmental conditions. According to REX, Atmos CORE will integrate seamlessly with Asobo Live Weather, ActiveSky FS, and other custom or imported weather presets, without interfering with existing simulator files. Improvements over default include more realistic ozone levels, cloud colour accuracy, shader appearance, cloud lighting, Rayleigh scattering, and atmospheric blending. Atmos CORE is described as fully customisable, safe and non-destructive, with a simple user interface. You will be able to alter different atmospheric parameter values directly, with the ability to save and share the changes as presets.  A single preview image, shared in the official announcement on the REX website, shows off more natural lighting, and improved cloud shading. No release date or pricing information has been shared yet, though the product is described as being “available soon.” ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffx750</id>
    <title>FlightFX Releases Cessna 750 Citation X for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffx750"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688009de832b7b7dc075134e_685df1e6de65db2240ef9c26_web11.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlightFX has released its Cessna 750 Citation X for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, offering a high-fidelity rendition of the high-speed business jet. Built from scratch, the aircraft features a custom HP 2000 avionics suite, advanced systems simulation, and a fully modelled cabin interior. Furthermore, the Citation X includes simulated pressurisation, electrical, fuel, hydraulic, and environmental systems, full VNAV capability, along with optional auto throttle integration. Both winglet and non-winglet variants are included, with accurate performance modelling. FlightFX has also included a custom Electronic Flight Bag, with SimBrief integration, Navigraph and OpenStreetMap support, and controls for ground services. The aircraft comes with dynamic lighting, various interactive cabin features, and a sound set recorded from the real aircraft. The full product description, including flight manuals and the official paint kit, is available via the FlightFX website. The complete feature list follows below: Systems Simulation &amp; Flight Modeling Electronic Flight Bag (VAMS 2.0) Visual Modeling Audio For all the latest news in flight simulation, stay up to date on Threshold!  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar095</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar095"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6880447240b155823c98bfd4_filth1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has issued a new update to their newly released Accu-Sim Piper Aerostar for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, adding persistent dirt and mud accumulation, multiple fixes, and more. Update v0.9.5, or “Filthy Update” as they call it, brings persistent dirt and mud accumulation on the airframe, and some eye candy features that are not present on the changelog but will be “noticeable once you load up the cockpit”. It’s now a bit different and more polish has been applied to the textures and modelling. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ -Added persistent dirt and mud accumulating over time -Added button to wash the aircraft in the EFB Maintenance tab -Added missing details to the propeller spinners -Autopilot: Fixed GA mode not activating from GS -Body shake physics from engine and buffeting -Enlarged walkaround volumes -Fixed clamshell door animation -Fixed prop governor side on the engine models -Fuel drain bottle visibility can be toggled now, off by default -Landing Gear Up light is amber -Low fuel warning fixed -Magnetos don't flicker when there is no fuel in the tank -Parking brake animation and persistence corrected -Quickview camera definitions -Reduced the visibility of blurred streaks on the blurred spinner -Removed clearcoat material from exterior model -Removed protruding objects on the rear wall of the cockpit -Saving HydrAuxSwitch -Support for "Custom" starting location on the MSFS map -Updated main textures -Visors folds out more, tooltips fixed -[Tablet] Lubrication oil adds weight The update is available right now through their store page. The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hs78v2</id>
    <title>Horizon Simulations Provides Update on 787 Version 2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hs78v2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68816e6dbb6c5ab3912fdf55_HS_787_AMX_SHOWCASE.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Horizon Simulations has shared a comprehensive development update on its freeware Boeing 787 project for MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, detailing some of the big improvements of the upcoming Version 2. Acknowledging a period of silence, Horizon Simulations explained that the team is entirely volunteer-based, balancing development with personal obligations. As a result, they avoid setting deadlines. However, they plan to share regular content updates moving forward, including monthly posts and in-depth “development dives”, highlighting features of the upcoming Version 2 release. Version 2 of the Horizon 787 will feature a major overhaul for all three variants, the 787-8, 787-9, and 787-10, with a focus on a significantly revised external model. Other enhancements include a new custom cabin and numerous visual and functional refinements. Among the key upgrades are accurately modelled CAC inlet doors that respond dynamically to environmental, hydraulic and engine conditions, as well as support for line number variations that reflect subtle real-world differences between each airframe. Engine animations have also been redesigned, with revised spool-up dynamics and improved visual effects between the Trent 1000 and GEnx powerplants. Other notable additions include a functioning APU door, a reworked vertical stabiliser, new lighting with shadow effects for more realistic reflections, and detailed control surface behaviour when hydraulic power is not available, including aileron, flaperon, and elevator droop, along with rudder deflection induced by wind. While the update does not provide a release timeline, Horizon Simulations emphasised that development is active and ongoing. Further details, including sounds, systems, and additional model improvements, are expected in future posts. For all the latest in flight simulation, be sure to stay updated here on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lst112</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Living Scenery Technology to Version 1.12</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lst112"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688252fa270d5b09160b11de_LST_Video_Thumbnail%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Living Scenery Technology, a free ground traffic plugin for XP11 and XP12, has recently been updated to version 1.12. The release introduces several new features and fixes, aimed at improving realism and flexibility for developers.  Designed to animate moving objects within sceneries, such as people, cars, and ground traffic, the plugin provides a versatile system for developers to create dynamic environments. Among the most notable additions is the "MINSPACING" command, which enables developers to set a minimum distance between vehicles on a route. Vehicles now decelerate gradually and stop if they get too close, simulating traffic jams and stoplights more accurately. Support for dataref operations has also been further improved, with an optional priority system. This resolves previous conflicts when multiple operations targeted the same dataref, allowing for more controlled animations, such as preventing vehicles from driving through occupied crosswalks, or managing door behaviour based on other traffic conditions. The update also further refines acceleration and deceleration logic. Rather than stopping and starting abruptly, vehicles now adjust speed smoothly based on waypoint conditions, resulting in more believable traffic flow. Additionally, version 1.12 introduces the “DREFCYCLE” command, which cycles a dataref through a specified pattern, ideal for features like animated jetways.  The update is available for download via X-Plane.org. Be sure to stay up to date with all the latest flight simulation news, right here on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/s43w162024</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases S43 Harvey Field and W16 Monroe Firstair for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/s43w162024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68816eb4f21807fcaae0c45e_monroe1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their rendition of S43 Harvey Field and W16 Monroe Firstair for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which improves on the 2020 version. Harvey Airfield is a privately-owned public-use airport in Snohomish (WA), categorized on the FAA's National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems as a regional reliever facility. It was established in 1944 by the Harvey Family, getting a restaurant, an administration building, and a maintenance shop in 1947.  It is mainly used for flight training in general aviation airplanes and helicopters, and offers fuel and aircraft maintenance. Monroe First Air Field is a public-use airport owned by the Washington State Department of Transportation. It opened in 1930 as a private airfield for Monroe Aircraft Corporation and was utilized in the following decade as a training base for the US Army.  The post-war period saw the airfield become a general aviation facility, which continues to this day, even after it was acquired by the Washington State Department of Transportation in 1980. Despite being small, it's considered a very important part of the state's history for its many purposes over its nearly 100 years of existence. The scenery features a reedition of a FSX/P3D classic ported initially to 2020 and now revamped for 2024 in its full glory, with dynamic night lighting, full PBR UHD texturing, high-detailed models, and more. It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.40, requiring at least 4.62 GB of free hard disk space to install (owners of the 2020 version get it for free). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/imaginesimatl24</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Releases Atlanta International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/imaginesimatl24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6881725b034ba9baa2d6970c_katlmsfs01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Imaginesim has recently released their rendition of Atlanta International Airport (KATL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing new models and improvements over the 2020 version. The update is free for existing 2020 customers and entirely overhauls the airport with new models, layout updates, performance improvements, new landscaping, and more. The complete changelog follows below: - Fantastic performance with comprehensive optimization. - New modelling and thousands of other improvements. - Custom interactive SafeGateTM Visual Docking Guidance (VDGS). - New landscaping, PBR and terrain modelling. - Fluid usage, even with complex airliner cockpits and high density AI coverage. - Interactive bespoke jetways and animations. - Instantaneous scenery cache loading and low simulator impact. - 15 square mile coverage of the KATL area. - Graduated ground extremities to seamlessly blend with any vector driven add-on. - Utilizes imaginesim's bespoke Operations Center configuration GUI. MSFS Marketplace customers will get the update over the coming weeks, whereas people who have purchased it from other platforms already have access to it. The scenery is available for purchase on their website for roughly $27.15. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2htul</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Tulsa International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2htul"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68818185c24495951b939268_tulsa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Tulsa International Airport (KTUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Tulsa, Oklahoma, and has a yearly average of 3.2 million passengers. The airport opened nearly a hundred years ago, in 1928, as Tulsa Municipal Airport. Its initial infrastructure was rather rough, with a one-story wood and tar “terminal” and landing strips and taxiways made of mown grass. It was busy enough at the time to be the “busiest airport in the World,” handling nearly 10,000 passengers a month, somehow outpacing Croydon Airport in London, Berlin Tempelhof, and Paris Le Bourget. In the early 1930s, Frederick Kershner designed a new terminal with an elegant Art Deco design, no more wood and tar. That building soldiered on until the 1950s, when the administration realized it was no longer sufficient for the traffic figures, leading to the construction of a new terminal in 1958. The new – and much bigger – terminal opened in 1961, qualifying it to become an International airport two years later. It hosted the 130th Fighter Wing in 1940 during the early stages of World War 2. Within a year of that, the War Department determined that Tulsa would become the site of an Air Force Plant, operated by Douglas Aircraft Corporation to manufacture and assemble bombers from 1942 to 1945. A year after the war, American Airlines purchased two ex-Air Force hangars to start their maintenance facilities in Tulsa, where they had nonstop routes to Los Angeles and San Francisco. In the 1960s, McDonnell Douglas still used the Air Force Plant for aircraft maintenance. The lease ended in 1996, when Boeing acquired it for aerospace manufacturing. The passenger terminal was renovated in the 2010s, designed by Gensler and Benham Companies. The ceilings were raised, passenger waiting areas were improved, and the gates were redesigned. It’s a hub for Omni Air International and Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality terminal model and its respective interior, custom jetways, custom taxiway labels, custom ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket (2020 / 2024) for roughly $21.63, requiring at least 2.87 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksad2</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Adelaide Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksad2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883dabffe1f0d96eedca117_mk_ypad_21-scaled.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing Adelaide Airport to MSFS 2020 and 2024. This marks the developer’s first entry into the Australian continent, offering users the opportunity to explore one of Australia's perhaps lesser-known aviation hubs, with a high level of detail and accuracy. Adelaide Airport is located approximately 4 miles west of the city centre and serves as the primary gateway to South Australia. It accommodates domestic, international, and general aviation traffic, and operates flights to over 30 destinations across Oceania, Asia, and North America. The airport also functions as a hub for Virgin Australia, a focus city for Qantas, and a base for Jetstar. With over 8.7 million passengers recorded in the latest fiscal year, it ranks as the fifth-busiest airport in the country. The scenery package features a highly detailed rendition of the airport, including a fully modelled terminal interior, updated taxiways, custom terrain elevation and airport lighting, and animated ground vehicles. Enhancements for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 include newwalkable jetways. The scenery is also compatible with AI traffic, and includes custom aerial photogrammetry and infrastructure, based on extensive reference material. The new Safedock FleX docking system is also depicted, as well as animated traffic. Adelaide Airport for MSFS is currently available via Orbx for $28.99 AUD, excluding applicable sales tax. Wider availability through Contrail, iniBuilds, and SimMarket will follow at a later date. You can also buy Adelaide Airport as part of ORBX’s Adelaide Airport &amp; City Bundle, which includes the Orbx Adelaide City Pack, now available at a 15% discount. The full feature list follows below: ‍Key Features For all the latest in flight simulation scenery and more MK Studios updates, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwpncl</id>
    <title>RW Profiles Announces Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwpncl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883e3c1db9ba2bf21ac98f3_97701c_bac5e30604b747988423d17c3ed79561mv2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. RW Profiles has announced its upcoming release of Newcastle International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Set to launch later this month, the scenery aims to deliver a high-fidelity recreation of one of the United Kingdom’s key regional hubs. Newcastle International Airport served over five million passengers in 2024, connecting the Northeast of England to more than 80 destinations across Europe, the Middle East, and North America. It is home to over 15 airlines, including British Airways, Jet2, TUI and easyJet. Despite its short runway, the airport also sees regular service from Emirates 777s. The scenery comes with a comprehensive set of features, in order to replicate the airport to a high degree of accuracy. These include fully hand-crafted ground textures, a detailed terminal interior, and a complete representation of the landside area. Airport buildings, objects, and surrounding infrastructure are modelled in high detail, with the layout reflecting the airport’s current configuration. Additional features include accurate night lighting, hand-placed and custom runway and taxiway lighting, animated jetways in multiple configurations, and a fully modelled general aviation area, complete with static aircraft and an FBO interior. Custom ground clutter, GSE, and a bespoke GSX profile are also included. The package is further optimised for performance, using LODs and instancing. You will also have access to configuration options that can disable certain scenery elements, including the terminal interior. The current feature list follows below: Newcastle International Airport for MSFS 2020 and 2024 is scheduled to release on July 30, 2025. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to keep an eye on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrbh1</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Teases Birmingham Airport for MSFS, Targets Aug. 1 Release</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrbh1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883ed371ae46b515563f918_523539154_18050624060547769_5117856982497558575_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Pyreegue Dev Co. has announced a provisional release date of Aug. 1 for its highly anticipated Birmingham Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update, shared by Pyreegue in a social media post, confirms that we won’t have to wait much longer for its release. The airport will include a custom GSX profile, developed by Hinshee, and preview streams are planned for the coming week. The upcoming scenery will depict Birmingham Airport in high detail, covering the airside, terminal buildings, detailed interiors and more. Located approximately 7 miles east-southeast of Birmingham city centre, Birmingham Airport is a major UK aviation hub. It served over 12.9 million passengers in 2017 and offers flights to destinations across Europe, Africa, the Middle East, North America, the Caribbean, and the Indian subcontinent. It is currently an operating base for easyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Further details on features and pricing are expected to follow ahead of the targeted release. For all the latest on Pyreegue’s Birmingham Airport, and more flight simulation news, be sure to stay updated on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfftl</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Fly the Line – Short Haul Edition</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfftl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6883fd20616b2a467859d99e_videoframe_16378.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Just Flight has released Fly the Line – Short Haul Edition,  a standalone application designed to introduce structured, career-based progression to the flight simulation experience. Being compatible with all major platforms, including MSFS 2020, MSFS 2024, X-Plane 11, X-Plane 12, Prepar3D v4 through v6, and Flight Simulator X, the program offers a versatile and personalised short-haul airline experience. Fly the Line allows you to assume the role of a short-haul airline pilot, starting as a Junior First Officer and advancing toward the rank of Fleet Captain. Career progression is guided by performance across scheduled flights, with players earning cash, XP, and skill points to unlock new abilities, lifestyle improvements, and boost well-being, factors that influence job effectiveness. The application features three distinct game modes: Career Mode, where you build an airline career with generated routes and weekly schedules; Free Play Mode, which offers access to all features from the start, and Schedule Mode, focusing solely on realistic schedules and immersive flying, without the progression mechanics. You can create up to eight personalised pilot profiles and 16 aircraft profiles, each with its own schedules and data. Route generation is based on real-world airline data, and offers short- to medium-haul sectors, ranging from 30 minutes to around six hours. The software also includes dynamic diversions, sightseeing flights, side jobs, and a progression system that unlocks over 30 pilot skills. Lifestyle upgrades, such as home furnishings and sim pit setups, appear in a 3D-rendered home environment. Each flight is logged in a logbook, detailing performance metrics and feedback on landing quality, as well as other parameters. You can also create a custom airline, using any aircraft. Fly the Line is available from the Just Flight store for $39.99 USD. The program comes with an installer and includes built-in tutorials.  For the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simworks-studios-provides-update-on-airvan-pc-12-and-more</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Provides Update on Airvan, PC-12 and More, for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simworks-studios-provides-update-on-airvan-pc-12-and-more"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/688409b1218da587bf89aa5d_523452896_1296718509122493_6898909485459796710_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimWorks Studios has recently issued a development update on social media, outlining progress across several ongoing projects, including the GA8 Airvan, PC-12, and FS2024 upgrades for the Kodiak series. Firstly, the developer stated that the MSFS 2020 version of the GA8 Airvan is nearing release, with the developer confirming that initial copies have already been distributed to ten users, ahead of launch. The MSFS 2024 variant is currently feature-complete; however, its release has been deferred by approximately one month to allow for additional testing following the rollout of Sim Update 3. Accompanying documentation, including the aircraft manual and a failures supplement for the SystemsPulse system, will be published next week, alongside the product page of the GA8. SimWorks Studios also stated that the Airvan will be released via the Microsoft Marketplace to begin with, with a direct store launch planned for a later date. The developer also shared updates on the Pilatus PC-12. The interior model rework has been completed, and is now entering the testing phase. In addition to improving FS2024 compatibility, the updated model features adapted Level of Detail (LOD) variants for better performance and reduced file size. The new cabin has seamless textures and enhanced customisability, allowing for more detailed liveries. Work on the PC-12 exterior model is expected to begin next week, with a teaser of the NG variant planned at a later date. SimWorks Studios is also working to enable hot-swapping between avionics configurations, the GNS, GTN and GTNXi, using the tablet system from the Airvan, which will be ported over to the PC-12. In closing, the developer noted continued progress on making both the Kodiak 100 and 900 compatible with MSFS 2024, with more news expected soon. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fenixbfupreview</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Teases Upcoming Major Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fenixbfupreview"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6886bd015bed0e2ee073dfd2_bfu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations recently published a 30-minute video showcasing some of the upcoming changes that will accompany the so-called Big Fenix Update, which is set to release on Tuesday or Wednesday. The changes include a complete rework of the landing behavior, using over 800,000 real-life landings from different A320 family aircraft, spanning their entire lineup (A319/A320/A321), the addition of the A319SL, a rare variant of the A319 only operated by a few airlines around the world, an entirely reworked cockpit for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 version, making use of its new lighting engine, and an interactive walkaround mode (also 2024 only), among many other tweaks and fixes. Furthermore, their A320 lineup will feature a working weather radar – only missing the tilt feature due to a sim limitation –, LIDO charts support (2024), sound improvements, and become less reliant on the Prosim base. Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (complete bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxbfu</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases “Big Fenix Update” for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxbfu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6887a3b2db6f22ef4f786a4f_videoframe_356352%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations today released the long‑anticipated, aptly nicknamed “Big Fenix Update”, a sweeping overhaul of the entire A320 family, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. The update delivers full MSFS 2024 support, major flight-model enhancements, and a range of system, livery, art, and EFB improvements. The update introduces full FS2024‑native modular SimObject support and rendering updates, along with new engine models, as well as the new A319 Sharklet variant, with custom performance data. The flight deck has been remodelled and retextured for MSFS 2024, complete with reworked display rendering, new soundsets, and a revamped livery manager featuring dozens of new liveries. Landing dynamics and fly‑by‑wire responsiveness have been retuned, with ground law, elevator deflection, AoA protection and αMAX handling improved across all variants. Flex temp unlatching logic, OP CLB/DES behaviour, and Flight Director pitch response in normal flight have all been refined. Performance has also been improved through reduced CPU load and optimised display rendering. A new LOD-system has also been implemented for all models, bringing further optimization. Flight model enhancements focus on improved ground‑law behaviour, AoA protection, and refined handling characteristics across all variants. Autopilot pitch response, flex temp logic, and Open Climb/Descent behaviour have also been reworked. Furthermore, Wingflex has also seen further improvement. The update introduces full support for MSFS 2024’s walkaround mode, with interactive cargo doors, chocks, power panels, engine fanblades and refuelling controls. Automatic connection of stairs and door opening on spawn-in has been added. New configuration options in the EFB allow control over ADIRS type, ACP style and ISIS display preferences. The update also brings support for the MSFS weather-radar, which is now fully implemented, within simulator limitations. Furthermore, the update includes various visual upgrades such as new cabin lighting, a new native iridescent windshield material, microscratches and refined glass decals for MSFS 2024. New sounds have been added to doors, cooling fans and avionics contactors, amongst others. A completely new IAE engine sound set is also included, with windmilling effects.  Walkaround mode now supports inside‑outside sound transitions and even avatar walking noises, though collisions may still cause occasional jitter. A brand‑new native EFB chart app is featured, with LIDO support and an option to switch between simulator and Navigraph sources. Pilot Brief PDF viewing, custom refuelling rates, take‑off performance tools with ACT count, chart annotations and automatic switching of weight units when importing from SimBrief are included. The EFB also now works in walkaround-mode.  For a further deep dive into flight model and fly‑by‑wire behaviour, an unlisted video on Fenix’s official YouTube channel offers detailed insight into control input processing and control surface responses.  You can watch it here. The full changelog for the update follows below: Avionics and Systems Art and Sound EFB Flight and Engine Models For all the latest in flight simulation news, stay up to date on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
