<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-08-29T18:31:46.161184+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lsszhou</id>
    <title>Li Scenery Studio Releases Zhoushan Putuoshan International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lsszhou"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68a7cfa63ca4dd36a4fe1782_zhou1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Li Scenery Studio recently released their rendition of Zhoushan Putuoshan International Airport (ZSZS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves Zhoushan in Zhujiajian Island, China, and has a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers. The construction work started in early 1994, and the challenges started from the get-go due to the terrain: a low-lying area of rice paddies, which demanded the placement of millions of cubic meters of landfill to raise the land a little bit above sea level. It wasn’t until 1997 that the airport was ready for inauguration. Upgrades were carried out gradually in the decades that followed its inauguration, ensuring that it could accommodate the ever-rising passenger figures. A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 2019 to consolidate it as the regional hub for aviation. Chengdu Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Express Airlines, China Southern Airlines, China United Airlines, Donghai Airlines, Fuzhou Airlines, Greater Bay Airlines, GX Airlines, Okay Airways, Qingdao Airlines, Shandong Airlines, Shanghai Airlines, Shenzhen Airlines, Sichuan Airlines, West Air, and XiamenAir serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, a basic terminal interior, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.53, requiring at least 69.34 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pfbjc1</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Updates Rocky Mountain Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pfbjc1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ac713fd3c75a38063dc5ea_YM0vwl%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Propair Flight has released an update for its Rocky Mountain Metropolitan Airport (KBJC) scenery for MSFS 2020 and 2024. The update was developed with community feedback and introduces a range of fixes and improvements to the popular airfield. Scenery changes include enhanced detail across the airport, corrected ILS, and new approach strobe lights for runway 30R, custom VOR and windsock models, and additional parking beneath the Sheltair arch. Performance has also been improved, with optimised textures and an option to disable static aircraft. Rocky Mountain Metropolitan is a public-use airport in Broomfield, CO, serving general aviation, corporate flights, and flight schools. Covering 1,700 acres, with three runways, it is the closest local airport to downtown Denver, and also hosts aerial firefighting operations. The airport has even accommodated the Boeing VC-25A of Air Force One in the past. Propair Flight's rendition features a detailed set of 3D models, high-resolution textures, custom ground polygons, and dynamic night lighting, closely replicating the airport and its surroundings. The update is available now through the Propair Flight webshop, as well as SimMarket and Orbx, for roughly $17.14. For all the latest news in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcafcl</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Alpha Flight Controls Lite Available for Purchase</title>
    <updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcafcl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ac78e54b6ddd3a933afddb_Screenshot_2025-05-01_at_16.50.20_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The Honeycomb Alpha Flight Controls Lite have just gone live on Honeycomb’s website and is now available for purchase. The Honeycomb Alpha Flight Controls Lite has a design similar to its more expensive version, but does not include the switch panel. Honeycomb emphasises that the Alpha Flight Controls Lite maintains "no compromise on quality”, due to the use of premium materials and precision components to ensure a durable and smooth-running control system. Honeycomb claims that the Alpha Flight Controls Lite provides a “high-end feel” and realistic elevator and aileron control comparable to premium models. The yoke boasts a near-identical design to the more expensive Alpha Flight Controls. It comes equipped with two programmable buttons and two-way rocker switches on each side, along with a POV switch located on the left side. Additionally, it features a robust steel shaft with a self-centring mechanism, minimal dead zone, and 180 degrees of rotation. With the yoke coming from an already established company, it offers broad compatibility and features seamless integration with MSFS 2020, along with a practical mapping guide for MSFS 2024. The Alpha Flight Controls Lite is one of four new products that Honeycomb announced earlier this year at FSWeekend, alongside the Bravo Throttle Quadrant Lite, the Foxtrot Aviation Stick, and the Sierra TPM Module. Honeycomb anticipates launching the rest of the products during Q4 this year. Our very own Magnus recently attended a press event hosted by Honeycomb in London, where he had the opportunity to get hands-on experience with the Alpha Flight Controls Lite, among other products. Read more about it here. ‍ The Honeycomb Alpha Flight Controls Lite is available now for $199.99 on Honeycomb’s website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simnordcph</id>
    <title>SimNord Releases Copenhagen Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simnordcph"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ad3b8d894861de2506fb89_cph1cph.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimNord has recently released their rendition of Copenhagen Airport (EKCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the second largest airport in the Nordic countries, serving Denmark and Southern Sweden with over 30 million passengers yearly. It was inaugurated in 1925, making it one of the first civil airports in the world and one of the oldest still in operation. The structure consisted of a large wooden terminal, a few hangars, a hydroplane landing stage, and grass meadows used as runways. A horde of sheep feasted on the grass meadows daily, constantly keeping them short. In the 1930s, passenger numbers grew quite significantly, reaching almost 100,000, prompting the construction of a new terminal, which was built between 1936 and 1939. It was designed by Vilhelm Lauritzen and widely considered one of the finest examples of Nordic functionalism, focusing on passenger comfort and overall efficiency. During World War 2, the airport was mostly closed for civil operations, aside from a few periodic flights to Sweden and Germany. During that time, they also got the first hard-surface runway, 1400 meters long and 65 meters wide. By the end of the war, Copenhagen was the most modern airport in Europe, primarily because it remained undamaged throughout the conflict, which many other airports in Europe could not say the same about. By 1948, it was already the third-largest airport in Europe, with 300,000 passengers yearly. This led to continuous expansion work to ensure the utmost comfort for everybody.  In 1956, Copenhagen hit the million passenger mark for the first time, largely due to its increased popularity among Hollywood stars and producers, giving it newfound glamour. In the early 1960s, a new terminal was built, able to handle 28 jets at the same time. This quickly became relatively suboptimal, kicking off another expansion program in the final part of the decade. Domestic traffic was relocated to a new terminal, and the international terminal got a new pier and arrivals hall. Furthermore, the airport also got a new control tower and a new 3,600-meter-long runway. By the 1970s, the airport was already handling 8 million passengers, which was not followed by any expansion work, as there were plans to build a new airport elsewhere, which was eventually ruled out due to the very high costs and work involved. Instead, they figured it would be cheaper to expand the current one to handle 20 to 22 million passengers yearly by 2000.  The expansion work kicked off in 1982. The aim was to build not Europe’s largest airport but one of the most efficient in terms of reachability. Furthermore, they wanted to create an “oasis” where passengers could relax before their trips.  ‍ In the late 1990s, the airport expanded again, creating a pier connecting the domestic and international terminals, a new arrivals hall, new baggage handling facilities, an underground railway station, and a new terminal able to handle 17 million passengers per year alone. ‍ In 2006, Copenhagen finally surpassed their target of 20 million passengers yearly, hitting 20,900,000 passengers. ‍ Shortly after, the administration announced their plans to build a new low-cost terminal, which was completed in 2010 and opened by easyJet.  It’s a hub for Danish Air Transport and Scandinavian Airlines, a focus city for Air Greenland and Finnair, and an operating base for Jettime, Norwegian Air Shuttle, and Sunclass Airlines. More than 50 airlines worldwide serve it, including Aegean, Air Canada, Air China, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, Finnair, Qatar Airways, and Turkish Airlines. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom ground poly, detailed buildings, custom aerial imagery, and more. ‍ It’s available on their website for roughly $25.58. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/erjpre</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Previews New ERJ Family 2.0 Cockpit for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/erjpre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68adb417cbe650a496d16e81_ERJ-FAMILY-2.0-X-CRAFTS-COCKPIT-10-transformed.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts has shared the first in-depth look at its upcoming ERJ Family 2.0 update, showcasing a fully reworked cockpit, with a new avionics suite, and major visual upgrades. The previews highlight extensive modelling work across the flight deck, with detailed views of the yoke, overhead panel, autopilot mode control panel, and the electronic flight bag, amongst others. We also see the redesigned primary and multi-function displays, a brand-new FMS, and new pop-up functionality for improved usability. According to the developer, all displays have been rebuilt, with much higher resolution, while a new EFB has been designed, specifically for the ERJs. Both FMS units can be popped out into 2D panels or dragged onto external monitors. Despite the increase in fidelity, X-Crafts says optimisation techniques developed during the Lineage 1000 project help to keep performance impact low. The Embraer ERJ family, short for Embraer Regional Jet, includes the ERJ 135, ERJ 140, and ERJ 145, as well as derivatives such as the Legacy 600 business jet and the R-99 military series. First entering service in the mid-1990s, the ERJ went on to sell more than 1,200 aircraft worldwide before being succeeded by Embraer’s newer E-Jets. The ERJ Family 2.0 is currently undergoing testing with X-Crafts’ pilot team and beta testers. If progress continues as planned, release is expected later this year, according to the developer. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/devdss</id>
    <title>Devinci Releases Blaise Diagne International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/devdss"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68adc399e97ddbb6b459a886_363181_2537590_410.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Scenery developer Devinci has recently released a new rendition of Senegal’s Blaise Diagne International Airport (GOBD) for MSFS 2024. The scenery has been rebuilt from the ground up for MSFS 2024 with a wide range of upgrades, including full PBR 4K textures, a detailed terminal interior, custom ground markings, and accurate night lighting. The developer has also included the Train Express Regional (TER) station, fire station, VIP facilities, and control tower, along with custom jetways and handcrafted aprons. Located roughly 27 miles east of Senegal’s capital, Dakar, in the Thiès Region, Blaise Diagne opened in December 2017 to replace the overcrowded Léopold Sédar Senghor International Airport. Named after politician Blaise Diagne, it now serves as the country’s primary aviation hub, handling over two million passengers annually. Furthermore, Devinci states that performance has been a key focus, with custom LODs, to ensure smoothness across a variety of systems. Owners of the previous MSFS 2020 version are eligible for a discounted upgrade to this 2024 release. You can view the feature list below: ‍ ✈️ Key Features ‍ Blaise Diagne International Airport for MSFS 2024 is available via SimMarket for around $21.80, including sales tax. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2kbhx</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Birmingham Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2kbhx"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68ae6973277151f0168b3acd_ukbhx1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Birmingham Airport (EGBB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the West Midlands in the United Kingdom and has a yearly average of 12.8 million passengers, making it the seventh busiest in the Country. The idea for an airport in Birmingham was first conceived in 1928, and a committee was created shortly after to research possible locations to start building. After much deliberation, Elmdon was deemed the best of the bunch, but the project soon went back to the drawing board due to the Great Depression. It wasn’t until 1933 that works resumed, with a new committee formed to oversee its construction. Before taking any steps, though, the newly formed committee went on a research trip to multiple successful airports in Europe, such as Schiphol (Amsterdam), Berlin (Tempelhof), Paris (Orly), Brussels, and London.  ‍ By January 1935, they had finally approached a company—Norman and Dawbarn—to advise on the construction and help design the airport as lead architects. Groundwork started in 1936, after the government allowed the airport’s development. A year later, in 1937, Norman and Dawbarn were authorized to begin drawing the airport’s project, the undertaking of which took 6 months to reach completion. It was not until October 1937 that the construction of the airport’s buildings would start, costing around 360,000 pounds. ‍ Prime Minister Neville Chamberlain opened the airport in July 1939 as Elmdon Airport. The terminal featured a modern (for late 30s standards) art deco design with an integrated control tower and was the airport’s main terminal until 1984.  The airport was requisitioned by the Air Ministry to be used by both the Royal Air Force and the Royal Navy as RAF Elmdon during World War 2. The military “occupation” replaced the original grass runways with two hard runways, 753 meters in length and 1,271 meters in length, respectively.  ‍ It was used as a testbed for Avro Lancasters and Stirling bombers manufactured in northeast Worcestershire. These bombers were transported via land to Elmdon because their local airport didn’t have a long enough runway. On July 8, 1946, the airport, which was celebrating its 7th anniversary, was reopened for civilian use, albeit still government-controlled. Scheduled services started in 1949 with British European Airways, flying passengers to Paris. Over the years, the airline eventually expanded its network to Zürich, Düsseldorf, Palma, Amsterdam, and Barcelona. In the early 1960s, they built a new terminal to handle international traffic and extended the main runway to 2.2 km, allowing the airport to handle larger turboprop aircraft and jetliners. ‍ By the beginning of the 1970s, Birmingham Airport was already reaching a million passengers per year, significantly congesting their subpar terminal infrastructure. In the 1980s, BHX became home to the world’s first commercial maglev system, a train levitated by magnets. This system ran for nearly 10 years but eventually faced discontinuation due to unreliability. It was replaced by a cable-hauled system in 2003. ‍ In late 2007, the airport’s administration devised a development plan for Birmingham called “Towards 2030: Planning a Sustainable Future for Air Transport in the Midlands.” The plan included changes to the terminals, alterations to the airfield layout, and infrastructure improvements. Unexpectedly, environmentalists and locals complained, as they didn’t want the construction of a second parallel runway.  The original plan—now canceled—could have created up to 250,000 jobs in the area, made the airport handle up to 70 million passengers annually, and led to around 500,000 aircraft movements in total. ‍ In 2008, the shorter runway (06/24) was decommissioned due to its length and noise impact. Instead, it became a taxiway, allowing the expansion of the apron.  Construction work on the new 3-storey International Pier kicked off in June of that same year, taking a bit more than a year to complete. Now, Birmingham Airport was fully compatible with the Airbus A380, which visited the airport during its 70th birthday. It was the first commercial service of the A380 in the United Kingdom that was not bound to London Heathrow. ‍ In 2010, it was announced that they would merge Terminal 1 and 2 into a single building and change the name from Birmingham International Airport to Birmingham Airport. They figured this could help create a new corporate identity that would better reflect their current position in the market and attract more people to fly from it. Research showed that while 8 million people lived within an hour of the airport, only 40% of them used it.  ‍ A new control tower was built in 2011, ultimately replacing the original one built in 1939. ‍ The plans for extending the main runway, originally submitted in 2008, were approved a year later, but the work was only completed in 2014, two years after their original target, which was the 2012 London Olympics.  In late 2016, 100 million pounds were invested in building a new baggage handling system and two new car parks. ‍ It’s an operating base for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways, and served by Aer Lingus, Air France, Air India, Aurigny, Brussels Airlines, Corendon Airlines, Emirates, Eurowings, KLM, Loganair, Lufthansa, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, SunExpress, Swiss International Air Lines, Turkish Airlines, Vueling, and WizzAir. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with full detail buildings, custom ground markings, custom night lighting, PBR textures, animated jetways, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.81, requiring at least 87.86 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bwso31</id>
    <title>Backwood Studios Releases Shady Cove Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bwso31"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68af1b980a359bb1e3506558_689abb5a7f1af.jpg.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Backwood Studios has recently released Shady Cove Airport (OG31) for MSFS 2024, bringing a detailed rendition of the small Oregon airpark and its surrounding community. The scenery recreates Shady Cove’s dirt runway, fly-in homes, custom hangars, and private fuelling facilities, alongside handcrafted static objects, custom vegetation, and more than 10 miles of custom roads that connect Shady Cove to the nearby Sutton Airstrip, also developed by Backwood. The 2024 version also adds new community homes, optimised ground textures, and bespoke lighting for both daytime and night operations. Shady Cove Airpark itself has deep roots in Oregon's aviation history. Originally opened in 1949 by pilots Edward T. Tepper and John P. Jones, the airstrip grew from a grassroots flying field into a small aviation community, perched on a plateau above the Rogue River. It remains active today, serving local pilots, Mercy Flights medical operations, and even Department of Forestry crews during fire season. The airpark is also a gateway to the Pacific Northwest’s natural attractions, including Crater Lake, Diamond Lake, and the Rogue River, offering both a scenic flying destination and a community hub. Backwood modelled not just the runway and hangars, but much of the town itself, creating a sense of life and place. Backwood Studios’ Shady Cove Airport is available now on OrbxDirect for $4.52, excluding sales tax. For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42hbr</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Hogsback Ranch for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42hbr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68af3b4fd01a5ea05b4de7e1_11_72091832-7c27-4b40-b50f-ae2675d60387.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has recently released Hogsback Ranch for MSFS 2024, introducing a fully revamped version of their private luxury airstrip for the new 2024 simulator. Located in Tehama County, California, the ranch combines rugged backcountry flying with high-end residential, giving a rather unique home base for flying in the northern Californian hills.  The package features two short runways, a 984-foot gravel strip and a 1,043-foot dirt strip, alongside a private hangar, solar-powered runway lighting, and an asphalt helipad. Approach paths are intentionally challenging, with cliffs, gates, and nearby power lines requiring some carefulness when committing to landing. Dynamic wildlife, hand-modelled vegetation, and Parallel 42’s TrailBlazer terrain technology are also used. Beyond the airstrip, the scenery recreates the entire ranch property. Highlights include stables, campsites, a swimming pool with custom lighting, and explorable interiors in Walkaround Mode. There are also plenty of micro scenes, for example, a “party mode” inside the main house, and smaller environmental details around the property. Hogsback Ranch also supports MSFS 2024’s new fauna and visitor systems. Owners of Hogsback Ranch for MSFS 2020 can upgrade to the 2024 edition for $2, using code HOGSBACK24, valid through Feb. 5, 2026. New customers can purchase the product for $14.00 USD, including taxes. Hogsback Ranch is available now via the Parallel 42 store for PC, with releases on Contrail, Orbx, and the in-sim Marketplace (PC and Xbox) to follow. ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wsszhe</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studio Releases Zhengzhou Xinzheng International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wsszhe"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68afc088aa630c478e9fb00a_zheng1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. WF Scenery Studio has recently released their rendition of Zhengzhou Xinzheng International Airport (ZHCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Zhengzhou, China, with a yearly average of 25.3 million passengers. Zhengzhou International was built in the early 1990s to replace the city’s former main airport. Its suboptimal location made expansion impossible, and city residents constantly complained about noise. The new project was much larger, with a 45,900-square-meter terminal and a 3,400-meter-long runway. It opened in late 1997, and the old airport was demolished soon after. Nearly a decade after its opening, the airport was expanded for the first time, with the main terminal becoming twice as big with 128,000 square meters of built area. A new expansion project—a new terminal, a second runway, and a ground traffic center—was approved in 2013. Construction started shortly after approval, and completion was achieved in 2015. The airport’s cargo traffic increased substantially after opening a Foxconn branch in Zhengzhou (the company that manufactures the iPhone for Apple). Between 2010—when it launched—and 2017, the yearly cargo volume went from 85,798 to 502,714 metric tons, with a record growth of 34% a year. Since late 2017, it has been the busiest airport in central China, surpassing Wuhan and Changsha in the process. It’s a hub for Cargolux and China Southern Airlines, a focus city for Shenzhen Airlines, and an operating base for Lucky Air. 9 Air, Air Cambodia, Air China, Air Macau, Batik Air Malaysia, China Eastern Airlines, Donghai Airlines, Hainan Airlines, Korean Air, Nok Air, Shandong Airlines, Sichuan Airlines, Spring Airlines, Thai Lion Air, West Air, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, PBR textures, custom clutter, and more. It’s available on SimMarket (2020/2024)for roughly $23.20, requiring at least 2.82 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ascsou</id>
    <title>Aeroscape Releases Southampton Airport for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ascsou"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b0c8ca94ec6d43dbfaebd2_11_72091832-7c27-4b40-b50f-ae2675d60387%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. New to the iniBuilds Store, Aeroscape has recently released Southampton Airport (EGHI), for XP12. The scenery features a highly detailed rendition of one of southern England’s busiest regional airports, with bespoke modelling, accurate ground details, and optimised performance, for Laminar’s newest sim. Southampton Airport, well known for its rather short runway, lies in Hampshire, four miles northeast of the city centre. The Airport has a long history, stretching back to its role as Eastleigh Airfield in the early 1900s. It became a hub of British aviation history when the prototype Supermarine Spitfire first flew there in 1936. Today, the airport is an important regional gateway, with connections across the UK and Europe. Aeroscape’s scenery includes custom-made textures for runways, aprons, and taxiways, alongside a fully recreated landside environment, with accurate vegetation, road layouts, parking barriers, and signage. Dynamic night lighting has been implemented throughout, with bespoke taxi signs and custom-modelled ground service equipment, scattered across the apron. The main terminal has also been modelled internally, with lighting and detailed objects, designed to reflect its real-world counterpart. You can view the full feature list below: ‍ FULL FEATURES LIST Southampton handled nearly two million passengers in 2016, though traffic fell dramatically after the collapse of Flybe in 2020. Since then, carriers including easyJet, Aer Lingus, KLM, and Blue Islands have restored connectivity, with routes to major destinations such as Amsterdam, Dublin, and Belfast. Aeroscape Southampton for XP12 is priced at $10.77 USD, and is available exclusively through the iniBuilds Store. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lca101</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lca101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b0cd0a91ade4a715bbecbd_FlightSimulator2024_2hpFwJrwRL_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a brief update this week, iniBuilds has released version 1.0.1 of their Larnaca International Airport (LCLK), for MSFS 2024. The update addresses a number of minor issues, including a fix for models that were not rendering SSAO correctly. In addition, the jetway previously serving Gate 47 has now been reassigned to Gate 48A. You can read the changelog below: Changelog v1.0.1 Larnaca International Airport, Glafcos Clerides, (LCLK), is Cyprus’ largest airport, located 2.5 miles southwest of Larnaca. Handling over 8.6 million passengers in 2024, it serves as the country’s primary international gateway, connecting Europe, the Middle East, and beyond. iniBuilds Larnaca version 1.0.1 is available now through the iniManager. For new customers, the product is available via the iniBuilds Store, for $13.47 USD, excluding taxes. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfrj14</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates RJ Professional, including MSFS 2024 Support, and New Variant</title>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfrj14"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b0d93504f10abe94b08df4_rj-professional-msfs_64_ss_l_250828094625.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has released version 1.4 of its RJ Professional for MSFS 2020 and 2024, adding native MSFS 2024 support, performance enhancements, and a new aircraft variant. The headline feature is the RJ100 QT (Quiet Trader), a semi-fictional freighter variant, with four liveries: DHL, FedEx, TNT, and a prototype scheme. While the real aircraft never left the drawing board, Just Flight has now brought it to life in MSFS. Version 1.4 introduces full support for MSFS 2024, custom cabin textures for each passenger livery, and new model LODs, to improve performance. In addition, the GNLU-910A FMS now supports SimBrief flight plan imports, while refinements have been made to cockpit logic, crew callout timing, and autopilot behaviour. Passenger operators also benefit from this update, with custom cabin textures now included, for every default RJ70, RJ85, and RJ100 livery. Elsewhere, the aircraft recieves additional LODs for performance improvements, in both sims. Following this is a complement of various fixes, including corrections to cockpit animations, hydraulic systems, and gear logic. The issue of EFB flickering in MSFS 2024 has also been addressed. Cabin crew callouts now follow more realistic procedures, while the altimeter and autopilot behaviour have been refined. GSX integration has also been expanded, allowing ground power and air connections via the jetway. To comply with the latest MSFS 2024 SDK, the navdata folder has been moved externally, with Navigraph Hub updated, to support the change. Documentation has been streamlined, and all manuals, operations, EFB, and GNLU-910A have been revised. A refreshed paint kit is also included, now covering the new freighter variant. You can read the full changelog here. Existing owners who purchased directly from Just Flight can download Version 1.4 now, via their account page, with third-party stores to follow soon. New customers can pick up the RJ Professional at 25% off until the end of August, through the Just Flight store. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2astar0911</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2astar0911"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations has recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, implementing circuit breakers and many fixes and improvements. Update v0.9.11 brings circuit breakers to A2A’s newest airplane, along with new additions and improvements to further refine the simulation. The complete changelog follows below: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsrt24</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Real Taxiways for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsrt24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b1d88f6a9d1247718ea115_real-taxiways-usa-class-b-c-d-and-non-towered-airports-msfs-2024_5_ss_l_250819085522.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has recently released new editions of its Real Taxiways add-on, now available for MSFS 2024. Building on the earlier MSFS 2020 version, this release brings refined visuals, layout corrections, performance improvements, and native support for MSFS 2024. Black Square offers the product in several, separately sold editions, one for Europe, one covering the United States, and an edition specifically for military airfields. A discounted bundle package is also available. This release features various new sign models, with revised textures, improved night-time lighting, and LOD optimisation, that keep them readable from farther away without pop-in. Installation is now simpler, with no separate texture setup required, while several airports have received layout adjustments and smaller signage fixes. Black Square notes that performance impact remains negligible, and airports can be excluded from the installation to avoid conflicts with freeware, payware, or World Update scenery. Marketplace and Xbox versions are planned for a later date. The following editions of the product are available: Across all packages, airports have received updated layouts, thousands of revised taxiway signs, and improved consistency with ICAO standards and regional naming conventions. In total, tens of thousands of signs have been reworked, aiming to provide a more accurate and readable navigation experience in MSFS 2024. Pricing is set at $39.99 USD for the Europe and USA editions, $44.99 USD for the bundle, and $19.99 USD for the military package. Existing MSFS 2020 customers are eligible for discounts on the new editions, with details distributed via email. Black Square’s Real Taxiways, as well as the full feature lists and changelogs, can be found on the Just Flight Store. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksrhu</id>
    <title>MK Studios Provides Update on Rome and Helsinki for MSFS, Targeting Fall Release</title>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksrhu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68b1e174318c5444a5dc3557_540514511_1197192542429031_5833321835656931320_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has recently issued a brief update on its upcoming projects, confirming the progress of Helsinki Vantaa (EFHK) and Rome Fiumicino (LIRF) for MSFS. The developer explained that the holiday period, along with the release of Sim Update 3 and work on various scenery updates, had slowed progress in recent weeks. According to MK Studios, the main cause of the delay was a lack of reference material for both airports, which has now been resolved. With the necessary resources in place, the team stated that development is continuing at pace, following what it described as a quieter stretch during the summer months. Alongside the announcement, MK-Studios shared three new preview images, showing progress on the upcoming sceneries. More previews will follow in the coming weeks, as work on the two airports advances. Both EFHK and LIRF represent large international hubs in Europe, and are considered major projects for the studio. With the schedule change, the releases are now expected in fall 2025, though no specific dates have been confirmed. We’ll keep you updated on their progress. For all the latest flight simulation news, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
