<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-01-29T18:21:05.137906+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbluk</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Banja Luka International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbluk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a84636052597a2761c6cf8_banja.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development of Banja Luka International Airport (LQBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Banja Luka in Bosnia and Herzegovina, with a yearly average of 460,719 passengers as of 2023. ‍ Construction started in 1976, and the airport was initially part of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, operating as a strictly domestic airport for many years. After the Bosnian War and the creation of Republika Srpska, Banja Luka was established as the capital, and the airport was granted international status and opened for civilian traffic in 1997.  ‍ The airport underwent heavy upgrade work between 2002 and 2003 for Pope John Paul II's visit in June 2003.  ‍ Aegean Airlines (seasonal), Air Cairo (seasonal), Air Serbia, Freebird Airlines (seasonal), Nouvelair (seasonal), Ryanair, Tailwind Airlines (seasonal), and WizzAir currently serve it. ‍ Developed by indie Radoslav Tucakov, the scenery features fully custom terminals and buildings, interior details, exquisite perimeter details, a custom village and air base near the airport, PBR texturing, and more. ‍ There's no information on the release date and pricing yet.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taiman</id>
    <title>Taimodels Releases Manchester International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taiman"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a859e05326a6f587cf3f15_manchester.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Taimodels has recently released their rendition of Manchester International Airport (EGCC) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the third busiest airport in the United Kingdom with a yearly average of 23.3 million passengers.  Construction work began in 1935, and the airport was partially operating by 1937 (the official conclusion happened a year later). KLM was the first airline to launch scheduled commercial flights to the newly opened airport in 1938. ‍ It was converted into an RAF base during WW2 and played an essential role in military aircraft production and parachutist training. ‍ The post-war period saw its return as a commercial airport, with rapid growth during the 50s and 60s, where it eventually managed to be Britain's second busiest airport after London Heathrow. ‍ ‍ The airport was heavily expanded in the 80s and 90s to keep up with the exponential growth figures, eventually leading to the millionth passenger in a month mark in 1987. Plans for a new terminal were put in place, and it was opened by Princess Diana as Terminal A in 1989.  ‍ From 1997 to 2001, a second runway was built, leading to many protests from locals because natural habitats were disturbed and listed buildings had to be demolished, but they didn't have another option. ‍ New expansion work started in 2019 to keep up with the ever-growing passenger traffic figures. ‍ EasyJet, Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways have operating bases in Manchester. Many airlines from around the Globe serve it, including Air Canada, Air France, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad, Finnair, KLM, Kuwait Airways, Lufthansa, Qatar, Scandinavian Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish, Virgin Atlantic, and more. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail models, SAM jetways, high-quality PBR textures, performance-friendly optimization, complete autogen around the airport, ground traffic plugins, and weather textures for X-Plane 12. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $26.11, requiring at least 3.78 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini103</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini103"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a9a2d24bcaac26dd4c31b3_a300mon.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued the third update for their recently released Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing many bug fixes, EFB improvements, and more. ‍  Update 1.0.3 brings animation and light position fixes, tweaks to the fuel system, and new EFB features for throttle calibration, draggable charts, and many system changes. The changelog follows below: ‍ ‍ Sounds Fixes/Changes  The update is available right now via iniManager for all owners.  The airplane can be purchased on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orygla</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Gladstone Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orygla"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aaee7deb1854891d1bf587_gladstone.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Gladstone Airport (YGLA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Gladstone in Queensland, Australia, with a yearly average of 240,000 passengers (as of 2011).  ‍ It was built on a bulldozed airstrip in 1953, with work completed in 1956 and its official opening in 1957, although it had been frequently used a few months prior. ‍ Nowadays, it’s owned and operated by the Gladstone Regional Council, which took the helm after the former owner (Gladstone-Calliope Aerodrome Board) was dissolved in 2007. ‍ Bonza, QantasLink, and Virgin Australia currently serve it with flights to Brisbane, Gold Coast, and Melbourne. ‍ ‍  The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, extensive terraforming, highly realistic aprons and taxiways, custom runway and taxiway light models, animated trains, realistic rail infrastructure, detailed terminal interiors, and crisp 15cm aerial imagery. ‍  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.26, requiring at least 1.03 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hlub</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Lubbock Preston Smith International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hlub"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aaf65a7fd8d4ba6f57327d_lubbock.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Lubbock Preston Smith International Airport (KLBB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Lubbock, Texas, with a yearly average of 520,000 passengers, making it the eighth busiest in the state. ‍ It opened in November 1937 as South Plains Airport. It was assigned to the World War 2 Army Air Forces Flying Training Command in 1942, then renamed South Plains Army Airfield and entirely converted to a military training airfield. ‍ The conversion process added three concrete runways, taxiways, a large apron, a control tower, and many large hangars made of semi-permanent materials, as they were intended for short-term usage. ‍  The base was activated that same year and remained in use by the military as a storage facility for two years after the war.  ‍ The end of 1947 marked its return to the government for civil use, and they built a passenger terminal around the southwest corner of the airfield that was actively used during the 50s and 60s. ‍ The passenger terminal was replaced by a bigger one in 1976, which is still in use today, albeit heavily upgraded over the years, with the latest one dating back to 2021. ‍ ‍ American Airlines, American Eagle, Southwest Airlines, and United Express currently serve it. Dallas Love Field is the busiest destination, with 168,000 passengers yearly, followed by Dallas-Fort Worth (147,000) and Denver (52,000). ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and high-detail models of the buildings, objects, and surroundings. ‍  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.24, requiring at least 3.84 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfl710</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker 70/100 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfl710"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aafd0d6258942e8a3fe157_fukker.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published a new development update reporting their progress on the Fokker 70/100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, focusing on sound recordings. ‍ The developers claim that one of the most difficult aspects of aircraft development for a simulator is getting access to a real aircraft for sound recording. While it’s relatively easier to access older aircraft in museums for recording switches, knobs, doors, and so on, engine sounds can’t be recorded as they are generally no longer functional, making that part rather challenging. ‍ They managed to get access to three real Fokkers during a maintenance run-up in The Netherlands, recording high-quality audio from the turbine from RR Tay 620s and 650s (Fokker 70’s engines and 100, respectively), from low to full power band.  ‍ ‍ To read more about the recording session, click here for the full development update.  ‍ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgrio</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Releases Rio Branco International Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgrio"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ad9ad07954411000e5657e_riobranco.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently released an upgraded rendition of their Rio Branco International Airport (SBRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Rio Branco, Acre, Brazil, with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers. ‍ It was inaugurated 24 years ago, replacing Rio Branco’s previous main airport, whose area was not government-owned and judicially given back to its rightful owner, meaning they had to start from scratch on another piece of land.  ‍ It was expanded for the first time in 2014, bringing the passenger handling capabilities up to 2,4 million passengers yearly. ‍ Azul, GOL, and LATAM serve it regularly with flights to their hubs. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside, custom ground clutter, custom ground service equipment, and more. ‍ ‍ ‍ It’s available in their store for roughly $6. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbskan</id>
    <title>DarkBlueScenery Releases Kansai International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12 </title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbskan"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ada099d5b1da0944054bc6_kansai.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DarkBlueScenery has recently released their rendition of Kansai International Airport (RJBB) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the Greater Osaka Area with a yearly average of 28 million passengers, making it the 3rd busiest in Japan. ‍ It opened in 1994 and was built to relieve overcrowding at Itami Airport, Osaka’s former main airport, with two large terminals designed by Renzo Piano. It’s the longest terminal in the world, with a length of 1.7km. ‍ Construction work started in 1987, and they had to build an artificial island with a sea wall, drainage system, and bridge to connect with the city. It eventually became the most expensive civil project in modern history, with a 15 billion dollar investment. The “growing pains” of creating an earthquake-proof artificial island paved the way for the New Kitakyushu Airport, Kobe Airport, Chubu Centrair International Airport, and even Hong Kong International Airport.  ‍ ‍ Its earthquake-proofness was tested just a year after its inauguration when Japan was struck by the Great Hanshin earthquake, whose epicenter was only 20 km from the airport. Yet, it didn’t sustain any damage at all. Four years later, its design was proven again when it survived a typhoon.  ‍ ‍ The fact it sits on an artificial piece of land has its downsides, though, with the total costs rising to 20 billion in the mid-2000s with all the maintenance work to stop it from sinking, which the engineers had predicted and expected. ‍ ‍ A new terminal building was inaugurated in 2012, further increasing its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ It’s a hub for All Nippon Airways, FedEx Express, Japan Airlines, Jetstar Japan, Nippon Cargo Airlines, and Peach Aviation. It’s served by many airlines from the neighboring countries and a few popular carriers from Europe, such as Air France, KLM, and Lufthansa. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K textures, custom ground markings, custom taxiway signs, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, accurate terraforming, and an accurately represented runway 06R/24L at its current status. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.41, requiring at least 808.75 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/330024</id>
    <title>Aerosoft’s Airbus A330 Shifted to MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/330024"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65aee96a5efaf1c7b2c4c0de_aerosoftdelay.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has published their first A330 development update for 2024, stating their decision to shift the development effort to the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, allowing them to “greatly expand the focus of the project.” ‍ Announced three years ago, in January 2021, their A330 project won’t be coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, as they have decided to focus on the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 instead. Aerosoft will include multiple engine options, including a simultaneous release of the Neo and Ceo variants.  Mathijs Kok, Aerosoft’s former project manager, has made a statement in the Aerosoft forums, saying it’s a “puzzling statement” and a “surprising twist,” given they had recently tuned and tweaked the engine simulation and the new simulator might render all that work useless, leading to a full rework, and, potentially, further delays. “As there is no known release date of FS2024 and nobody knows how much adaptation will be needed, you end up with a project with no scheduled release date”, he completed.  ‍ Their decision to release for MSFS 2024 leads to many questions because little is known about the sim’s innards, how the backward compatibility will work, and how much it could further complicate the development process.  There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxf11</id>
    <title>Flying Fries to Release Hughes XF-11</title>
    <updated>2024-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxf11"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b045192e008a06b9168b2f_07.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Developer Flying Fries who you may know for the freeware “Scrapyard Monster” that was released in early 2023 has plans to release a payware version of the Hughes XF-11 Mk I. With development already charging ahead the project has an anticipated release date within Q1 of 2024. The Hughes XF-11 was an aerial reconnaissance aircraft designed for the US Army Air Force. It is based on a highly modified version of a plane designed by Hughes as a private venture. Taking inspiration from the P-38 Lightening the XF-11 features 2 huge Pratt &amp; Whitney Wasp engines paired with 8 bladed contrarotating propellers by Hamilton. The XF-11 had a reported top speed of 390 knots at 33000 feet and a maximum altitude of 42000 feet. The XF-11 will feature a highly detailed interior and exterior model with 4k textures, an era-correct autopilot as well as the option to use a Garmin GNS 530 or GTN 750. Pilots looking for a more challenging experience will have the option to enable random failures with configurable severity. Flying Fries has stated that the hope is to have the aircraft released in February but there hasn’t been any information about a price for the plane. You can check out Flying Fries’ other works on their website here. Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for all the flight sim news that matters to you!  ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwsday</id>
    <title>Realworld Scenery Releases Dayton International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwsday"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b2ea03aa3931a6f1438c41_dayton.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Realworld Scenery has recently released their rendition of Dayton International Airport (KDAY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Dayton, Ohio, with a yearly average of 580,000 passengers. ‍ ‍ It opened in 1936 as Dayton Municipal Airport, with three 1,100-meter concrete runways and connecting taxiways. Further development was only to happen in 1959 when a new $5.5 million terminal designed by Yount, Sullivan, and Lecklider went under construction.  ‍ The terminal was renovated for the first time in 1989, designed by Levin Porter Associates and costing around the ballpark of $50 million. Further renovation happened a decade later, coming at $25 million and reaching completion in 2002. ‍ ‍ American Air, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, and United Express serve it. Atlanta, Chicago O’hare, and Charlotte are the busiest destinations, with 122,960 passengers, 103,320, and 72,390, respectively. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, a custom-designed starting hangar for general aviation, high-resolution ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.03, requiring at least 1.92 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bb757j</id>
    <title>BlueBird 757 January update </title>
    <updated>2024-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bb757j"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b2ee8317a65ef1bfbb8781_4.PNG"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BlueBird Simulations have released another comprehensive video about the development progress of their 757 which is in development for Microsoft Flight Sim. The video features many members of the development team giving a run down on what they have been working on along with the project manager Shervin giving a detailed update on progress, what has been done and what is to come.  ‍ An update on 2024 and what is to come The update video begins by explaining that last year lead programmer Eric retired from flight sim dev work, shortly after Shervin brought 3 new programmers on board who have spent the last 5 months rebuilding the 757 to make it a full study-level aircraft, departing from the original plan of making it a mid-level aircraft. Shervin has informed us that they are optimistic for 2024 and have gone into some detail about what this means, although no promises can be made for a 2024 release the team is positive about the progress being made and overall excited for what the coming year holds.  ‍ The all-important sounds The second big announcement of this in-depth update is the welcome news that Boris from Boris Audioworks has joined BlueBird to develop the sounds for the 757! As those of you who have used Boris’ sound packs for MSFS over the years will know, this is a very welcome announcement! The sound of the 757 is gorgeous and thanks to Boris we will be able to enjoy those beautiful 757 and RB211/ Pratt and whitney sounds in stunning detail.  ‍ Jacks update The video continues with a brief segment featuring one of the lead programmers, Jack. He gives us a rundown of the work that has been going on behind the scenes with the FMC, IRS and Weather radar system.  ‍ ‍ Dave’s Update In the next part of this nearly 30-minute update video, we hear from another programmer, Dave. Dave gives a run down of what he has been working on over the last few months. Dave gives us a detailed run-through of the IRS system and the CDU. He also gives us some teasers of the beautiful 3D works he has been masterfully working on.  ‍ ‍ Hooman’s update Hooman joined the BlueBird team a few months ago as an Aircraft system software developer. In his detailed portion of the video, he gives us a rundown of the work behind the scenes in developing the various systems of the 757 and their logic. Using system schematics Hooman has painstakingly gone through the process of making the systems as realistic as possible and in this section he shows us briefly how he does it! We get a rundown of the electrical system and how he converts schematics into code using what can only be assumed is some sort of wizardry.  ‍ Romain's update:  Real-world airline pilot Romain has been hard at work over the last few months helping to develop and tune the Pratt and Whitney engines along with finalising the final versions of the RB211s. The current engine work is set on refining fuel flow and drag parameters. Romain also is actively working on the flight model, as he has been over the last 2 years.  ‍ Conclusion Toward the end of this video update, we are shown an abbreviated scope of work for the upcoming 757. It is also confirmed in this section that BlueBird is partnering with Navigraph to bring a realistic and highly functional EFB to the aircraft. We are also shown a brief preview of the BlueBird 767 virtual cockpit! The 767 is being developed separately from the 757 but one thing is certain, it will share its level of detail!  ‍ You can watch the full video update here: </summary>
    <published>2024-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcbrev</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Swindled by Partner and Selling Itself to Another Company</title>
    <updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcbrev"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b44ed1636980b359de61f9_FqPdY6maIAAbGSf.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In an announcement made both on their support Discord server and Facebook Page, Honeycomb Aeronautical CEO Nicki Repenning provides a lengthy update on the state of the company, and alleges how he, and by extension, the entire customer base who had pre-ordered products were taken advantage of by Honeycomb’s parent company, and now ex-business partner, whom is yet to be named. ‍ He starts out by apologizing for the extended delay in communication, saying that “I’m not trying to make any excuses or deny my responsibility for what happened,” and that he should have “acted sooner,” and he “[has] no one but myself to blame for that.” ‍ Continuing, he starts off with the story on how Honeycomb was founded as a business idea in 2012, and he was going to use his experience with Saitek, and take advantage of the gap between low-end and very-high-end products, and provide high-quality products at a decent price point. In 2016, he found a partner to start Honeycomb with, who he was good friends with, and was head of a company that was selling various video game accessories already in the United States, an accomplishment that Repenning helped with. Repenniing had agreed that his partner would run the financial side of the business, as well as use the company and connections his partner had in the manufacturing industry in Asia based in Hong Kong to manage the manufacturing. Repenning was to provide the designs and his partner was able to convert those designs into something that could be mass produced. Additionally, they agreed that his partner’s companies would handle the distribution. ‍ He alleges that during the time the Alpha Flight Controls were being developed, his partner kept pushing off finalizing their shareholder agreement, but when the company was finally established, Repeninng discovered that he had no shares or ownership in Honeycomb. After confronting his partner about this, his partner explained that this was a requirement for the loans. Repenning goes on to allege that to this day, no agreement has been signed.During Honeycomb’s first two years of operation, Repenning was concerned mostly with product development, and did not suspect anything wrong. However, by mid-2022, Honeycomb and his partner’s company wasn’t doing so well, so he looked at the finances in more detail. Repenning alleges that, “every invoice and purchase order, one by one, I discovered that the service fees added to the factory cost (for the services provided in Hong Kong) were significantly higher than what we had agreed,” and “the sales prices on the invoices to my partner’s distribution companies were lower than agreed.” He confronted his partner about this, but the partner just passed it off as “just an accounting error” and it would be fixed. Most shocking of all, he alleges that the money from Charlie Pedal pre-orders did not go to the manufacturing, and had “gone elsewhere.” He then flew to Hong Kong “to meet with the factory and my now soon-to-be ex-partner to find out what was really going on.” He was able to negotiate a deal between the manufacturer, his “soon to be ex-business partner,” and “where my partner and his companies would no longer handle sales and distribution and I would also handle the factory partner directly. As part of the agreement, I was committing to help the factory recover the outstanding invoices by paying a significant premium on the existing stock as well as on the Charlie production. In exchange, the factory agreed to manufacture the Charlie, despite the outstanding debt, but I had to pay for the injection tooling as well as a 50% deposit of the production cost upfront.”  ‍ Repenning elaborates that “since it is highly unlikely that I will receive the payments for the pre-orders from my ex-partner, I am currently working on several finance deals to be able to start production as soon as possible.”  ‍ He continues on with giving us an update on the state of Honeycomb currently, saying that its online storefront, run through Shopify, has been closed and is no longer accepting refunds, so the only way to get money back is through a bank or credit card company. According to Repenning, this is also the state of RMA’s, due to being controlled by his business partner, which wholly owns the Honeycomb company based in Hong Kong, they have been unable to ship return labels. Repenning goes on to mention that “The one good news is that we have reached an agreement, that he will sell his assets in Honeycomb if I can find a new partner to buy him out,”  and he is in talks with other potential buyers that will help continue the Honeycomb product lines.  ‍ He also writes a heartfelt thank you to his tech and support staff, despite being caught up in this situation and being without payment, “have stayed with me.”  ‍ To conclude his statement, he apologizes for the lack of communication, and thanks everyone for their patience. ‍ You can read the full text of his update on Honeycomb’s Facebook page here. ‍ Threshold will be following this story as it unfolds, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msxpir</id>
    <title>MisterX's Hakodate Airport Scenery Pirated</title>
    <updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msxpir"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b4ffca7269cdcd348b6756_2024-01-27%2014_05_48-RJCH_Comparison_2.jpg%20-%20IrfanView.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In the never-sleeping world of flight simulation, the release of new airport scenery is always a moment of excitement for the avid simmer. This was the case with the recent introduction of Hakodate Airport (RJCH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, developed by AC Scenery. This addition promised an immersive experience for pilots flying to the island of Hokkaido in Japan, featuring custom ground textures, night lighting, and photorealistic details. However, this initial excitement was soon overshadowed by allegations of copyright infringement, casting a dark shadow over the integrity of this release and its developer. The controversy surfaced when MisterX (also known as ShortFinal Design), a highly esteemed developer in the flight simulation community, raised serious allegations about the newly released scenery. MisterX has been a known name in the X-Plane scenery world for many years and he is known for popular sceneries such as his renditions of San Diego International Airport (KSAN), San Francisco International Airport (KFSO) and City, Los Angeles International Airport (KLAX) and many more.  In a discussion in our Discord, MisterX stated, “That scenery is a blatant rip-off of my X-Plane freeware.” These claims were further supported by comparisons between MisterX's original work and the AC Scenery product, revealing striking similarities in models and textures. ‍ Because of these allegations, we immediately removed the article promoting the Hakodate Airport scenery from our editorial—pending further investigation. Sadly, this incident is not an isolated case in our world of flight simulation. Copyright infringement, unfortunately, has been a recurring issue, affecting both developers and the community. In the past, there have been several instances where assets from established developers have been used without consent, leading to legal battles and community uproar. These cases range from minor texture copying to complete model theft, impacting both freeware and commercial products. The implications of such actions are profound, discouraging developers from investing time and effort into creating new content and potentially stifling innovation in the community. The scenery has since been taken down from Simmarket, where it was available at the time when MisterX contacted Threshold.</summary>
    <published>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777cok</id>
    <title>PMDG Previews 777's Flight Deck for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777cok"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b5c06d89a825451fb8d74e_777cock.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published a new development update in their forum featuring work-in-progress flight deck previews of their upcoming Boeing 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Randazzo begins with a promise: they will try to be more transparent with their development process, showing stuff behind the scenes, like their recent trip to compare their 777 with the real 777. He emphasizes they have never done it before but have been considering it since Mathijs Kok joined the team and advocated for more sharing.  The beta process is ongoing, and they have been focusing on killing conflicts between their C++ code and Microsoft Flight Simulator’s Clang compiler, aiming for high stability. With the release window potentially getting closer, they have been working on preview images and video, which will roll out gradually. PMDG is feeling very good about the project and is looking for a suitable release timeline, which will be communicated beforehand.  ‍ Their new preview showcases parts of the cockpit that make their 3D modeler happy, details that were impossible with the previous platforms. They think it’s the finest 777 simulation yet created outside and even inside the enterprise environment, with more to come on that later. ‍ “We are absolutely certain she will meet even the highest expectations for 777 lovers and 777 interested simmers alike”, concludes Randazzo.  ‍ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orybcg</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Gold Coast Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orybcg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65a6f8a807177ff354b795a4_ybcg1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Gold Coast Airport (YBCG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Gold Coast and Tweed Heads, Australia, with a yearly average of 6.4 million passengers, making it the 7th busiest airport in the country. ‍  It was built in 1936, consisting of three grass strips whose sole intent was to provide an emergency landing spot for aircraft flying between Brisbane and Sydney, with passenger service only beginning three years later. Regular service was only to begin after WW2, with Queensland Airlines and Butler Air Transport, followed by Ansett in 1950 and Trans Australia Airlines in 1954. ‍  Taxiways and runways were fully paved by 1958, allowing for the operation of larger, heavier aircraft such as the DC-9 and L-188 Electra. ‍  The current passenger terminal was opened in 1981 by Acting Prime Minister Douglas Anthony. The following year saw the main runway extended to 2,042 meters, allowing for the operation of wide-body jet aircraft. It was later extended to 2,500 meters sometime in 2007. ‍ The passenger terminal was upgraded in 2010, with an expansion that doubled its total size, accommodating a decade's worth of growth in passenger volume. It was then expanded again in 2016, 2019, and 2022, with a 30,000-square-meter expansion and overall infrastructure modernization.  ‍ It's a hub for Bonza. AirAsia X, Air New Zealand, Eastern Air Services, Jetstar, Qantas, QantasLink, Rex Airlines, Seair Pacific, and Virgin Australia serve it regularly. ‍  Developed by Matteo Veneziani, the scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, 4K textures, an interior on the main terminal, unique GSE vehicles, dynamic airport lighting, custom ground textures, custom animated jetways, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍  It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.20, requiring at least 4.70 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
