<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-11-05T18:36:11.635431+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx2656</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx2656"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f14fa969afcc22cfd797fa_a319_a321_3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations recently updated their A320 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, addressing various issues and improving overall stability. Update v2.4.0.2656 addresses an issue where the thrust lever null zone would not save with uncalibrated thrust levers, fixes the elevators and ailerons not drooping fully down when unpowered, mitigates a potential CPDLC handover crash, among other things. The complete changelog follows below: 2.4.0.2656  Avionics and Systems EFB Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (full bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blcbundbon</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Beechcraft Baron &amp; Bonanza Bundle for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blcbundbon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69025efe10a5a0a6dfa70b45_bundle1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has recently released an aircraft bundle with the Beechcraft Baron and Bonanza for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Unlike their earlier steam gauge overhaul add-ons, this bundle features its own 3D models and custom sounds.  The bundle brings one of the most technically advanced simulations for Microsoft Flight Simulator (according to the developer), with an intricate reciprocating engine simulation, over a hundred possible failures, 12 hot-swappable radio configurations, and a custom turbocharger, pressurization, and cabin temperature simulation.  Furthermore, Black Square’s new Electronic Flight Bag allows you to configure the aircraft, manage payload and failures, monitor engines, electric schematics, and more. On top of that, the custom failure system features persistent wear, MTBF, and scheduled failures for nearly every component in the aircraft, and the tridimensional gauges are subject to the laws of physics, meaning they can become stuck and require tapping on the glass to become unstuck again. In the navigation department, there are multiple navigation suites to choose from, ranging from various eras of both planes’ long history: from a humble no-GPS Bendix-King RNAV system to a modern Garmin GTN 650/750 (PMS or TDS), a slightly humbler GNS 530/430 combo, or the classic KLN 90-B. It also features the KFC 150 autopilot, the RDR1150XL weather radar, and more. The Beechcraft Baron set includes three distinct airframes: the normally aspirated B58, the B58TC, and the B58P. The latter is from the early 2000s, and the former two are from the 1980s. It also accompanies six different interiors and nine different liveries. On the other hand, the Bonanza set also includes three variations: the A36, the A36TC with an aftermarket turbo-normalising package, and the B36TP turboprop conversion. Similarly, it also sports six interiors and nine liveries. Overall, the package includes an entirely custom exterior model, a custom sound pack from Boris Audio Works, higher-quality materials, fine-tuned performance tables, more avionics options, and much more. The bundle is available on the Just Flight store for roughly $64.99, requiring at least 3.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carb390</id>
    <title>Carenado Teases B390 IA for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carb390"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6902655801dc90c1d37b973b_beec.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado has recently teased the development and imminent release of a B390 IA rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a light business jet designed and manufactured by Beechcraft. ‍ The Beechcraft B-390 Premier IA was an updated version of the Premier 1, which was designed in the mid-90s, first flown in 1998, and certified in 2001. The IA was like a real-life patch to fix some lingering issues with the project, such as the subpar brakes, noisy cabin, and cockpit, which many deemed below par. Said upgrade rolled out in 2006, and over 163 new Premiers were built in five years. ‍ The little jet is powered by two Williams FJ44-2A Turbofan engines. It cruises at 841 km/h, has a range of 950 miles, a service ceiling of 41,000 feet, and, depending on the configuration, can carry 6 to 7 passengers. ‍ There’s no information regarding pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vasexp</id>
    <title>VA Systems Launches "The Explorer," an App Designed to Search Real-World Flights</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vasexp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6903c4b92bbc7ec47a9e06ad_Skjermbilde%202025-10-30%20205526.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. VA Systems has just launched a new web app named “The Explorer.” This app is designed to search real-world airline schedules and, with one click, dispatch them directly with SimBrief. According to VA Systems, The Explorer provides users with quick access to their entire airline schedule database. Users can filter flights by departure and arrival airports, airline, aircraft type, time of day, and duration. These filters can be combined for more precise results. Once a flight is found, it can be sent directly to the user's SimBrief account for dispatching. Additionally, support for custom airframes from the user's SimBrief account is coming soon. The Explorer utilises a user-based pricing model, meaning a subscription is not necessary. Instead, users pay using a system of “Credits” by purchasing various credit packs. One credit is equivalent to one row of results returned. Users can set a limit on the number of results to control their spending. Accessing the Schedule view costs 20 credits. Saved searches, or “cached” searches, remain available for one hour, while schedules are stored for 24 hours. This allows users to view the same items multiple times within the time frame without incurring additional charges. ‍ Credits can be purchased in packs, with the following pricing structure: ‍ ‍ VA Systems estimates that 1,000 credits will last for 1-2 months. ‍ For more information about The Explorer, check out VA System’s website ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwumctm</id>
    <title>WinWing Announces URSA MINOR Combat Throttle Metal</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwumctm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6903cd8894914d995304c217_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. After recently opening pre-orders for its URSA MINOR 32 Throttle Metal, WinWing has just announced an all-new throttle quadrant, the URSA MINOR Combat Throttle Metal. Although information about the upcoming throttle quadrant is sparse, the team has shared some details, including the pricing. The throttle quadrant will include hall sensors and is described as having an "uncompromising performance core." Although not much additional information has been released, it is positioned as an entry-level option. The price for the throttle quadrant is set at $154.95. We will keep you informed as soon as the team provides any new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozaab6mtq</id>
    <title>MOZA Launches New AB6 FFB Flight Base and MTQ Throttle Quadrant</title>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozaab6mtq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6903d049f77942ead3d5e6e9_Skjermbilde%202025-10-30%20214803.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. MOZA has just updated its product line, featuring the new AB6 Force-Feedback Base and MTQ Throttle Quadrant. ‍ The AB6 FFB Base is being launched paired with the MHG Flightstick and a desk mount. The AB6 is a smaller and more affordable version of the AB9. MOZA claims that the AB6 accurately transmits all control forces, ranging from a gentle touch for trim adjustments to strong feedback during a stall buffet, delivering 6NM of direct drive torque. The MHG Flightstick features a fighter-inspired design, over 25 mappable inputs, and an integrated Hall-effect rudder axis. Additionally, it includes a two-stage trigger and hat switches. The MOZA AB6 FFB Flight Base is priced at $399 ‍ The MOZA MTQ Throttle Quadrant aims to combine military flying and civil aviation in one unit. Featuring easily interchangeable throttle handles, with users being able to switch between fighters, Boeing airliners and Airbus airliners. The MTQ Throttle Quadrant includes 10 programmable buttons, 3 rotary knobs, 3 toggle switches, and a dedicated landing gear lever. ‍ Fighter-style handles are included, with the TQA Throttle Module (Airbus) and the TQB Module (Boeing) being sold separately. The MOZA MTQ Throttle Quadrant is available for $199, and additional Throttle Modules can be purchased for $39 each. ‍ For more information about MOZA’s new offerings, check out their website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgpoa24</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Upcoming Porto Alegre Airport Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgpoa24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6904de3bb2a49e9f6a278fa7_alegre1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Brazil Land Games has recently previewed their work on updating their rendition of Porto Alegre Salgado Filho International Airport (SBPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024. It is the ninth busiest airport in the country, with nearly 8 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic). Originally called São João Federal Airport, it was just an air club, with its first flights dating back to 1923. It saw commercial action for the first time in 1932, when VARIG (the oldest Brazilian airline) replaced their seaplanes with land airplanes, adopting Porto Alegre as their hub. It took eight years to commission an actual passenger terminal. Its current name was adopted in 1952, after Joaquim Pedro Salgado Filho, a local politician who had died a year prior (air crash). It’s a focus city for Azul Brazilian Airlines, with a significant domestic network (fifteen destinations) and international legs to Punta del Este and Montevideo (Uruguay). The other two Brazilian giants, GOL Linhas Aéreas (thirteen domestic destinations) and LATAM Brasil (5 domestic destinations), are also regularly seen around POA. TAP Air Portugal is the sole European visitor, coming from Lisbon. Not much was said besides the pictures themselves and the fact that it’s still undergoing development. Threshold will keep you updated! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carb390pre</id>
    <title>Carenado Previews Upcoming B390 1A for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carb390pre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6902655801dc90c1d37b973b_beec.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Carenado recently shared further previews of their upcoming Beechcraft B-390 Premier 1A for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which is said to be “on final approach” and “ coming soon.” The new previews show more of the externals, one shot of the flight deck, and a shot of the cabin.  The Beechcraft B-390 Premier IA was an updated version of the Premier 1, which was designed in the mid-90s, first flown in 1998, and certified in 2001. The IA was almost like a real-life patch to fix some lingering issues with the project, such as the subpar brakes, the noisy cabin, and the cockpit, which was deemed below par by many. The aforementioned upgrade rolled out in 2006, and over 163 new Premiers were built in five years. The little jet is powered by two Williams FJ44-2A Turbofan engines. It cruises at 841 km/h, has a range of 950 miles, a service ceiling of 41,000 feet, and, depending on the configuration, can carry 6 to 7 passengers. ‍ There’s no information regarding pricing or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jsrafs</id>
    <title>JATSim Designs Releases Rand Airport for MSFS 2020/MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jsrafs"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69055404f1087bae1f721fc4_367589_FAGM-16.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. JATSim Designs has recently released its rendition of Rand Airport (FAGM) for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing one of South Africa’s most historic airfields to the simulator. Located in Germiston, near Johannesburg, Rand Airport first opened in 1931, and quickly became one of the most advanced facilities in the Southern Hemisphere. It served as the region’s main international gateway, and operated as a hub for Imperial Airways, later South African Airways. During the Second World War, the airport played a crucial role in supporting military operations and training. With the opening of Jan Smuts Airport (now OR Tambo International) in 1952, Rand transitioned to a general aviation field. Today, it remains active as a centre for flight training, maintenance, and airshows, retaining much of its heritage and historical infrastructure. The scenery is available on simMarket for $14,50, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmenev</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Previews Harstad/Narvik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmenev"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69078862027ea8c130f37701_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently provided a sneak peek of its upcoming scenery for Harstad/Narvik Airport in Microsoft Flight Simulator. While details are still limited, the team has showcased the Harstad Flyklubb hangar and emphasised that every aspect has been meticulously recreated to match the real-life hangar. Although there is limited information about the release date, price, or features, the team announced that more previews will be available soon. We will keep you updated as soon as more information is released. Finally, although it wasn't mentioned in the original Facebook post, the team shared at the end of the previews in their Discord server that Stavanger Airport (ENZV) is also in development. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcfeoc</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Updates Free E-Jets for X-Plane 11/12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcfeoc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6907a67a7b1842713b5b06e6_FREE-EMBRAER-E-JET-E175-E195-FOR-X-PLANE-DOWNLOAD-AIRPLANE-01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Developer X-Crafts has recently released an update for its freeware versions of  Embraer E175 and E195 for X-Plane, introducing a new weather radar, visual refinements, and full compatibility with X-Plane 12.3. The update continues the developer’s support for its freeware range, which has seen over 50,000 downloads to date. The key feature in this release is the weather radar, available exclusively in X-Plane 12.3. Other updates include improved navigation map visuals and behaviour, fixes to display transparency, and general MFD performance improvements. Two versions of the aircraft are available: v3.1 for X-Plane 12 and v2.5 for X-Plane 11. Both are compatible with all major operating systems, though Mac users must run X-Plane in Rosetta mode to ensure full plugin functionality. The Free E-Jets package includes several features typically reserved for payware aircraft, such as a Ground Operations Menu, Load Planner for weight and balance, and on-screen checklists.  A step-by-step demonstration flight video is also available, designed to help users familiarise themselves with the aircraft in under an hour. The Freeware E-Jets are simplified versions, relying mostly on default X-Plane systems. These aircraft were originally part of X-Crafts’ payware lineup, but were later released for free, following the launch of the E-Jets v2 series.  While the freeware models still offer an enjoyable experience, they differ from the payware E-Jets in fidelity. The Free E175 and E195 v3.1.0 are available now via X-Crafts’ website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sofbrs</id>
    <title>SoFly’s Bristol Airport Releasing on Friday</title>
    <updated>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sofbrs"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690a1568a698ab902b58902d_sofly-bristol-airport-eggd-msfs2024-01.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SoFly recently announced the development and imminent release of Bristol Airport (EGGD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which will land on the virtual shelves on Friday (07/11).  Built on top of a former RAF airfield, Bristol Airport was inaugurated in 1957, replacing Bristol’s former main municipal airport (Whitchurch).  In 1958, a 200,000-pound passenger terminal was built, part of the administration’s effort to make it the city’s de facto airport. Four years later, a new control tower was built. In 1969, the runway underwent its first expansion, and the terminal was extended to handle the predicted figures for the 1970s and beyond. In the early 1980s, despite being served by 17 charter airlines, the airport was operating at a loss until Les Wilson took over as managing director and completely turned the tide. He held this position until his tragic passing in a car accident in 1995.  The mid-1980s slight recovery from the crisis allowed the administration to expend an extra dime or two on the construction of a new international departure lounge. Four years later, a new concourse area was opened, and planning for a new terminal kicked into action, leading to its eventual approval in 1994. Work started in 1997, shortly after FirstBus Group bought a 51% stake in the airport, heavily investing in its new infrastructure. The terminal, which cost 27 million pounds, was ready by 2000.  Passenger numbers reached the two million mark for the first time that year. A year later, the airport was purchased by a joint venture for 198 million pounds, and 50% of it was sold again in 2006. In 2015, the terminal was expanded again with a larger departure lounge and an outdoor terrace, followed by a new terminal extension adding 9,000 square meters. The project reached completion in 2017. It’s a focus city for easyJet, Jet2, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. Aer Lingus, Aurigny, Blue Islands, Edelweiss Air, KLM, Loganair, Pegasus Airlines, and Sun Express also serve it. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life elevation data, full GSX integration with animated doors, a dynamic airport environment, PBR texturing, dynamic seasons, and performance-friendly optimization. There’s no information on the pricing yet, but the scenery is set to release on Friday.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/twddoh</id>
    <title>Tuwaiq Designs Releases Hamad International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/twddoh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b49ce30d3407ce90fc65d_367846_Screenshot_2025-10-16_161906.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Tuwaiq Designs has released Doha Hamad International Airport (OTHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, marking the latest addition to the developer’s ongoing Qatar Project series. Opened in 2014, Hamad International replaced the old Doha International Airport and quickly became Qatar’s main aviation hub. It now serves as the home base of Qatar Airways, and is widely regarded as one of the most luxurious and architecturally impressive airports in the world.  In the years leading up to the FIFA World Cup 2022, the airport underwent a major expansion, adding new lounges, additional gates, and an enlarged terminal area, to accommodate growing passenger traffic. Tuwaiq Designs’ recreation of Hamad International aims to capture the airport’s scale and sophistication. The scenery includes accurate terminal models, with fully modelled interiors.  Furthermore, the scenery features PBR textures and custom ground surfaces, realistic lighting, reflections, and wear effects across runways and aprons.  Performance has also been carefully tuned with optimised LOD models, balancing frame rates and visual quality. Here’s the feature list: Tuwaiq Designs’ Hamad International Airport (OTHH) is now available on simMarket for $31.59, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsslhm</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Saint Lucia Hewanorra International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsslhm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b505a161b228f735b1bff_368086_Screenshot_2211%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TropicalSim has added another Caribbean destination to its Microsoft Flight Simulator lineup, releasing Saint Lucia Hewanorra International Airport (TLPL) for both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Hewanorra International Airport is the larger of Saint Lucia’s two airports, situated near Vieux Fort, on the southern end of the island, around 33 miles from the capital.  It is the main international gateway to the island, receiving traffic from airlines such as Air Canada Rouge, American Airlines, British Airways, Delta Air Lines, JetBlue, United Airlines, and WestJet, connecting the island to North America and Europe. TropicalSim’s scenery aims to closely mirror the real airport, featuring a newly modelled terminal, detailed interiors, and ultra-high-definition PBR texturing across the main structures and ground polygons.  The developer has also included native MSFS dynamic night lighting. The airport is designed to integrate seamlessly with the default simulator scenery. The scenery is available now on SimMarket for $20.96, including taxes. FEATURES For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cs76co</id>
    <title>CowanSim Updates S-76C++ for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cs76co"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b5d5eddab362deb9006c3_572814144_1421247343334345_8566726297088210018_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Cowan Simulations has released a significant update for its Sikorsky S-76C++ helicopter for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, now live on the Microsoft Marketplace. The update introduces enhancements to the helicopter’s autopilot, stability, and EFIS systems, with a focus on improved handling and more realistic system behaviour. SAS stabilisation has been refined, force trim and ATT modes are more accurate, and autopilot transitions should be smoother. Below 60 knots, ATT mode now holds bank for improved hover performance, while a cyclic trim failure will correctly revert to SAS mode as a failsafe. Furthermore, AFCS indicators now show actuator position, waypoint readouts are more accurate, and fail flags have been added across several displays. The engine governor has been retuned for better throttle stability, and OEI performance limits have been updated to reflect real-world behaviour. Additional tweaks include improved yaw control, better ILS tracking, enhanced VR eyepoint accuracy, and fixes to float physics and radar alt behaviour. For the full changelog, visit the CowanSim Discord. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tpmfox</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Aeronautical Releases Sierra TPM Module and Foxtrot Aviation Stick </title>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tpmfox"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/690b89ee6d2057b38c4ce87d_last%20ned.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Honeycomb Aeronautical has just launched two new peripherals: the Sierra TPM Module and Foxtrot Aviation Stick.  Both products are now available worldwide, and slot into the brand’s existing Alpha, Bravo, and Charlie ecosystems. The Sierra TPM Module is designed for general aviation flying. It features three metal, vernier-style throttle, propeller, and mixture controls with fine adjustment, a low-profile trim wheel, a parking brake, a flap lever, and a landing gear lever, all accompanied by LED status indicators. The unit is designed to replicate real GA panels and integrates seamlessly with other Honeycomb hardware. The Foxtrot Aviation Stick is suitable for various types, including Airbus, aerobatic aircraft, and helicopters. It utilises an advanced gimbal mechanism, with 16-bit Hall Effect sensors for precise input, and offers adjustable linear resistance. without a centre detent, and includes a twist axis for rudder control. The grip is ambidextrous, featuring multiple programmable buttons, rocker switches, and a POV hat, along with an integrated switch panel, for starters, radios, and autopilot. Honeycomb says the new hardware is intended to give simmers more specialised controls, particularly for GA flying, while keeping the build quality consistent with its existing lineup. For more information, visit the respective Launch 2025 pages.  Both products are available worldwide, with the Foxtrot Aviation Stick priced at $149.99 and the Sierra TPM Module at $249.99, through Honeycomb’s official webshop. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
