<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-03-23T18:22:45.408453+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/faddha</id>
    <title>Final Approach Design Simulation Releases Dhaka Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/faddha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640e37356c311e2a8248b461_dhaka1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1359685"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Final Approach Design Simulation has recently released their rendition of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (VGHS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Dhaka City, the Capital of Bangladesh.   The airport was initially inaugurated in the early 1980s as Dacca International Airport, then re-inaugurated three years later as Zia International Airport. It was built with consultancy help from Aéroports de Paris, the group behind Charles de Gaulle, Orly, and Le Bourget. The terminal area saw its first expansion work in 1992, with the addition of boarding bridges and equipment and a multi-story car parking for over 500 vehicles. Further upgrades came 20 years later down the line, with the addition of ILS, distance measuring equipment, and two new boarding bridges. The latest upgrade involved the interiors, with several improvements to the main concourse and toilets.  With four terminals, two for international flights, one for domestic operations, and one for VIP personnel, Dhaka Airport handles an average of 6 million passengers annually. A fifth terminal, Terminal 3, is under construction and said to complete in 2024, with 26 boarding bridges, 12 conveyor belts, and 115 check-in counters.  It’s the main hub for Biman Bangladesh Airlines, offering 29 destinations both domestically and internationally. Regent Airways, Novoair, US-Bangla Airlines, Sky Air, and EasyFly Express also use Dhaka as their hub. It’s visited by 31 international airlines, including Air Arabia, Air India, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Qatar Airways, and Singapore Airlines.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly detailed ground poly, 4K PBR textures for ground and 3D buildings, high-detail 3D buildings, static vehicles, ground service equipment, animated jetways, custom ILS, terminal interior, custom dynamic lighting, realistic night textures, AI traffic support, updated taxi layout with two new taxiways, LOD optimization for performance, custom volumetric 3D grass, and realistic tree vegetation.  It’s available on SimMarket and iniBuilds Store for roughly $23.28/22.85, respectively, requiring at least 1.83 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nmm777</id>
    <title>NMM: Stratosphere Studios 777-300ER/ERF</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nmm777" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640e422b4e36b905b5cc81c1_777_icon11.png.55cbbee9a0f2fd05f8e1bf55f6605403.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="279629"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Stratosphere studios 777-300 for XP12 is the latest aircraft to feature in our no-money Monday series, highlighting the very best and brightest in freeware aircraft and scenery.  The team behind the 777-300 have been keeping sim pilots up to date in their development forum. Recently they have informed everyone that the primary modelling of the aircraft both exterior and interior are more or less done, with 50 functional buttons and systems and they are now working on fine-tuning the 777 and making it as realistic as they possibly can The aircraft currently features detailed modelling, a detailed EICAS and EFIS system along with default avitab integration.  This exciting freeware aircraft is available to download on the Xplane.org forum  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwphx</id>
    <title>BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim Release Phoenix Sky Harbor International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwphx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640eb072c700f6b04fa6bb28_phx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2502340"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim have partnered up again to develop a rendition of Phoenix Sky Harbor International (KPHX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 8th busiest airport in the United States and 11th in the World.  Sky Harbor’s history goes back to 1928, when it was built by Scenic Airways, making it the fourth airport in Phoenix. The airport was sold not much after to Acme Investment Company as a consequence of the Stock Market crash of 1929. They owned it for six years, and then the city of Phoenix purchased the whole thing for $100,000.   The Wall Street Journal ranked PHX as the best airport overall in the country among the 20 largest, with praises to its short screening waits, fast wi-fi, good restaurants, and cheap Uber fares to get downtown.   With a yearly average of 45 million passengers, Phoenix consolidates itself as one of the busiest hubs in the World. Southwest (36.21%), American Airlines (33.46%), and Delta Air Lines (7.04%) compose the top three carriers in market share, with Denver (1,087,000), Seattle-Tacoma (831,000), and Las Vegas (813,000) being the busiest domestic destinations. Internationally, three tourist destinations in Mexico take the crown, with San José del Cabo being the busiest (352,461), followed by Puerto Vallarta and Cancún, with 245,749 and 215,088, respectively.  The airport has two terminals (T3 and T4), with T1 and T2 marked as “retired.” Terminal 3 has 25 gates, and Terminal 4 has 92.   The scenery features an accurate rendition, with high-resolution custom ground textures, landside buildings, airline codes assigned to their respective parking stands, FSLTL traffic compatibility, animated jetways, custom ground markings, and an animated Sky Train.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $23.30, requiring at least 3.50 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to troponaut on the Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/caebol</id>
    <title>Caelus Aerial Releases Bologna Guglielmo Marconi Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/caebol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/640f83b4909590574abd594f_bol1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="969172"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Caelus Aerial has recently released their rendition of Bologna Guglielmo Marconi Airport (LIPE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 8th busiest airport in Italy with a yearly average of 9 million passengers.  The airport's history dates back to 1933, when the original airport was erected. It was in the 1970s that they built the current one, 500 meters away from the former. The old one turned out too small to handle the passenger volume increase from there onwards. The "new" terminal, recently expanded, covers an area of 36,100 square meters, with 24 departure gates and 5,500 square meters of shopping area.   The airport is one of the Italian hubs for Ryanair, with 53 non-seasonal destinations and 14 seasonal. WizzAir is another prominent visitor with 11 destinations in Eastern Europe. The airport is visited by multiple non-LCC European carriers such as Aegean Airlines, Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Swiss, TAP, and Turkish Airlines, along with a list of other rather popular LCCs such as Eurowings, easyJet, and Vueling.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport with detailed models of all the buildings, accurate runway, apron, and taxiway markings, PBR materials, and partial interior modeling of every part of the terminal that faces the apron, an animated monorail, surface movement radar, weather radar, and runway guard lights.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $16.93, requiring at least 588.82MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winlet</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Alfredo Vásquez Cobo International for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winlet" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6410ece742bbf39f4b153ba9_let1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3021293"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Alfredo Vásquez Cobo International (SKLT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Leticia in Colombia.   ‍  Inaugurated in 2003 and named after the former governor of the Department of Amazonas, of which Leticia is the capital. It’s the main gateway to southern Colombia and an essential hub for air transportation of regional products, such as rubber and nuts. The traffic figures sit at around 100,000 passengers a year.   It’s visited by Avianca, LATAM Colombia, and Viva Air, with direct flights to Bogotá. SATENA, a government-owned regional carrier, also operates in Leticia with routes to La Chorrera, La Pedrera, San José del Guaviare, and Tarapacá.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail model of the main terminal, custom ground markings, landside buildings, custom clutter, and landmarks.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.85, requiring at least 228.31 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmxmum</id>
    <title>Project MAX Releases Mumbai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmxmum" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6410fa6836623341ca172952_vabb1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3119200"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Project MAX has recently released their rendition of Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport (VABB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Metropolitan Region of Mumbai, India. It’s the 2nd busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 49 million passengers, and the 41st in the World.  Mumbai International Airport was conceived as RAF Santacruz in the 1930s and played an essential role during World War 2 while housing several Royal Air Force squadrons. It covered an area of 610 hectares, with three runways. It saw the first bits of civil action in the late 40s when the RAF handed it over to the Director General of Civil Aviation, which had the RAF hangars converted into a passenger terminal. It was only a short time until they had to expand, with the construction of a new terminal sometime in the late 50s and new equipment that would allow nocturnal operations.   The jumbo jet era brought even more traffic into the already constrained airport, with a terminal that could only handle about 600 passengers at the same time having to deal with twice that amount. It quickly became the most congested airport in the country, awarding it an honorable mention from Time magazine as a “black hole” rather than a terminal building. To make matters worse, the International section caught on fire in 1979, killing three people. The airport owners were urged to expand the structure with a 110 million rupee project expected to reach completion by 1981. Construction began in 1977, earning its end in late 1980.   The airport saw further modernization work proposed in 2003, when it was already handling 38% of the country’s aircraft movement, rounding up at around 13.3 million passengers, leading to another congestion nightmare. A consortium won the bid to operate, manage, and modernize the airport, a process that happened progressively over the years.  It’s a hub for many Indian airlines, including Air India, AIX Connect, Vistara, Akasa Air, Go First, and IndiGo, offering a comprehensive domestic and international network. It’s visited by many carriers from all around the globe, with the most prominent being Air France, All Nippon Airways, British Airways, Cathay Airways, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Singapore Airlines, Turkish Airlines, and United Airlines.  The scenery features a detailed 3D model for the terminals, buildings, props, and landside buildings, detailed ground poly, custom ground markings, a detailed terminal interior, high-detail airside with ground service equipment and static aircraft, specular mapping and PBR on ground poly, dense fps-friendly custom autogen, bonus 3D scenery of VAJJ, night textures, and custom AFCAD. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.12, requiring at least 433.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blsdub</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Dublin Airport Upgrade for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blsdub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641227e976190e662a19a218_du1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="336395"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released their updated rendition of Dublin Airport (EIDW) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, adding the new northern runway, multiple bug fixes, performance improvements, and more!  Dublin Airport is the 12th busiest airport in Europe, and the 1st in Ireland, with a yearly average of 30 million passengers. It hosts their flag carrier Aer Lingus, the low-cost carrier beast Ryanair, and TUI Airways, with a significant route network that encompasses most of Europe and some key cities in North America.   The updated scenery features current ortho imagery, the new northern runway, fully custom terminals, buildings, and landside buildings, partially modeled terminal interiors, custom 4K PBR SAM jetways, custom HD forests and vegetation, 3D volumetric grass, 3D trees, optional animated ground traffic (airside and landside - XP 12 only), 3D people at selected locations, custom HD PBR vehicles, an accurate layout as of 2023, fully custom dynamic lighting, 4K PBR ground textures, wholly accurate ground markings, thousands of accurately placed objects and textures, full Traffic Global compatibility, and a fully accurate airport layout referenced from the latest charts.  It’s available on the Boundless Store for roughly $18.98 (temporarily discounted from the base price of $25.31), requiring at least 2.1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/adipwm</id>
    <title>AeroDesigns Releases Portland International Jetport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/adipwm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64162f77353639cc044e95cf_jet1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="152312"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AeroDesigns has recently released their rendition of Portland International Jetport (KPWM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Portland in Maine with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport was conceived in the late 1920s as a landing strip for Dr. Clifford Strange. It saw commercial action for the first time in 1931, with a Boston-Maine Airways flight from Portland to Boston. The city of Portland eventually purchased the airport and renamed it to Portland-Westbrook Municipal Airport, which explains its origin code (PWM).  Portland Jetport is served by eleven domestic airlines: American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. Cheapflights consider it the third most affordable airport in New England.  Originally intended to be just a port of their KPWM for X-Plane 11, the scenery’s assets were entirely reworked, including ground textures, ground markings, taxi layout, a complete retexturing of the terminal building (externally and internally) with extra clutter to provide even better immersion. It also includes extra work on details such as dirt, extra ground service equipment, etc.   It features highly accurate and detailed 3D models of the terminal (internally and externally), detailed landside buildings, custom-modeled jetways, HDR, accurate night lighting, high-resolution ground textures and markings, custom PBR for all textures, accurately placed ground clutter, fully customized runway and taxiway lighting, and a custom GSX profile, packaged into the scenery folder.  It’s available on the Contrail Store for roughly $18.26 (excluding VAT), requiring at least 1.23 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbsbei</id>
    <title>DarkBlueScenery Releases Beijing Capital International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbsbei" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6416390f3ea2020411c1000b_pek1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2453585"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane.  DarkBlueScenery has recently released their rendition of Beijing Capital International Airport (ZBAA) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, one of the two international airports serving the Metropolitan Area of Beijing, in China. Pre-pandemic, the passenger figures sat at a whopping 100 million passengers annually (2018), placing it among the busiest in Asia.   Opened in March 1958, the airport initially had a single terminal building and a 2,500-meter runway. It was extended to 3,200 meters in 1966 and 3,800 meters in 1982. The second runway was built in 1978, 3,200 meters long. Around that same period came the new Terminal 1, large enough for 12 aircraft but soon proven inadequate given the traffic boom in the 1990s, justifying further expansion that came to fruition in 1999, with the opening of Terminal 2 and a total renovation of Terminal 1.   The Beijing Olympics called for further expansion work to handle all the extra work, bringing a new runway and a new terminal (T3), which was the largest man-made structure in the World in terms of area coverage. After hosting the Olympics, it quickly rose to the top among the busiest airports in Asia, surpassing Tokyo Haneda.  It’s a hub for Air China and Hainan Airlines, offering a broad domestic and international route network. It’s visited by many airlines from all over the World, including Air France, Cathay Pacific, Egyptair, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Japan Airlines, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Singapore Airlines, Thai Airways, and Turkish Airlines. Cargo-wise, it houses Air China Cargo and China Postal Airlines and gets visited by many cargo carriers from all over, including Cargolux, FedEx, Lufthansa Cargo, and Singapore Airlines Cargo.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, high-detail 3D model of the terminal, cargo buildings, custom night lighting, updated ground layout, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.99, requiring at least 1.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barcia</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Rome-Ciampino International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barcia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64163f5a3b87d45f63ea3a16_cia1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="414356"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Rome-Ciampino International Airport (LIRA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the secondary international airport of Rome, averaging 5 million passengers per year.  Ciampino is one of the oldest airports in operation, dating back to 1916. It was the airport of choice for Umberto Nobile on his expedition to the North Pole ten years after the airport’s opening with the airship Norge. It was the first aircraft to reach the north pole and fly across the polar ice cap from Europe to North America. Four years later, Ciampino was the testing ground for the first helicopter prototype, designed by Corradino D’Ascanio.   Captured by the USAF during late World War 2, it became a USAF military airfield, used as a transport air base by C-47 Skytrains, and temporarily flying A-36 Apaches right after its capture from the German forces. ‍ Before the opening of Fiumicino, Ciampino was Rome’s main airport, with an average of 2 million passengers a year. It saw its darkest age during the next couple of decades after Fiumicino’s opening, handling only charter and executive traffic until low-cost carriers embraced it in the early 2000s. It went from stagnation to one of the fastest-growing airports in Italy, with a whopping 16.75% increase from 2005 to 2006 and 9% from 2006 to 2007, sitting at that 5 million ballpark up until recently (with an apparent drop during the pandemic).  It’s a hub for the low-cost giant Ryanair, with thirty-two European destinations. WizzAir is also a frequent visitor, with six destinations.   The scenery features a high-detail terminal with custom ground markings, custom ground clutter, a detailed parking lot, landside buildings, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.27, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/alklar</id>
    <title>Alkee Creations Releases Larestan International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/alklar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6416439fb87dcfda2a43c9e9_lar1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2183638"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Alkee Creations has recently released their rendition of Larestan International Airport (OISL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Lar, in Iran.   With its initial operations dating back to 1983, it was an exclusively domestic airport until the end of the Persian Gulf War, when it got its first international route to Dubai.   The airport is owned by the Government of Iran and operated by Iran Airports Company, featuring a single terminal that can handle up to 250,000 passengers a year.   The annual figures sit at 161,000 passengers annually (as of 2017). It’s served by five airlines, including flydubai (Dubai), Iran Air (Doha, Dubai, Kuwait City, and Tehran-Mehrabad), Kish Air (Najaf, Tehran-Mehrabad), Pars Air (Tehran-Mehrabad), and Qeshm Air (Dubai, and Tehran-Mehrabad).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the passenger terminal with its interior, PBR texturing on most models, accurate ground layout, taxi signs and taxiways according to real-world charts, accurate windsock positioning, and FPS-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.44, requiring at least 297.47 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsskuc</id>
    <title>The Secret Studio Releases Kuching International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsskuc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64179473b915f1077ed78f4f_kuc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="803491"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Secret Studio has recently released their rendition of Kuching International Airport (WBGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Kuching Intl serves the southwestern region of Sarawak, in Malaysia, sitting just 11 kilometers south of Kuching. The structure is partially shared with RMAF Kuching, which houses the 7th squadron of the Royal Malaysian Air Force.   The airport started as an airstrip in 1938, with 640 meters of total length. The first terminal building came nearly 12 years later, relatively small, “L” shaped, and single-story. The runway then was just 1,372 meters long. With the rapid growth in the 50s, the early 1960s saw further expansion work, with a new runway lengthening and a terminal enlargement.   The 1970s started with plans to transform Kuching into an international airport, which demanded further runway length and terminal size expansions. It all came to fruition within that decade, with the runway reaching 2,454 meters in length, and the new terminal opened in 1983, replacing the old one with a three-story, 13,000 square meters passenger terminal.  The early 2000s brought a massive increase in traffic figures, making the now-old terminal feel cramped. They have decided to build a new terminal from the inside out and progressively replace the old bits. It was inaugurated in January 2006, with full completion in April of that same year. It increased the terminal size from 13,000 to 46,000 square meters, along with a runway extension from the former 2,454 meters to 3,780 meters.   KIA is served by nine airlines (AirAsia, AirAsia X, Batik Air Malaysia, Firefly, Malaysia Airlines, MASwings, MYAirline, Royal Brunei Airlines, and Scoot), sporting a significant domestic network and a couple of international destinations.   The scenery features custom-made buildings that match as closely as possible with reference data, a custom CAT I ILS for runway 07, a detailed rendition of the main passenger terminal with its interior, retail booths, and stores, and a custom-made VDGS system.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.11, requiring at least 467.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/caprin</id>
    <title>CanadianFlightSimStudios Releases Prince Rupert Airport for MSFS and XP</title>
    <updated>2023-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/caprin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6417b6e698a66b751ca2d5f9_5718e7_513edd9c965f4c13949932f0b7e6c1da_mv2.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="526478"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Canada4XPlane, who rebranded to CanadianFlightSimStudios to better represent their product line, has released Prince Rupert Airport (CYPR) for both Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12. Prince Rupert Airport, located in the Pacific Northwest in the province of British Columbia, is an island airport that sees a plethora of general aviation traffic while also servicing various commercial airlines, such as Air Canada Express and Northern Thunderbird Air. The field contains a single runway at a length of 6000 feet, allowing for various aircraft types. The scenery contains various similar features available in both the MSFS and XP12 versions, including custom vegetation models, nearby landmarks, HDR lighting, and even a custom mesh to bring the airport surroundings to life. The MSFS and XP12 feature lists can be seen below. Microsoft Flight Simulator Feature List: X-Plane 12 Feature List: ‍ CanadianFlightSimStudio’s rendition of Prince Rupert Airport is available for both Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12 for CAD $13.00 via the developer’s store, or via Orbx for AUD $13.00. The stores are linked below. CanadianFlightSimStudio’s Store: X-Plane 12 Version Microsoft Flight Simulator Version Orbx Store: X-Plane 12 Version Microsoft Flight Simulator Version ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/320neo</id>
    <title>Toliss Release A320 NEO For X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/320neo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6419fb20501b9dfbeffb3d18_315337_ToLiss_A320_NEO_store_images_-_Picture25.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3030524"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane aircraft developers Toliss have released their all-new A320 Neo for XP11 and XP12. The aircraft comes as the latest edition to their fleet of Airbus products, which includes the A319, A321 and A340. This latest release aims to simulate the NEO version of the A320 to the highest level possible with many new and improved features not seen before on Toliss aircraft.  Some of the featured highlights of this new aircraft include:  This latest edition to the Toliss fleet can be picked up from the Xplane.org store for $89.99 </summary>
    <published>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmds12</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS SU12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmds12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641b72c5f77af91b0b0a0e18_pin1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2801136"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued a new update to their 737 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding SU12 compatibility, bug fixes,  navdata format changes, and structural work to support the upcoming Universal Flight Tablet better.  Among the bug fixes, it’s important to mention that PMDG has addressed the parking brake bug introduced with SU12 Beta. It’s a temporary fix that will give mostly regular operation but with some oddities if the user has high-end pedals, as the parking brake could be set or released without entirely depressing both pedals. They mention it will be reverted to the usual logic once Asobo fixes the problem.  In the announcement post, PMDG briefly mentioned the status of the remainder of the 737 lineup in regards to their Marketplace availability, saying it’s still being prepared and the release date will vary according to Microsoft’s approval process, which has been sped up recently but they hesitate on setting a specific timeline. The same applies to the upcoming Xbox compatibility, with no timeframe but work being done in the meantime.   The Universal Flight Tablet is progressing nicely, with a functioning Operational Performance Tool and charts. Both features are soon to hit testing for validation. They also mention further work on improving the UI/UX before the testing begins, which is why they haven’t shown any screenshots yet.  They finish with the NAVDATA progress, which is still underway and soon to hit testing, allowing for advanced FMS lateral path management capabilities once it’s done.  The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600), $49.99 (737-900), and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Pictures are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lshmd8</id>
    <title>Leonardo Software House Updates MD-82 and Releases MD-83 &amp; MD-88 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lshmd8" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641c248fe177817d2f170b29_le1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="997779"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stefano from Leonardo Software House has announced in their forum an upcoming update to the MD-82 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with the release of two expansions, the MD-83 and the MD-88, free for previous owners (of the P3D version).  The new update brings quality-of-life enhancements while keeping your previous settings and airframes. The fixes include MDClient CTD mitigations, SimBrief import unit mismatch (pax weight approximations), improved visual effects for engine smoke and engine fire, compatibility improvements with default jetways, and documentation changes. The full changelog follows down below:  FIXED - fixed issue when changing APPROACH while already navigating the STAR; - fixed issue in W&amp;B efb app resetting changes when reopening app (if SimBrief/PFPX option not set); - fixed issue in MDClient crashing to desktop when printing subsequent ACARS messages; - fixed approximations issues for pax weight when importing from SimBrief using lbs units; EFFECTS - improved engine smoke effect; - improved engire fire effect; MODEL - fixed wrong uv mapping of lower aft antenna; OTHER - added option to force 'norm to' in efb perf app (so it shows the same values as the speed card); - changed jetwey setup to have it properly set on defualt scenery. Many add-on scenery do not comply with ASOBO req, and the result is poor there; - elevator will always be displaced when resting or taxing very slow on a windy day, even after end of first flight; - added compatibility for MD-83/-88 extension pack; - added volume settings for BG music in Load Manager; - when realistic mode is enabled, ACARS LOAD SHEET can have small random varation with respect to OFP; DOCUMENTATION - updated Fly the Maddog X Quick Guide MSFS 2020; - updated Fly the Maddog X User Manual MSFS 2020.  The MD-83 &amp; MD-88 expansion is free for previous owners (Prepar3d version). It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $26.96, requiring at least 212.95 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
