<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-12-19T18:18:01.175102+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aarc25</id>
    <title>Ant's Airplanes Releases CA-25 Winjeel for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aarc25" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6579115385f40d45baf51ed8_mediaslider01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="876549"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Developer Ant’s Airplanes has just released their latest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the CAC CA-25 Winjeel. This is Ant’s third aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, following the Tiger Moth, and the Ultralight Drifter. Ant’s also have a history of developing aircraft for FSX and P3D, and they also develop freeware for all three simulators. The CA-25 is a fixed wing, three seat, piston-driven taildragger and it was designed and built by the Commonwealth Aircraft Corporation in Australia. It was developed exclusively for the Royal Australian Air Force and it was used as their main training aircraft for four decades. The first CA-25 flew in 1955, and deliveries started later that same year. In total, 62 Winjeels were produced, and there are only 30 airworthy aircraft left today, with most being privately owned. The Ant’s Airplanes rendition of the CA-25 is based on a 1956 airframe, registered VH-OPJ, and has been modified to have an extra seat, bringing the total to 4 seats. Some of the features of the Ant’s CA-25 include: For more information and videos on the Ant’s Airplanes CA-25 Winjeel, you can head to their website. You can pick up the Winjeel at Simmarket, with availability on the Just Flight store coming soon as of the time of writing for $17.95 USD.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lgmvms</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Landmarks of Germany - Mecklenburg-Vorpommern for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lgmvms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657a65a8f4cd409103a0100d_84_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2217423"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. German developer FSDG have just released another product for their Landmarks of Germany series for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Their newest product covers the German Federal State of Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, in the northeast of the country, bordering Poland to the east, and the Baltic Sea to the north. In the pack, FSDG has included over 1,000 individual objects covering the whole state. Castles, famous buildings, bridges, television towers, radio towers, water towers, radar towers, chimneys, antennas, solar parks and lots of lighthouses can be found at their exact positions all across the state. This pack hopes to offer an enhanced VFR experience, and is part of a set that will eventually cover the entire country of Germany. You can get Landmarks of Germany - Mecklenburg-Vorpommern at the Aerosoft Store or FSDG's Website for €8.40, excluding VAT.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skytam</id>
    <title>Skyline Simulations Releases Queen Tamar Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skytam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657b597975792750158eabab_tamar.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="972536"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyline Simulations has recently released their rendition of Queen Tamar Airport (UGSM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Mestia in Georgia, with a yearly average of 9,300 passengers as of 2022.  Mestia Airport was part of Georgia’s plan to increase regional tourist figures. It was built in 2010 with a GEL 8 million investment, with an architectural project that boasts a modern glassy style that contrasts with the natural surroundings and does not impact the environment. Designed and created by Jurgen Mayer-Hermann, the BBC considers the airport one of the world’s most beautiful.   With a 1,158-meter runway at 1,456 meters above sea level, the range of aircraft that can fly into this airport is limited. It’s currently only served by Vanilla Sky with their Let L-410 UVP-Es, taking passengers to Kutaisi, where passengers can connect with the rest of Europe.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, custom ground textures, custom 3D vegetation, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.68, requiring at least 644.37 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siachm</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Chiang Rai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siachm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657b6b31fd1f29d498da796e_chia.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="956365"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Chiang Rai International Airport (VTCT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the provinces of Chiang Rai and Phayao in Thailand with a yearly average of 1.6 million passengers.  It was opened in 1992, built to accommodate 3 million passengers per year and large widebody aircraft (747, 777, 787, A330, and A340).   There are plans to expand the airport, including an additional taxiway, more shops, and a runway extension. It’s expected to reach completion sometime in 2030.  While the airport had been operating at capacity for a while before the pandemic, the numbers have since plummeted and are still not showing signs of recovery.  Nok Air, Ruili Airlines, Thai AirAsia, Thai Airways International, Thai LionAir, and Thai VietjetAir currently serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom animated jetways, custom ground textures, hand-placed taxiway guidance signs, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.93, requiring at least 311.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs90ea</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Releases E190/195 for MSFS in Early Access</title>
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs90ea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657b76260cb563a1c0f2ebb9_01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="934187"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio has recently released their rendition of the Embraer 190 and Embraer 195 for Microsoft Flight Simulator in an Early Access stage. This is the continuation of their well known E-Jets Series, which already includes their rendition of the Embraer 170 and 175. The Embraer 190 and 195 are stretched versions of the Embraer 170 series airframe. Built by Embraer in Brazil, the E190 and E195 differ from the shorter variants in the series with a more powerful engine, a larger wing, and larger horizontal stabilizer. The E190 entered into service in 2005 with JetBlue, and the E195 entered into service with FlyBe just a year later in 2006. The FlightSim Studio E190/195 is currently in an early access stage, with features such as a custom Autopilot system with LNAV and VNAV, and a custom FMS still being in development. As of the time of writing, the FSS E190/195 boasts features such as: For more information on the E-Jets Series by FlightSim Studio, you can head to their website. You can purchase the FlightSim Studio E190/195 at the Aerosoft Store for $39.99 USD.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxtpx</id>
    <title>FlightFX Teases New Cockpit Images of "Project ApX" for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxtpx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657bda5f25c7be3b68f1f797_Screenshot_2023-12-06_002847.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="2018984"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has recently released teaser photos of the cockpit of their next aircraft, which they dub “Project ApX” for Microsoft Flight Simulator. FlightFX, known for their general aviation aircraft, such as the highly popular Cirrus SF50 G2, and the Honda Jet, Project ApX is shaping up to be another exciting development in the MSFS General Aviation market. Project ApX was announced last month, and speculation has abounded around what FlightFX’s next project would be. Now that these teaser photos have been released, many flight simmers have predicted that Project ApX is the popular Cessna Citation X business jet. The photos also show a great amount of detail, with high quality textures and models, from the seats to the switches. All of this hints at a very promising aircraft for the sim. While FlightFX have not given any other details on Project ApX as of yet, or much on their next project, the Piaggio Avanti II, Threshold will keep you updated whenever they do, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a143</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a143" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657ccd9615031f61fa9848d9_a2a-comanche.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2289134"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently released a new update to their Accu-Sim Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, improving support for loading saved flights, fixing sound issues, and more.  Update 1.4.3, the fifth product update so far, brings versional parity with the newly released marketplace version of the Comanche, along with addressing a sound looping issue with the Wwise sound engine, and a couple of other changes that follow down below:   The aircraft is available on their website for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rofe24</id>
    <title>Registration Opens for FlightSimExpo 2024</title>
    <updated>2023-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rofe24" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657f4cb3ccb1ec3cd08f06cb_FSExpo_2024__coverphoto.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="361949"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. FlightSimExpo, one of the world’s largest conferences dedicated to all things flight simulation, has just opened registration for their 2024 event in Las Vegas, hosted at the Tropicana Resort from June 21st through the 23rd.  FlightSimExpo connects simmers, developers, and exhibitors in-person and online, and has hosted over 5000 people since the event started in 2018. Registration for the in-person event starts at $80 USD, but those who are Flight Simulation Association Captains get 20% off that price, and First Officers get 10% off. Becoming a Flight Simulation Association First Officer is free, so we highly suggest that you take advantage of this deal when registering. For those who can’t physically make it to the event, you can register for that and watch live and recorded seminars for $15 USD. We on the Threshold team are very excited for next year’s expo, and some of us on the team will be in Las Vegas for the event, and we hope to see some of our community members in Vegas!  You can register for the expo using this link!  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/olborb</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Olbia Costa Smeralda V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/olborb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/657fa56832773be891c94d81_olbia.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="589633"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their new rendition of Olbia Costa Smeralda Airport (LIEO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 15th busiest airport in Italy with a yearly average of 2.9 million passengers.  It was built in 1974 and underwent heavy expansion work 30 years later, with a new 42,000 square meter terminal that could handle up to 4.5 million passengers a year, costing 81 million euros.  It’s visited on a seasonal basis (summer, primarily) by Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, AeroItalia, Air France, AirBaltic, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, easyJet, Edelweiss Air, Eurowings, flydubai, Iberia, ITA Airways, Jet2.com, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Smartwings, Swiss, Transavia, Volotea, Vueling, and WizzAir.   Developed by Matteo Veneziani, Olbia V2 is entirely scratch-built, with nothing left from V1, featuring new 4K textures, a terminal interior with passengers, new GSE vehicles, new ground layout, high-resolution ground textures, Olbia POIs, a fully modeled rendition of the Olbia harbor, performance-friendly optimization, and new animated jetways with custom sounds.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.12, requiring at least 3.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddrbfi</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Designs Releases Boeing Field for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddrbfi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580b34856ca39e17f82840e_KBFI_MSFS_13.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="377404"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Designs has recently released his latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, being KBFI Boeing Field in Seattle. This is Drzewiecki’s third Seattle-area scenery, following the release of Paine Field and Renton. All three of these airports serve as sites for production or delivery of Boeing’s lines of aircraft.  Boeing Field, officially known as King County International Airport, is situated five miles south of downtown Seattle. It served as Seattle’s main passenger gateway, until the larger Seattle-Tacoma Airport opened in 1944. It was crucial in the production of many early 737 series of aircraft in the 1960’s, due to the fact that Boeing’s other narrowbody production facility at Renton didn’t have enough capacity. Today, it mainly serves as a cargo airport, and is the site of the Boeing Delivery Center, where new 737’s are delivered after going through final preparation. The Drzewiecki Designs rendition of the airport has many features, including: As of the time of writing, you can get this airport on the Aerosoft store, but that will expand to other vendors shortly. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arjacx</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Jackson Hole Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arjacx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580bf79a03380541094b6b1_656e6ac492899.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2980147"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos have just recently released their rendition of the famous high-altitude airport, Jackson Hole, for X-Plane 12. Situated in the rocky mountains, Jackson Hole Airport is a popular destination for those looking to explore the Rockies! Jackson Hole Airport was originally created in the 1930’s, and it was chosen for its advantageous location within Teton County. The airport was declared a National Monument in 1943, and eventually merged with the Grand Teton National Park in 1950. Jackson Hole is the only commercial airport in the United States to be part of a National Park. The runway was extended to its current length of 6300 feet in 1959. The original Frontier Airlines was the first airline to serve Jackson Hole, with flights to Salt Lake City, Denver, and Billings using Douglas DC-3’s and eventually Boeing 737-200’s. The terminal was completely rebuilt between 2009 and 2014.  Today, the airport is the busiest airport in Wyoming, seeing over 450,000 passengers per year. It has nonstop service to 15 destinations during peak seasonal times by 8 different airlines, and has year-round service by Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, United Airlines, and Delta Air Lines. It is the main destination for many ski resorts surrounding the airport. Axonos’ rendition of the airport includes many features, such as: You can add this airport to your virtual world for $22.99 from their store. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cjrrms</id>
    <title>CJ Simulations Releases Rafale for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cjrrms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580c1d1cb114fa2cbe8f941_410880261_884190530376367_9027274731770291189_n.jpg.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1924057"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CJ Simulations, known for their renditions of fighter aircraft, have just released their rendition of the CJS Rafale for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Developed in partnership with CodeNameJack and DC Designs, it is another rendition of a very popular European fighter, following their release of the Eurofighter Typhoon last year. The Rafale is a French multi-role fighter, built by Dassault Aviation. It was developed out of the need of a new jet fighter for the French Air Force and Navy. The initial variant of the Rafale, the Rafale A, first flew in 1986, but after many changes and delays, the production version of the Rafale, the Rafale C, was introduced in 2001. Today, the Rafale is primarily used by the French Air Force and Navy, as well as the Egyptian Air Force and the Indian Air Force. ‍ The CJS rendition of the Rafale includes features such as high quality 3D interior and exterior modeling, various simulations of Rafale systems, and much more! You can get the CJ Simulations Rafale on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $35 USD. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aabsms</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Announces Breezer Sport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aabsms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580d3b844dfd2023f4e8866__0019_Breezer-Sport-4.jpg.078b2911e50f730b24ee90d8f3f1b9ad.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="68785"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. German developer Aerosoft has announced that they are developing the Breezer Sport, and is their latest foray into the aircraft market for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Aerosoft, known for their simulations of airliners, such as the CRJ series, and their upcoming Airbus A330 project for MSFS, moves into the GA market with this announcement. The Breezer Sport is produced by the German aircraft manufacturer with the same name, Breezer Aircraft. The Breezer Sport is a light-sport, single engine aircraft that was developed in the late 90’s. The first flight was in 1999, and entered into production in 2001. A few years later in 2005, the Breezer Sport earned a light-sport rating by the FAA, and entered into the US market. It is powered by a Rotax 915 iS/iSC engine, and can hold up to two people, and is unique in its class for its aluminum construction.  A full feature set has not been announced yet, but Aerosoft has said that the aircraft will feature an authentic interior and cockpit layout, according to documents from Breezer themselves, as well as an animated glass canopy, glass cockpit with AS3 Touch, and a simplified implementation of the original RSFlight EMU. Aerosoft also has announced that the Breezer Sport will come with an animated kneeboard with original checklists, and a tablet. Aerosoft has not announced a release date or price, but Threshold will keep you informed whenever they do, so stay tuned for this and for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmt7eb</id>
    <title>PMDG 777 for MSFS Enters Beta Testing Phase</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmt7eb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65810afd41ff70b683b4e3c8_PMDG_777_cabin.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="921140"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a recent development update on their forums, PMDG’s CEO, Robert Randazzo announced that their upcoming Boeing 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator has entered the hands of beta testers.This marks another milestone in the process of release of the highly anticipated aircraft for the simulator.This news comes after the release of their first preview image a few weeks ago, which set the community aflame with speculation on details about the aircraft. Randazzo says that we shouldn’t expect much yet, but more previews will be coming.  ‍ Also in this development update are updates on progress about the Marketplace, and updates to the Universal Flight Tablet Concerning the Marketplace, for PC, Randazzo tells us that the new updates will be coming, and it is only a matter of time before Microsoft approves the update and pushes it to the public. On the Xbox side of things, Randazzo says that they “continue to work on the testing and trouble-shooting tools that we need in order to collect sufficient data to demonstrate to the platform developer that the communications layer for C++/WASM airplanes is partially or fully inoperative on the Xbox platform.” He continues on to tell us that “We are working to find a way to disable the broken tablet functionality when running on Xbox so that we can at least keep Xbox users up-to-date with any other improvements and non-tablet changes that we make.” There also is a new update to the PMDG Universal Flight Tablet, which Mr. Randazzo says will be the final one for 2023. The full changelog follows below: 12817: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Navigraph map-type choice (IFR low/high/etc.) should be persistent (rmurdoch) 12610: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Save users pref of aircraft symbol in settings (rmurdoch) 12832: [EFB - Performance and Computational] New menu data for 777 (cbpowell) 12635: [EFB - General] Day/Night should default to most applicable and allow over selection please (rmurdoch) 12831: [EFB - General] Make signal bar reflect currency of airplane pings (rmurdoch) 12569: [EFB - General] Utilize MSFS built-in airport data for OPT (rmurdoch) ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csep</id>
    <title>Cockspur Previews Embraer Phenom</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csep" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658186f80a6d95c71de41267_411482272_346823951428489_1348043931857465735_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="656188"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur, known for their Cessna C162 and C510 Mustang, have previewed their upcoming Embraer Phenom 100. Originally announced earlier in December, there hasn’t been much information about the upcoming release. The Embraer Phenom 100 is a very light business jet that made its first flight in 2007. The powerplant of the Phenom 100 (EMB-500) is two Pratt and Whitney PW600 turbofan engines providing almost 4,000 lbf of thrust combined. Requiring only one pilot the Phenom 100 has room for up to 5 passengers depending on the configuration. With a service ceiling of 41,000 ft and a cruise speed of 400 knots, the Phenom 100 has a maximum range of 1,178 nmi. In the post on their Facebook page, Cockspur has provided several screenshots of the exterior of the plane. While there haven’t been any previews of the interior so far it looks as though Cockspur have provided excellent exterior modelling and impressive texturing. There’s currently no indication of when we could see a release of the aircraft or at what price point. For all of your flight simulation news updates be sure to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gksfar</id>
    <title>GKS announces development of the F-111E Aardvark</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gksfar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6581ce19756d1c4e755d44d2_HOG.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="88654"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Golden Key Studio has unveiled their latest project, the development of the F-111 for MSFS, following their previous release of the MiG-21Bis Fishbed. The announcement was made via the flight simulator forums today. The Aardvark, an aircraft of the 1960s, was manufactured by General Dynamics and stands as a supersonic-capable medium-range multirole aircraft. It served various roles, excelling as an attack aircraft, bomber, reconnaissance, and electronic warfare platform. Primarily operated by the US Air Force and the Royal Australian Air Force, this aircraft witnessed over 500 units produced across six distinct variants. GKS has dedicated its efforts to the F-111E variant, powered by Pratt and Whitney's TF-30 engines that enable the F-111 to achieve speeds of up to Mach 2.5. Streamlining its high-speed capabilities is a swing-wing design reminiscent of the F-14 Tomcat. GKS has offered a sneak peek into the intricate details of the cockpit, ensuring a well-detailed version of its unique side-by-side seating cockpit. Judging by the screenshots shared by GKS, the exterior model appears to be nearing completion and or completed. While GKS has provided sparse details regarding pricing and release dates, we can anticipate additional information in the near future. Stay tuned to Threshold for updates on this exciting addition to the MSFS lineup.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
