<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-12-18T18:32:20.292773+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/300113</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A300-600R for MSFS 2024 Compatibility</title>
    <updated>2024-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/300113"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661a650af25ee1803d0c545c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A300-600R product line, making it compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, albeit in a Beta state with a few caveats. Version 1.1.3 introduces compatibility with the newly released flight simulator, but there are some known issues to be aware of for the time being: terrain display problems, loss of overhead Korry switch and ambient packs/bleed sounds when switching views, random TCAS RA errors from the plane itself and networking issues. Initially released a year ago for MSFS 2020, the add-on features a detailed custom flight management system with SIDs, STARs, an SEC flight plan, custom VNAV and LNAV, an IDC radio with CPDLC and ACARS, custom systems, two engine options (PW and GE), a realistic RNAV, custom maintenance functions, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.59, requiring at least 8.81 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/m24127</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases New MSFS 2024 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/m24127"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/674f7277bb1f0ce33ab07974_msfs24-2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft recently issued a new update (1.2.7.0) to its newly released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This update allows users to enable/disable MSFS 2020’s (Marketplace) individually ported content, provides additional stability and performance fixes, and more. Update 1.2.7.0 is the most significant so far, addressing a few items that were previously requested by the community, such as the option to individually enable or disable ported marketplace content from Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, and bringing a considerable list of fixes, warranting further stability and better performance. The complete changelog (for stability and bug fixes) follows below: ‍ Stability &amp; Performance ‍ General Bug Fixes ‍ Please refer to the official release notes for the full spectrum on a per-aircraft basis. ‍ The update is available right now on all supported platforms. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mkslszh</id>
    <title>MK Studios Release Zurich for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mkslszh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6759af67cdc516021ba75d3f_lszh_slider_2_1600x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MK Studios has released its latest scenery for MSFS20 and 24. The team has headed to Zurich, Switzerland's largest city, offering many custom features and high-quality models. Zurich acts as the main gateway into Switzerland having served 28.9 million passengers in 2023. It is also the main base for the flag carrier airline: Swiss. Allowing for routes across Europe and further. The team have made sure to allow for compatibility with both sims allowing users from FS20 &amp; 24 to utilise it. The scenery is filled with high-quality textures on the building's exteriors, interiors and groundwork. All working together to give an accurate depiction of the airport. This is paired with custom objects to match real life, increasing realism. Concourse A,B and E feature a modelled interior, this is a growing feature we are seeing in sceneries that adds a level of depth to the terminal buildings when parked at the gates. Below is the full feature list: MK Studios Zurich is priced at £15.11excl.VAT and can be purchased from the Contrail Shop.  Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and join the community through our Discord.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hsupda</id>
    <title>Headwind Simulations Updates Airbus A339X and SU95X for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hsupda"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6759c353fc21d89e622f2dbd_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Headwind Simulations has recently released updates for its A339X and SU95X projects for MSFS. The new update integrates SayIntentions.AI ACARS and CPDLC into both aircraft. SayIntentions.AI is an AI ATC (Air Traffic Control) plugin designed for various flight simulators. It provides features such as ATC, copilots, cabin crew, and more, all powered by artificial intelligence. A key component of the ATC functionality in SayIntentions.AI includes ACARS (Aircraft Communications Addressing and Reporting System) and CPDLC (Controller-Pilot Data Link Communications). These systems facilitate communication between the ground and the aircraft, allowing for interactions between air traffic controllers and pilots. ‍ With the recent integration of ACARS and CPDLC from SayIntentions.AI into Headwind Simulation’s aircraft, users can now access these features. Please note that a Premium Membership is required to utilise this feature.  The latest updates for the A339X and the SU95X are now accessible via the Headwind Simulations installer. Since the update is part of the pre-release channels, be sure to select this option for the most recent update. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ejpmsf</id>
    <title>easyJet Partners with MSFS to Bring Aircraft to MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ejpmsf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6759dc526043566e92a3dd29_easyJet%20takes%20flight%20in%20Microsoft%20Flight%20Simulator%202024%20%20.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Low-cost-carrier easyJet has announced that they have partnered with Microsoft Flight Simulator to “bring its aircraft to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024”, according to a press release put out on Monday. To promote this new partnership, they have announced a competition to win the “Premium Jumbo Deluxe Edition” of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 for Xbox Series X|S. To participate, one must be a citizen of the UK or Ireland and over 18 at the time of entry, follow both easyJet and Xbox UK on Instagram, and commenting where you would fly to using the in-game easyJet livery on their Instagram post. Contestants have until Dec 13, when Microsoft will pick three winners for the “Premium Jumbo Deluxe Edition”. “We’re excited to be a part of the Microsoft Flight Simulator community, which is not only a fantastic opportunity for us to share our passion for flying with players around the world, but something we hope will help to inspire the next generation of pilots and aviation enthusiasts”, commented Captain David Morgan, easyJet’s Chief Operating Officer. In their press release, easyJet also says that Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 “features easyJet’s A320 family of aircraft including the A319, A320, A320neo and A321neo”; however, the base sim only includes the A320neo and A321LR, both by iniBuilds. Whether this means that there is an effort to bring the rest of easyJet’s fleet, including the A319ceo and A320ceo, to the base game is still unknown. ‍ Threshold has contacted easyJet for comment, but as of the time of publication, they have not responded. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/319110</id>
    <title>ToLiss Updates A319 to v1.10</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/319110"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6759f9f4e087f39b003e7b77_a319%20-%202024-09-19%2019.24.30.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ToLiss has released an update for the A319, after nearly a year since the last one. The v1.10 update brings improvements to aircraft systems and failures, as well as various bug fixes. The update has improved the hydraulic systems, MCDU, ECAM, and FMGS, added new failures, such as slow and rapid decompression, cargo smoke, wind shears and high lift failures (e. g. Elevator faults), brought visual improvements, and added new circuit breakers (bringing the total number of interactive C/B to 242!), as well as adding the ISCS (Interactive Simulation Control System) to the EFB. The full changelog is as follows: - ISCS in EFB - Hydraulic improvement package: 	. Added simulation of trapped hydraulic fluid in asymmetric actuators such as landing gear or spoiler actuators. 	. Fixed the PTU overheat when ENG1 is failed. - MCDU improvement package: 	. CLR command is now indented in scratchpad as in real life 	. DIR TO page prefills the RADIAL IN on the DIR TO page as required 	. FPLN Page Destination EFOB turns amber, if below minimum required. - ECAM improvement package: 	. Overspeed warning now triggers based on actual flap/slat position and not lever position (PFD barber pole is still lever position driven as in real life.) 	. Removed duplication of system titles if the same system shows multiple subsequent rows of ECAM messages. 	. Weight display logic for SD: Prior to engine start, the dashes are now cyan. Weights now only show after engine start, like in real life. 	. Status page improvement: Approach procedures for hydraulic faults 	. Rework of the ECAM messages for electrical bus failures to represent a newer FWC standard - FMGS improvement package: 	. Added possibility to use Airport ICAO codes as waypoints 	. Bug fixes for the path computation leading to an overall much stabler path computation in complex procedures. 	. Empty flight plan shows as PPOS / Discon rather than just "End of flpn" and can be built up from there. 	. VIA selection is now automatic, if there is exactly one VIA that matches the selected FINAL and STAR. 	. Constraints of first waypoint in STAR are not dropped anymore. 	- Added cross track error display on ground prior to departure - New failure modes: 	. Slow and rapid decompression 	. THS jam. 	. Cargo smoke, including latched closure of the isolation valves 	. Added high lift failures, including loss of SFCC channels and slats/flaps lock 	. Windshears with correct REAC W/S detection and indication. - Visual improvement package: 	. Added AoA Vanes to fuselage model 	. Fixed the tiller textures 	. Animated the flap lever guard 	. Correct the eye reference ball colors and location 	. Fixed text overlaps on the overhead panel - Added new Circuit breakers (for high lift, air conditioning packs, ...) bringing the total to 242 - Added pitch influence to the RADALT value, so that the RADALT decreases when you pitch up (like IRL) - Added limitation with filtering to the maximum number of waypoints shown on ND when WPT overlay selected. - Quick starts for engine and APU are now available on the Joystick/Actions tab. - Mapped flight number to x-plane dataref "sim/cockpit2/radios/actuators/flight_id" for third party plugin interfacing. - Improved Master Warning flashing frequency. - Terrain on ND drawing around the airport is now inhibited for areas of same elevation as the airport. - If you select a livery with 2 OWE pairs, the maximum number of passengers will increase to 160. - Added selected heading value on ND, if in ARC mode the heading bug is not visible. ‍ Bug fixes: - Fixed issue with the interaction between the CLR button and the status page - Fixed issue with status page overflow. - The emergency generator now consumes hydraulic fluid. - The magnetic variation model now updates for the current year. - Fixed FMA alignment of armed modes and issue with empty boxes - Extended the permissible value range for FCU speed window to 399kts and Mach 0.99 like in real life - Extended the permissible value range for FCU altitude window to 49000ft like in real life - ISI startup correction: QNH is also visible during ISI startup; moved QNH to right location. - Removed CHG CODE field for other phases than PREFLIGHT or DONE. - Improved string termination on MCDU string datarefs. - Fixed an issue with SID route in alternate plan on first alternate plan programming. - Fixed an issue with waypoints preceded by a discon where the outgoing leg is of the CI/CD/CR/CA or VI/VR/VD type. - Fixed FMA indication for managed descent on profile with significantly too slow speed. - Fixed behaviour of the FCU HDG managed dot when a managed mode (NAV, LOC, APPR) is armed. - Fixed shape of the ADF2 needle on the ND. - Removed GS indication on ND, when the associated ADIRU is OFF or invalid. - Made the deceleration when descending through the SPD LIM altitude smoother. - Fixed issue with the beta target leading to excessive rudder deflection and spoiler extension on the wrong side. - Corrected the color of the RAM Air Inlet indication when open in flight. - Disabled autobrake if 2 or more SECs are lost. - Fixed a bug that could cause sending many requests to the Hoppie network in a short period of time. - Miscellaneous other bug fixes Due to the migration of the updater repository, ToLiss recommends to perform a clean reinstall and download the aircraft from the store.  ‍ The ToLiss A319 for X-Plane 11 and 12 is available for purchase on the X-Plane.org store, Aerosoft store and Simmarket for approximately $89.99. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx553</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Family for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx553"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad407b9d14c3f4c8b8d0e_sharklets19.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has issued a micro-update to their A320 Family (A319/A320/A321) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing more fixes to their 2024 port on systems, art, and tweaks to the EFB (both platforms). Update 2.3.0.553 is the fourth product line update since it was made compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It further enhances compatibility and improves overall stability by mitigating an issue where the aircraft would restart upon switching camera views or changing settings. A potential crash when handling inputs was also found and addressed. On the art side of things, they have fixed the registration and SELCAL not appearing at all, although they still appear black for the time being, and rain now travels in the correct direction. Their EFB has also undergone tweaking to fix potential errors when retrieving METARs with invalid data and to remove a slight pixel gap at the bottom of the app bar. The product line is available on their website for roughly $114 at the time of writing. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tc52rd</id>
    <title>TorqueSim Announces CitationJet C525 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tc52rd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/675b6d68a1e84a15d670efcc_CJ_05.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane developer TorqueSim has announced the release date of their CitationJet C525. The aircraft has been in development for over five years and is slated for release on December 12th at 17:00Z TorqueSim has stated that the aircraft will be “study level”, and says it will include a fully custom Honeywell avionics suite designed to closely replicate the functionality of the real-world aircraft, including immersive sounds, as well as a highly detailed cabin. The CitationJet family includes the original C525, along with the C525A, B, and C variants, each of them having their own submodels. The aircraft depicted in the simulator is the original Model 525, which had its first flight in 1991.  The CitationJet is part of the Take Command! product line sold on the X-Aviation store. It has previously featured the Cirrus SR22 G1000 series by TorqueSim. The developers, who started in 2018 are also the ones behind aircraft like the Take Command! SR20 and BN-2 Islander. The Take Command! TorqueSim CitationJet C525 will be exclusive to X-Plane 12, and will be available for purchase on the X-Aviation store on December 12th at 17:00Z for $84.95. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more! Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777060</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777 Lineup for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777060"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG has recently issued an update to their 777 lineup (777-300R and 777F) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The update cleans up a few items that required attention after the 777F release and addresses issues on the 777-300R caused by code changes to accommodate the 777F.  Update v2.00.0060 eliminates the ghost cargo door advisory and its associated TOCWS trigger on the 777-300ER and adds numerous model cleanups, logic fixes, and more. The changelog follows below: ‍ They have also published new information on the status of their Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 port: they are now able to run code and debugging in MSFS 2024 after a recent update, but the memory allocation error from 2020 appears to be present in 2024 as well – despite PMDG reporting it in the past –, bringing the development effort to a halt as C++ WASM projects seem to rely heavily on advanced memory allocation techniques used by modern C++ compilers. That means they cannot run, build, or test code properly within MSFS 2024. The 737 family will soon receive an update to address the issue with the Universal Flight Tablet not loading properly. There’s no exact prediction of when it will be available for Marketplace users, but it should be coming soon for PMDG.com customers. PMDG’s aircraft lineup is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $74.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tscj52</id>
    <title>TorqueSim Releases TakeCommand! CitationJet 525 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tscj52"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/675dd9b123b88309489808a8_CJ525_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TorqueSim has released their long-awaited CItationJet 525 for X-Plane 12. After more than six years of development, one of the most popular business jets is finally here! Produced to replace the ageing Citation I and IIs, the Cessna CitationJet 525 had its first flight in April 1991 and has since been developed into Model 525A, 525B, and 525C. Over 2000 CitationJets have been produced, making them the most produced business jets. Capable of cruising up to altitudes of 41,000ft and equipped with two Williams R-R FJ44-1A turbofan engines, this T-tail jet can fly at Mach 0.65 for around 1560 nautical miles ( ~2880km). The TorqueSim’s rendition of CitationJet 525 features an authentic flight model with custom airfoils, custom soundpack, high-resolution textures, custom-developed electrical, hydraulic, fuel, and pneumatic systems, custom Honeywell avionics. It also supports RealityXP GNS/GTN, as well as the upcoming TDS Sim GTNXi. The TakeCommand! CitationJet 525 is available for purchase at the X-Aviation store for $84.95.  It is compatible with X-Plane 12 only and can be used on MacOS 12+ (at least Monterey), Windows 10+, and Linux (support is provided only for Ubuntu 24.02 LTS). The recommended specifications for it are CPU with 4+ Cores (3 GHz+), 16+ GB RAM, and NVIDIA or AMD GPU with 4+ GB VRAM. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tds113</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Updates GTNXi Pro for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tds113"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e10a747dd07f4648ff2d5e_tds3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TDS Sim Software has recently released an update to their GTNXi Pro Suite, adding compatibility with Microsoft’s latest flight simulator. While their original plan was to make it compatible as soon as MSFS 2024 was out, a WASM gauge issue made it impossible for a few weeks. However, Asobo has finally managed to address the show stopper—to an extent—as another update blocked the display. A community developer found a workaround that will suffice until an official fix is out. The development team is excited about the new platform and all its possibilities, gauging what they can benefit from and the work it would entail. They have coded the new executable to detect the exact MSFS platform (whether 2020 or 2024) and correctly share it between platforms. Each MSFS version has its own different WASM gauge. ‍ Owners of the base GTNXi package will have to upgrade in order to get compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Refer to this link for further information on acquiring the upgrade. ‍ The GTNXi Pro is available on their website for $68.20, whereas the pro upgrade from the standard package retails for $26.20. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsreli</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2025 Registration Now Live</title>
    <updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsreli"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/675eb096c9332f13371db2d2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Registration for FlightSimExpo 2025 is now open. The event will be held in Providence, Rhode Island, providing an opportunity for aviation enthusiasts to engage with the latest advancements in flight simulation. Tickets are now available for purchase. There are various ticket options available for the event, detailed below: ‍ - Non-FSA Members: The ticket price from Friday to Sunday is $80. - FSA First Officers: The price is $72. - FSA Captains: The price is $64. However, the first 250 FSA Captains to register will only pay $50. ‍ Please note that ticket prices will increase on March 1st, so be sure to purchase your tickets before then to take advantage of the best pricing. ‍ All ticket packages include entry to seminars and exhibition halls from Friday through Sunday. Attendees will also receive access to recordings of post-event seminars, a complimentary drink at Friday’s reception, and coffee and tea on Saturday and Sunday mornings. ‍ If you cannot attend FlightSimExpo in person, you can sign up for live and recorded seminar access for $15. FSA Captains will have free access to this content. For information about travel and logistics for attending the expo, please visit the FlightSimExpo website. FlightSimExpo 2025 will take place in Providence from June 27 to June 29. Registration is now open, and you can purchase your tickets online. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tls321</id>
    <title>ToLiss Updates A321 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tls321"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6760462cd421d550c227fa13_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ToLiss has just released V1.7 of its A321. This update introduces numerous new features and bug fixes.  ‍ This update - the first in over a year, mostly follows the pattern established by V1.10 of the A319, which was released just a few days ago. However the A321 also gets its fair share of exclusive updates. ‍  V1.7 includes enhanced hydraulic, MCDU, ECAM, and FMGS systems for greater realism, alongside new visual details, failure modes, and operational improvements like quick engine starts and improved terrain rendering.  ‍ The A321XLR also receives a set of exclusive changes, like fuel capabilities that more accurately match the real-life aircraft, the implementation of the RCT fuel panel, and passenger limits that reflect the number of over-wing exits. Here is the complete list of changes provided by ToLiss:New features:- ISCS in EFB- Hydraulic improvement package:	. Added simulation of trapped hydraulic fluid in asymmetric actuators such as landing gear or spoiler actuators.	. Fixed the PTU overheat when ENG1 is failed.- MCDU improvement package:	. CLR command is now indented in scratchpad as in real life	. DIR TO page prefills the RADIAL IN on the DIR TO page as required	. FPLN Page Destination EFOB turns amber, if below minimum required.- ECAM improvement package:	. Overspeed warning now triggers based on actual flap/slat position and not lever position (PFD barber pole is still lever position driven as in real life.)	. Removed duplication of system titles if the same system shows multiple subsequent rows of ECAM messages.	. Weight display logic for SD: Prior to engine start, the dashes are now cyan. Weights now only show after engine start, like in real life.	. Status page improvement: Approach procedures for hydraulic faults	. Rework of the ECAM messages for electrical bus failures to represent a newer FWC standard- FMGS improvement package:	. Added possibility to use Airport ICAO codes as waypoints	. Bug fixes for the path computation leading to an overall much stabler path computation in complex procedures.	. Empty flight plan shows as PPOS / Discon rather than just "End of flpn" and can be built up from there.	. VIA selection is now automatic, if there is exactly one VIA that matches the selected FINAL and STAR.	. Constraints of first waypoint in STAR are not dropped anymore.	- Added cross track error display on ground prior to departure- New failure modes:	. Slow and rapid decompression	. THS jam.	. Cargo smoke, including latched closure of the isolation valves	. Added high lift failures, including loss of SFCC channels and slats/flaps lock	. Windshears with correct REAC W/S detection and indication.- Visual improvement package:	. Added AoA Vanes to fuselage model	. Fixed the tiller textures	. Animated the flap lever guard	. Correct the eye reference ball colors and location	. Fixed text overlaps on the overhead panel- Added new Circuit breakers (for high lift, air conditioning packs, ...) bringing the total to 242- Added pitch influence to the RADALT value, so that the RADALT decreases when you pitch up (like IRL)- Added limitation with filtering to the maximum number of waypoints shown on ND when WPT overlay selected.- Quick starts for engine and APU are now available on the Joystick/Actions tab.- Mapped flight number to x-plane dataref "sim/cockpit2/radios/actuators/flight_id" for third party plugin interfacing.- Improved Master Warning flashing frequency.- Terrain on ND drawing around the airport is now inhibited for areas of same elevation as the airport.- If you select a livery with 2 OWE pairs, the maximum number of passengers will increase to 160.- Added selected heading value on ND, if in ARC mode the heading bug is not visible.- A321neo package specific improvements:	. Adapted fuel capacities for the XLR to the real life values that are now available	. Implemented the new RCT fuel panel for the A321XLR Bug fixes: - Fixed issue with the interaction between the CLR button and the status page - Fixed issue with status page overflow. - The emergency generator now consumes hydraulic fluid. - The magnetic variation model now updates for the current year. - Fixed FMA alignment of armed modes and issue with empty boxes - Extended the permissible value range for FCU speed window to 399kts and Mach 0.99 like in real life - Extended the permissible value range for FCU altitude window to 49000ft like in real life - ISI startup correction: QNH is also visible during ISI startup; moved QNH to right location. - Removed CHG CODE field for other phases than PREFLIGHT or DONE. - Improved string termination on MCDU string datarefs. - Fixed an issue with SID route in alternate plan on first alternate plan programming. - Fixed an issue with waypoints preceded by a discon where the outgoing leg is of the CI/CD/CR/CA or VI/VR/VD type. - Fixed FMA indication for managed descent on profile with significantly too slow speed. - Fixed behaviour of the FCU HDG managed dot when a managed mode (NAV, LOC, APPR) is armed. - Fixed shape of the ADF2 needle on the ND. - Removed GS indication on ND, when the associated ADIRU is OFF or invalid. - Made the deceleration when descending through the SPD LIM altitude smoother. - Fixed issue with the beta target leading to excessive rudder deflection and spoiler extension on the wrong side. - Corrected the color of the RAM Air Inlet indication when open in flight. - Disabled autobrake if 2 or more SECs are lost. - Fixed a bug that could cause sending many requests to the Hoppie network in a short period of time. - Miscellaneous other bug fixes The update is available now for all owners of the ToLiss A321. A clean install from the store is recommended due to the migration of the updater repository. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vrmm12</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases The Maldives for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vrmm12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6760852a77a0b142abb11e5a_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Sim Development Group (FSDG) has just released its newest scenery for X-Plane 12. The developer revisits the Maldives, a region they have previously created sceneries for in other flight simulators. According to FSDG, the scenery includes a detailed and accurate depiction of Velana International Airport (VRMM), featuring its new terminal and a large seaplane base. The scenery also includes the islands of Hulhumalé and several surrounding islands. ‍ Velana International Airport is located on Hulhulé Island in the southern Kaafu Atoll, surrounded by crystal-clear blue water. In recent years the airport has undergone significant changes including the construction of a new code F runway, and a new seaplane terminal. Additionally, a new passenger terminal is under construction, slated for completion in 2025. ‍ A full feature list can be found below: The scenery is now available on the FSDG website for approximately $21. ‍ FSDG promises additional Christmas surprises later this week. For updates on that and more, stay tuned to Threshold. Additionally, remember to join our vibrant community on Discord.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl289</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl289"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/676214f7f4048962925fc0b5_geni1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs recently released their first update for the Airbus A321ceo package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, bringing AOC service performance improvements, EFB enhancements, system tweaks, external model changes, and more. Update v11.0.1.289 incorporates a range of improvements, fixes, and optimizations (in Lefteris Kalamaras’ own words), aiming to enhance functionality and user experience. The key highlights follow below: AOC Service: EFB Enhancements: Systems Improvements: Exterior Model Updates: Sound Enhancements:  Documentation Updates:  ‍ The update is now available through the FSLabs Control Center (Experimental channel).  ‍ The aircraft is available in their store for roughly $69.  Screenshots were gently provided by Genista on Discord. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/erjx12</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Publishes ERJ Family Development Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/erjx12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/676228db8f59052d3782d60f_erj1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts recently published a blog post outlining their plans for a future update to its ERJ Family, which will add many new features and be fully compatible with Laminar Research’s latest flight simulation platform.  ‍ The development update begins with a quick explanation of why the ERJs have not seen many updates since their focus shifted to the E-Jets, which required further attention due to their heavy reliance on automation and increased system complexity.  ‍ When X-Plane 12 came out, X-Crafts intended on making it compatible as soon as possible, but they quickly realized it was not going to be as straightforward of a job as they thought it would due to how different the new simulator was in some ways, rendering the airplane unusable without workarounds. ‍ Addressing the issues would require a lot of extra work and effort, which made creating a compatibility patch rather unfeasible and illogical, given they could rebuild it instead and make a major upgrade out of it rather than just a mere patch.  ‍ They have been working on the ERJ Family v2 upgrade for a while now and feel ready to share how things are progressing and bring a close look at the new features that will accompany the new version. ‍ An industry specialist created the flight model from scratch, fully optimized for X-Plane 12. Real ERJ pilots are currently testing it to ensure it is as accurate as possible within the simulation. Unlike the X-Plane 11 version, where default X-Plane systems drove hydraulics, fuel, and anti-ice systems, v2 will bring custom-made systems and a new and more accurate FADEC system to control the Thrust Rating. The pop-up screens—familiar to E-Jets customers—were also implemented in V2. There is an openable PFD, MFD, and EICAS that can be freely moved around the screen or placed on another display. Autopilot settings can be controlled directly from the pop-up PFD by scrolling while hovering over the values. The nav map has also seen a substantial visual upgrade, with a brand-new, high-resolution display, including the PLAN mode.  They are also working on implementing the Electronic Flight Bag from the E-Jets into the ERJs, which will allow users to control ground objects, doors, performance calculations, weight and balance, and more. A secret set of features—which remains unmentioned—is also in the works. The update will also improve the sounds, taking full advantage of the new audio technologies embedded within X-Plane 12. ‍ Due to the amount of work involved and all the new features, the ERJ v2 Update will not be a free upgrade. They intend to charge a $20 fee for v1 owners, and the base price for new customers will also suffer a slight increase.  ‍ There is no release date yet, but X-Crafts plans on releasing the Lineage 1000 first, which is scheduled to come out before the end of February if everything goes according to plan.  ‍ Please refer to the original blog post for further information on the update. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
