<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-10-05T18:23:10.578694+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/magtij</id>
    <title>MagMexico Releases Tijuana International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/magtij" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650e0cbbf533d63a8b75d3a5_tij.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3132387"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MagMexico has recently released their rendition of Tijuana International Airport (MMTJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the San Diego-Tijuana transborder agglomeration with a yearly average of 12.3 million passengers. ‍ It was inaugurated in 1951 as “Aeropuerto Federal de Tijuana,” with a 2000-meter long runway and a single passenger terminal, that was eventually replaced in 1970 by a much bigger one, part of a $8.7 million project that also included a runway lengthening. ‍ In the 1980s, Tijuana was the fastest-growing city in Mexico, which led to further expansions in that decade. ‍ The airport was privatized in 1995, becoming part of the Pacific Airport Group, which consists of 12 airports, with its headquarters in Guadalajara.  ‍ Under the new helm, it was expanded and renovated in 2002, with many changes to accommodate the Boeing 747. By then, Tijuana was one of the most important airports in Mexico. ‍ A cross-border express bridge was inaugurated in late 2015, allowing passengers to access the airport directly from the United States, with a North American terminal. ‍ Aeroméxico, American Eagle, Calafia Airlines, Mexicana de Aviación, Viva Aerobus, and Volaris serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, animated jetways, dynamic lighting, detailed hangars and buildings, custom ground textures, precise AFCAD, static aircraft and vehicles, animated radar facilities, native volumetric grass and vegetation, and more.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.26, requiring at least 1.24 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxdua</id>
    <title>FlightFX Releases DuPage Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxdua" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/650e1b6110149496041872e2_dupage.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1966346"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightFX has recently released their rendition of DuPage Airport (KDPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the city of West Chicago, Illinois, with a yearly average of 135,000 aircraft movements. ‍ It was built on former sheep-grazing land in the late 1920s by two Chicago entrepreneurs, and the U.S. Army eventually requisitioned it during World War 2 for training purposes. They built hangars and paved two runways, activating it in 1943. The hangar and the runways still exist, although one of the runways is now a taxiway. ‍ Howard Aircraft Corporation opened a factory across the road a year later, in 1944. They built more than 500 aircraft for the military, which was then pushed across the street for testing at the airport.  ‍ The airport was sold back to the county for $1 after the war, followed by a post-war boom that led to a new control tower, a new runway, and expansion plans that only came to fruition almost four decades later. ‍ Midway’s example (being unable to grow because of urban development around it) made the administration hurry to purchase more surrounding land and make it bigger, taking it from 360 hectares to 1,100 hectares by 1992, warranting control over all the property surrounding the runway complex and providing a larger buffer zone.  ‍ It has an FBO offering fuel, parking, de-icing, catering, lavatory services, and a little passenger terminal.  ‍ 95% of the yearly traffic corresponds to general aviation, 4% to air taxi, and less than 1% to military traffic. There are 255 aircraft based at the airport. ‍ They recently opened a U.S. Customs and Border Protection (C.B.P.) facility on the first floor of the DuPage Flight Center FBO. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, built in coordination with the DuPage Airport Authority, with on-site photography of all major facilities used for reference, custom ground textures, high-resolution photographic textures, custom night lighting, interior modeling of key structures, in-hangar parking spaces, static G.A. and corporate aircraft, reworked landscaping, and ambient lighting improvements. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $14.75, requiring at least 2.92 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdbl2</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Delays Block 2 Release for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdbl2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6358191032e01e7ba85063f3_fenix1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3158078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aamir Thacker, Fenix Simulations’ CEO, has made an announcement on their Discord regarding the upcoming IAE update for their A320 add-on, initially scheduled for release in September.  After progressing quickly with the CFM external engine model, they have decided to delay the release of the Block 2 update so that users can get both engines with the new model instead of just the IAEs as previously planned.  Their work on the IAE model made them more familiar with external engine development and significantly sped up the process with the CFMs. The new timeframe for the Block 2 update with both engine models is sometime in October.  They have also confirmed an entirely rebuilt cabin for Block 2, with more detail, increased performance, and a lower VRAM footprint. ‍ The Fenix A320 is available on their website for roughly $60.98, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfszgg</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studio Releases Guangzhou International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfszgg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6511e05c253a653b1b073f1c_zggg1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="101762"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WF Scenery Studio has recently released their rendition of Guangzhou Baiyun International Airport (ZGGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Guangzhou and Foshan with a yearly average of 40.2 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in China. ‍ The airport opened 19 years ago, replacing the former Baiyun Airport (from 1932), which was deemed too small for the predicted passenger figures and unable to be expanded because of urban development around its area. It was built 28 kilometers north of the city, making it immune to curfews and noise restrictions, thus allowing it to operate 24 hours a day.  ‍ It features two terminals, with Terminal 1 having three concourses and Terminal 2 - opened recently - being one of the world’s largest terminal facilities with 808,700 square meters.  ‍ It’s a hub for 9 Air, China Southern Airlines, FedEx Express, Hainan Airlines, and Shenzhen Airlines. As the busiest airport in China, the visitors list is quite substantial and mainly from Asia.  ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, animated jetways, dynamic lights, custom ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $25.31, requiring at least 5.64 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Tang0 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inisou</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Southampton Airport and Release Date for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inisou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6511e0073d60b921fbc5fc5f_image.thumb.png.c3abacbb5482daf71e74dbc25a66cf24.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1003571"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has announced that their next project is Southampton Airport (EGHI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. After initially teasing their next project a few weeks ago with a few screenshots, many eagle-eyed simmers in the community deduced that it was Southampton in the United Kingdom. That was officially confirmed today with a post by iniBuilds on their forum.  Southampton Airport was originally built in World War 1 for the Royal Flying Corps, and in 1917, was handed over to the United States Navy Air Service for a short period of time. It also served in a critical role for ground and air training for the Royal Navy in World War 2. It was also the site of the first flight of the Supermarine Spitfire. In the modern era, the airport is a hub for regional and international travel, and is home to many airlines including British Airways, easyJet, Aer Lingus, and Loganair. It also serves many operations to and from the Channel Islands. In their announcement, iniBuilds said that: “We have gone into extreme detail into this scenery and you can see that we have covered a lot of detail in all areas of the airport.” They also provided an explanation on why they picked Southampton, mainly because many on their scenery team, including their Head of Scenery Development are based in Southampton. Also in their announcement, iniBuilds provided a list of features that can be expected with the upcoming scenery, which include: ‍ They also included a trailer for the airport:  ‍ The scenery will be released on Friday, September 29th with a price of £12.99 excl. VAT, or $15.86 USD. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jin32n</id>
    <title>Head of MSFS: iniBuilds Creating A320neo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jin32n" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6514b10b1bfe043fe0752dba_FS2020-Aircraft-Airbus_A320neo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1283631"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a developer livestream hosted on Twitch on Wednesday, Jorg Neumann, the head of Microsoft Flight Simulator has revealed that UK based developer iniBuilds will be developing an Airbus A320neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 to be included with the release of Sim Update 14.  ‍ According to Neumann, the aircraft will be “completely new” and is “going to sit side-by-side, next to the Asobo A320neo that shipped with launch.” He also elaborated on quality goals, saying, “Quality goal is similar or better than the A310 that you already have and love.” Along with that, he explained why iniBuilds and Asobo wanted to create this aircraft from the ground up: “The reason why we did that is because it’s going to be more complex, and we didn’t want to break all the activities that we’re doing with the A320 already, that would have been a ton of work.” Neumann also confirmed that it will be released along with Sim Update 14, expected to come in late Q4 of 2023, around the holiday season. ‍ This news comes into a market with many different offerings within the Airbus A320 family of aircraft for MSFS. Developers such as Fenix, LatinVFR, FlyByWire, and Aerosoft all either have A320 family products already on the market, or in development as is the case with FlyByWire and Aerosoft. What this news means for these projects is unknown.  ‍ As of the time of writing, iniBuilds, who have previously worked in collaboration with Microsoft and Asobo in bundling their Airbus A310 with the simulator, have not publicly announced what kind of feature set their A320neo would have, let alone its existence.  ‍ As further news comes in about this exciting new development for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Threshold will keep you updated, so stay tuned! </summary>
    <published>2023-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mawu15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Announces World Update XV: Northern Europe and Greenland</title>
    <updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mawu15" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6514df76ed08456e7a5e8230_capture_cover.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="836045"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In the Microsoft September development livestream hosted on Twitch, Microsoft and Asobo have announced World Update 15, which covers Northern Europe and Greenland, in partnership with Gaya Simulations. The update includes many improvements for the landscapes of Scandinavia, including, 5 bespoke airports, new cities with photogrammetry, 90 new Points of Interest, 3 bush trips, 3 discovery flights, 3 landing challenges, and brand new Digital Elevation Maps with a resolution of 40 centimeters.  Nine cities were announced to receive photogrammetry, including Oslo in Norway; Visby, Malmö, and Linköping in Sweden; and Aarhus, Copenhagen, Frederikssund, Roskilde, and Odense in Denmark. A tenth city, Gothenburg, was also teased, but it is still in development and going through further review by the Swedish Military, before being given the full green light.  The 5 hand-crafted airports are: Many of the bespoke airports, as well as the POIs have been created in collaboration with Gaya Simulations, known for their sceneries, and have worked with Microsoft before on World Update 14.  ‍ While an exact release date has not been set for World Update 15, Threshold will keep you updated when it does, so stay tuned for that, and even more high quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ib3an3</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases A300-600's 3D Model for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ib3an3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6515ba0313874d8b4a20b5c1_gabnriel.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1661196"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently published five new screenshots of their upcoming A300-600R(F) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing their work on the engine &amp; APU interior, and more. ‍ While the centerpiece of the teaser is the new images, they also mention that the detailed engine and APU interiors will be part of the maintenance system built into their Electronic Flight Bag. ‍ The Airbus A300-600 was the final variant of the A300 to be ever built (excluding the Beluga), featuring the modern avionics implemented with the A310, bringing a fully featured glass cockpit that removed the need for a flight engineer, an improved wing with a recambered trailing edge, single slotted fowler flaps, and the removal of slat fences. Three hundred thirteen units of the A300-600 were sold, and many are still flying today. ‍ There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msu13r</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 13</title>
    <updated>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msu13r" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651603c1597fbb56b23779c9_sc6vzv.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="219811"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has released Sim Update 13 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which includes many changes, bug fixes and improvements, and community requested fixes. The main focus for this Sim Update was many small fixes and changes to many facets of the simulator.  ‍ The main volume of changes came for the 747-8 and 787-10, which both have received fixes to their avionics by Working Title. Most notably, being the addition of SimBrief integration in both aircraft, as well as the addition of an EFB for the 787. The new EFB also allows for takeoff calculations, which you can send directly to the FMC. Another highly requested feature, step climbs, have also been implemented. ‍ The Garmin glass cockpits have also received improvements and changes courtesy of Working Title. Terrain and Weather Radar improvements have been of primary focus for this update, allowing users to control the gain of the weather radar through the settings pages.  ‍ On their September Development livestream, which happened just yesterday, they provided a list of some of the bigger community requests:  You can read the full list of the myriad of changes that Sim Update 13 brings on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Forums. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ineghi</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Southampton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ineghi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6516fed147230803ed1c7809_south.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="417634"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Southampton Airport (EGHI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Hampshire with a yearly average of 631,458 passengers.  The airport’s history dates back to 1910, when its meadows were used as a take-off and landing spot for monoplanes, then known as Eastleigh Airfield. It was then transformed into an aircraft acceptance base for the Royal Flying Corps during World War 1.  ‍ During the interwar period, the site served as a transit camp for refugees who wished to sail to America. Hangars were converted into dormitories for them.   Southampton Corporation purchased the site in 1932, naming it Southampton Municipal Airport, with part of it being utilized by the RAF after 1935.   Supermarine, a former British aircraft manufacturer, opened a test flight facility there and built a shed. Cunliffe-Owen Aircraft followed suit, later being bought out by Ford and utilized to manufacture Ford Transit vans until its closure in 2013.  During World War 2, the airport was transferred to naval command and renamed HMS Raven, spending most of it as a ground and air training facility. It was handed back to civilian ownership soon after, in 1946.  Thirteen years later, it was purchased by a racing pilot and began its transformation into a proper regional airport, with a concrete runway in 1963 and a railway station right beside it.   It’s served by Aer Lingus, Aurigny, Blue Islands, British Airways (seasonally), Eastern Airways, easyJet, KLM, and Loganair.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-crafted ground textures, a true-to-life landside recreation, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, an up-to-date layout, fully modeled local points of interest, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.85, requiring at least 2.47 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsschi</id>
    <title>FSSDesigner Releases La Chinita International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsschi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651706bd88d5780dcbdcd5cd_chi.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="276583"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSSDesigner has recently released their rendition of La Chinita International Airport (SVMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Venezuelan city of Maracaibo with a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers (as of 2008).  It opened in 1969, creating a gateway to western Venezuela and consequently alleviating the traffic on Simon Bolivar International Airport, serving the capital city of Caracas.  ‍ Nowadays, it’s the third busiest airport in the country, only behind Caracas and Porlamar. ‍ It’s served by Avior Airlines, Conviasa, Copa Airlines, LASER Airlines, RUTACA Airlines, Turpial Airlines, and Venezolana. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom taxiway signage, custom approach lighting systems, GSX compatibility, custom static objects, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.44, requiring at least 867.65 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfstaw</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Tawau Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfstaw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6518738547ce331c55baa8b2_taw1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="682575"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Tawau Airport (WBKW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Tawau Division in Malaysia with a yearly average of 572,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was opened in 2001, replacing the former Tawau Airport, whose runway was one of the shortest in the country, and the administration decided to build a new airport from scratch instead of dealing with extra expansion work (that they had previously conducted in the 60s and 80s).  ‍ ‍ With a 2,685-meter-long runway, a much bigger terminal building, an instrument landing system, and night certification, the new Tawau Airport became an essential asset to the region’s economy.  ‍ It is currently suffering from limited capacity issues, with expansion plans to increase the numbers to at least 2.5 million passengers annually.  AirAsia, Firefly, Malaysia Airlines, MASwings, and MYAirline serve it. ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, custom groundpoly, custom jetways, and AI traffic compatibility.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.71, requiring at least 1.01 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgbsb</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Teases Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgbsb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65187ccd758cc3b372e8acd3_bsb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="691720"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently shared screenshots of their progress on Brasilia - President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR), the third busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. ‍ A proper terminal building was inaugurated in 1971, designed by Tércio Fontana Pacheco, a Brazilian Air Force architect. ‍ The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more, divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. ‍ New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. ‍ It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. ‍ The upcoming scenery is said to feature animated moving walkways, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, detailed landside, and more. There’s no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrs108</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Lays Plans for X-Plane 12.0.8 and Beyond</title>
    <updated>2023-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrs108" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651c786fa41cb40d1c0c88c1_a330.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="262358"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has made a blog post summarizing what is planned for X-Plane 12's recent future, including a new versioning scheme, engine model improvements, improved landing gear physics, and more. ‍ With the recently shipped 12.07, Laminar included three months' worth of rendering engine improvements, new cirrus clouds, lower VRAM footprint, improved cloud rendering, and OpenXR integration. For the next update, they have already laid out most of the futures that will ship with it.  ‍ The upcoming patch will bring a new naming scheme, giving Laminar "more numbers to play with," as the previous two digits could only go so far and, therefore, limit the number of patches they could potentially churn out.  ‍ They expect a beta build to be ready in a week or two, focusing on improving the flight model, networking/multi-monitor, and tools for using X-Plane with projectors: projector warping/blending will be available for X-Plane Professional license owners. ‍ With data from Pratt &amp; Whitney and Phillip Ringler, Austin Meyer has improved how the platform simulates engine performance, with jets, turboprops, and reciprocating engines following real-world figures more closely.  ‍ The landing gear physics was also improved, with better wheel inertia, weld modeling, and ABS revisions, making sure it stops the wheels from locking realistically. ‍ Last but not least, jet aircraft in X-Plane 12 will now accurately simulate how jets use their fuel to cool their oil, with the oil heating the fuel and its consequent dissipation through the wing's skin, operating as a radiator.  ‍ They have also laid out plans for 12.1.0, bringing real weather improvements, cloud shadows on the water, better bloom lighting effects, robust contrast adaptive sharpening, softer ground shadows, MSAA improvements, improved CPU performance, and better water opacity. ‍ They finish with a price hike announcement, from $59.99 to $79.99, allowing Laminar to expand its team and warrant its future development. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsipvu</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Provo Municipal Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsipvu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651dec48b559ecb068fde964_pvu.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="583290"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Provo Municipal Airport (KPVU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Provo in Utah with a yearly average of 145,000 passengers. ‍ Originally an uncontrolled airport, its control tower was built in 2005, followed by major improvements to the terminal in 2011, bringing it up to the required standard to receive airline service.  ‍ After three years of work, a brand new passenger terminal was completed in 2022 at a total cost of $40 million. It has four gates and can be expanded to ten in the future. Allegiant has announced plans to open a four-aircraft base at the airport, with Breeze following suit. Both are the only airlines operating in Provo. ‍ With two FBOs and a flight school, it’s also a significant regional general aviation airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a full 1:1 terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, high-definition PBR textures, custom orthophoto, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on Verticalsim’s Shop for $14.99, requiring at least 1.89 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsq850</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases TBM 850 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsq850" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/651ec4e1b0116e311d9bc3d1_tbm.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="299595"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently released their rendition of the Daher TBM 850 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a high-performance single-engine turboprop plane introduced in 1990, with 1,000 built as of October 2020 across multiple variants. ‍ Its development dates back to the 1980s when Mooney and SOCATA (the original manufacturer of the TBM) started a joint venture to develop a new, enlarged turboprop design. It was marketed as the TBM 700 and became the world’s first high-performance single-engine passenger aircraft to enter production. ‍  The sales were booming, creating new variants and model improvements, which eventually resulted in the TBM 850’s release in 2008, offering 850 horsepower instead of 700, a modern avionics system, and a ceiling of 31,000ft.  ‍ ‍ Black Square’s TBM 850 brings nearly 100 possible failures, persistence, realistic 3D gauges, multiple navigation systems varying from the Bendix KNS-80 to a Garmin GTN 750, along with com radios, a transponder, and a weather radar. It also includes a 100-page manual with usage instructions. It was built from the ground up, meaning it’s not part of their Steam Gauge Overhaul series and is said to be their most advanced aircraft so far. ‍ The newly released TBM 850 is available for $41.99 on Just Flight, requiring at least 502 MB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
