<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-06-12T18:25:03.943859+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oblmme</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Landmarks Melbourne for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oblmme" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629c27e343478aa71debd393_2-99a69df0352e53b3fa7c31060b20f1e6.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="776134"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Australian scenery-maker Orbx has today announced the forthcoming release of a landmarks pack based in their home city, Melbourne. The company’s head office is located at Essendon Fields Airport, which they have also recreated in-sim. “Welcome to the cultural and sports capital of Australia and the hometown of Orbx! With about a third of its current five million residents born outside of Australia, Melbourne’s skyline mirrors its inhabitants’ diversity, from Gold Rush and Victorian architecture to ultra-modern skyscrapers. Moreover, the city is home to Australia’s second busiest airport, Tullamarine (YMML) and its busiest seaport.” “While World Update 7 Australia added photogrammetry to Melbourne and about a dozen Orbx-made POIs, this new  Melbourne pack has another 200 custom-made buildings and structures, along with the many other enhancements and features our Landmarks series is known for.” The group have also added a number of animated features to the bustling city, including metro trains, hot air balloons and horses at two of Melbourne’s racecourses. The following feature list was provided: Check out World Update VII, which Orbx played a hand in creating, here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obkboi</id>
    <title>Orbx Boise for Microsoft Flight Simulator Available Now</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obkboi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629c90ec70a3b2347002e50c_2-209d23f7bf69ae55bfa70ea80a5c2f77.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="748742"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Idaho’s Boise Air Terminal has now seen an entry in Microsoft Flight Simulator courtesy of Orbx, who’ve made the city's Gowen Field their latest release for the platform.  The airport serves a dual civilian/military purpose and is also home to the state’s largest building — the control tower, which stands at a not-so-impressive 295ft or approximately 90 metres. Orbx’s rendition for the sim includes the following features: Boise is served by eight airlines in the current day, with a route network of 26 destinations. This is in stark contrast to its previous passenger-serving efforts, in which customers previously awaited their aircraft in what the developer describes as an ‘ageing Varney Airlines (now United) hangar’. The rather more modern, current terminal was opened in 2003. You can purchase Orbx Boise for $16.70 AUD (approx. US$12.04 | €11,23 | £9.64) from OrbxDirect.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inissa</id>
    <title>iniScene Development Update: KSAT Previewed, KBUF Coming to X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inissa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629d19e18cf55655316b0708_image.thumb.png.7e7cc59bccface0bcae0f3a1b0c22659.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="706950"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery-making subsidiary of development house iniBuilds, iniScene, has seen a busy last couple of months -- firstly with the release of Buffalo-Niagara (KBUF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator as well as the forthcoming release of San Antonio (KSAT) for the same platform. In a development update published today, the team have given some insight into the next steps moving forwards from three of their current projects. Ubaid Mussa, iniBuilds chief executive, addressed the group’s London Heathrow rendition first. “To start the year, in January we released our first mega-airport iniScene London Heathrow EGLL for Microsoft Flight Simulator.” “This was a fantastic project and we worked with some great people who engage with the airport daily to create a faithful rendition. Being our first mega-airport we learnt a lot, and as you can always expect from us, have reflected and are working on an update covering performance, night lighting and greater detail on road markings.” iniScene have opened a forum thread for users to share their wish-list for a free update to the product, which you can find here. Mussa confirms that iniScene London Heathrow will not be making its way to Prepar3D or X-Plane at this time. Turning their most recent release, Buffalo, the team express their thanks for great community reception to the product -- it is also now confirmed that work has started on the X-Plane 11 rendition of KBUF, which will see the light of day in further development updates. San Antonio is the final topic brought up in today's development update. Mussa acclaims iniScene's work as 'some of our best', and that KSAT will bring details 'not seen before in some of our other products'. "We plan to start release preparations for this airport very soon, and are working on the final details!" In addition to KSAT we are currently working on a few other projects which we will share more information on in the next couple of months along with a brand new product offering for you heli pilots. The CEO says a development update regarding iniBuilds' aircraft project will come in due course.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asa330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Showcases A330 Progress for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asa330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629d3bfab6eba1b253885528_A330_VC_001.jpg.7c42a2b930c392aedf55d403fdf5ca75.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="232195"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Airbus A330 will mark the third Microsoft Flight Simulator aircraft release for German developer Aerosoft, creators of one of the platforms' first complex products in the form of the CRJ series. Earlier this week, the development house provided new previews inside and out of Airbus' smallest widebody as well as some additional insight into various features. Aerosoft founder and spokesperson Mathijs Kok once again did the honours. He was careful to note that despite virtual cockpit 3D work being complete, the team is yet to add in decals and weathering -- essentially, these previews are not entirely representative of the final product. In a subsequent post on the same forum thread, Kok shares some new exterior previews too. When questioned by one community member about the apparent 'dumbing down' of Aerosoft's Twin Otter for the Xbox platform and whether this would be mirrored in the A330, Kok had this to say. "I do not know why you think that, the modelling and texturing were absolutely not dumbed down, was simple not needed. Nor will the A330 be. Both are optimized for Xbox use though, meaning they are fully done with MSFS technology. So not 8K textures but 2K with decals ending up with detail." A price has not been decided for Aerosoft's A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, nor a release date as yet.  You can find the original previews on the forum thread for the aircraft here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mynnfs</id>
    <title>Sierrasim Announces Nassau-Lynden Pindling for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mynnfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629d53fcacf98ec96a558cad_285190442_3484183708475644_8869966591637855385_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="181174"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Scenery developer Sierrasim Simulation has announced their latest product for Microsoft Flight Simulator: Nassau’s Lynden Pindling Airport (MYNN) in the Bahamas. The airport will be native to the platform, as the development group has not previously tackled Nassau for other simulators. The news was publicised via Facebook, in which is short post was shared. “Coming Soon - MYNN- Lynden Pindling International Airport MSFS PC/Xbox" Watch this space for further news. Check out the group's previous release, Olaya Herrera Airport (SKMD), in another article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdnapl</id>
    <title>RDPresets Debut Naples Airport in Latest Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdnapl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629db7d8db3dbefc6a0d23c8_wing-tra-737_orig.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1701430"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Creators of Rotterdam-The Hague for Microsoft Flight Simulator, RDPresets have announced that Naples’ airport will be their next pursuit for the platform.  With this news the developer doubles the number of projects they’ve got on the go, as work on Marseille continues concurrently. “[Marseille] has hit some major bumps in the road, some items failed our Quality Assurance and are requiring some remodelling, this will take time and has set Marseille back two release slots, meaning as it stands two other airports will come before it." The developer explains that the delay is necessary to ensure quality. "But this does allow me to announce you our first new airport which is in Italian [sic], “Aeroporto di Napoli”." "We’re incredibly proud of how this product is currently being developed and it’s going at an incredible pace. We’re using a new texture method ensuring a higher texture resolution, but at the same time using less texture sets. "It took us some time to perfect this and arguably we’re still learning it, but we feel it is really good already and worthy enough to put it above our current Rotterdam airport quality." RDPresets want to go 'the extra mile' in ground detailing with Naples, saying that the final product will 'truly give you an idea of arriving or departing [at an airport with proper weathering]. They have not offered a release date as yet, but maintain that the first in-sim images of Naples will debut shortly. It was also revealed in the development update that the brand is working on a hub software for their products. The software will be called RDHome. See the source post for this article on the RDPresets website.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mvpcce</id>
    <title>Milviz Discusses Updates for PC-6 Porter and Cessna 310R</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mvpcce" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629e70ea2b797332fd34fdff_286338871_5346744258703239_4442868559021534495_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="465253"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The tail-dragging turboprop PC-6 Porter from Milviz will shortly see an update according to developers, who are currently working on 'stage 2' of the Pilatus craft. The aircraft was first released for Microsoft Flight Simulator in September 2021 in a typical land-faring configuration. Milviz's stage 2 is set add floats and tundra tyres to the available set-ups. An option for an older steam gauge cockpit with 'multiple radio options' will also be available according to the developer. Speaking to the status of the update, the team had this to say -- "Development is ongoing, but we are a bit behind schedule. Hope to have some pics with the floats in the coming weeks." Stage 2 of Milviz's PC-6 Porter will see a price rise for new customers, but existing users will be able to upgrade for free. The developer says that your initial purchase will entitle you to any future updates for this products. In the same Facebook post, the team also made brief mention of their latest release, the Cessna 310R. The twin piston craft's service pack is "nearly finished!" See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42mex</id>
    <title>Parallel42 Announces New Airstrip; 'Scenes' to Sell Separately</title>
    <updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42mex" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629ef27127ce87013d8a92d5_0_bETJs4vXIrxSLDhT.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="289353"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Parallel42 continues their unique ‘scenes’ series with Mexican Mountain, a bush camping spot in Green River, Utah. The series is tailor-made for the group’s FreedomFox aircraft, which was released in December 2021. ‘Scenes’, small fictional airstrips dotted around Microsoft Flight Simulator’s backcountry, come free to customers of the FreedomFox and are stocked with plenty of room to park up on multiplayer adventures.  Edson Soriano, managing director at Parallel42 commented that the dioramas “continue bringing value to your time flying FF/F2.” The latest creation in the series, Mexican Mountain — which has been given the fictional ICAO ‘42MX’ — has been made in collaboration with several real-world pilots operating in the area. Green River makes for a dramatic backdrop for bush flying, with large elevation changes, ridges, cliffs and pinnacles but to name a few prominent features. “Mexican Mountain truly is…out there, the views are tremendous, &amp; you’ll have plenty of places to practice STOL landings nearby and you’re a short hop away from Moab.” Mexican Mountain will be available for free to owners of the FreedomFox Complete Package (incl. all Orbx customers) and will be available separately on the Microsoft Marketplace for $7.99 USD.  Starting with Mexican Mountain, previously released ‘scenes’ will also be migrated to the Marketplace so users without the FreedomFox Complete Package can use the strips too.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ownrel</id>
    <title>RWY26 Debuts in MSFS with Teaser &amp; Release of Owen Roberts Intl. Airport</title>
    <updated>2022-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ownrel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629ff2f20ddc54e420f6d68a_omg.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="528129"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A few hours ago, Runway 26 Simulations has officially made their debut on Microsoft Flight Simulator with the announcement of their first product on the platform, Owen Roberts International Airport (MWCR). Shortly after the news drop, the team got it released on SimMarket. The real airport is the main international gateway for the Cayman Islands. Consisting of a single 2,398 runway with a recently upgraded terminal, the airport is home to the nation’s flag carrier, Cayman Airways and sees over 1 million passengers traversing through the airport. The airport is a major facilitator to Cayman Islands’ reliance on imported goods, processing 1.5 million and a quarter of a million pounds of cargo and mail respectively. In a Facebook post briefly captioned “Behold... First scenery for MSFS2020…” The team also dropped a trailer on their YouTube channel, providing a quick walkthrough of the airport rendition. On the product page, there’s not much in the way of information, with the notable omission of a basic feature list. We do know that it comes at a rather light 175MB package. The developer is recognised for its scenery creations focused around Central America, and the push into MSFS with the West Carribean airport is something to be expected. If you’re up for some scenic flying, you could begin your journey by exploring George Town. The airport, priced at 15 Euros - is an accessible ask. Presumably, this will mark the beginning of more caribbean airports to come, particularly from Runway 26, stay tuned as we’ll keep you in the loop on future developments from the development team.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcf15u</id>
    <title>DC Designs Updates F-15 Eagle for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcf15u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1c2c7136b9a0e4636524f_284544172_3265782867076023_2111639058208303226_n.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="416453"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Military aircraft developer DC Designs have released a new update for their F-15 Eagle product for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The McDonnell Douglas craft was first made available on the platform in January 2021. The update was quietly added to the Just Flight website today, with some of the main drawcards being a new fly-by-wire control system and re-done cockpit and instrument panels. Here’s the full changelog: DC Designs’ F-15 Eagle, which includes the C, D, E and I variants, is available for purchase through Just Flight’s online store. It retails at $40.99 USD.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/assfra</id>
    <title>Aviotek Showcase First Screenshots of Frankfurt (EDDF) for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/assfra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1c7c791183b53a0b7ef48_287006497_1925031934362597_6289553976030141825_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="136348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Being both Germany’s busiest airport and Lufthansa’s primary hub, Flughafen Frankfurt is a large undertaking for any scenery developer, perhaps none less so than Aviotek Simulation Software, whom began on the airport in late 2020. Today, the group published the first in-simulator screenshots of EDDF, which will be coming to both X-Plane and Microsoft Flight Simulator. It appears to be the former that the developer tackles first, as the images, posted on Facebook, come from Laminar’s sim. X-Plane has traditionally been the home of Aviotek, who have previously released five products for the platform via X-Aviation. “Now it’s time to fill the ramp with our pretty vehicles and equipment,” reads the social media post. “There are still some improvements required, objects to be placed and bugs to fix, but the team is working day and night to deliver the best rendition possible for both the simulators, so you can really feel-there.” There is no release date or price that has been made available as yet. It is also not clear whether the Microsoft Flight Simulator rendition of Frankfurt will be available at the same time. You can find out more about Aviotek’s Frankfurt project in a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vskboi</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Announces Boise for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vskboi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1ced70fb718609759fdbf_287024476_4807808412656800_2786903833022319994_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="161459"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Boise’s relatively small airfield makes headlines for the second time this week with another developer announcing they’re bringing Gowen Field to Microsoft Flight Simulator. This time, the creator is Verticalsim. The scenery-maker has previously covered KBOI in X-Plane and in-line with previous releases, is now working on bringing their extensive catalogue of products for Laminar’s sim over to Microsoft Flight Simulator. Verticalsim published the following feature list with the announcement: Though a release date has not been mentioned, users likely won’t have to wait long for Boise to launch as based on previous releases Verticalsim tends to have a very short turnaround. Threshold will keep you posted.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ausham</id>
    <title>AUscene Teases Hamilton Island Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ausham" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1d4302cfb6ba96ea3783d_284513968_514946167039563_5900949890880924501_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="218117"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Australian tourist destination Hamilton Island and its airport, YBHM, has received more attention today in the form of a new development update from AUscene. The airfield is one of two projects the developer currently has underway for Microsoft Flight Simulator. On release, Hamilton Island will move alongside the developer’s ‘Reefworld’ area scenery covering the Great Barrier Reef. The two will be offered as a bundle pack due to their proximity. Today’s development update focused on the terminal’s interior, which the developer initially debated whether to include at all. “After much consideration we decided to add the Terminal Interior and are excited to finally be able to share some previews with you all! Hamilton Island will be our most extensive product with plenty of details for you to discover at the Airport, Marina, Resort and Dent Island.” See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdsrr</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Releases Sedona Red Rocks for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdsrr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a40727f36d7d0ea90ba84a_Screen%20Shot%202022-06-10%20at%2011.08.20%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2179245"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, X-Codr Designs released Sedona Red Rocks for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery, which comes with detailed models/textures and custom orthoimagery, will provide users with an immersive flight in the stunning Sedona region of Arizona, allowing them to experience the area’s famous geological wonders. According to the developers, an array of different rock formations ranging from Cathedral Rock to Capitol Butte are hand modeled and textured after their real life counterparts in Sedona.  ‍ Additionally, NAIP orthoimagery has beenused to “cover up glaring shadows” while performance has been optimized to minimize the scenery’s impact on the users’ computers. Finally, Sedona Airport (default or X-Codr’s upcoming rendition) has been seamlessly blended into this product. For a complete list of features,, visit the developer’s website. Currently, the Sedona Red Rocks by X-Codr Designs can be purchased in the MSFS MarketPlace for $14.99 USD. For other Microsoft Flight Simulator news, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lmmelb</id>
    <title>Landmarks Melbourne by Orbx Now Available</title>
    <updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lmmelb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a523d5c1fdbb460479f0d5_629-da56ab81442ca2bd8215be740378f006.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1383373"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Home to the Australian Open, the Australian Grand Prix, and Orbx's Australian Headquarters, Melbourne is the group's latest destination in the Landmarks series and was made available yesterday. The product boasts another 200 points of interest over the simulator's default skyline from World Update 7 -- which Orbx also had a hand in creating. "Welcome to the cultural and sports capital of Australia and the hometown of Orbx!" reads the product description. "With about a third of its current five million residents born outside of Australia, Melbourne’s skyline mirrors its inhabitants’ diversity, from Gold Rush and Victorian architecture to ultra-modern skyscrapers." The feature list reads: Landmarks Melbourne is available for $17.89 AUD (US$12.62 | €11,99 | £10.24) from OrbxDirect. To see more images, check out a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrpro</id>
    <title>FSRealistic Pro Released</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrpro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a52b4474c14f14cf317a77_unknown%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3111061"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Effects management system FSRealistic 'Core' has now been available for seven months, having been initially released in November 2021. In the time since, rkApps have taken to improving upon the work seen in that product with the new FSRealistic Pro. The 'Pro' version builds upon the effects included in 'Core', with the developer proclaiming a "growing list of 28" different interactions. Speaking to Threshold, the developer explains the leap forward that the 'Pro' version has made:  "After a long period of time that Asobo didn't support camera movements, it has recently released a partial support and we have now finally managed to make a breakthrough with amazing real camera effects to create a more-than-ever realistic flight experience." "We are proud to be the first company to offer such level of realism and excited to offer you [the chance] to join the ride!" FSRealistic Pro is available for EUR 28.00 from simMarket here. Users of 'Core' are able to upgrade at a discounted price of EUR 5.60. Threshold is giving away two copies of FSRealistic Pro to readers of this article. To enter, simply write a comment below this article. The winners will be drawn in 24 hours.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
