<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-02-12T19:13:15.870093+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orblandperth</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Landmarks Perth City Pack for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orblandperth"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697c67bc7818f1668870592b_per1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released a landmark pack for Perth (Australia), designed to complement their new Perth International Airport (YPPH) airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The comprehensive pack aims to bring Perth to life with its vibrant skyline, adding hand-crafted custom models to further improve the experience when flying in and out of Perth International. There are over 40 custom-modeled buildings around the city, along with improvements to vegetation, better object placement (buildings, bridges, static boats, vessels, and cranes), custom night lighting around Elizabeth Quay, an airstrip at Langley Park for landings in the city centre, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.56, requiring at least 2.55 GB of free hard disk space to install. There’s also a bundle with the landmarks pack and Perth airport, offering a 10% discount.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidfwnew</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares New Previews of Upcoming Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidfwnew"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697c6b5a04d151fa56087d5c_dfw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently shared a couple of new screenshots of their upcoming Dallas/Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, set to release soon.  DFW is the third-busiest airport in the world, with an average of 82 million passengers per year. As expected from such figures, the airport’s size is quite substantial, and not many developers have tried to tackle it in the past.  iniBuilds claims to have captured every corner of the airport, bringing an incredible hub experience to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The scenery promises an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom high-definition jetways, a high-resolution ground poly, performance-friendly optimization, over 180 hand-crafted models, custom ground service equipment, and much more. There’s no pricing or release date yet, but iniBuilds says it’s “coming soon”. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kdfwre</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kdfwre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697d24a797a8a9478ab897a3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just released its version of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This airport serves the Dallas–Fort Worth–Arlington metropolitan area and was the world’s fourth-busiest airport by passenger traffic last year, welcoming an impressive 85.6 million passengers. The airport began commercial operations in 1974 under the name Dallas/Fort Worth Regional Airport. It was renamed Dallas/Fort Worth International in 1985. Initially, the airport had just four terminals, but it has since expanded to five, with plans for a sixth terminal underway. With seven runways, the airport accommodates nearly 90 million passengers each year. It serves a variety of airlines and is a hub for American Airlines, Ameriflight, Southern Airways Express, and UPS Airlines, while also serving as a base of operations for Frontier Airlines and Spirit Airlines. These airlines, along with many others, offer destinations worldwide. iniBuilds has included a comprehensive set of features in the scenery package. It features highly detailed models of all airport buildings, objects, and surrounding areas, as well as a full HD ground polygon. The airport layout is up-to-date, and it includes high-definition jetways and dynamic airport lighting. Additionally, the package contains a fully modelled and animated Skylink Air Train system, among a variety of other features. The newly released Dallas Fort Worth International Airport is now available from iniBuilds for $27.57. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia340109</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia340109"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697d8c6a45b2779e35785123_a340lol.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, focusing on system stability, operational accuracy, and visual refinements across multiple liveries and models. ​ Update v1.0.9 includes fixes to FMGS, navigation systems, CPDLC/ACARS, and flight planning logic, along with mitigations for performance calculation, waypoint handling, auto-flight, and indications. Furthermore, it also refines visuals across multiple liveries and models, restores a few missing callouts, and improves their timing and behaviour. The complete changelog follows below: V1.0.9SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED SayIntentions - After receiving a handover, the DCDU no longer shows the active ATC UnitFIXED SayIntentions - Unable to request ATIS via CPDLC / ATC MenuFIXED Missed approach was shown in green in the MCDUFIXED Direct To issueFIXED FPLN A, DTO clips TO wpt NM textFIXED ACARS flight log page 2 bugsFIXED ACARS post flight report message not triggering COMPANY MSG in EWDFIXED FADEC not powering off as expectedFIXED ND FIX range rings not drawing centered on selected fixFIXED Beyond ATC integration not working as expected (CPDLC / METAR / ATIS)FIXED No DISCON to IAF when selecting STAR without VIAFIXED WIND request missing RETURN promptFIXED Engine 1 controls reverse indication for all four enginesFIXED Unable to enter 0°C temperature into PERF REQ pageFIXED DEPART REQ fields not auto-populating after INIT requestFIXED SID not listed in alphabetical orderFIXED Entering navaid on NDB R field blanks the page after briefly showing identifierFIXED Issues with Along Track WaypointsFIXED Issues with datalink system implementationFIXED Not possible to enter a custom ETP1 waypoint on the FIX INFO pageFIXED Heading bug disappearing on mini-compass rose in PFD while not in managed HDG modeFIXED DEGE3W INTCPT KLO R252 not shownFIXED Manually adding a constraint above FL100 automatically adds 250 knotsFIXED 10,000 ft speed limit waypoint inserted too earlyFIXED Format and calculation issues on INIT B and FUEL PRED pagesFIXED Company message FMC message not showing on FO side FMSFIXED APU door closes even without any electrical power FIXED Incorrect HDG maintained when on TRUEFIXED Course pointer incorrect in ND when on FIXED Unable to enter pilot waypoint on FIX INFO page FIXED Reference thrust indication switching to climb thrust immediately after liftoffFIXED Company Message memo remaining on after all messages viewedFIXED DDRMI compass card not showing TRUE heading when selected FIXED MCDU datalink status page issues ART 🎨FIXED Aerolíneas Argentinas missing engine decalsFIXED HiFly 9H-TQM missing under-wing registrationFIXED TAP CS-TOC missing under-wing registrationFIXED Fuel jettison valve black color lostFIXED Lufthansa livery updateFIXED GPU cable clipping through connection cableFIXED VIP livery Iran EP-IGA right winglet decal clipping / incorrect angleFIXED Light bleeding through couch backrestFIXED HiFly TQZ small line below right-hand stabilizer SOUNDS🔊 FIXED Printer paper sound split in two FIXED Flap sound delayed on first extension FIXED EVAC HORN OFF not silencing cockpit horn FIXED Missing RA callouts (90 / 80 / 70 / 5) FIXED Flap sounds delayed when moving from Flaps 0 to Flaps 1 FIXED Hundred Above and Minimum callouts tonal mismatchFIXED ISIS STD QNH button playing double-click sound FIXED No Smoking sign missing tone FIXED Cockpit door open / close sound only playing when inside cockpit ‍ It’s available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $61.92, requiring at least 7.02 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a350121</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a350121"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68042934f3c420d62ca6c3da_china2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, refining systems and usability, delivering multiple bug fixes, and improving overall consistency across all phases of flight. Update v1.2.1 focuses on greatly improving the FMGS, navigation, VNAV, and auto-flight behavior, whilst also addressing a variety of bugs affecting the general flight experience. It also brings improvements to thrust logic, true north handling, etc. The complete changelog follows below: V1.2.1SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED Cannot enter AIRINC fixesFIXED Cannot click DIR TO box to input textFIXED PERF DES Page – PRED TO time value always incorrectFIXED Issue with cancel button clickspot on OISFIXED No rudder deflection shown on F/CTRL page on groundFIXED Predicted wind/speed ECAM with all WXR settings selectedFIXED Landing report not displayingFIXED FO MFD cursor not aligned with mouseFIXED True north reference missingFIXED Non-standard GP angles shown incorrectly on NAV RAD pageFIXED A/THR not disconnecting via instinctive pushbuttonFIXED Direct To clearing out flight plan in edge casesFIXED Issue converting speed to Mach when switching AP speed modeFIXED QNH value flashing on power-on with no MCDU dataFIXED Engine oil quantity indicationFIXED OPT and REC MAX FL decreasing after step climbFIXED Default transition altitude incorrectFIXED VNAV and PFD indication issues on RNP approachesFIXED Rudder indicator showing pedal position instead of actual rudderFIXED Terrain texture flickering on VSDFIXED Disengaging ATHR during climb gives incorrect thrust modeFIXED Floating bracket and ETP logic brokenFIXED NEW DEST in SEC FPLN not starting from selected pointFIXED AWY/WPT mismatch in secondary flight plansFIXED POSITION/MONITOR page BRG/DIST logic issuesFIXED Unable to create hold around custom waypoint in secondary planFIXED FD OFF HDG/TRK bug disappearing from NDFIXED Keyboard input issue when entering NEXT WPTFIXED DIR TO lat/long not working on NDFIXED DTO field remembering previous entry if not executedFIXED Entering FROM P.POS DIR TO not showing waypoint on next pageFIXED Cannot enter first SID from dropdown listFIXED Odd vertical deviation dashed path shownFIXED ND range indications displacedFIXED RTE SUMMARY database logic issueADDED Cancel or reset button on ATC COM D-ATIS page ART 🎨FIXED Improve cabin lightingFIXED GPU models clipping with GSX heavy pushback trucksFIXED Co-pilot model missing by defaultFIXED Pilot models missing from external cameraFIXED Spoiler animation slowing excessively near end of travelFIXED Beacon light spalsh refinedFIXED Missing ADF antennasFIXED Brake smoke effect triggering too soonFIXED Strobe effects missing physical double-flash EFB📱FIXED Autocovers option not workingFIXED ACARS pending update stuck and METAR symbol issuesFIXED Keyboard input issues affecting EFB entriesADDED EFB option to adjust cabin lighting SOUND 🔊FIXED RA callouts delayed near touchdownFIXED Certain RA callouts missingFIXED Minimum and Hundred Above callout tone mismatchFIXED APU and engine fire test volume too low with ANR enabledFIXED Engine 2 throttle lever missing soundsFIXED Split printer sounds in FS24 ‍ It’s available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $82.57, requiring at least 13.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcraep20</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Announces Airport Enhancement Package 2.0 for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcraep20"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697d958615d4f4125fbdc969_klax-mid-after.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr has recently announced a substantial update to their Airport Enhancement Package add-on for X-Plane, bringing procedurally generated life to over 36,000 airports around the globe. While the original AEP focused on replacing key assets (ground textures, common buildings, and service vehicles), AEP 2.0 aims to add to airports, not just replace assets around them. After months of development and tinkering, the developer has managed to create a program that reads and understands the global airports, procedurally generating overlays that greatly enhance the experience with tire skids on taxi routes, runways, and service roads, additional clutter at gates and near buildings, grunge, oil leaks, rust, and random ramp clutter, yielding a more lifelike experience around every airport in the simulator. While the procedural generation is the new star of the show, it doesn’t mean AEP no longer replaces assets, with over a thousand custom assets in total, including new pavement textures, service vehicles, new cars, all of the legacy hangars (and new ones), and various clutter objects. There are a couple of things that are still being worked on before release, such as more baggage cart variants, old long metal hangars, cargo area clutter, stability testing for a new feature yet to be announced, and beta testing. They also use this opportunity to seek people willing to help stress-test the new product and aid in shaping the final release through their contact page or Discord.  Furthermore, the developer has also mentioned that it will be a free upgrade for AEP 1.0 owners. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/afl7m0226</id>
    <title>AirfoilLabs Provides 737 MAX Development Update</title>
    <updated>2026-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/afl7m0226"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697fbf63aca5820403823dd6_AFL737MAX8-2026-01-3023_46_28.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AirfoilLabs has recently shared a development update on their upcoming Boeing 737 MAX for X-Plane. The update primarily focuses on exterior modelling, animation systems for future failure implementation, and progress on the display suite. Both the tail and wings have undergone extensive modifications. AirfoilLabs reports that the work on the rudder and horizontal stabiliser is now complete, featuring fully animated systems, new textures with PBR, and added vibration effects. The wings have also been improved. For instance, the geometry has been refined, and separate components such as the slats, flaps, and spoilers have received individual animations. AirfoilLabs stated that the engines have undergone a complete overhaul, including animations for the engine cowling and cover, mesh enhancements, reverser animations and more. The display systems have undergone significant improvements, and many are now complete. Below is a comprehensive list provided by AirfoilLabs: No release date for the 737 MAX has been announced yet. AirfoilLabs states that the next steps include further work on the exterior model, animations, and avionics. ‍ For more details on the AirfoilLabs 737 MAX, check out the development update. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdcape</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Cape Verde Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdcape"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698192060a8b67a2d031d26b_cape1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Amílcar Cabral International Airport (GVAC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Espargos, Sal, in Cape Verde, with an average of 1.2 million passengers per year. It was built in 1939 by the Italians as a pit stop for flights from Europe to South America, though their involvement ended quickly due to World War 2. It wasn’t until the end of the conflict that Portugal purchased it from Italy and began its completion, becoming fully operational by 1949. For a bit more than a decade, between 1963 and 1975, the Portuguese Air Force operated at the airport, providing support to military air connections between Portugal and its African provinces and serving as an operational base for patrol aircraft occasionally deployed there. To this day, it’s still an important stopover for international flights and one of the most common ETOPS destinations, in case any flight encounters a failure mid-crossing the ocean. It’s a hub for Cabo Verde Airlines, and served by AlbaStar, Air Senegal, Binter Canarias, Bulgaria Air, Corendon, easyJet, Edelweiss, Enter Air, Luxair, Neos, Royal Air Maroc, Smartwings, Sunclass, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, TUI Airways, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Deutschland, TUI fly Netherlands, TUI fly Nordic, and Vueling. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, detailed 3D models, a custom interior for the passenger terminal, realistic night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ​ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20, requiring at least 60.59 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/linovilar</id>
    <title>Linovt Releases Vilar de Luz Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/linovilar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698195ba9dc5d4463a0b7ea8_vilar1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Linovt has recently released their rendition of Vilar de Luz Airport (LPVL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a regional airfield serving Porto, in Portugal. Construction of the airfield began in 1992, and it wasn’t opened to traffic until late 1995.  It currently houses a Cessna Maintenance Center, an ATPL flight school (Nortávia), and Skydive Maia, a popular skydiving school and centre. Furthermore, it also houses Porto’s Aero Club, founded in 1935. It’s a VFR and MVFR daytime-only airport due to the lack of runway lighting and approach systems, and is mostly used for general aviation (flight training, circuits, etc.).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, a realistic runway elevation profile, detailed landside, a fully modeled Skydive Hangar interior, a fully modeled Café interior, custom airport vehicles, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.88, requiring at least 104.79 MB of free hard drive space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ​ ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gayacorfu</id>
    <title>Gaya Simulations Announces Corfu International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gayacorfu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6982b9dce5585d5256e97996_Gaya_LGKR_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Gaya Simulations has recently announced their return to consumer-facing development with a Corfu International Airport (LGKR) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Corfu, Greece, with an average of 4.3 million passengers per year. ​ It was founded in 1937 and was taken over by the Axis forces shortly after, serving as a base for transport and fighter aircraft. During most of its early life, the runway was only 600 meters long. ​ It wasn’t until 1949 that Corfu would get its first runway expansion, adding 200 meters in total length, and then nearly doubling a few years later to accommodate larger aircraft. ​ The first passenger terminal was built in 1962, and its International debut happened three years later.  ​ With its newly granted international status and an ever-rising yearly passenger count, a new terminal was built between 1968 and 1972. ​ As of 10 years ago, Corfu International was privatized and acquired by a joint venture between Fraport and the Copelouzos Group. The deal will be valid for 40 years as of 2017. ​ It’s a focus city for Aegean Airlines and Ryanair. Air France, Air Serbia, Arkia, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Edelweiss Air, Eurowings, ITA Airways, Jet2.com, Luxair, Neos, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Sky Express, Smartwings, Swiss, Transavia, TUI, Volotea, and Wizz Air also serve it. ​ The developers promise an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality 3d models, and up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, custom ground service equipment, and more. ​ There’s no information regarding pricing or the release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx3203311</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx3203311"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69843c2c8d9b7a73ed284de5_2537590_20260126233651_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a small service update to their A320 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, fixing some crashes, improving overall stability, and more. Update v2.4.0.3311 is a small update that aims to fix some crashes, improve overall stability, add support for the BeyondATC ATIS, and update the EFB user guide. The complete changelog follows below: ​ Avionics and Systems EFB Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (full bundle), $67.17 (A320 only), or $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fslneopwout</id>
    <title>FSLabs Releases Long-Awaited Pratt &amp; Whitney A21N Update </title>
    <updated>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fslneopwout"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698461cdd40da797865d1379_neoo1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently released their long-awaited Pratt &amp; Whitney engine update for the A321neo, alongside a new cabin, systems improvements, quality-of-life tweaks, and much more. It is their largest update yet for the A321neo family, bringing the long-awaited Pratt &amp; Whitney GTF engine variant with all its quirks, major system enhancements, visual upgrades, a new autosave system, wingflex, refined ground controls, and a new passenger cabin, greatly enhancing their latest product, which we have reviewed during its initial release. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ A21N: Fix for EIU engine start logic (PACK FAULT related) A21N: Fix for FADEC ATHR with WAI/NAC A21N: Fix for LEAP engine starts A21N: Ground model and acceleration tuning. Flap Full CL reduced. A21N: Fix for Nose Gear Slamming on Derotation A21N: Lift Tuning for Flap Full. A21N: Updated engine models with recalculated bleed config tables.  A21N: OWE Hinges Added.  A21N: AP TCAS FCU logic updated A21N: EEC fix for N1 CMD A21N: ENG1(2) HIGH VIB Limits A21N: Fix for Flap Full lift issue on approach A21N: Fix for X-Bleed starts A21N: Updated F3 VLS  A21N: Updated FULL VLS.  A321: CEO Rotation Tweak. (less jump off the deck) ALL: Derotation Tweaks.   ALL: End Flight freezing issue resolved  ALL: Fix for VLS issue in cruise. ALL: Fix for engine sim temperature limits ALL: Ground yaw acceleration tuning ALL: ISIS colors updated ALL: Payloads save/load state fixed ALL: Transponder save/load state fixed ALL: AP TCAS Added.  ALL: ATSAW Added.  ALL: Grid MORA Added.  AOC/ATSU: Adds SayIntentions as Weather and ATIS Source. AOC: Fix for LDP Runway Exit selection when ASDA is 0 but LDA has a value. AOC: Half deg wpt parsing in Simbrief route AOC: NOAA API update ATHR: Responsiveness improved.  ATSAW: Improved Altitude Reporting for online traffic. ATSU: Blocks OOOI Messages when using Beyond ATC ATSU: Correction to A21N MZFW/MTOW Mass and Balance Charts ATSU: Fixes for loadsheet and perf request ATSU: ITA/AZ Added. ATSU: WMT and IBS added. ATSU: IATA - Reads Fltsim.cfg as priority before checking ATSU db ATSU: Fix for non sequential Provider numbers. Bleed: NEO N1 Bump for X-Bleed Start Fixed. Bleed: Supplementary Air Conditioning Start Logic Fixed. Brakes: Pedal input mapping revised.  Brakes: Updated Keyboard Braking effectiveness.  CDLCU: Cockpit Door closes at the end of boarding if its still open. CDLCU: Logic for door locking / unlocking for NEO / cabin aircraft CEO: Adds PFD Tailstrike indicator  CIDS: Cabin Lighting Power Interrupts for AC Source Change CIDS: No Smoking and No Portable Elecs Logic Fix. CIDS: Repeated Chimes not playing Fixed. CIDS: Residual Cabin Pressure Warning Light logic added CIDS: Residual Cabin Pressure Warning Light logic added CIDS: Seatbelt/No Smoking/No Ped/Gear Downlock Chime timing corrected. CIDS: Stops Cabin Ready being reset for Type 2 at 2000ft. CIDS: IFE Emissive Control CPDLC: Adds Beyond ATC Support CPDLC: Fix for CPDLC Sending Logoff during station handover.  Console / Floor lighting now properly powered DMC: Fuel used reset for NEO PW DRAIMS: FO INT/RAD Sw Fixed.  DRAIMS: Fix for BRT/DIM Issue DRAIMS: BRT/DIM logic fix DRAIMS: F/O side RAD/INT switch Asobo-style no longer affects CPT side instead DUs: Colour Updates for CEO And NEO.  DUs: ND WX Radar drawing smoothness improved ECAM: FUEL SD - Fixes 1 ACT Fuel Feed Lines. ECAM: Stop Overflow and STS Dwg on top of each other. ECAM: Fix for LEAP AVAIL Flags ECAM: ENG SD Data Values set correctly when FADEC is unpowered. ECP: save/load state fixed EWD/SD brightness ECU LEAP: Correction to Minimum Cool Time for Low EGT. ECU LEAP: Correction to Motor Timing exit paths. EFB: 3ACT Fuel load displayed correctly on EFB EFB: Briefing - Fix for Briefings not reloading when starting a new flight. EFB: Cache location warning corrected EFB: Fix for opening multiple documents in the viewer EFB: Fix to make Doc scrollbar visible EFB: Fixes for Bow Tie on W+B Chart due to compression at Low GW. EFB: Larger on-screen virtual keyboard EFB: Lockscreen letter alignment fixed EFB: Manuals - Column Hide and Add Manuals work again. EFB: Map - Aircraft Type Name filters.  EFB: PW W+B Graph Formed Correctly. EFB: W+B - A21N W+B Data Corrected. EFB: W+B - Graph is now drawn based on aircraft MTOW/MZFW in cfg. EFIS: Pressure Set back to Simconnect 1013.15/or set value. EIS: NEO MSN 12000 or later is default fitted with F/S Speed out of Scale. Can be overriden by FltSim.cfg Options - eis_sf_spd=0 EIS: S/F Speed Out of Scale added. Selectable via Options&gt;Various&gt;Pg3 EIU: Randomise Time Since Shutdown when loading in. ELAC: ELAC flare law improved on NEO ELAC: Roll logic improved ELAC: NEO fix for ELAC flare law ELAC: With Dual LGCIU Failure CONF 2 triggers Direct law (was CONF3). Engines: Ground acceleration rates tuned for PW and LEAP FAC: Mach Buffet tables corrected FAC: Fix for Dual FAC Fault. FAC: Added protection limits to tail strike function FADEC: Boot Timings fixed for all engine types.  FADEC: Ground breakaway and accel tuning. FADEC: Updated with PS3 Shadow logic. FCDC: Forwarding of GND SPLR State to FWC. FG: RNP path fixed FG: Pitch command and FD loops - gains adjusted FM: GS Mini: Correction to GS Mini Additive for NEO aircraft. FMGC: Time Markers added FMGC: ETP Added FMGC: NAV logic fixed for initial turn direction.  FMGC: SEC INIT A - Cosmetic and functional differences. FMGC: AC STATUS Change Code Logic Corrected FMGC: AC STATUS Idle Value Shared between FMGCs  FMGC: AC STATUS NavDb Format changed FMGC: AIRWAYS Cosmetic changes. FMGC: ALL - TIME to UTC Transition now respects if a ETT is entered on an RTA page. FMGC: APPR PERF - SEC VLS/VAPP not linked to PRI VLS/VAPP FMGC: APPR phase FPA limits rules modified for constant speed segments FMGC: ATC COMM: CDPLC Inhibit when no DCDU installed FMGC: Added DB Holding FMGC: Added Save/Load and Autosave FMGC: Adds override to FMGC TMPY prompt for no Left ASCII and arrow instead. FMGC: Airways - Title Formatting. FMGC: Airways - To/Via Formatting FMGC: Alt Prefixes should retain color in SEC FPLN FMGC: Altn Fuel Preds added to Fuel Pred page. FMGC: Amber EFOB Applicable to ACT FPLN Only. FMGC: CHECK MIN DEST FOB Conditions Changed. FMGC: CHECK MIN DEST FOB active for PRI FPLN Only. FMGC: CLB - Presel Display formatting when presel is below 100kt. FMGC: CLB - Presel Input Params. FMGC: CMS - Fix for CMS Requiring two Clicks to Open FMGC: CRZ ALT PROG PAGE fix FMGC: CRZ PERF - Fix for Title Format FMGC: CRZ PERF - Presel Validation FMGC: CRZ PERF - T/D Dashes when no CRZ Alt Entered. FMGC: CRZ PERF - TD Time not orphaned FMGC: CRZ PERF - TD not displayed when not computed. FMGC: Can only access DIR TO Pg with Valid FMGC Position. FMGC: Check Min Dest EFOB S-pad msg. FMGC: Closest Airports EFOB/Wind Added FMGC: Colour Updates for CEO and NEO.  FMGC: Constant Mach - Removing Start WPT when opened from a Non-CRZ WPT removes MACH if entered. FMGC: Constant Mach - Cosmetic updates FMGC: Constant Mach - Entry Formats updated to "0.NN" or ".NN" or ".N" or "NN" FMGC: Constant Mach - Manually entered Wpts Large Font FMGC: Constant Mach - Removing start WPT when opened from a CRZ WPT, reverts to Autofilled WPT. FMGC: Constant Mach - SEC Title Size Corrected FMGC: Constant Mach - prepopulates Start waypoint FMGC: DEST EFOB BELOW MIN active for PRI FPLN only. FMGC: DIR TO - Adds --END-- Message. FMGC: DIR TO - Adds S-Pad message if FMGC lose Position whilst on DIR To Pg. Kicks out to FPLN pg. FMGC: DIR TO - Bracket Size and alignment. FMGC: DIR TO - END should only be shown if list has contents. FMGC: Deleting SEC FPLN resets Init A/B FMGC: Dir To - Font Format for Automatically Generated Rad-In/Out| FMGC: Dupe - Added ILS Suffix FMGC: Dupe - Adds Freq Header for NAVAIDs. FMGC: Dupe - Adds Lat Long Header. FMGC: Dupe - Corrected ADF Freq Format. FMGC: Dupe - Corrected Inval Dashes for Distance FMGC: Dupe - Corrected NM Format. FMGC: EFOB - EFOB Turns Amber immediately, 2min delay on S-pad message. FMGC: EFOB below Min Dest Fuel Amber conditions and S-pad message conditions fixed FMGC: EIS/FM added UTC CSTRS (RTA) lines in CSTR indication for ND FMGC: ENABLE ALTN based commit forcing CL phase FMGC: ENABLE ALTN/NEW DEST FORCED CL PHASE disabled while in DONE or PREFLIGHT FMGC: ETP: New ETP Status Logic FMGC: ETP: Sequenced Update FMGC: ETP: Wind Reset on Load FMGC: ETP: Winds Initialse correctly. FMGC: ETP: Fix for NaN Timings. FMGC: ETP: AC To ETP Seq Added. FMGC: FMP: Min Dest FOB Synced between FMGCs FMGC: FPLN: / Colour follows Alt. FMGC: FPLN: Alt " for Repeated Constraints Fixed FMGC: FPLN: Correction to EFOB Dashes. FMGC: FPLN: EFOB Dashes Corrected. FMGC: FPLN: ETT goes green when passed ETT FMGC: FPLN: FROM WPT should not have --- under Speed. FMGC: FPLN: Key Input Logic Corrected. FMGC: FPLN: Manual Wpts Dashed Preds. FMGC: FPLN: PPOS Wpts should not show speed. FMGC: FPLN: Repeated SPD/ALT Constriants do  not have / FMGC: FPLN: SEC MAPT Colours Fixed FMGC: FPLN: T.WIND Corrected FMGC: FPLN: V1 on FROM WPT when On Gnd. FMGC: FPLN: WPTs with CMS Show CMS MACH in SPD FMGC: FPLN: When ETT entered, ETT is listed as FROM UTC time. FMGC: FPLN A: FPLN Dist Dashed if FMGC PPOS not valid. FMGC: FPLN B: Dist Units Logic Corrected. FMGC: FPLN B: Correction to Slash colours. FMGC: FPLN B: EFOB Location Corrected. FMGC: FUEL PRED: Final Time Entry Validation FMGC: FUEL PRED: Fix for NOT ALLOWED When entering fuel page. FMGC: FUEL PRED: Phase 1 - Blanked Preds for PRI FPLN. (Work after Eng Start) FMGC: FUEL PRED: Placeholders when units are Lbs. FMGC: FUEL PRED: SEC FPLN Fuel Pred Page Layout FMGC: FUEL PRED: SEC FPLN Page Title. FMGC: FUEL PRED: Sec Fuel Pred Scroll Keys FMGC: FUEL PRED: Sec ZFW/ZFWCG Input FMGC: FUEL PRED: ZFW Amber Slash. FMGC: FUEL PRED: ZFWCG Max CG Corrected (45) FMGC: FUEL PRED: LW Dashes Format fix. FMGC: Fix Info: DTG renamed DIST. FMGC: Fix for EFOB Value not going Amber in SEC FPLN FMGC: Fix for SEC FPLN TIME to UTC Transition FMGC: Fix for SEC INDEX Title FMGC: Fix for total dropouts caused by certain SIDs FMGC: FixInfo: Fix for negative time. FMGC: Fixes for Manually Entered ALTN FUEL for ALTN PREDs. FMGC: Fuel Pred: Fix for No Dashes on LW in SEC FUEL PRED. FMGC: Fuel Pred: Pri Fuel Pred - Data entry in FWC Phase 1 inhibited except in RSK3. FMGC: Fuel Pred: Unit Weight Selections set in placeholders. FMGC: Fuel Pred: Ability to set a  Min DEST FOB below computed level FMGC: Further last time/fuel fixes FMGC: Handle STYs during STR removal FMGC: Handle STYs/STEs as part of the STR during STR/STY collapsing FMGC: Holds: Added COMPUTED Function to reset manually edited holds. FMGC: Holds: Fixed behaviour with no FMGC Pos. FMGC: Holds: LastExit Time takes in the account Time at 1st Wpt, regardless if FMGC is in UTC or TIME mode. FMGC: Holds: Removed CLR Function on LSK1/2/3 FMGC: Holds: Temp Color of Computed fixed. FMGC: Holds: Fixed Time Insert FMGC: Holds: Adds Computed. FMGC: Holds: Adds Last Exit FMGC: Holds: Cannot insert hold without Valid FMGC Position FMGC: Holds: Dist entry greater than 99.9 inhibited FMGC: Holds: Fix for Time/Dist Entry and Computed Clear. FMGC: Holds: Fix for Time/Dist Entry and Computed Clear. FMGC: Holds: Fixed Last Exit behaviour with Extra Fuel less than 0. FMGC: Holds: Fixed Last Exit behaviour with Extra Time less than 0 in UTC mode. FMGC: Holds: Fixed Last Exit behaviour with negative extra time in FMGC TIME mode. FMGC: Holds: Fixes Brackets FMGC: Holds: Fixes TMPY Colours FMGC: Holds: Fixes Title FMGC: Holds: Fuel Dashes Corrected. FMGC: Holds: Hold Distance not calcuated when preds are invalid fixed. FMGC: Holds: If User Entry MIN DEST EFOB then that is used in predence over Extra Fuel for Calcs. FMGC: Holds: LAST EXIT FUEL cannot be below FOB at 1st Wpt FMGC: Holds: Last Exit Min Fuel Func Corrected FMGC: Holds: Last Exit Min Time Func Corrected FMGC: Holds: Manual Entries blocked without FMGC POS. FMGC: Holds: SEC Title FMGC: Holds: SEC WPT Formatting FMGC: Holds: Time Formatting FMGC: Holds: Time entry greater than 9.9 inhibited FMGC: Holds: time/dist below 0 will now give a FORMAT ERROR FMGC: Holds: Last Time Fixed with a User Entry and Computer Min Dest EFOB. FMGC: INIT A: Fix for not Allowed Inputs. FMGC: INIT A: INIT REQ Availability. FMGC: INIT A: Input Handling FMGC: INIT A: Access Winds. FMGC: INIT B: FUEL PLANNING TITLE. FMGC: INIT B: MIN EFOB CALC Corrected. FMGC: INIT B: SEC Title. FMGC: INIT B: Title Position Corrected. FMGC: INIT B: User Entry for ALTN is blocked if no ALTN Dest in FPLN. FMGC: INIT B: Title Fixed. FMGC: INIT B: Final Time Entry Validation FMGC: INIT B: Fix for Input Conditions on RSK1. FMGC: INIT B: Placeholders when units are Lbs. FMGC: INIT B: Unit Weight Selections set in placeholders. FMGC: INIT B: ZFWCG Max CG Corrected (45) FMGC: LL XING functionality added FMGC: Lat Rev: AC Position Invalid S-Pad msg fixed when selecting ppos hold with no fmgc position FMGC: Lat Rev: Corrections to Keyinput Validation to remove ghost pages FMGC: Lat Rev: DEPT WPT shown as LEG_IDENT until Phase is greater than Preflight FMGC: Lat Rev: DISCO Wpt Lat/Long Removed. FMGC: Lat Rev: DISCO Wpts title fixed. FMGC: Lat Rev: Enable Altn Disabled on Manual Wpt. FMGC: Lat Rev: Enable Altn conditions Fixed. FMGC: Lat Rev: FROM Wpts have Lat/Long FMGC: Lat Rev: Hold with FMGC POS Unavail sets S-pad msg. FMGC: Lat Rev: LL XING Position Fixed. FMGC: Lat Rev: Manual Wpts do not have FIX or NEW DEST. FMGC: Lat Rev: NEW DEST Conditions Fixed. FMGC: Lat Rev: NEW DEST Position Fixed. FMGC: Lat Rev: No FMGC Pos Hold inhibit for PPOS wpts only. FMGC: Lat Rev: SEC Co-ords White. FMGC: Lat Rev: Title Position Fixed. FMGC: Lat Rev: MANUAL Waypoint Formatting FMGC: MIN EFOB: Logic Updated. FMGC: NEW DEST based commit should force CL phase FMGC: New Navaid - Title adjustment FMGC: PERF CRZ - Adds Titles to T/D, S/C, S/D Preds. FMGC: PROG REPORT - Fix for EFOB/FOB Dashes being swapped. FMGC: PROG REPORT - Title Location Fixed. FMGC: PROG report page updates FMGC: Preds - Min Dest EFOB fuel calc corrected. FMGC: Prog Report - SAT Only avail from Takeoff Phase FMGC: Prog Report - T WIND Only avail from CRZ. FMGC: Prog Report - Unit Weight Selections set in placeholders. FMGC: RAD NAV Fix for ADF and ILS ID Positions FMGC: RAD NAV VOR ID Alignment. FMGC: RAD NAV Accepts /XXX.X frequencies. FMGC: RAD NAV Cosmetic updates FMGC: RTA: DIST Dashes added &amp; ETT Dashes added FMGC: RTA: DIST Label Position and display conditions FMGC: RTA: ETT and UTC switching fixed FMGC: RTA: Fix for not being able to compute RTA in some circumstances.  FMGC: RTA: Managed Speed Mode with no Predictions FMGC: RTA: SEC Formatting FMGC: RTA: SEC Title Corrected. FMGC: RTA: Title Formatting FMGC: RTA: UTC Time Corrected FMGC: RTA: Whole page Formatting FMGC: S-Pad: Fix for A/C Pos invalid amber not populating on offside FMGC FMGC: S-Pad: Fix for TIME TO EXIT Msg. FMGC: S-Pad: Logic for AC Position Invalid Amber fixed. FMGC: S-Pad: Not in Database Corrected FMGC: S-Pad: Adds Time To Exit Check FMGC: S-Pad: AWY/WPT MISMATCH Corrected FMGC: S-pad: Fixes non returning messages for AC POS INVAL. FMGC: SC/TC handling when IP is invalid FMGC: SDY/SID/SDE Collapsing Updated.  FMGC: SEC AIRWAYS Page Cosmetic and Functional Differences. FMGC: SEC FPLN: Auto Fill Default CI if Init B filled. FMGC: SEC FPLN: V1 Speed Colour Fixed. FMGC: SEC INIT A: Init Req Avail in all phases. FMGC: SEC INIT B: Title Fixed. FMGC: SEC TO PERF: Disables Uplink FMGC: STR/STY collapsing Updated FMGC: Step Alts - Fix for NO OPTIMAL  FMGC: TO PERF Max EO/ACC/THR RED Altitudes. FMGC: TO PERF TO SHIFT with no FROM/TO FMGC: TO PERF Transition Altitude with no FROM/TO FMGC: TP Leg should be treated as a PPOS in Vert/Lat and FPLN Pgs FMGC: TRA - TMPY FPLN Fix FMGC: Updated SEC FPLN formats FMGC: VERT REV: Fix for RTA Availablity. FMGC: VERT REV: Fix for Title Location to avoid SEC clash. FMGC: VERT REV: SEC SPD LIM has RTA Func. FMGC: VERT REV: Corrections to Keyinput Validation to remove ghost pages FMGC: VERT REV: Dest Wpts Fixed. FMGC: VERT REV: RTA/CONT MACH removed from PRI/SEC ALTN Routes FMGC: VERT REV: SEC EFOB/EXTRA Fuel Colour fix. FMGC: VERT REV: SEC Step Alts avail FMGC: VERT REV: SPD LIM - CONST MACH and RTA Avail. FMGC: VERT REV: SPD LIM and DES LIM availability changes. FMGC: VERT REV: Wind Data Avail on Missed Appr Wpts - Fixed FMGC: VERT REV: Cosmetic Issues FMGC: VERT REV: Option Availability FMGC: VERT REV: Title fixed. FMGC: VERT REV: MANUAL Waypoint Formatting FMGC: VERT REV: Title Format. FMGC: VOR CRS - Enabled on Startup FMGC: Fix for fmgc_nd_mora state. FWC F10D: Fix for AFT SMOKE CAB FAN condition FWC F10D: Fix for AFT SMOKE ECAM trigger FWC F10D: Fix for FWD SMOKE CAB FAN condition FWC F10D: Fix for AFT SMOKE CAB FAN Condition FWC F10D: Fix for AFT SMOKE ECAM Trigger FWC F10D: Fix for FWD SMOKE CAB FAN Condition FWC F10D: Fix for HYD-GREEN + YELLOW SYS LO PR FWC F10D: Fix for Improper ATHR OFF ECAM (INVOL)  FWC F10D: Fix for Improper RETARD Calls. FWC F10D: Fix for Speeds Not Inserted ECAM FWC F10D: Fix for V1/VR/V2 Disagree ECAM FWC F10D/F9C: ECAM Proc Fixes for GREEN + YELLOW SYS LO PR FWC F9C: Fix for G+Y SYS LO PR FWC F9C: Fix for Speeds Not Inserted ECAM FWC F9C: Fix for V1/VR/V2 Disagree ECAM FWC F10: Missing C/B TRIPPED logicsheets added FWC F10/F9C: AP TCAS related ECAMs and Logic. FWC F10/F9C: Revised C-Chord Logic. FWC F10: ENG1(2) HIGH VIBRATION ECAM fixed FWC All: Fix for STS Reminder. FWC All: Fix for AP1+2 INOP with LGCIU1+2 fault. FWC All: Status Normal timer duration updated to 3s from 5s FWC All: Fix for Status page not displaying "NORMAL" when the page is open and a fault is cleared. Fuel: Fix for Fuel Transfer for 1ACT Config  Fuel: Fix for FuelCG Arm calculations with ACTs installed. GCU: Fix for NEO GEN Minimum N2 GCU: NEO LEAP - Gen only connects after Avail Flag is shown GPS: Crash when GPSSAT file is corrupted fixed.  GPWS: Inop if LGCIU is faulty. GSX: Cleaner service added to turn around GSX: Fix Crash in Reverse search when Profile has UTF-8 Char in string GSX: Fix for parsing gate number when 0 is in the middle (e.g. 505) GSX: Gate selection fix Hardware: Added Handling for Momentary and Latched IR Buttons.  Hardware: Added Missing ECP PB Event.  Hardware: Hardware Events for MIP Hardware: Hardware Events for WW Minor Airbus Throttle and PAC-32 Hardware: Simconnect Events added for AIR  Hardware: Simconnect Events added for ATASW  Hardware: Simconnect Events added for ELEC  Hardware: Simconnect Events added for FUEL  Hardware: Simconnect Events added for HYD IR: Quick Align Logic Fix.  Lights: DOME Light Power Interrupts for AC Source Change Lights: Fix for 2 Tail Nav Lights showing Lights: Corrected Light Positions for Logo and Tail Nav. Lights: Beacon light location updated on top of all models MCDU: Additional Changes to TO PERF Page MCDU: Adjusted Logic for entering a PDB Bearing, to require 3 digits. MCDU: Adjusted Logic for entering a PDB Distance, to require a leading digit. MCDU: Fix SEC TO PERF Size/Colour MCDU: Fix V1/VR/V2 Disagree S-pad Logic. MCDU: Fix for SEC FPN page not opening under some conditions with a custom EO Proc loaded MCDU: Fix for V1/VR/V2 Disagree Message MCDU: Lat Rev - TMPY Fpln &gt; changed. MCDU: NAVAID - Freq Location for VOR/NDB MCDU: NAVAID - Removed FOM for ILS and LOC NAVAIDs. MCDU: New Route - RTE can be saved with no name, and defaults to SRTEn where n is 1-5. MCDU: New Route - Store ACTIVE FPLN Requires a FROM &amp; TO Airport in the ACTIVE FPLN MCDU: New Route - Store SEC FPLN Requires a FROM &amp; TO Airport in the SEC FPLN MCDU: RUNWAY - Changed ILS to LS. MCDU: Various Options: Fixes Cycling of Brake Fan Options MCDU: WPT - Co-ordinates are Large font MCDU: WPT - Title Updated MCDU: RADNAV Accepts /XXX.X frequencies. MCDU: RADNAV Cosmetic updates Model: Updated NEO Cabin.  Model: Added ACF cabin D3 door visibility option Model: Corrected NEO Wear Pin Locations.  Model: Adds BrakeFans with Covers to option list as well as no Brake fans, and Brake Fans.  Model: Adds Strobe Blockers on sharklets ND: ADS-B ONLY Message added. ND: ADS-B Only Targets added. ND: CSTR Alt placement fixed. ND: Fix for ND Redraw  ND: Fix for WX radar going outside clip area ND: Symbol Tweaks ND: Wpt CSTR Alt Alignment fixed. ND: WX Radar drawing smoothness improved PFD: Fix for localizer not received on choosing dep rwy Payloads: Revamped Cargo distribution to target - will now attempt to distribute the payload as per the loading guidelines within CG Envelope. Payloads: Fix for Max Num Passengers only (no zones written) in the FltSim Cfg corrupting the payload system Protections: Improved aProt limits during heavyweight turns.  SD Display: COND page - Temps displayed in even numbers SD: CRZ Temps rounding correction SEC: Reverse Thrust 1(2) Inhibition with Dual SEC 1+2(1+3) Failure. SEC: GND SPLR Fault status. Sounds: Cabin PA volume increases after first engine start. Sounds: Cabin Power Interrupts for PA. Sounds: Fix for no sounds playing in MSFS 2024 SU4 and beyond when Mute Audio in Background selected in FS options Sounds: Improved Cockpit Wind Sounds.  Sounds: Stop Disarmed Doors being played on taxi out in some conditions. Sounds: Fix for touchdown sounds playing in flight Sounds: All sound files bit rate updated, elec sound updates Sounds: PW engine start cabin sounds added TCAS: REDUCE RANGE TA message only shows on ND if TCAS is in TA or TA/RA TCAS: DMC Comparison function updated.  Tiller: Updated Turning Rates VC: DU screen tint reduced 50% to allow clearer low brightness settings VC: Fix for Mismatched DU Splashes on FCU VC: Updated DU and Window Glass.  VC: glass reflections updated VC: Fix for flickering VC: Improved Trim wheel smoothness. VC: Fixed EMER CANC and STBY NAV guard glass VC: NEO Removes MID CALL button from ACF.  VC: Fixed 1ACT Panel.  VR: Fixes for OpenXR WHC: Icing build up on cockpit windows with aircraft unpowered Wingflex: Updated Wing Model.  Wingflex: Updated Wingflex Physics model.  XPDR: save/load state fixed As far as system improvements go, the PW update brings a full Equal Time Point (ETP) simulation, with sequenced ETP calculation, wind-aware prediction logic, automatic re-initialization on load, corrected UTC and timing behavior, and dynamic recalculation based on aircraft performance and route progression. Furthermore, the developers have refined the Flight Management System with improved fuel planning, vertical navigation, and route editing. The holding pattern logic has also been improved. Vertical and lateral navigation were tweaked to ensure better waypoint handling, corrected constraint formatting, refined DIR TO logic, enhanced airway and manual waypoint validation, and more. Numerous cosmetic corrections were also carried out around the MCDU pages to ensure maximum acuity.  The navigation tweaks brought on by this update will lay the groundwork for the implementation of FLS (Flight Management Landing System), which is already in active development. ‍ The passenger cabin has been entirely reworked, with high-resolution textures, per-variant accuracy, animated window blinds, customized lighting environments, and a fully functional cabin signage system.  The core systems have also been massively improved, with engine and FADEC logic refinements across the board, spanning the start sequencing, thrust management, bleed configuration tables, and revised acceleration and breakaway behavior. ​ The add-on is available in their store for roughly $69.95 + VAT. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd73924</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Boeing 737-900 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd73924"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6985fdacfdd4a0c0f3ab198d_1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released their rendition of the Boeing 737-900 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, nearly 50 days after bringing over the first member of the 737 lineup to the new simulator.  It’s their second product built natively for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 (the 777 was mostly just a compatibility patch), with a lidar-scanned flight deck, improved textures and lighting, new sounds, upgraded systems, and more. ​ As did the 738, it leverages the simulator’s capabilities to lay the groundwork for a truly native product line that will follow after all the 737 lineup members are out (only the -700 and -600 are pending now). The complete changelog follows below: It’s available on PMDG.com for roughly $50, and owners of the MSFS 2020 version are entitled to a 60% discount ($20 total). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phomun24</id>
    <title>PhotoRico Releases Muñoz Marín International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phomun24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698ad8a28f11f50024789c8a_marin1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PhotoRico has recently released their rendition of Muñoz Marín International Airport (TJSJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving San Juan, Puerto Rico, with an average of 13.4 million passengers per year. Planning for the airport’s construction began in 1945, when the government recognized they’d need a newer, larger airport to keep up with the air traffic demands of the following decades, since the region's main airport had a very short runway and could not be expanded further.  The project received approval in 1946; work began in 1947, and by 1949, they had completed the first phase, which involved cleaning, filling, leveling, and draining the soil. By the latter half of that year, they were already paving the runways and taxiways. The inauguration only took place in 1955, six years later, with a six-story passenger terminal, a control tower, a 2,400-meter-long runway, and basic aeroportuary infrastructure. ​ The 1960s brought further expansion, including lengthening the runway for jets and the addition of a second runway (which was only completed in the 1970s).  ​ In the late 1980s, a $137 million investment was announced to expand the passenger terminal and make multiple improvements to the airport, which were carried out between the 90s and early 2000s.  ​ It was followed by another terminal expansion in the early 2000s, making Terminal B slightly larger and remodeling the hotel, among other minor things. In the 2010s, despite the significant drawbacks of the 2008 crisis (leading, for example, to American Airlines greatly reducing its presence), the airport underwent further work, including a new passenger terminal, new pavement, new lighting systems, press conference rooms, and more. ​ It’s a hub for M&amp;N Aviation and Tradewind Aviation, and a focus city for JetBlue. Air Canada Rouge, Air Transat, American Airlines, Arajet, Avelo Airlines, Avianca, Cape Air, Contour Airlines, Copa Airlines, Delta Airlines, Frontier Airlines, Iberia, Southwest Airlines, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and WestJet also serve it. ​ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully detailed terminals, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom taxi lights, performance-friendly optimization, and custom weathering. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect (2020/2024) for roughly $22.38, requiring at least 1.60 GB of free hard disk space to install.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbnordranch</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Nordheimer Creek Ranch for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbnordranch"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698da14a41739045d96b5fdb_nord1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Nordheimer Creek Ranch (CA107) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a tricky airstrip tucked into a steep, narrow mountain valley in California.  Located in the Six Rivers National Forest (Orleans, California), the Nordheimer Ranch Airfield is one of the most challenging airstrips in the United States, with a punishingly short runway and difficult terrain, with no margin for error. The area is known for its high-altitude lakes, dense forests, and diverse wildlife, attracting tourists from all over. Furthermore, its rich past continues to attract attention to this day, be it the remnants of old mining operations and the ancient fruit trees left by homesteaders centuries ago. It’s also famously known for world-class kayaking and rafting, with the nearby Nordheimer Campground being a very popular base for rafters. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airstrip, with high-fidelity visuals, PBR texturing, advanced collision modeling for out-of-cockpit exploration, and much more. ​It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $8.53, requiring at least 485.70 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rloghdlg</id>
    <title>realops Simulations Releases Ground Handling Plugin for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rloghdlg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/698da48ac1caa516f03291cd_real1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. realops Simulations has recently released their newly announced ground handling plugin for X-Plane 12, bringing GSX-like features to Laminar Research’s newest simulator.  realops aims to simulate ground handling operations like never seen before in X-Plane 12, with realistic boarding, refueling, baggage handling, catering, and more. While optimized for Type C aircraft (B738, A320, etc.), it works with any airplane thanks to custom presets. The developers claim their next-level animations will greatly enhance the ground handling experience in X-Plane 12, alongside accurately modeled 3D objects, physical aircraft loading (Zibo and LevelUP), many liveries for common ground handling and catering companies, full SimBrief integration, and much more. It’s available on their website for roughly $34.11, requiring at least 4 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
