<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-03-02T18:29:43.152208+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdmon</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Monastir Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdmon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b75a1f81f063cb854f0eb5_mon1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSDG recently released their Monastir Habib Bourguiba International Airport (DTMB) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Monastir, Tunisia, and has a yearly average of 1.6 million passengers. Its origins date back to World War 2, when it was known as Monastir Airfield and utilized by the United States Army Air Force during the North African Campaign. In the following decades, Monastir Airport experienced significant growth and expansion, driven by Tunisia's increasing popularity as a tourist destination. It's a hub for Nouvelair and is served seasonally by Air France, Air Serbia, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Discover Airlines, Eurowings, Smartwings, Sundair, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, and Tunisair. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, custom ground clutter, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $14.02, requiring at least 872.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350feb</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases 2nd Trailer for Upcoming Airbus A350</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350feb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b80e68c27ff464d40bbd80_fiddy1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released the second trailer video for their upcoming Airbus A350 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showing glimpses of its exterior and interior through elaborate cinematics. They have also published a FAQ section for the airplane in their forums, containing relevant information on operating the aircraft and the differences between the MSFS 2020 and 2024 versions.  As previously informed, the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 will not feature a cabin, avionics bay, crew rest area, LIDO charts (MSFS 2024 exclusive), dynamic weathering, or per-livery configuration.  The airplane will be available sometime next week for roughly $75.96.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukegae</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases City of Derry Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukegae"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b862c2c399a1d9c4a43cad_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 has just released its latest Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 scenery. This time, the team has focused on the City of Derry Airport (EGAE) in Derry, Northern Ireland. The airport serves approximately 150,000 passengers each year. The airfield opened in 1941 as a Royal Air Force base and was used for military purposes until the 1950s. After that, the airport saw limited usage, with Emerald Airways operating a route to Glasgow. The airline constructed a new terminal building and control tower for the airport, with the first Glasgow flights commencing in 1967.  ‍ A little over a decade later, Loganair began offering a few routes from the airport. Over the years, the airport has undergone various extensions and upgrades as it continued to grow and new airlines started to operate there.  ‍ Today, airlines such as easyJet, Loganair, Ryanair, and Volotea serve the airport, providing destinations like Edinburgh, London, Manchester, and more. As a result, the airport handles approximately 7,000 aircraft movements and welcomes around 150,000 passengers annually. The scenery includes features like detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, night effects, highly detailed airport vehicles, vegetation, PBR materials, and static GA aircraft. The newly released City of Derry Airport is now available on SimMarket for approximately $15.69. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdsxpl</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Software Releases GTNXi for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdsxpl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b8aa3b775bfb8b837cd407_Torquesim_CJ525_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. TDS Sim Software has recently released GTNXi for X-Plane 11 and 12. The GTNXi is a rendition of the Garmin 650Xi and 750Xi navigation with support for both Navigraph charts and data. Like its real-life counterpart, the GTNXi provides the pilot with various features, such as full autopilot control laterally and vertically (including support for LPV approaches), 8.33kHz COM frequency spacing, the ability to fly RF legs, a Glide Range Ring, a Smart Glide, and a Nearest Airport Indication Arrow. It also supports dual GPS/Flight plans, per-device CDI, mouse wheel zoom-in/out of the map page, full VC integration and a 2D pop-up available concurrently, worldwide live METAR, SmartGlide, and much more. The full list is rather lengthy, but it can be found in the .pdf manual included with the addon. The TDS GTNXi comes with VC integration support for X-Plane 12 for the following add-ons: If your favourite general aviation plane isn’t on the list, don't worry! The GTNXi comes with Legacy VC Integration, which can detect and install the TDS add-on into all add-on aircraft that provide a legacy GTN 3D bezel unit. According to the developers, this will be useful for users with X-Plane 11 aircraft, as those will not come with TDS GTNXi VC Integration standards. More information about this can also be found in the .pdf manual. If the aircraft doesn’t have VC-integrated GPS support, you can always use it as a 2D pop-up. The TDS Sim Software’s GTNXi can be purchased here for roughly $ 68.20. It requires X-Plane 11/12, Windows 10 (version 1909) or Windows 11, Intel Core i5-12600K or AMD Ryzen 5 3500, at least 16GB of RAM memory, Nvidia RTX2070 or AMD Radeon RX 5700XT, with at least 4GB of video card memory, and at least 6GB of free space on hard disk. Navigraph subscription is also required for database updates and charts. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcejf2</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family Version 2.0 in Open Beta</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcejf2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bafc7338327ff2605895b8_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The E-Jets Family for X-Plane, developed by X-Crafts, has just launched version 2.0 in an open beta. The full release is expected in just a few weeks. This update includes a variety of new features, improvements, and fixes, and introduces a rendition of the Embraer Lineage 1000. The latest update is filled with exciting new features. The E-Jets now offer three distinct lighting options: X-Plane default, dynamic, or natural lighting. Please note that these features are only available in X-Plane 12 and not in X-Plane 11. Additionally, users can now simulate the real-life noise-cancelling headsets used by pilots. The Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) has also been updated significantly. Both the fuel and auto brake systems have been completely overhauled. These are just a few highlights of the changes; for the complete list, please refer to the release notes. The current price for the full E-Jets Family is $134.95. It is important to note that once version 2.0 is fully released, the price will increase to $149.95. Additionally, the upgrade price will rise to $74.48. If you choose to purchase or upgrade to the full E-Jets Family before the 2.0 release, you will receive the Lineage 1000 for free. The full release is currently estimated to be on the 1st of March. The E-Jets Family can be found at the X-Plane.Org Software Store. For instructions on using the open beta for the E-Jets, refer to the helpful guide provided by X-Crafts. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtind</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Indianapolis International Airport v2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtind"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67baff41eb25e6456b1a9a05_kind1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. DominicDesignTeam recently released their new rendition of Indianapolis International Airport (KIND) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Indianapolis with a yearly average of 4.7 million passengers, making it the busiest in Indiana and the 43rd busiest in the United States. It opened in 1931 to replace Stout Field, which used to be the city’s main airport at the time.  Indianapolis was one of the main transcontinental flights and rail service stops between Los Angeles and New York City. It was started by Trans World Airlines’ precursor, Transcontinental Air Transport. Its original terminal used to be on the east side of the airfield, now demolished (1957-2008). It was replaced by a new terminal in late 2008, with 110,000 square meters of built area between parallel runways.  It’s a hub for FedEx Express and an operating base for Allegiant Air and Republic Airways. Aer Lingus (to begin in May), Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines,.and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, custom ground markings, custom jetway, custom animations, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.41, requiring at least 960.10 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddipkk</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Kraków John Paul II International Airport V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddipkk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bb05fb1759e5bb4273fc8d_epkk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their new rendition of Kraków John Paul II International Airport v2 (EPKK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves the city of Kraków, Poland, and has a yearly average of 11 million passengers, making it the second busiest airport in Poland. Its construction began in 1964, with its eventual opening for civil aviation three years later, in 1967.  During its first four years of operation, Kraków Airport didn’t have a passenger terminal, which was only built in 1971. The 1970s also brought a runway extension, new taxiways, and the installation of high-intensity runway lights. In the late 1980s, the administration decided to build a new terminal, which opened in 1993. Shortly after, in 1995, an apron modernization followed. Further modernization was carried on in 2002 to ensure readiness for more international operations. A brand new terminal was constructed between 2013 and 2016 to ensure it could handle the extra traffic brought by Ryanair’s second Polish base, which opened in 2012. Two years ago, Kraków became Poland’s first regional airport to pass the 9 million passenger threshold. Such impressive traffic figures and eventual projected growth led to plans for a new terminal to better accommodate the extra influx.  The scenery features a high-quality rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, custom night lighting, a high-definition terrain mesh, performance-friendly interior modeling, an up-to-date ground layout, static aircraft, custom ground service equipment, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.88, requiring at least 1.52 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cploot</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes More ChasePlane Footage</title>
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cploot"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a03568493d826e0a991328_cp1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 has recently published two more videos showcasing their upcoming ChasePlane add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, going through setting up custom views and shortcuts. ‍ The first video goes in depth about views and smart views, demonstrating how to import default views, adjust and rename views, delete and create passenger views, use smart views in the cockpit and cabin, create external views, and reorganize views. The second video, on the other hand, demonstrates the shortcut system, including their mini-bar HUD, view configuration, compatible devices, camera mode assignments, view, group, and world shortcuts, rotating through views, and flyby and tower cameras. Please refer to this post for further information on ChasePlane's many features. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cplpri</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Announces Changes to ChasePlane’s Pricing System</title>
    <updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cplpri"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bca30a67eda37f60e7572b_chase.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently made a blog post announcing their decision to stop charging an extra fee for cloud storage and offer the full experience in a single lifetime package. The community did not take too well to their original idea of charging extra for cloud storage due to how much it would cost Parallel 42 to keep the structure running. The options ranged from 5 dollars for a yearly subscription to 20 dollars for lifetime access.  ‍ Even though community access was not required to share camera presets, as ChasePlane also features a powerful importer/exporter tool that allows people to simply share the files over on Discord or any file hoster, the backlash was immense due to how negatively the subscription system is generally viewed by simmers and gamers alike.  ‍ With that in mind, Parallel 42 has decided to include the access with the base package without any extra charges. They will commit to the ever-growing expenses of running such cloud infrastructure while meeting their original price target.  ‍ Such a decision was not made haphazardly; they conducted a very deep cost analysis to ensure it wouldn’t eventually backfire.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350stt</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Publishes Statement on Upcoming A350’s Status for MSFS 2020/2024 </title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350stt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67b80e7ec27ff464d40bd692_fiddy2.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently made a statement in their Discord server, shedding light on some lingering questions about their upcoming A350 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. These questions mostly concern the lack of stability observed on showcase live streams, performance information, and a release date confirmation. They begin with vague information on how the aircraft performs, stating it will differ depending on hardware, but it should be within the same ballpark or marginally better than the Fenix A320. To further aid performance, they will also offer low-resolution texture options and no cabin option (MSFS 2024 only, as 2020 doesn’t have a cabin to begin with).  In addition to their own navigation data, iniBuilds will also include Navigraph’s WASM to ensure maximum stability. Following the showcase streams and feedback, they have already addressed a multitude of items, including the checklist crash, the WASM crash at Atlanta International Airport, overall stability improvements, sound improvements, and art tweaks. The complete changelog follows below: Systems: Sounds:  Art: ‍Some gear wire clipping and animation issues resolved ‍ iniBuilds also emphasizes the importance of running Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 SU 1 Beta to warrant the best experience possible with the 2024 version of their upcoming A350, especially if you use Navigraph. Non-Navigraph users don’t have to be on the latest beta, but it’s still advised nonetheless.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350rel</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Airbus A350 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bf1797199e80fda0eaa13a_fitty1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their long-awaited rendition of the Airbus A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, featuring advanced flight systems, immersive cockpit details, interactive avionics, and more. After a day of exclusive live streams and a statement concerning some of the observed issues and their respective fixes, iniBuilds’ latest widebody is finally landing on everybody’s desktops after a fourteen-month wait since its official announcement in December 2023. Their A350 features realistic systems based on real-world data and pilot feedback, with over 200 ECAM messages, ADS-B TCAS, a custom terrain radar, GPS jamming simulation, CPDLC integration, Navigraph and SimBrief support, a true-to-life 3D cockpit model with 1:1 proportions, a true-to-life cabin (MSFS 2024 only), a detailed exterior model of both available variants at launch (-900 and -1000), an authentic WWise sound set, authentically recreated A350-specific system sounds, an advanced EFB with full ground equipment control, LIDO charts (MSFS 24 only), comprehensive GSX integration, detailed take-off and landing performance calculation, and much more. Regarding platform differences, the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version does not feature the passenger cabin, per-livery configuration, dynamic livery weathering, and LIDO charts. For the full experience, iniBuilds recommends Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 on the SU1 Beta branch. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $75.71, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nic024</id>
    <title>JustSim Releases Nice Côte D’Azur Airport for MSFS 2024 </title>
    <updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nic024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c08e965c6bec6720738c3c_neat1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. JustSim has recently released their rendition of Nice Côte D’Azur (LFMN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Bouches-du-Rhône, Alpes-Maritimes, and Monaco, with a yearly average of 14.1 million passengers. It covers an area of roughly 3.7 square kilometers partially reclaimed from the sea, with 72% of it utilized by its two parallel runways and the passenger terminals, which can handle 52 aircraft movements per hour.  Terminal 1 has 25 gates and a total area of 52,000 square meters, handling domestic and intra-European flights. The newest terminal, Terminal 2, has 29 gates and a total area of 57,800 square meters and can take up to 8.5 million passengers annually.  It’s a focus city for Air France and easyJet. It is served by Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air Transat, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, Delta Air Lines, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, Icelandair, KLM, Jet2.com, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, Transavia, and more. The scenery is part of their “NG” series, now ported to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It features custom ground textures, highly detailed 3D models, animated custom ground vehicles, custom animated jetways, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.25, requiring at least 3.20 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tacsia</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Tachileik Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tacsia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c0b450be88de3d1b2cf834_tachi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SiamFlight recently released their rendition of Tachileik Airport (VYTL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which serves the homonymous town of Tachileik in Myanmar. Established in the late 1940s, when Myanmar was undergoing significant changes following its independence from British colonial rule, it initially only featured basic infrastructure, with a very modest airstrip whose only goal was to facilitate transportation in the mountainous region, which was largely underdeveloped at the time. Its strategic location near the Thai border historically transformed Tachileik into a gateway for trade and cultural exchange between Myanmar and Thailand. During a good part of the 20th century, when Myanmar's economy became increasingly isolated due to political instability and international sanctions, Tachileik became a key hub for informal cross-border trade in textile, electronics, and agricultural products. In the 1980s and 1990s, as Myanmar began to open up its economy cautiously, Tachileik Airport saw gradual improvements in its infrastructure. The government recognized the potential of the airport to boost tourism and regional trade, particularly with Thailand. During this period, the airport was upgraded to accommodate larger aircraft, and regular flights from Yangon and Mandalay were introduced. This development was part of a broader effort by the Myanmar government to promote tourism in the Shan State, which is known for its scenic landscapes, ethnic diversity, and cultural heritage. Despite its successes, Tachileik Airport has faced numerous challenges over the years. The region's remote location and underdeveloped infrastructure have often hindered its growth. Moreover, political instability and ethnic conflicts in Shan State have occasionally disrupted airport operations and deterred tourists. However, in recent years, the Myanmar government has tried to modernize the airport and improve its facilities. Upgrades to the runway, terminal building, and navigation systems have enhanced safety and accommodated larger aircraft. Looking to the future, Tachileik Airport is poised to play an even more significant role in the region's development. Plans for further upgrades and expansion are underway to transform the airport into a major regional hub. The ongoing development of the East-West Economic Corridor, a key initiative under the Greater Mekong Subregion (GMS) program, is expected to enhance Tachileik's connectivity and economic potential. As Myanmar continues integrating into the regional and global economy, Tachileik Airport will remain a vital link between the country and its neighbors. Mann Yadanarpon Airlines, Mingalar Aviation Services, and Myanmar National Airlines serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a custom passenger terminal, an accurate runway elevation profile, custom ground service equipment, and more. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $6.28, requiring at least 36.86 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ven024</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Venice Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ven024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c1f7dbdfbb0decb95e5891_venice1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Barelli MSFS Addon recently released their Venice Marco Polo Airport (LIPZ) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport serves Venice and Padua, Italy, and has a yearly average of 9.3 million passengers. Although officially inaugurated in 1960, its roots can be traced back to the early 1920s when the first airfields in Venice were established.  The post-WW2 era's rebuilding effort led to the development of Venice Airport in the 1950s, ensuring it could easily accommodate the predicted traffic demand. Its location was strategically chosen to protect Venice's relatively fragile environment while keeping it relatively accessible to the residents.  The 1960s and 1970s brought significant growth in passenger figures, rapidly transforming it into one of Italy's main hubs for domestic and international travel.  The subsequent decades brought terminal improvements and runway extensions to accommodate larger aircraft, coinciding with the rise of low-cost carriers in Europe, which also significantly boosted passenger figures at the time. In 2002, a new passenger terminal was built, designed by Antonio Citterio. It featured state-of-the-art infrastructure at the time. It's a focus city for easyJet, Ryanair, Volotea and Wizz Air. Aegean, Aer Lingus, Air Arabia, Air Cairo, Air Canada, Air France, Air Transat, American Airlines, Asiana Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, ITA, KLM, LOT, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Portugal, and United Airlines also serve it. The scenery features custom ground textures, custom ground service equipment, custom jetways, custom night lighting, landside buildings, and more. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $18.32, requiring at least 225.84 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mks024</id>
    <title>MKStudios Updates Sceneries &amp; Publishes Development Update</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mks024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c1fcdf310dd807b8877632_studio0.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MKStudios has recently posted in their Discord community about the release of updates for three of their sceneries and fresh new information about the progress on Düsseldorf and Seattle-Tacoma for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. ‍ Firstly, Zurich, Dublin, and La Guardia have been updated with compatibility fixes, further optimization, and bug corrections. The respective changelogs follow below: ‍ They have also announced Montreal and Malaga will be their next sceneries in line for compatibility updates. They look forward to SU1 leaving beta so they can benefit from the extra stability that benefits both players and developers. ‍ Düsseldorf (EDDL) is said to be progressing well and is scheduled to release in Spring (March to May). Thanks to the community, they have been able to get insider pictures, which will aid them in achieving high detail standards. Seattle-Tacoma, on the other hand, is a few steps behind. Work has been completed on the surroundings and ground polygon, but the terminal is still being worked on. They are confident it won’t take much longer than Düsseldorf, though. Rome (LIRF) and Helsinki (EFHK) Rebooted are also in progress. Once Düsseldorf and Seattle are out of the way, they will soon enter the priority development pipeline. The expected release date is in the summer. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350101</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bf17ea670f86dba34bb126_fitty10.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued the first update for their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The update fixes various system and EFB bugs and improves performance, 3D art, and sound balancing. The community has been helping iniBuilds to identify and mitigate potential WASM crashes, which plagued the release day for many customers. While they managed to fix a few before the actual release, some were still looming around and were promptly addressed by the developers. Update v1.0.1 brings a substantial changelog, with items ranging from animation fixes to sound level adjustments. The complete list follows below: v1.0.1Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️Improvement – 1000 SimBrief ProfileFixed – RAT AnimationFixed – FS20 STBY compass bugFixed – ISIS inHG period displacement bugFixed - Before TO checklist: PACK line must be changed – improvement based on pilot feedbackFixed - Avionics door see through when in open positionFixed - Cockpit door open without OPEN lightImprovement – When ENG ANTI ICE is on on ground, FF now increases per engine. Pilotfeedback based on line operations whereby increased fuel flow should be something pilotsconsider when planning taxi fuel with with long taxi times during icing conditions and is aspecialty of the A350 as it is an exceptionally large increase.Fixed – DIRECT Law activation bugFixed - Selecting a DTO from the ND causes disco in active FPFixed - AFS BUG and latched descentFixed - Magenta target speed dot (while in selected speed) mimics the selected speed insteadof showing us what the managed speed target would be.Fixed – ELEC Bus failure improvementsFixed - VOR needle part visible when no station tunedFixed - Incorrect Squawk green digit colours when onFixed – Fuel temps got too lowFixed - Manually tuned M bugFixed - RNV approach NM in PFD shifted bugFixed - LW different in PERF APPR vs FUEL/LOAD bugFixed - TRK/FPA FPA window when on ALTFixed - Noise info present in CLB page after noise completeFixed – PRESS bugFixed - No FMA box around THR CLB&lt;&gt;DCLB changeFixed - FLS beam, dashes are too bigFixed - Incorrect Vmax at conf 1Fixed - Landing CABIN READY does not resetFixed - Odd clipped level off arrow in ND, related to FCU and -ALT CSTR interactionFixed - Step clb distance issue FPLNFixed – WASM crash for CTR_Gauge_Draw crash - Cycling SD via ALLFixed -CFG &amp; Disable assistanceFixed – WASM Crash for MFD_Gauge_Draw - Pressing "up" arrow on NOTEPAD after inputtingtextFixed - GD not visible during climb on selected speed and incorrect short term managed spdFixed - CTR exception when using SD "all" button or hitting video in No CabinFixed – WASM crash due to memory allocations [LNAV crashes, or SB import]Fixed - Sim rate limited to 2x in some situationsFixed - Cant clear FIX INFO if you navigate away from the TABFixed - G/S mode inhibit on SURV page doesn't workFixed - Can't manually tune ILS frequencies with numbers that are behind decimalFixed – FADEC power on time delay when using o/h buttonsFixed - Seems like editing the ALTN messes up with the VDFixed - Incorrect Vmax CONF3Fixed - Incorrect G/S indication with G/S deselectedFixed - Radio mins limited to 100 ft or above - should accept below?Fixed - No A/Floor protection in place when A/THR is switched off manuallyFixed – SEC plan swapping with activeFixed – FS20 Interactive points affecting jetway placement for -900Fixed - Update max mach in cfgs causing overspeed warnings with some third party ACARSFixed – Delay in pulling chartsFixed - OIS - GSX Menu - Clicking "Next Page" closes and resets the menuFixed - [0.0.018][FS20] OIS remove "Performance Mode" toggleFixed - OIS TO PERF THS for TOFixed - LBS fuel display center tanks not truncating valueImprovement - Overhaul of NG auth systemFixed - OIS Enroute Map - Standard - Disable OSM hyperlinkFixed - Some options syncing issues -Fixed - Loadsheet Lbs handling improvementFixed - Loadsheet update improvement for pax countFixed - Enroute map attribution link will open a new window instead of locking the OISFixed - Some performance improvements to perf handling 3D Art 🎨🖌️Addition – Supplementary EXT Power CableFixed - Nose gear hose bit doesn't move with gearImprovement -FS20 Performance Exercise on Node count &amp; vertex count for those who are CPUlimited Sounds🔊🎧Fixed - FS20 excessively loud gear dragImprovement - Reduced gear drop sound volumeImprovement - Tweaked FS20 engine levelsFixed - Increased FS20 aft engine volumeFixed - FS20 aft engine volume positioningAdjusted - FS20 manipulator vol levelsFixed - manipulator 3D spatializationFixed - Modified volume of some misc interactions (door, tray table etc)Fixed - Tweaked engine levels overwingFixed - Smoothened transition to buzzsaw outside of toga takeoffFixed - negligible difference to gear drag vol with environmental sound sliderFixed -Eng whine mixing improvementsFixed - Adjusted position of nose gear thud on rotationFixed 'crashing' sound heard on rotationFixed - Retard callout volume level ‍ They have also released the official paintkit, which is available right here. The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
