<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-08-25T18:24:57.078881+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/splibd</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Bari Karol Wojtyła Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/splibd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bf777fd7e2f9b4dc325850_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimPixel has recently released their version of Bari Karol Wojtyła Airport (LIBD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located in the Italian city of Bari, about 5 miles from the city center. In 2023, the airport handled just under 6.5 million passengers, making it the 10th busiest airport in Italy. The airport was originally built as a military airfield and opened in the 1930s. It was seized during the Second World War and began receiving civil flights in the 1960s. Alitalia was one of the first airlines to fly to the airport, offering routes to Rome, Catania, Palermo, Ancona, and Venice. In 1981, a new passenger terminal was built, and in 1990, the airport underwent a runway extension and terminal upgrade. Another renovation took place in 2000, resulting in the construction of a new passenger terminal, which was completed in 2005. Today, the airport serves as a hub for various airlines including easyJet, Ryanair, and Volotea, offering a wide range of destinations across the world. With approximately 6.5 million passengers and 50.000 aircraft movements yearly, the airport continues to be a vital transportation hub. The newly released version of Bari Karol Wojtyła Airport boasts a range of features, such as high-resolution textures, custom 3D models, dynamic lighting, detailed interiors, static aircraft, ground vehicles, and more. The add-on requires 2.94 GB of storage space and is available on iniBuilds for around $16.7. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwitre</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Announces Trenton-Mercer Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwitre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66bfa7fb66a9852f1acfe6e7_trenton1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios recently announced the development of Trenton-Mercer Airport (KTTN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This joint civil-military airport serves Trenton in New Jersey and has a yearly average of 917,000 passengers. The airport’s history is more than a century old. Its first airplane landing was in 1907 when it was just a small airfield on Alfred Reeder’s farm. It was opened to the public in 1929 as Skillman Airport. It was used for aircraft testing during World War 2 when a nearby General Motors factory switched from building cars to Grumman TBF Avenger torpedo bombers for the United States Navy. The facility was greatly expanded to accommodate the testing needs. After the end of the war, it was returned to the county and renamed Mercer County Airport. However, it remained partially military, with a Naval Air Warfare Center, which only closed in 1997. The airport’s name was changed again in 1995 to its current name (Trenton-Mercer Airport), after the city of Trenton, which is the state capital and county seat of Mercer County. Many plans were made to replace the old terminal, which residents along the flight path opposed. As a compromise, they renovated it in 2013, bringing it up to standard.  An eventual replacement was finally drafted in 2021, considering environmental concerns, and with 125,000 square feet of total area instead of 24,780 from the old one. FAA approved the project a year later, and the terminal was set to reach completion by mid-to-late 2024, but construction had yet to start by May 2024.  It’s served by Frontier Airlines, with flights to Atlanta, Fort Lauderdale, Orlando, and Tampa.  ‍ The scenery will feature custom ground textures, custom buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  There’s no release date or pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hgpt</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Gulfport–Biloxi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hgpt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c08231815ba3daf9cd8447_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Gulfport–Biloxi International Airport (KGPT). Situated in Gulfport, Mississippi, the airport serves the Gulfport-Biloxi metropolitan area and accommodates just over 685.000 passengers annually. In 1942, the airport opened as a training field for the United States Army Air Forces. Originally named Gulfport Army Airfield, it served as a training field until 1946, when it was placed into reserve status. In 1949, the airport was transferred to the City of Gulfport to be used as a civil airport. Passenger and cargo services started in the early 1950s. Since the transformation into a civil airport, the facility has been operated by a variety of airlines, including American Eagle, Breeze Airways, and others, offering flights to destinations such as Las Vegas, Tampa, and Atlanta. The airport handles just over 50.000 aircraft movements annually. The scenery includes an accurate airport representation, hand-crafted ground textures, dynamic lighting, highly detailed models, and more. The newly released scenery is now available on Orbx for approximately $12.33 and requires around 2.40 GB of disk space. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/1921rw</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Announces Release Window for A319 &amp; A321 Expansion</title>
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/1921rw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c0d7894ca0c3305ad044b4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After their recent introduction of the upcoming Fenix A319 &amp; A321 expansion, the team has just released a new post featuring a variety of liveries and art previews. The developer has also provided details about the release window for the new expansion. The team has rebuilt the fuselage textures from the ground up for the new expansion. For example, the A319 will now have stronger skin deformation on the airframe due to being in a higher pressurisation cycle state. The team has also provided a screenshot clearly showing these changes both below and above the cockpit windows on the A319. Additionally, the team informed us about their decision to offer both dual overwing exit and single overwing emergency exit options on the A319. This choice was made to provide users with the most realistic experience, allowing them to replicate real-life aircraft configurations used by specific airlines. Implementing this new option required the team to update reflections on the ECAM, cabin artwork, wing layout, and other related aspects. When it comes to the A321, the team had to make a decision. This time, the choice was between a two-class or single-class layout for the A321. Again, the team decided to include both layouts and the option to change between them, similar to the A319's overwing exit option. The team has confirmed that the new window textures are included, along with the unique double-slotted flaps on the A321. Additionally, they have shared a video comparing the full TOGA on the various aircraft versions with their respective CFM versions. As of now, the livery manager boasts a total of 450 liveries, with even more on the way. Lastly, the team has announced that the highly anticipated A319 &amp; A321 expansion will launch next week. Once more information is available, or the expansion has been released, Threshold will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a31921</id>
    <title>Fenix A319/321 Trailer Released, Release Date Revealed</title>
    <updated>2024-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a31921"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c3397c9c9405bc5a432ec7_A319_SMOL_A320_FENX_A321_FBIG.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The long-awaited release date for Fenix A319 and A321 is finally here! In the Expansion trailer made in classic Fenix style, at the very end of the video, one can see that the Expansion is releasing today!  After ‘Introduction to A319 and A321’ and ‘The Livery &amp; Art Preview’ dev updates were posted on Fenix’s website, lots of rumours began circulating the community about the release. Luckily, we didn’t have to wait much for more news.  The exact time of release is not known yet, unfortunately, but we do know the price! As stated earlier, the Fenix A319 and A321 Expansion will cost £39.99 (≈ $51.79). And as always, Threshold will keep you updated as to when the Expansion will be available for purchase. If you do not own Fenix A320, the Fenix team has you covered! There will be a special limited-time bundle deal! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeeddf</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Further Previews Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeeddf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c4f4dabf1b18f8b362076d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AviationLads has just released a new video featuring the highly anticipated Frankfurt Airport (EDDF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator by Aerosoft. In the video, Rafi, Jo, and Lukas discuss the development of the upcoming scenery while showcasing the airport. The 10-minute video provides an extensive look at the airport and includes the development conversation. The video provides a detailed look at all the features that the airport will have, demonstrating the extensive planning and consideration put into its creation. The pricing, release date, and features of the scenery have not been announced yet. We'll keep you updated with more information as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/niupnw</id>
    <title>Nimbus Studios Publishes Updates, News, for X-Plane 12 Products</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/niupnw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c74db5425936a0e2d5af43_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus are a renowned developer of the X-Plane community, bringing sceneries, aircraft and more to the simulator. As they transition products across from XP11 to XP12, bugs are fixed and textures improved.  ‍ X-Plane 12 Updates Nimbus Studios are wrapping up some important updates for their popular add-ons to ensure they work smoothly with the latest version of X-Plane, 12.1.2. Here's what's coming: Nimbus Studios has clarified that these updates are mainly focused on making sure everything works well with X-Plane 12.1.2, rather than adding new features. Importantly, all these updates will be free for existing users. ‍ New Project Updates  During FSExpo, Nimbus announced their latest two projects: ‍ Boeing 707: For the first time, Nimbus Studios is developing a jet-powered airliner simulation, starting with the Boeing 707. The team is focused on creating a detailed and realistic experience, featuring a meticulously crafted 3D cockpit. To make full use of the latest technology in X-Plane 12.1.2, they’ve completely redone the cockpit UVs and repainted the 3D models, showcasing their commitment to high quality. Pilot Challenge – Mission Editor: Another major announcement is the "Pilot Challenge," a mission editor that will change how users interact with X-Plane. This innovative tool lets users create, share, and fly missions with almost endless possibilities. The editor features an intuitive interface, allowing customization of interactions based on factors like position, time, speed, and altitude, making the simulator experience even more immersive. Some of the showcased features include Search and Rescue, Military Ops, Crop Spraying and Mountain Ops. We will make sure to provide the latest updates and news on these developments. In the meantime make sure to join our Discord community, to keep in the loop!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mswu17</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XVII: Germany, Austria, and Switzerland for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mswu17"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c75ba8538bac6749c13a6f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released its latest world update, World Update XVII: Germany, Austria, and Switzerland. The new update includes 10 TIN cities, 116 POIs, and three hand-crafted airports. The updated cities include Linz, Salzburg, Vienna, Berlin, Frankfurt am Main, Hanau, Karow, Potsdam, Bern, and Zurich. They have been significantly improved using recent aerial photographs and TIN surface modelling. Thanks to the new update, flight sim enthusiasts can explore a variety of cities in Austria, Germany, and Switzerland. Also included in the update are a total of 116 points of interest (POIs). In Austria, a total of 38 are included, 42 in Germany, and 36 in Switzerland. The three new hand-crafted airports are Salzburg Airport, Munich Airport, and Bern Airport. Each country in the new world update has received its own new hand-crafted airport. The new world update is available for free on the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msll19</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Local Legend 19: Focke-Wulf Fw 200 Condor for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msll19"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c771d123d66dc3266aea60_Banner_Image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released its nineteenth Local Legend. This release introduces the historically iconic Focke-Wulf Fw 200 Condor aircraft to Microsoft Flight Simulator. This addition allows enthusiasts to experience the sleek and powerful aircraft within the world of flight simulation. The Focke-Wulf Fw 200 Condor is a German four-engined airliner manufactured by Focke-Wulf. It made its first flight on July 27, 1937. Initially designed as an airliner, the aircraft was later used for military purposes as well. Civil operators of the aircraft included Deutsche Luft Hansa, BOAC, and Det Danske Luftfartselskab, while military operators included the Luftwaffe, Royal Air Force, and Spanish Air Force. A total of 276 aircraft were built. The new add-on comes with a total of three liveries including Classic Passenger (Black), Classing Passenger (Red), and Classic Metallic. The newly released add-on is now available on the in-sim Marketplace for $14.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/awltac</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases Tacloban Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/awltac"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c7bf10e5ac6389efdabf91_rpva1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airwil Sceneries recently released their rendition of Daniel Z. Romualdez Airport (RPVA) for X-Plane 11 and 12. This airport serves Tacloban, the Philippines, and has a yearly average of 1.5 million passengers.  It was constructed as an airstrip for the US Air Force during World War 2, housing multiple bombing and fighter units throughout the conflict. It was converted into a commercial airport soon after and renamed from San Jose Airstrip to Tacloban National Airport. In late 2013, Typhoon Haiyan demolished the terminal and the control tower, leading to a reconstruction effort. A few days later, it reopened for turboprop aircraft, and by November 14, it could already welcome narrowbody jets such as the 738 and A320. The passenger terminal was expanded in 2017 to accommodate the ever-growing passenger traffic figures, adding 1,100 square meters of floor area and an additional 275 seats in the pre-departure area, raising the total to 635. This sufficed for at least three simultaneous flights, whereas it could just barely handle two beforehand. Approval for the construction of a new terminal, capable of handling up to 1,670 passengers/hour, was granted in 2020. Construction started that same year and is halfway complete as of early 2023.  It’s served by Cebgo, Cebu Pacific, PAL Express, and Philippines AirAsia. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom POIs, custom ground clutter, custom interiors, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.66, requiring at least 3.76GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flycwl</id>
    <title>SoFly Announces Cardiff Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flycwl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c7c6035adad60c48e07851_cardiff1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SoFly has recently announced the development and imminent release of Cardiff Airport (EGFF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Cardiff, Wales, with a yearly average of 859,000 passengers. It was built as RAF Rhoose in 1941 and started operations a year later as the home grounds for the No 53 Operational Training Unit, which trained future Spitfire pilots for World War 2 and beyond. It was abandoned right after World War 2, only to be brought back to life in the early 1950s after the Minister of Civil Aviation brought up his wish to build an airport in South Wales. After much deliberation between the options, they decided to repair the abandoned RAF station and invest whatever was necessary to convert it into a commercial airport.  It was then inaugurated in 1952 as Rhoose Airport, with Aer Lingus being the first to start scheduled commercial service routes from their base in Dublin. Flights from the former main airport in Cardiff (Pengam Moors) were transferred to Rhoose in 1954, featuring flights to France, Belfast, and Cork.  In early 1965, the airport was transferred to Glamorgan City Council, which started a five-year development plan that included a new tower, a new terminal building, and a runway extension. The runway was further extended in the 1980s, marking its renaming as Cardiff-Wales Airport. The new extension attracted British Airways’ attention, as it could accommodate their Boeing 747s for maintenance.  ‍ A 100 million pound development strategy was announced in 2005, aiming to extend and upgrade the terminal. It was anticipated that it would attract up to 5 million passengers within a decade, a 150% increase. Only 3 million pounds were actually spent, half funded by the Welsh Government, refurbishing and redeveloping the passenger terminal. Further upgrade work was carried out in 2017 at an extra 4 million pounds. ‍ Aer Lingus, KLM, Loganair, Play, Ryanair, TUI Airways, and Vueling serve it. ‍ The upcoming scenery promises an accurate rendition of the airport, with an animated hangar, full GSX compatibility, highly detailed custom models, custom ground texturing, custom terminal interiors, and more. ‍ It’s set to release next Thursday (the 29th) for roughly $15.71.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍ ‍   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wed261</id>
    <title>WorldEditor Updated to Version 2.6r1 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wed261"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66c9a51af38b120466621386_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The X-Plane developer software ‘WorldEditor” has just received an update. The main portion of the update is set to bring new features for X-Plane scenery developers. The software is a key tool for devs, allowing them to modify and customize existing airports in X-Plane. One of the features to come with this update is the ability to now offer dual jetways. Each jetway can be assigned to a door on the aircraft, reducing the chances of jetways clipping through each other. In addition, devs can also export polygonal data (with exclusions) to third-party software to help design custom scenery elevations. Other minor updates include Shape Entities, Non-integer spacing for strings and tiles shader effects on ground textures. Finally, the team have added the feature to manually create 3D terrain. This feature was showcased on the iconic island of Saba and St Barths in the caribbean. Both airports have terrain around them that causes difficultly when departing or arriving. With all these new features, we can hope to see new sceneries being created for X-Plane, with high quality and exciting new options.  ‍ Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news, and remember to join our Discord Server!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arfpfa</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Release Further Previews of Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arfpfa"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ca097c9e4cb3970791d815_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After receiving the trailer in April this year, Areosoft has been hard at work developing their rendition of Frankfurt Main Airport. The team have released the second part of their interview to discuss progress. The video showcases the terminal interiors, airfield night lighting and some features that lie to the south of the airport. The video started with the team discussing how important being in touch with the real airport has been in development. The connection allowed them to stay accurate throughout the ground layout. The interior of an addon scenery plays an important role in improving the level of detail. 3D interiors create a depth of feel when pilots are parked on the stand. The team mentioned that it will not be 100% accurate as that level of detail will require an increase in resources and a reduction in performance. In addition, time spent modelling interiors could be spent on other finer details of the airport. The next portion of the video discusses night lighting. One challenge they faced was the vast amount of lights to be placed around the airport and the location they have. An interesting fact is that Frankfurt features over 40 different floodlights. Each has been modelled differently by the team. An approach into Runway 25R, will showcase the vast terminal and perimeter lighting system. The final portion of the video showcased some of the features you can find to the south of the airport. The largest apron is used by the Lufthansa Technical team, with most of the maintenance on Lufthansas fleet taking place there. Also, a new general aviation ramp to the southwest of the airport allows the flow of small aircraft operations. As the team close in on development, we will keep a close eye on the progress and make sure to provide the latest news!  ‍ Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold and join our Discord Server.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsve13</id>
    <title>Black Square Updates Velocity XL for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsve13"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ca45601905964bf68df4b7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square recently released an update for their Velocity XL add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing the aircraft to version 1.3. The new update includes various new features and bug fixes. The Velocity XL now supports the Working Title G3X Touch and is interoperable with TDS GTN and PMS50 GTN. In the simulator, users can now choose between the two GTN providers before spawning in the plane. Additionally, the aircraft now features new handcrafted 4K window surface imperfections, providing users with a more pleasant experience during low sun angles. The new version includes several bug fixes. The battery voltage curve has been adjusted, the internal attitude indicator type flag has been changed to electric instead of vacuum, and the parking brake is now automatically set when loading the aircraft on the ground. The updated Velocity XL is now available for download and can be purchased at Just Flight for $27.99.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bstb12</id>
    <title>Black Square Updates TBM 850 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bstb12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ca490f92c08630d33878fa_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square recently released a major update for their TBM 850 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The aircraft has been updated to version 1.3. The new update includes numerous new features and bug fixes. Some of the most notable features in the update include a new tablet interface, added wing flex, improved de-icing visuals, functional weather radar gain, and much more. This new major update has given the aircraft a variety of new features, making it as realistic as possible. The new version also includes numerous bug fixes. Due to the large number of fixes, we have included the complete changelog for the entire update below: ‍ v1.2 - Major Update: Tablet, Exterior Elements &amp; RNAV Autopilot ‍ ‍ New Features: ‍ - NEW TABLET INTERFACE!  The same great tablet interface you’ve come to enjoy in the Black Square Duke’s added to the Black Square TBM 850 for free.  Configuring options, hot-swapping avionics, payload settings, failure management, from the tablet, with real time visualizers for engines, electrical schematics, and environmental systems. - Improved environmental system accuracy necessary for the tablet visualizer - Exterior elements available via the tablet interface, such as pitot covers with “Remove Before Flight” flags that blow in the wind, engine covers, wheel chocks, and external power cart. - Improved external power logic for use with the exterior elements options on the tablet. - Wing flex added. - The KNS80 RNAV unit is now capable of controlling the autopilot when no GPS is selected as the primary radio.   See the “Using the KNS-80 RNAV Navigation System” for more information. - Added turbine engine specific failures enabled by the improved engine simulation required for the tablet visualizer, such as compressor stall and surging, P2.5 bleed valve failures, and fuel control unit failures. - Improved deicing visuals on the exterior model.  Ice will now break off of the leading edge of the wings only where there are boots, and melt slowly from heated surfaces. - Added SU15 ground handling parameters. - Added functional weather radar gain, controlled by the existing gain knob. - New sections added to the manual on the tablet interface, and control inputs and output variables, extending the manual from 109 to 160 pages.  Enjoy! - More equipment temperatures are now calculated for display on the tablet. - Instant Beta on Touchdown option added to the tablet interface.  Due to hardware deadbands, Black Square aircraft do not enter propeller beta range after touchdown if the hardware controller was already in the beta range before touchdown.  Enabling this option will apply full beta after touchdown to begin slowing the aircraft without the need to “bump” your hardware throttle. - Added true Pitch Sync functionality to yoke CWS buttons.  Pressing and holding “L:var_PilotCws” or binding “K:SYNC_FLIGHT_DIRECTOR_PITCH” to hardware controls will now allow the aircraft to be maneuvered in pitch while temporarily disabling the autopilot pitch servo. - A persistent tablet option has been added for a static tablet position more comfortable for VR users.  The option, titled “VR Tablet Static Position” will affix the tablet in a location farther away from the camera, obscuring as little instrumentation as possible. - Improved propeller governor simulation for smoother speed adjustments when testing overspeed limiter, and propeller governor failure is now gradual. - Added a visual detent to the power lever to indicate the flight idle position, as already exists in the Turbine Duke. - Reverse compatibility for VATSIM clients that use “COM RECIEVE ALL” for monitoring COM2 audio while transmitting on COM1. - Added emissive light source on the overhead panel lighting posts. - High bleed air flow torque performance reduction simulated. - Added support for 0.5 kHz ADF frequency tuning on the KR 87.  A secondary click on the power knob will increment the standby frequency by 0.5 kHz, which will indicate on the display with a small dot to the left of the frequency. - PMS50 WTT Mode has been integrated natively, so no additional packages are required to enjoy the advanced autopilot features available with the PMS50 GTN 750 as the primary source of navigation. - L:Var outputs have been added to all annunciator lights for use with home cockpits. - Added support for WeatherSquare 4000. ‍ ‍ Bug Fixes: ‍ - Finally!  There is a solution for the simulator’s internal rounding error when setting COM frequencies above ~134 MHz.  These frequencies will now work properly with 3rd party air traffic control clients in all Black Square Aircraft. - Gas generator vs. density altitude curve corrected for throttle response. - ITT and torque curves adjusted for more correct limiting factors at altitude. - Parasitic drag scaler increased by 1%.  High altitude cruising speeds are now correct to the knot based on POH tables. - Dynamic oxygen consumption was erroneously using the outside air pressure, rather than the interior cabin pressure to calculate the biological oxygen requirement.  Oxygen consumption in a partially pressurized cabin will now be substantially reduced. - Fixed several oversights in the electrical system pertaining to the essential bus tie. - Fixed annunciator panel test logic so active annunciators do not illuminate when the currently tested circuit does not have power. - Fixed GPS OBS setting with EHSI course knob when using WT GNS and PMS50 GTN. - Engine Trend Monitor shaft horsepower and specific fuel could read slightly high when ram air pressures were low. - RNAV distance would wind up to 999.9nm when a valid DME station was tuned, but the aircraft was on the ground.  This was due to interpolation added for autopilot control. - Performance fix for when both PMS50 GTN 750 and TDS GTNxi 750 are installed. - The autopilot would not follow the NAV2 VOR course deviation when selected on the EFS 40 EHSI in some circumstances. - Volume knob momentary push on the TDS GTNxi was producing “Knob Stuck” warning. - Airframe deicing controller circuit breaker was not tripping with failure. - Torque will no longer diminish at middle throttle settings when using time acceleration. - Overtorque annunciator warning and ETM exceedence redline adjusted. - Annunciator panel test switch inverted to test correct circuit. - Elevator control sensitivity reduced at low dynamic pressures. - VR Pilot Camera position set to match non-VR pilot viewpoint by default. - Fixed secondary GNS 530 com volume knob incorrect animation name. - Fixed COM 1 KX155 volume knob animation that had a lower maximum position than the COM 2 KXX155. - Increased glareshield light emissive intensity. The updated TBM 850 is now available for download and can be purchased at Just Flight for $41.99.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsprst</id>
    <title>Black Square Previews Starship for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsprst"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ca51b54455b99e3836f107_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently created a product page for their upcoming Starship add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Even though the developer mentions that the aircraft is a few months away from release, the new product page includes new previews and information, and also shows the progress made on the add-on. The upcoming Starship by Black Square will be one of the most technically advanced aircraft simulations for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The aircraft will have an accurate recreation of the Collins avionics suite, the most advanced pressurization and cabin temperature simulations in MSFS, and over 230 possible failures. Additionally, the aircraft will feature a new tablet interface, which will allow users to configure all options, manage payload, control failures, and monitor the engines from one place. The developer has not yet announced a specific release date for the aircraft, but has indicated that it is still a few months away. The price for the upcoming Starship has also not been announced yet. Additionally, an extensive PDF operating manual for the aircraft will soon be available once it is completed. We will continue to provide you with updates as soon as more information becomes available. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
