<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-11-20T18:31:42.863871+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nzawan</id>
    <title>NZA Simulations Releases Wanaka Region for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nzawan"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672c356b8f0c30410d5c981b_wanaka1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. NZA Simulations has recently released their rendition of Wanaka Airport (NZWF) and its surroundings for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring over 5000 square kilometers of enhanced terrain, nine airports, and more. Wanaka Airport serves the town of Wanaka, in Otago, New Zealand, with a passenger average circling around the 5 digit mark (exact numbers are not available).  It was built in 1984 on top of a pre-existing private airstrip owned by Tim Wallis, a Kiwi businessman and aviation entrepreneur, ultimately replacing Mount Iron Aerodrome, which used to be Wanaka’s only airport and deemed too small for their plans back then. Air New Zealand started scheduled services in 2004, canceling them after only nine years due to low demand (which would only peak during airshow weekends). Local businesses rapidly stepped in to fill the gap, albeit unsuccessfully.  ‍ In late 2020, SoundsAir started a scheduled service route to Christchurch airport, which is currently the airport’s only commercial traffic.  Other than the airport itself, the package also offers a 5000 square kilometer coverage around its surroundings, with nine airports in total, four helipads, 20+ mountain huts, 3D models, PBR texturing, high-resolution aerial imagery, 3D interiors for the main airport, Skydive Wanaka Hangar &amp; Customer area, Whare Kea Chalet Hut, Aspiring Helicopters, and Makarora Hangars. Below is a map with all the airports, airstrips, and landmarks included: It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $21.72, requiring at least 4.19 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sharks</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases Sharklets Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sharks"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672ad40126a28c4a9b738d5a_sharklets20.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations has recently released the long-awaited sharklets update for their Airbus family lineup (except for the A319) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, at no extra cost and with a wealth of new features. While the A320 and the A321 will be getting the sharklets as of right now, the A319 will take a while. They claim it's been a bit tricky to obtain reliable data on it, as not many exist in real life.  The sharklets are more than just a visual thing. Airbus went the extra mile to warrant similar handling and overall behavior between both variants, mainly on the "software" side of things, making it hardly noticeable if one doesn't look closely enough. Fenix Simulations claims to have accurately replicated the subtle system differences and flight dynamics behavior, warranting a realistic experience. The flight model has been adjusted to the sharklets, with a bit more lift on the wings, less drag, and extra energy on flare, which is said to be subtle but noticeable if you pay close attention. Regardless, the fly-by-wire system should make the overall handling feel relatively homogeneous across all variants, as in real life. As previously mentioned, there are also software changes, with upgrades to the two elevator and aileron computers, three spoiler elevator computers, and the two flight augmentation computers, as well as less significant changes to the ECAM, fuel, FMGC, and more.  Among these ELAC changes, Fenix Simulations highlights the Load Alleviation Function, which alleviates wing structure loading, as the extra weight of the sharklets also means more strain on the wings, making them bend more aggressively in extreme conditions. The LAF system rapidly deploys ailerons upwards while in-flight or spoilers 4 and 5 to prevent that. The FBW system was also tweaked to accommodate the new system and its inherencies. Ground physics also underwent improvements. The tiller mapping from the real A320 was applied to their add-on, adding a bit of extra weight to the taxi phase across their entire range of aircraft (wingtips included). They have also built a custom wingflex model to accommodate the more obvious sharklet wingflex, taking into account a lot of factors such as localized forces, fuel tank level, etc. It has also been backported to the wingtip fences. They also reinforce that it's mostly a work in progress and might not be perfect initially. The ADIRS model has been upgraded to the newer version, applying to both aircraft. The old one has been ultimately retired as it's rare in currently flying A320s anymore. The ACP was also upgraded, and the old one was phased out. They plan on bringing both the old ADIRS and ACP as options in the future. The new digital standby instrument has also been added as an integral - and forced - part of the sharklets modernization, complete with the correct degraded displays and its functions. Lastly, the ACT tanks were added to the A321, allowing for realistically operated transcontinental flights and routes like Finnair's HEL—PMI. The presence of the ACTs also means less space in the cargo compartment, which is also modeled. The complete changelog follows down below: Avionics and Systems The update is available right now via Fenix Installer. The full bundle (A319/A320/A321) is available on their website for roughly $103.87. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avrorj</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Avro RJ Professional for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avrorj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672e4d368f3171d57da27d35_erejota1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight has recently released their rendition of the Avro RJ for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, bringing a high fidelity simulation of all three variants (RJ70, RJ85, and RJ100) of the popular short-haul regional airliner manufactured by British Aerospace. ‍ The RJ is objectively an upgraded BAE 146, featuring a modern cockpit (for the early 1990s), and newer engines featuring FADEC and digital avionics. Their revamp allowed the model to remain relevant in times when the 146 was getting too old for modern-day aviation due to its analog systems, and other manufacturers already had their own “future-proof” alternatives. The add-on features an accurate rendition of the airplane, with all three variants created from real-world aircraft plans and comprehensive photography of the real thing, sporting a highly detailed passenger cabin and galleys customized for each variant, custom-modeled ground equipment, high-resolution textures, a custom-coded GNLU-910A FMS, and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ VARIANTS ‍ All three variants of the RJ are included: ‍ ‍ MODEL ‍   COCKPIT ‍   LIVERIES ‍ The RJ comes with a variety of liveries representing the aircraft's numerous operators from all around the world:   RJ70 ‍ RJ85 ‍  RJ100 ‍  A PSD Paint Kit is also available to download, allowing for the creation of custom livery and cabin textures. ‍   SYSTEMS ‍ RJ Professional features fully custom-coded aircraft systems with a high degree of complexity and depth, including:   Air-conditioning and pressurisation system ‍ APU ‍ Auto-flight system ‍ Communication system ‍ Doors and stairs ‍ Electrical system ‍ Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) ‍ The aircraft is equipped with a tablet EFB for controlling various aircraft options and payloads, including: ‍ The EFB can also be used for flight planning and monitoring: ‍ FDE and effects ‍ Fire protection system ‍ Flight controls ‍ Flight Management System ‍ Fuel system ‍ Hydraulic system ‍ Ice and rain protection system ‍ Indicating and recording systems ‍ Landing gear ‍ Lighting ‍ Navigation systems ‍ Oxygen system ‍ Passenger cabins ‍ Pneumatic system ‍ Power plant ‍ Sounds ‍ ‍ OTHER FEATURES ‍ The add-on is available in their store for $69.99 (or in a bundle with the 146), requiring at least 2.6 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs24cd</id>
    <title>FS24 Collector's Edition Delayed: Aerosoft</title>
    <updated>2024-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs24cd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/672eff2b71d294a8af0119f8_MSFS2024_Steelbook.jpg.avif"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Update Nov. 15 - 1700z: Microsoft have now provided comment on the delays and have outlined a plan to address the situation. Read more about it here. ‍ In an email sent out to customers this week, Aerosoft has stated that orders for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 Collector’s Edition have been delayed. Delays will affect orders made on Aerosoft’s EU Store, but orders made on their US Store will be delivered on schedule. According to the email, the delay has been caused by “unexpected shipping delays to our warehouse in Germany”. Aerosoft has not expanded on what specifically caused those delays. An exact timeline has not been given as of the time of writing, but they expect shipments to begin to customers “in the first week of December”. Aerosoft has further confirmed that activation codes will not be sent in advance of delivery on release day of FS24 on November 19th, but instead come delivered with the physical items, so simmers who bought the Collector’s Edition in Europe will have to wait until their package arrives. As of the time of writing, Microsoft has not yet commented on the delays, but Threshold will keep you updated, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a22k24</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Publishes Statement on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a22k24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/662a8a712346f3e8020357cc_comanche4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. A2A Simulations has published a statement on its plans for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 development. The statement includes news on its Comanche 250 port for the new platform and its upcoming Aerostar 600. They have recently been granted access to the new SDK, and the Comanche 250 appears to work fine in MSFS 2024, with only a few issues requiring addressing, but Accu-Sim (the core system of their Comanche and all future planes) plays nicely with it. It should be available for the new simulator on day one or shortly after. A2A also said they will be providing assistance to transfer over the airframe state, files, and stuff to the new simulator when the time comes. Regarding fully bringing the Comanche to MSFS 2024 standards, it’s still under evaluation given the extra requirements for compliance, which has yet to be gauged whether it will be a lot of work. Therefore, no decision has been made yet about a native version for 2024. The 2020 version, though, should work in the new simulator just fine, albeit without the extra features that could be made possible with the latest SDK standards. They are still working on the Aerostar 600, albeit with the difference that the potential release date has been moved to 2025, as they need to reconsider their requirements for the new SDK. They reiterate aircraft development for MSFS is their top priority, and they plan on releasing more aircraft next year. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdocx</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Document Center</title>
    <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdocx"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6731c0376ba223ae6bb08c33_pmdgtext.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently released their own Document Center for their current product line. It features all of the documentation and support files, which are fully and freely available online with a wealth of content. Whereas they once used to be provided with the product files only, they will now be entirely available online, so Xbox and xCloud users can access the manuals from the comfort of any web-browsing capable device. Given its online nature, the manual can be updated much faster than usual, allowing them to quickly roll out any necessary changes or tweaks to their guides without requiring an actual aircraft update – or extra download – for that.  The manuals are available without a log-in wall, allowing potential customers to skim through them and judge the quality without committing to purchasing the aircraft. The Document Center is available through this link. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl321</id>
    <title>FSLabs Confirms Airbus A321-X for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl321"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67325a8b59834d034f96e79f_labus.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs recently confirmed the development and potential imminent release of their A321-X for Microsoft Flight Simulator after one of their forum members found a link to a new FSL webpage with references to the new product, which has yet to be officially announced.  Lefteris Kalamaras, FSLabs’ CEO, has confirmed the veracity of the leaked information and even attached two screenshots of the upcoming product. He also reiterated that some leaked information was merely placeholders and not representative of what would come. FSLabs rose to fame in 2016 after releasing the first high-fidelity Airbus A320 add-on in history. This add-on allowed Microsoft Flight Simulator X and Prepar3d users to experience the day-to-day operation of one of the most popular airliners of all time, one that had not yet been developed to such standards (which quickly changed within five years). ‍ While there’s no official feature list or any other concrete information for the time being, the company is known for pushing the boundaries of realism with most of their products, and that might be the case with their first step into the “new” simulator.  It’s also unknown whether it will be available for MSFS 2020, 2024, or both. Threshold will ensure that you are covered should further information be revealed.</summary>
    <published>2024-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwiad</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release Washington Dulles International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwiad"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67339250778ee59c56758176_iad1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. BMWorld and AmSim recently released their rendition of Washington Dulles International Airport (KIAD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Washington, D.C., with an average yearly of 25 million passengers. Opened in 1962, it’s one of the three major airports – and second busiest – serving the Metropolitan Washington Area, along with Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport (KDCA) and Baltimore/Washington International Airport (KBWI).  The original design was tweaked for the first time in 1985 when it no longer suited its role as Washington’s main airport. Midfield concourses were constructed to facilitate walking between terminals for connecting flights and other such activities, consequently unclogging the main terminal. Concourses C and D were the first to be built, followed by A and B, with the former only reaching completion in 2004. Plans call for a new three-story south concourse covering 51,000 square meters in total area, ultimately replacing Concourse A’s regional gates from the late 1990s. It’s a hub for Southern Airways Express and United Airlines and served by Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Allegiant Air, All Nippon Airways, American Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, Turkish Airlines, United Express, Virgin Atlantic, and WestJet. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution custom ground textures, custom ground markings, an up-to-date airport layout, a detailed terminal area, animated jetways, fully modeled terminal interiors, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $21.09, requiring at least 1.58 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ms24ti</id>
    <title>Microsoft Announces Release Times for FS24</title>
    <updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ms24ti"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6733cf07b5cc85101ff1202a_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has recently published a schedule outlining the release times for its new simulator across various time zones worldwide. The simulator will launch at 16:00 GMT, which means that New York will see the release in the early afternoon, Amsterdam in the early evening, and Tokyo will experience the release just after midnight. With just one week remaining until the release of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the excitement is beginning to build. Now that the specific release time is known, it's time to make plans to ensure you're ready to download it as soon as it's available. Microsoft has not yet provided answers or solutions for the delay of the Collector’s Edition we discussed earlier. ‍ We will update you as soon as Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is released or if we receive any further news regarding it. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navatc</id>
    <title>Navigraph Releases Live Traffic and ATC Sectors Beta for Navigraph Charts</title>
    <updated>2024-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navatc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6734e35f06867cbd9b73a4b1_atc1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has recently added live traffic functionality and ATC sectors to their Charts app, albeit in beta. The new functionalities will allow users to visualize virtual network traffic from VATSIM or IVAO and easily spot where to load in for the best coverage possible. ‍ The all-new real-time traffic visualization will show online traffic on major networks and display highly useful information upon clicking on the aircraft, such as ETA, PIC, type, current airspeed, altitude, etc. Toggling the ATC sector info will also display all current active sectors with ATC on, revealing extra information upon interaction, such as frequencies, controller’s name and rating, uptime, and more. Furthermore, they have also added a “gate availability” system on the map to ensure you never load on top of another pilot again. The system even displays a handy list with all the available stands so that you don’t have to do that work yourself. Navigraph has also mentioned they won’t stop there, with more to come in the future, and even subtly hint at a potential live traffic display on their built-in in-game panel for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It’s already available for Navigraph subscribers on the app’s newest update. New subscribers can get the charts app and their updated navdata on their website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jet111</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Updates E-Jets for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jet111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67361a028366088a0243d02d_E-JETS_FAMILY_BY_X-CRAFTS_E170_016.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts has recently issued a new update to their E-Jets lineup for X-Plane, bringing ILS autotune compatibility improvements, pitch attitude tweaks, and more. They have also announced their biggest Black Friday sale yet, with discounts ranging from 30 to 50%.  Update v1.1.1 focuses on improving what had been implemented in 1.1.0, which added automatic speed management, ILS autotune, steep approach capabilities on compatible aircraft, and next-gen pop-up displays. The changelog follows below: As previously mentioned, they have also announced their biggest Black Friday discounts yet. The E170 will be a record 50% off, and the other E-Jets will get a 30% discount. X-Crafts also plans to add an upgrade discount for users wanting the full lineup. Refer to their official blog post for further information. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mu24cd</id>
    <title>Microsoft Provides Update on FS24 Collector's Edition Delay</title>
    <updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mu24cd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67377c6b80ea609535670160_IMG_3422.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In an announcement made on their website Wednesday, Microsoft addressed the delay in shipping the Limited Collector’s Edition of the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, as well as outlining their plan to make sure customers are able to access FS24 on release, in just four days. For context, Aerosoft, the vendor for the Limited Collector’s Edition, sent out an email to customers on Nov. 5, announcing that people who have pre-ordered the Limited Collector’s Edition outside of the US before Nov. 6 can expect delays in shipping and delivery. However, U.S. customers will not be affected. You can read more about that here. Microsoft begins by thanking customers who pre-ordered the Limited Collector’s Edition, and apologising, saying that they are “heartbroken that our shipping solution for regions outside of the United States have suffered an unexpected delay”.They also confirm that Limited Collector’s Edition pre-order customers outside of the U.S. can expect deliveries to start in the first week of December. To address these delays, Microsoft has announced a plan to ensure affected customers are able to play on release day, which is as follows: Additionally, when customers receive their Limited Collector’s Edition package, they will have to redeem the code on the physical token provided for the Aviator’s Edition of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 to keep access to the sim. According to Microsoft, “As long as you sign in with the same account when redeeming the token, then all your progress in the simulator will remain”. They also posted a FAQ addressing inquiries from the community. As of the time of publication, pre-orders for the Limited Collector’s Edition are still available on the Aerosoft Store for $259.99 USD. ‍ If you’re wondering when FS24 will be available for you, check out our article covering release times for FS24. Us on the Threshold team are excited for the imminent release of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and we will keep you updated on all of the newest developments regarding the new sim, so stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwpir</id>
    <title>BMWorld Accused of Piracy; Products Removed From Multiple Vendors </title>
    <updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwpir"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6737ada669f0a65e71498fad_eba5cc_cb8bea2af25441ce8bf155e7619752d1~mv2.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a bombshell statement published on Wednesday, Amir Salehi, owner of Flightbeam Studios accused fellow scenery developer Alexey Unishkov, better known as Beautiful Model of the World (BMWorld), of distributing pirated addons from multiple developers, including Flightbeam themselves. This comes on the heels of BMWorld/AmSim's release of Washington Dulles.  As of the time of publication, multiple flight sim product vendors have pulled BMWorld’s products from their stores, including his products developed in collaboration with Pavel of AmSim. ‍ Salehi details how he became suspicious of Unishkov, initially due to BMWorld/AmSim developing the same airports as Flightbeam, at around the same time. Then, a user on the AVSIM forums, going by the username of “Peter113” caught their attention, having few posts, with most of them being critical of Flightbeam’s products. Peter113 also posted screenshots comparing the BMWorld/AmSim rendition of KSFO to Flightbeam’s teasers of their rendition of the same airport. Threshold asked Salehi for comment on the identity of Peter113, and we were provided with a screenshot of the display name history for that user on AVSIM, which seems to indicate Peter113 was actually Pavel, frequent collaborator with Unishkov. Salehi continues on to his main point, saying that in September 2020, they identified and banned a user for distributing pirated files, specifically Flightbeam’s KPDX. Flightbeam achieved this by using a “tag” unique to the user’s scenery files, and checking it against the pirated files. That user was, according to Salehi, none other than Unishkov. They confirmed that it really was Unishkov by matching the email he put up on his website in his earlier days of flight sim development. Salehi says that they “discovered this information in July 2024, [and] we patiently awaited the developers’ decision to move on, hoping that the situation would dissipate”, but they are “now confronted with an egregious display of unprofessionalism and toxicity”. Umberto Colapicchioni, owner of FSDreamTeam, corroborated Salehi’s claims in a post on AVSIM, saying that Unishkov pirated products from them as well. Lars, founder of Contrail, added in the same forum thread that Unishkov was banned from Contrail for sharing a pirated copy of LatinVFR’s KMIA. ‍ Unishkov took to the AVSIM forums on Thursday to respond to these allegations, saying “I GUARANTEE THAT I HAVE NO RELATIONSHIP WITH THE PIRATE COMMUNITY AND HAVE NEVER HAD ANY RELATIONSHIP WITH THE PIRATE COMMUNITY!!!” He continues by decrying the actions of Salehi and others, claiming that they are “illegal accusations”, “defame[d] my honor and dignity”, and they “posted my personal data online without my consent, which is also illegal”. Unishkov ends his statement by defending his work, stating “I put my soul into every airport!!!”, and “I ask the author of the accusations to go to court to prove my guilt or to delete posts that contradict the law, contain slander, insults, and also to delete my personal data”.  Pavel (AmSim) also posted a response on his Facebook page defending Unishkov, claiming “the incident 4 years ago is not evidence of BMW's [Unishkov’s] involvement in the pirate community”. He also attacks the developers making the accusations, saying they “are trying to use dishonest methods of struggle [competition] against us”, and that the situation is “not at all about piracy (which does not really exist), but about the desire of competitors to kill our company”. ‍ In response to the claims made by Salehi, Lars, and Colapicchioni, multiple vendors of flight sim products pulled BMWorld and AmSim’s sceneries from their storefronts, including iniBuilds, Orbx, and SIMMARKET. iniBuilds announced on their forums and Discord server Thursday that they have pulled BMWorld’s products from their store temporarily, until “the situation is fully clarified and a definitive resolution is reached”, and that “these allegations,…touch on issues we take very seriously”. Orbx CEO Anna Cicognani stated in a forum post that “Orbx has decided to remove all BMW and BMW+AmSim products from its platforms due to a data protection breach”, and they are “actively communicating with the developer”. SIMMARKET posted on their Instagram announcing they have “temporarily suspended sales of all products from BMWorld”, due to “activities involving alleged intellectual property infringement”. All three said that existing BMWorld/AmSim customers will retain access to their products. ‍ This situation is still evolving, and Threshold is committed to keeping you up to date with all the latest developments, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pm2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Statement on MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pm2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67394c53db7a44e176e6bc13_1250410_20231128215337_1-88398891.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a statement on their Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 plans, including potential upgrade fees, the upcoming 777F, and future products. They claim to have been given access to the new platform, stating it’s a “spectacular platform” with a visual quality never seen before, which gets them excited about what is to come. While singing high praises for MSFS 2024, they are unsure how long it will take to convert their product lineup, let alone gauge the amount of work required. Hiccups with the new platform are expected, as they have faced with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, and they will be “forgotten in no time once the fixes roll out.” “The team at Asobo has incredible depth of skill and energy and they will come through”, concluded Randazzo. ‍ Most of their development team is already running the new simulator. However, they have been unable to prove cross-compatibility with their MSFS2020 lineup, which is said not to be a surprise to them, nor unexpected. In other words, they do not yet have a clear picture of the state of their products against the new platform. ‍ Compatibility-wise, Microsoft has been contacting PMDG to address minor issues with their 737 lineup, which Randazzo assumes has to do with their testing effort to ensure near-flawless cross-compatibility between the two platforms. ‍ From the release of MSFS 2024 onwards, their products will fall into three categories: MSFS2020 only, MSFS2020/24, and MSFS 2024 only. The former means the product won’t function in 2024, the middle will mean it will load in the new simulator, albeit without any 2024-specific features, and the latter means it will only work in the new platform (747-400 and 747 Classic Whale, for example). ‍ On whether their current product lineup will be updated to include MSFS 2024 features, Randazzo has said they plan on it, but they are still evaluating the SDK and how much work will need to be carried on for that to happen reasonably.  ‍ Their provided list sheds some light on which of their add-ons will get special treatment: the 737, 77W, and all future products. The DC-6, on the other hand, might not get upgraded at all.  ‍ While the 77W feature upgrade will be charged, Randazzo promises a small fee or none at all. The 737 lineup will get a modest upgrade charge, as it’s said to be receiving a significant upgrade. ‍The 777F, rumored to be released in late October, is waiting on MSFS 2024 for compatibility testing. Their current plan is to release it for both platforms at no extra charge, but the “option is on the table” to not release it for 2020 at all in exchange for greater features—and increased development time—and platform singularity. ‍ They will continue to support their MSFS 2020 product lineup, but their long-term strategy is to move all new development to the new simulator, meaning MSFS 2020 might not see any new releases. ‍ PMDG’s product lineup is available on PMDG.com, ranging from $34.99 to $74.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mrfs24</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2024-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mrfs24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673bddf79fe0f69194d99625_MSFS2024_JPG-9de6e8972db1e3f8fc95-scaled.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Today is the day flight simmers around the world have been waiting for months to arrive. Microsoft has released its highly-anticipated follow up to their longest running, critically acclaimed franchise, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Developed in collaboration with French developer Asobo Studio, the new simulator includes many gamechanging features, and highly-requested community fixes from the previous version, in what Microsoft is calling “The Most Ambitious Flight Sim Ever”.  Headlining features include the all-new Career system, 3D ground textures, first-person mode, overhauled weather and physics engines, and more, adding realism to their “digital twin”. Microsoft also claims that they have drastically reduced install size for this release, which was a widespread complaint about MSFS 2020, to around 30 gigabytes, compared to MSFS 2020’s gargantuan 300 gigabyte install with all World Updates installed. This has been enabled through Microsoft’s full embrace of cloud streaming through their Azure servers, putting most of the simulator in the cloud, including the entire in-sim Marketplace. With FS24, Microsoft and Asobo have broken new ground by collaborating with many developers who previously were primarily third-party developers, such as Orbx and iniBuilds. Nowhere is this more apparent than in the aircraft category, with 14 different development teams working on base aircraft for the simulator. However, it’s not just aircraft that are getting all the love, base systems have also gotten new features with every vertical obstacle being added in, as well as an Electronic Flight Bag with Charts, being developed by Orbx and Working Title respectively. Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is available for purchase on both Steam and the MS Store, in four different editions, with Standard Edition on the low end, and Aviator Edition on the high end. The main differentiator between each edition is how many planes and handcrafted airports come as default, with the Standard Edition containing 70 default aircraft and 150 handcrafted airports, while the Aviator Edition contains 125 aircraft and 160 airports. (For a full breakdown, see our previous article about what each edition contains.) Standard Edition - $69.99 - Steam - MS Store Deluxe Edition - $99.99 - Steam - MS Store Premium Deluxe Edition - $139.99 - Steam - MS Store Aviator Edition - $199.99 - Steam - MS Store This release marks the turning of a new chapter in the flight simulation genre. With MSFS 2020 amassing 15 million players and with nearly 5,000 Marketplace creations over its lifetime, expectations are high for the new sim. The Threshold team are very excited about this new entrant into MSFS history and we will be sure to keep you all up to date with the latest news and high-quality reviews throughout this next chapter, so stay tuned!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mamldi</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Video Addressing MSFS 2024 Launch Day Issues</title>
    <updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mamldi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/673d4cab13e6f471151dafa2_Screenshot%202024-11-19%20at%208.21.31%E2%80%AFPM.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In a video posted to their YouTube channel, Microsoft has released a launch day development update regarding the situation of the recently released Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Hosted by Head of Microsoft Flight Simulator Jorg Neumann, Asobo CEO Sebastian Wloch, and Xbox Senior Community Manager Jayne Reynolds, the update comes as a response to many users who are experiencing issues while downloading the sim, such as software crashes, long download times, and missing default aircraft. Neumann starts off by stating that they “are really proud in what [sic] we’ve accomplished with the sim” and they knew “the excitement was high for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024”, but he acknowledges that they underestimated the extent of the excitement for the new sim and that it “has overwhelmed our infrastructure”. Wloch says that they “have been struggling for a few hours with one of our services” and explains that the root cause of the issues has been a cache overflow in their servers. He goes further into detail, saying when “they [Players] start, they are…asking a server for some data, and that server is going to catch [sic] it in a database…and that database is currently getting saturated”.  Wloch then describes what they have done to address the issue: “We’ve tried to restart the services, we’ve taken measures to throttle the number of people who can come in [download],...and it worked well during [sic] maybe half an hour or so and then all of a sudden, the cache collapsed again so we’re restarting…[and] trying to investigate”. ‍ Neumann continues by reassuring the community, acknowledging that they know “a lot of people are frustrated” but they “want to be as transparent and open as possible”, and adds that “the team is on it”. Finally, Reynolds concludes by thanking the community for all their feedback and that “We appreciate each and every one of you, and we’ll see you in the skies soon”. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
