<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-12T18:18:44.308721+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/silkun</id>
    <title>Silvercrest Creations Releases Kumasi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/silkun" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d1e6dc477a92b0d753132a_kum.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3095999"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Silvercrest Creations has recently released their rendition of Kumasi International Airport (DGSI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Kumasi in Ghana with a yearly average of 500,000 passengers.  The Royal Air Force built the airport in the early 1940s to serve as a military air base, becoming a civilian airport two years after the conflict was over upon authorization granted by the British Empire.  ‍ A decade later, the airport underwent major redevelopment work on the runway and infrastructure, ensuring proper viability for commercial operations. The runway was improved again twenty years later with lights for nocturnal operations. ‍ A new terminal was built in 1993 - commissioned by President Jerry John Rawlings -.Then, in 1999, it was changed from a military and commercial hybrid into a commercial airport only. ‍ New terminal improvements came in 2008 for the African Cup of Nations and between 2014 and 2022, including a full expansion with the construction of a new 7,000 square meter terminal with VIP lounges, restaurants, commercial areas, three boarding gates, a central screening system, and an IATA compliant baggage handling system.  ‍ The airport is currently served by Africa World Airlines and Passion Air, with flights to Accra and Wa. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D model of the passenger terminal, custom objects, a terminal interior, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.87, requiring at least 432.56 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cowsd4</id>
    <title>New updates regarding COWS Diamond DA42!</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cowsd4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d2d8fe12a1ce1c15f0c0ae_webimage-B0D3B2B8-0249-4B85-A370BCE815CD4CEA.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="972618"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Jacob provided an update covering the progress of the DA42 for X-Plane 12 via their Discord Channel. COWS is known for their meticulous flight testing and aims to provide the most accurate DA42 for X-Plane 12. With flight testing from real-world DA42 pilots, this iteration of the Diamond will likely be the most accurate you can buy. Improvements in the visual modeling and texturing, aiming to make the model as visually appealing as the MSFS counterpart.  Progress advancements for the in-house COWS NXi, a replica of G1000, are also highlighted. The development of the NXi may take slightly longer than anticipated, but steady progress has been made. Highly configurable, the NXi will feature in-depth renditions of the many complex configurations of the displayed GPS map. The addition of RAIM prediction to the map is a notable progress. See the map NXi in action here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more news regarding the progress of COWS DA42! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sswr26</id>
    <title>Sim Skunk Works Releases SF260</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sswr26" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d2ee4fc81b4e5709d37170_323944_image4.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="518586"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Sim Skunk Works has released their rendition of the SIAI-Marchetti SF260. The release comes after a lengthy hiatus following the development group's last release, their rendition of the FRF-104G Starfighter.  ‍ ‍ The SIAI-Marchetti SF260 is typically marketed as a military and aerobatics trainer. Boasting a 6-cylinder air-cooled Lycoming engine attached to a Hartzell 2-blade constant speed propeller the SF260 has a cruise speed of 160 kts and a range of over 800 nautical miles.  ‍ ‍ Currently, the SF260 is available from SimMarket for €23 and features a fully animated 3D cockpit, high definition PBR textures, and fully modeled systems. The aircraft is also slated for future release on both Orbx as well as the MSFS Marketplace. ‍ ‍ Threshold looks forward to keeping you up to date on all things flight simulation!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmsrha</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Horta Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmsrha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d33f03b1e2ef5455a8b422_horta1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="362818"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations has recently released their rendition of Horta Airport (LPHR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the municipality of Horta in the Azores with a yearly average of 250,000 passengers.  It was inaugurated in 1971 by President Américo Tomás during his efforts to connect the Azores with Portugal, sporting a single 1,600-meter-long runway and a simple passenger terminal, which underwent a huge renewal process in 2001.  The airport has been growing more popular among tourists lately, leading to runway lengthening plans in the near future.   It’s served by Azores Airlines (Lisbon) and SATA Air Açores (Corvo, Flores, Ponta Delgada, and Terceira).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom night lighting, PBR materials, custom surroundings, real-world-based terraforming profile, up-to-date CGL data, animated objects, and custom parking positions as per real life.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $16.39, requiring at least 1.53 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/matmdg</id>
    <title> “A New Adventure”: Industry Veteran Mathijs Kok Joins PMDG</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/matmdg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d39204053f087afdcb280d_1250410_20230710233634_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1494104"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Yesterday morning, Mathijs Kok reappeared on the Aerosoft Forums under a new account - weeks after announcing his departure from the company after 20 years of service -defending his former company with a statement on how he shaped the forum as he'd enjoy it if he were a customer, and then signing the post as "Mathijs Kok - PMDG Simulations." ‍ As PMDG had not officially announced such a move, the community wondered whether it was an elaborate prank rather than the next big transfer of the flight simulation niche. For a while, there were no answers from either Aerosoft or PMDG, but Robert Randazzo broke the silence, confirming that Mathijs had, in fact, joined PMDG: "I'm personally thrilled to welcome my very long-time friend, Mathijs, to the PMDG team. I'll have more to say on this topic a bit later - and I may or may not shine a light on some of what we'll have him doing as part of our expansion going forward". "Anticipate him hanging back a bit while he gains his footing and gets up-to-speed. Our culture is very different from the one he has left behind after two decades- and his role here will be quite a bit different as well. There are a few key moments in PMDG's history- and it has been 15 years since we made specific, positive changes to improve the wider skill level and capabilities of our team. Mathijs coming aboard the PMDG team is one of numerous changes taking place in the background that go a long way toward my strategic objectives for PMDG- and I assure you you will be excited when you see what that plan looks like.", he concluded. ‍ ‍ Mathijs himself had also made an appearance on PMDG's forum, thanking everyone for the support and explaining his decision to leave Aerosoft after so many years: "As a project manager, you have a task and resources, and they were not well aligned in my opinion. Aerosoft in 2023 is also a very different company than it was when I joined". "When he (Robert Randazzo) offered me to join his team, I did not hesitate. I did not even think about it. It feels like an adventure. One that is very welcome and really reinvigorated my love for the hobby and its users", he added. ‍ ‍ Then, he stated how PMDG's structure suits his style better, with no sales department or marketing office aiming exclusively at production and sales happening almost automatically in response to a great product. ‍ Threshold will keep you informed on the matter may Robert Randazzo reveal his new position at PMDG.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inlppd</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Ponta Delgada - João Paulo II Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inlppd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d3963c85019f537ebbc02b_lppd1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="611286"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Ponta Delgada - João Paulo II Airport (LPPD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the municipality of Ponta Delgada in the Archipelago of the Azores with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport's construction started in 1963, with the official inauguration only happening six years later in 1969 by President Américo Tomás. Its primary purpose was serving inter-island connections and Europe, with regular flights to Lisbon beginning a year later.  A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1995 when the airport also got its current name after the Pope's visit to the Azores four years prior.  The following decade post-new terminal brought massive growth in passenger traffic, which has been steadily growing, connecting the Azores to the world.  Azores Airlines, Binter Canarias, British Airways, Edelweiss Air, Iberia, Lufthansa, Ryanair, SATA Air Açores, Smartwings, Swiss, TAP, Transavia, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Netherlands, and United Airlines all serve it, with most of them only offering their services during summer. It's also the most important cargo airport in the archipelago, handling over 10,000 tonnes yearly.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, hand-made textures, custom POIs, true-to-life landside recreation, a detailed terminal interior, an official GSX profile, and more.  It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.55, requiring at least 3.06 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winbsa</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Benito Salas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winbsa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d3a1aa257b3f6140bd6125_benito1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2764768"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Benito Salas Airport (SKNV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Neiva in Colombia with a yearly average of 270,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was built on land that once belonged to Bertha Borrero de Valenzuela (La Manguita Farm), Abacú Lozano, and Silvestre Falla Borrero, totaling up to 130 hectares. It was inaugurated under the government of President Misael Pastrana Borrero in 1974, with the terminal design signed by Antonio Uribe Martínez, a famous architect from Bogotá, making use of modern lines, large terraces, thick walls, and exposed brick facades. ‍ The airport is currently undergoing a renovation process that includes a new control tower and an improved parking garage. ‍ It’s served by Avianca, EasyFly, and LATAM Colombia, with daily flights to Bogotá and Cali (EasyFly only). ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom ground equipment, an up-to-date layout, a custom terminal interior, custom night lighting, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.84, requiring at least 995.73 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fv2bl1</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases A320 V2 Block 1 Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fv2bl1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d4fc1d20f1131e285fa6fb_v2-release.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="379095"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently released their biggest update so far for their A320 add-on, adding a new display rendering method, new pax layout, flight model improvements, and more.  According to the developers in a development update published earlier today, the update almost got delayed due to a game-breaking issue, which they managed to fix after three days of extensive testing.  Update v1.5.1.193 will bring substantial changes to the aircraft, easily noticeable through the hefty changelog with multiple fixes and additions. The highlights of V2 Block 1 are the new displays, performance improvements (which we have previously covered and shown some of their benchmarks), and a new flight model, with tweaks to the airplane’s behavior on multiple stages of the flight. The changelog follows down below: ‍ V2 Block 1 A320 CFM V1.5.1.193 [APP] [EFB] [DISPLAYS] [FM, FBW &amp; AUTOFLIGHT] [AVIONICS &amp; SYSTEMS] [VISUALS] [SOUND] [KNOWN ISSUES] ‍  The developers also warned about the fact that the aircraft is transitioning from a nine-month release to a completely different build tested by their internal circle of testers, reinstating that even though they have tested it a lot, oddities could happen on various hardware configurations.  The second part of the V2 update - Block 2 - is set to release next month, bringing an improved 3D model, a new engine option, and tweaks to some of the systems.  The add-on is available on the Fenix Simulations store for roughly $63.65.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flytee</id>
    <title>Fly X Simulations Releases Teesside International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flytee" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d51e374343d6f91839bd3f_tee1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="757840"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly X Simulations has recently released their rendition of Teesside International Airport (EGNV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving North East England with a yearly average of 200,000 passengers.  It started as an RAF airfield in 1941, housing the RAF and the Royal Canadian Air Force during WW2.   Twenty years later, the airfield was developed into a civil airport named Tees-Side Airport. Many airlines served it during its first decade, including British Midland, BKS Air Transport, Dan-Air, Autair, and Channel Airways.   The 1970s were particularly rough for Teesside regarding scheduled services, with holiday flights becoming its primary source of passenger traffic through the wings of Northeast Airlines, Britannia Airways, Aviaco, Spantax, and Aviogenex.   Privatization came in 1987, with local authorities retaining their shares and the airport getting its current name: Teesside International Airport.  The airport was heavily upgraded in 2017 after a troublesome decade post-2008 crisis leading to a massive drop in passenger traffic figures leading to many airlines abandoning it for other nearby airports.   The renewal and subsequent takeover in 2018 brought back a lot of traffic, and the figures have been rising ever since.  BH Air, Eastern Airways, KLM, Loganair, Ryanair, and TUI Airways currently serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR texturing, custom orthophoto for the airport and surroundings, custom terminal interior, custom ground textures, high-resolution textures, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $15.25, requiring at least 2.76 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthpva</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Puerto Vallarta Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthpva" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d5279471883bb3ca9c9dae_val1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1449461"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Licenciado Gustavo Díaz Ordaz International Airport (MMPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Puerto Vallarta in Mexico with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. ‍ The airport’s history dates back to the early 20th century when it started as a small airstrip serving the then small fishing village of Puerto Vallarta. In the 1960s, with Puerto Vallarta’s tourist boom, the government decided to invest in its potential and build a proper airport, which only started in the early 1970s, inaugurated in 1974. ‍ The airport has been upgraded and expanded multiple times ever since, with the most recent one starting in 2022, allowing for 65% more operations a year. ‍ It’s served by multiple airlines, including Aeroméxico, Aeroméxico Connect, Air Canada, Air Transat, Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Finnair, Flair Airlines, Frontier Airlines, Magnicharters, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, Sunwing Airlines, Swoop, TAR, TUI Airways, United Airlines, United Express, Viva Aerobus, Volaris, and WestJet. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail buildings, PBR texturing, custom animated jetways, custom ground poly, improved taxiway and runway lighting, hand-placed objects and clutter, and custom night lighting.  ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.73, requiring at least 339.26 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cssdvu</id>
    <title> Crosstail Studios' A-1H Skyraider Dev Update</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cssdvu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d650eb3a496e72855c8eb9_366375757_666912625484279_6941976853579164448_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="265516"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Crosstail Studios has made amazing progress in their A-1H Skyraider module for DCS World. They have all been working day and night in order to produce a realistic rendition of this magnificent aircraft. There are multiple areas which are touched on in this article ranging from Flight Model changes to their Future development plans. ‍ The journey has just begun! With plans to infuse life-like animations and intricate textures. Stay tuned, as they continue to develop this amazing aircraft and more updates come to light. In conclusion, Crosstail Studios continues to provide development updates to this module and although no pricing information or release date has been confirmed, Threshold will keep you informed as more news comes to light. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a120</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a120" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d65769ea6688dd6d79da83_comanche45.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="714985"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  A2A Simulations has recently updated their Accu-Sim Comanche to version 1.2.0, improving animations, ground physics tweaks, auto-rudder support, and more.  It’s the second update since its release in mid-July, bringing 40 changes. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ ‍ They finish the update announcement with a note saying they are still investigating an issue where the tablet is unclickable on SU13 Beta for VR users.  The add-on is available on their store for $49.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfshou</id>
    <title>Windsock Simulations Bringing Houston Hobby to X-Plane 12!</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfshou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d67b17ef330ca4edb342d6_364801211_615774600538721_677912053120229073_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="230414"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Windsock Simulations has announced a partnership with FSim Studios which will bring their rendition of Houston's William P. Hobby airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12.  William P. Hobby Airport (KHOU) is located 7 miles from downtown Houston and is the oldest operating airport in the area. Houston Hobby as it's referred to features 4 runways and acts as a main operating base for Southwest Airlines. The airport sees over 13 million passengers each year and has flights operating to most parts of the United States as well as international service to many Central and South American destinations. Windsock stated in their announcement that the project is still in its early stages but is progressing quickly. They have not announced a release date, yet but have said "we don't expect it to be long…" Threshold is excited to bring you future updates on this and many other projects! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pu7071</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pu7071" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d6c38610115e25ed35735c_1250410_20230529191347_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2156550"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently updated their 737 Lineup to version 3.00.0071, improving its stability, performance, and functionality on PC and Xbox. The new update focuses on performance improvements for lower-end machines and the Xbox Series S, improving memory usage. They have also fixed the engine spool behavior in low RPM ranges and made some AFDS roll control mode law adjustments, initialization sequence improvements, and back-end changes for future EFT compatibility. The complete changelog follows down below:   Robert Randazzo has also informed us about a delay on the 737-700 and -800's 3.00.0070 update on Marketplace (a version behind), which should match the other members of the lineup on 3.00.0071.   The EFB is still undergoing testing, with them recently pushing a build to their beta team with changes based on their feedback. They are already discussing a potential release date.  The 737 Lineup is available on PMDG's Store for $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800), $49.99 (737-900), and $34.99 (737-600). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/teaneo</id>
    <title>Threshold Exclusive: Aerosoft Developing A321neo Alongside A330neo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/teaneo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64d6ec3b8a303ebccfee5d41_Airbus%20Neo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="514500"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. German flight sim developer Aerosoft is planning to develop an Airbus A321neo alongside the previously announced A330neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  ‍ According to a post on the website of the German Ministry of Economic Affairs and Climate Action, Aerosoft has received €459,000 from a grant to partially fund their development of the “AirbusNEO series”, which includes the A330neo and A321neo.  ‍ ‍ The grant was set up by the German government in 2019 to help boost the games sector within Germany, and to make Germany a hub for game development in Europe. The German government has provided up to €50 million each year in grants, and has funded over 400 different video game projects. ‍ Currently, Aerosoft has been hard at work on their highly anticipated A330ceo project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which has come under new management after their previous product manager of more than twenty years, Mathijs Kok, left Aerosoft for the PMDG team. As of the time of writing, Kok’s new position at PMDG has not been revealed to the public yet.As for the A321neo and A330neo, there are a lot of unknowns about their respective projects. The posting on the website says that, “Numerous functions, animations and sound effects are to be developed using state-of-the-art tools that have not yet been implemented in Microsoft Flight Simulator”, suggesting that the complexity of these two aircraft will be something unlike their previous work in MSFS. We do not know when an intended release date would be, which aircraft will be released first, or if Aerosoft plans on releasing them as a bundle, as suggested by the post.  ‍ At this point in time, much about both aircraft are up to speculation, but what we do know for certain is that they are planned, and they are coming in the near future.Threshold will keep you updated on all the developments regarding the upcoming Aerosoft airliners, so stay tuned! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mwitmg</id>
    <title>Matt Wagner Interviewed on 'The Mover and Gonky Show'</title>
    <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mwitmg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b327f6678e65e8f3e4d339_DCS_2.8_World_Combat_Flight_Simulator-04.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1140902"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Matt Wagner was recently Interviewed on 'The Mover and Gonky Show'. This was a two hour long video which included a DCS World Q&amp;A. There are some interesting points made in the video so I encourage you to watch the video aswell.  A Broader Scope:The grand vision is to have a battlefield where ground units can operate seamlessly alongside helicopters and jets. This would mean an immersive experience where users could transition between different theaters of war, each detailed and realistic. ‍ Ground Movement Animation:One of the focal areas for the Eagle Dynamics team currently is the ground movement for infantry. The older animations have stood the test of time but are now due for a refresh. An updated animation is in the works, promising more fluid and realistic movements, in sync with the advancements in game development technology. ‍ New Additions and Updates:While some might be disappointed about the absence of Ukraine and Taiwan maps due to their sensitive nature, the future holds promise: Media Influence:The recent release of Top Gun 2 has spurred an interest in DCS modules. The movie's success resulted in a surge of sales for DCS modules, prompting Eagle Dynamics to release the special 'Be a Maverick' pack, which bundled the F-14, F/A-18, and Supercarrier. ‍ Challenges and Solutions:It's not just about adding new content, but also about refining existing modules: ‍ Potential Future Additions:Questions have arisen regarding the addition of certain aircraft like the SAAB Gripen or the Rafael. The challenge in adding 4+ gen aircraft is the acquisition of necessary resources. However, with partnerships and introductions, nothing is off the table. There's even been talk about the Flanker being introduced as a full-fidelity DCS module, though data acquisition remains a significant hurdle. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
