<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-12T18:24:22.264308+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stebac</id>
    <title>Stellar Simulations Releases Bacolod-Silay Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stebac"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663556114517c0a446b242b9_bacolod1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stellar Simulations has recently released their rendition of Bacolod-Silay Airport (RPVB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Bacolod Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers as of 2022. The airport’s site was initially used as an airfield during World War 2 but was abandoned immediately after. Parts of the airfield became a sugarcane plantation. In 1997, a Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) study indicated the need for expansion at four Philippine airports, and Bacolod City Domestic Airport was one of them. It was relatively small for the traffic it was getting, and expansion was impossible, which led to the construction of a brand-new airport. Construction started in 2004, with a 900-day deadline to complete it. During the digging work, the remains of the former WW2 airfield and aircraft wrecks were found. The airport’s construction was considered complete by mid-2007, but there was debate at the time due to a pending runway extension that wasn’t complete yet. Commercial operations started in January 2008, replacing the old Bacolod City Domestic Airport.  Cebgo, Cebu Pacific, PAL Express, and Philippines AirAsia serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a custom terminal interior, landside buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground clutter, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.69, requiring at least 360.74 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmpet</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases St. Pete-Clearwater International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmpet"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663699602c7a5f3bd8629a57_pete1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of St. Pete-Clearwater International Airport (KPIE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Tampa Bay Area with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers as of 2023. Construction started in 1941 and was acquired shortly after by the United States Army Air Forces to be used as a training base. It was returned to the County after the end of WW2, renamed Pinellas International Airport. Its current name only came to be in 1958 because Pinellas County was not a very attractive name from a tourist standpoint, according to the airport manager (people didn’t know where it was). The administration spent $22 million on heavy renovation work in 2009, which included larger gates, jetways, new plumbing, and overall modernization. ‍ It’s an operating base for Allegiant Air, which flies to a wide range of destinations. Sun Country, Minneapolis’ local airline, also flies to St. Pete seasonally. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, LODs for optimization, a simple terminal for optimal performance, custom static models, custom taxiway signage, high-resolution PBR texturing, custom aerial imagery, an official GSX profile, and more. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $16.99, requiring at least 1.76 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pc6tp12</id>
    <title>Thranda Releases PC-6 Turbo Porter for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pc6tp12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6638e7992dbb7609a6801316_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda has just released their rendition of the Pilatus PC-6 Turbo Porter for X-Plane 12. Thanks to its superb STOL performance, and easy-to-maintain design, it is used all around the globe to deliver goods where regular aircraft cannot fly. With its first flight in 1959, the PC-6 Porter was produced at Pilatus Flugzeugwerke in Switzerland. It has been built in both a piston engine version and a turboprop-powered version and was also produced under license by Fairchild Hiller in the USA. After 604 planes were built, during a span of 63 years, Pilatus ended its production in 2022. ‍ Powered by a Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-27 turboprop 550 hp engine, the Turbo Porter can cruise at an altitude up to 26.800 feet, with a maximum speed of 125 knots. This gives the plane a range of 1,612 km (870 nm) or 730 km (390 nm) with maximum payload. Due to its amazing STOL capability, the Pilatus PC-6 can take from a runway as short as 195 meters (640ft) and land within a distance of 130 meters (427ft). Thanks to its performance, it holds the record for the highest landing by a fixed-wing aircraft, at 18.865 feet (5,750 m), on the Dhaulagiri glacier in Nepal. ‍ The Thranda PC-6 is a part of the DGS - Dynamic Generation Series, which takes full advantage of X-Plane’s flexibility and in-sim modifications. Some of the included features are: customizing a livery in-sim, changing instrument layouts with different panel configs, switching between different airframe configurations, high-fidelity and precise flight dynamics, and much more. Some of the notable features available in the XP12 version are:  The EFB has loads of apps, such as the Aircraft Options App, Weight and Balance app, Instrument Options app, Dynamic Panel app, Static Livery app, DynaFeel app, Log Book app, Checklist app, Ground handling app, Dynamic Livery app, Flight Computer app, and more. Thranda Pilatus PC-6 Turbo Porter is available for purchase on the X-Plane.org store for 44.95$, requiring at least 4.1GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrda5</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Releases DA-50RG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrda5"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66390d796daaee72c63eda15_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyward Simulations has just released their rendition of the Diamond DA-50RG for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The DA-50RG is a single-engine aircraft made out of a carbon fiber airframe, mostly used for general aviation and training purposes. Introduced in 2007, it was designed to replace the aging single-engine DA-40. After the Economic Recession in 2009, the DA-50 project was put on hold, and by 2019, no model other than a prototype was made. In 2020, a new version with a Continental CD-300 engine and retractable gear was announced. Later on, it became known as the DA-50RG. With a service ceiling of 20,000ft and a maximum speed of 191 knots, the Diamond DA-50 has a range of 750 nm (1389 km). Skyward Simulations DA-50RG comes with an accurate 3D model, True-to-life definition textures, Custom-coded systems, including ECU &amp; TKS, Ground Idle function simulated, Accurate flight model, Working Title Garmin G1000NXI integration, Included handpainted liveries, and immersive custom sounds by Boris Audio Works. This addon is available for purchase on the Orbx store for roughly $16.39 USD and will require at least 2.08GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fokker</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker 70/100 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2024-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fokker"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663a88bea8c3082851548d9e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has just released a development update for their upcoming project, F70/100 Professional for MSFS, on their website. Since the last dev update, developers have been busy working on implementing Hydraulic, Flight Control, and Landing Gear Systems, as well as fine-tuning engine and flight models to match the Fokker 70/100 performance. For the first time, the functioning displays were previewed. The next systems to be worked on will be Autopilot and Autothrottle. On the artistic side of development, JF has made quite an impressive list of liveries, representing the extensive use of Fokker 100s worldwide. Ranging from the old but golden American Airlines bare-metal livery, European classics such as KLM and Air France Regional, to today’s operators of this quite rare aircraft; QantasLink, Virgin Australia, and Alliance. Additionally, the list includes the Fokker Services House livery and the Slovak Government livery. The list features a variety of eras and operators, such as:  Unfortunately, we only got Fokker 100 previews in this update, however, the next update will feature screenshots and more info on the shorter variant, the Fokker 70! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsedds</id>
    <title>Backwood Studios Releases Eddsfield Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsedds"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663b73c6525a1cc25aa4900c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Backwood Studios have recently released their rendition of Eddsfield Airfield for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a little airfield in East Yorkshire. Edd Peacock created the airfield in the early 90s and is still in operation today. Offering a peaceful escape from everyday life, Edd wanted an airfield to fly from without politics, committees or hassle. Nestled in the Yorkshire countryside and surrounded by hills and endless green fields, it gives out a specific, calming charm.  ‍ Old Edd’s Trailer Cafe can be found in the heart of the airfield. This antique-like building offers a feel of how life used to be during the good ol’ times. It doesn’t matter if you came here to grab a bite between your flights, or to listen to stories from other aviators and veterans, Eddsfield is ready to welcome you! This scenery features automated hangar doors, animated people and animals, night lighting, custom 3D-modelled vehicles and buildings, a fully functional fuel station, GA parking, and over 50 km of custom-added roads. Eddsfield Airfield is available for purchase on Orbx for 7.52 USD and requires at least 0.97GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdter</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Teruel Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdter"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663c57c28af77f5ee750fcc9_teruel2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Teruel Airport (LETL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a maintenance and storage airport in Teruel, Spain, inaugurated 11 years ago. Originally a military airbase, the airport was repurposed into a maintenance/storage facility due to its dry climate, which is highly suitable for long-term aircraft storage. It played a considerable role during the pandemic, storing over 100 airplanes from multiple carriers. Given the lack of passenger traffic, the airport features only a basic terminal and has no infrastructure for passenger handling. It also houses the PLD Space Propulsion test facility, where they conduct rocket engine tests. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, dozens of parked aircraft, performance-friendly optimization, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.54, requiring at least 775.67 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ptdbbs</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases The Dukes Bundle</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ptdbbs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663d72e7d7cfb5042bb636d5_black-square-piston-turbine-duke-bundle_37_ss_m_240313162327.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Up-and-coming development team Black Square have released their second stand-alone aircraft add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the highly anticipated Piston and Turbine Duke bundle. Known for their Steam Gauge Overhaul packs for existing aircraft, the Duke Bundle is Black Square’s first attempt at a stand-alone aircraft.  The Beechcraft 60 Duke, which first flew in December of 1966, was originally outfitted with two Lycoming TIO-541 turbocharged six-cylinder engines, each outputting 380 horsepower. With its pressurised six-seat cabin the Duke was originally designed to fill the gap in the market between the Beechcraft Baron and Queen Air. The Black Square Dukes Package features multiple GPS and Radio options, 130 possible failures, and a multifunction tablet, the developer also claims it features “the most advanced pressurisation and cabin temperature simulations in MSFS.” The Dukes also feature a custom sound set created by Boris Audio Works. You can find the Black Square Piston and Turbine Dukes bundle here for $69.99. Be sure to keep your eye on Threshold to stay up to date on everything flight simulation! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sda50u</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Releases DA-50RG Update</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sda50u"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663e7c4f711d871e6c35467a_DA50-5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Coming just a few days after its initial release, developer Skyward Simulations has published the first update for their new Diamond DA-50RG that was released for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The updates bring changes to both the Flight model and textures of the aircraft addressing both functional and visual bugs.  Flight model change log Flight Model &amp; Systems Improved flight model. Improved startup Improved engine cooling  on the ground at idle Faster warm-up Improved ground idle and flight idle logic Added Xfer pump auto shutoff Added Fuel slosh bug fixes.  3D and Texture change log Fixed low-res/wavy default liveries Dynamic registration added  Fixed emissive textures on the right G1000 Fixed sun-visor reflectiveness Fixed gear decals Various other texture improvements Users of the DA-50RG can install the update from the Contrail app. Be sure to keep an eye on Threshold for the latest in flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nncnfs</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates Navigraph Charts with New Features</title>
    <updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nncnfs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f51c907e7d16c1f089136_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has recently released an updated version of its popular Navigraph Charts, which includes a new feature to enhance navigation assistance. Thanks to data from Microsoft, Impact Observatory, and Esri, users can now display land cover details such as forests and glaciers on the map. In addition, the new update includes a terminator layer that shows day and nighttime on the Naivgraph globe view and Mercator map. These new features are available to users with the Unlimited Subscription plan, which provides access to Navigraph Charts. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mssu15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Posts Development Update about Further Delay to Sim Update 15</title>
    <updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mssu15"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f5c512009038b7a042874_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has provided an update on the status of Sim Update 15 on their forum. The team has decided to postpone Sim Update 15 further due to some new issues. The release date of 7th May had to be delayed due to some issues with WASM. Unfortunately, the team has not yet shared a new release date for Sim Update 15. On a positive note, a new beta build, version 1.37.17.0, has been released for those enrolled in the beta program. This update includes several bug fixes for the beta program. We will keep you informed as soon as the team provides more information on Sim Update 15. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lva340</id>
    <title>LatinVFR Releases Airbus A340-300 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lva340"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f5dffe863734a7d952c13_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LatinVFR recently released its version of the Airbus A340-300 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This four-engine airliner had its maiden flight in 1991 and has been used by many airlines since then. The aircraft has an impressive length of 208 ft 11 in (63 m). The A340-300 was introduced as the first of four variants of the A340 model. Along with the -300 variant, Airbus also developed the -200, -500, and -600 variants. With a total of four engines, the A340-300 has a range of 7.300 nautical miles (13.500 km). The -300 variant turned out to be one of the more popular variants, being used by many airlines such as Lufthansa, Emirates, and SAS. The new add-on offers a range of features, including a highly detailed external and interior model, a realistic cockpit, an EFB, VNAV implementation, realistic sounds, a variety of liveries, and much more. The add-on requires 11.17GB of storage space and is available on the in-sim Marketplace for approximately $29.49. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pesbod</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Releases Bordeaux-Mérignac Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pesbod"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66407a23a9e61deacd2d9eb1_bordeaux1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pilot Experience Sim has recently released the second version of their Bordeaux-Mérignac Airport (LFBD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the commune of Mérignac with a yearly average of 7.7 million passengers. It was built in 1910 to host a major Aviation Week event, making it one of the oldest French airports.  In the early 1930s, the French Air Force heavily upgraded the airport by constructing many new hangars, surface improvements, and more. A passenger terminal was built in 1935, officially going from an air station to an airport.  With World War 2 looming, the government invested more money in transforming Bordeaux into a proper military base, adding two runways, which were completed in 1939 and 1940, respectively. Mérignac’s brand-new runways were quite attractive to the Germans during their invasion of France. The structure was mostly new, and the runways were long and hard, ideal for their operations. They rushed to complete the work on runway two, and soon enough, it became one of their air bases. It was heavily bombed in 1944, and the German soldiers blew up the last remaining buildings before leaving the area.  Repairing was carried out right after the war, between 1945 and 1947. Prisoners of war built a terminal, a restaurant, offices, and a control tower. They were meant to be temporary and made of wood, but an actual replacement only happened twelve years later. In 1959, a new terminal was inaugurated, designed by Raymond Mothe. It was expanded several times, and its capacity maxed out at 2 million passengers annually. Further expansion occurred in the early 2000s, bringing its passenger handling capabilities to over 6 million a year. It’s a focus city for easyJet, Ryanair, and Volotea. Aer Lingus, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Turkish Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, 3D people, custom aerial imagery, PBR texturing, custom static aircraft, and more. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.40, requiring at least 4.58 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2wpb</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases North Palm Beach Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2wpb"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66407f115972d4e91e7d4a11_beach1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of North Palm Beach County General Airport (F45) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving West Palm Beach, in Florida, with a yearly average of 100,000 aircraft operations. Opened in 1994, it’s the county’s newest airport. It sits right next to the town of Apix, a former rocket testing facility created as part of Project Suntan during the Space Race. Covering an area of 741 hectares, with a huge part of it dedicated to environmental preserves, it has two asphalt runways and a single turf runway. Both asphalt runways are the exact same length (1,311 meters) but have different widths (30 and 23 meters, respectively). The turf one is slightly shorter, at 1,121 meters. The traffic consists mainly of general aviation activities (93%), with the remaining 7% corresponding to air taxi operations. There are 264 aircraft based at the airport in total. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, PBR materials, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.77, requiring at least 22.22 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/axybcg</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Gold Coast Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/axybcg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6640963972d7a8203075fdc3_663bec1616443.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos have released their rendition of Gold Coast Airport (YBCG) for X-Plane 12, serving Gold Coast and Queensland, with a yearly average of 5,7 million passengers. ‍ Created in 1936, it was originally named Coolangatta (Aboriginal word for "Place of Good View"), consisted of three grass runways and served as an emergency airport for airmail aircraft flying between Brisbane and Sydney. With the first regular passenger service starting after WWII, it received service from Ansett Australia, Trans Australian Airlines and Butler Air Transport with DC-3s and DC-4s. In 1958, runways and taxiways got paved, allowing the usage of jet planes such as DC-9, and some bigger prop planes like L-188 Electra. Despite the name change in 1989, Gold Coast Airport still retains its original ICAO and IATA codes: YBCG/OOL.  The latest terminal expansion was completed in 2022 and includes more than 19 new parking stands, out of which 4 are equipped with jetbridges. Today, Gold Coast Airport serves 10 airlines flying to 26 different destinations in 3 countries, as well as two more seasonal destinations.  The Axonos YBCG features a highly accurate representation of YBCG with a new apron and taxiway, 3D grass, custom HDR night lighting, PBR and HD textures, color-corrected orthophotos and animated marshalls. ‍ This scenery is available for purchase at the OrbxDirect for roughly $19.89 and requires at least 2.32GB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsyam</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Yamagata Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsyam"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66409d15f59e34317076fd59_yama1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Yamagata Airport (RJSC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Yamagata in Japan and has a yearly average of 223,000 passengers. ‍ It was opened by the Imperial Japanese Navy in World War 2 and briefly used by the United States military after the war. Later, it was utilized by the Japanese Self-Defense Force as a training facility.  It was turned to civilian control in mid-1964 as a third-class regional airport. Eight years later, the runway was extended to 1,500 meters, leading to a reclassification to Class II in 1979. A new - and final - extension happened in 1981, followed by the construction of a new terminal building in 1984. International charter services started in 1981, taking full advantage of the newly expanded runway. Destinations included Finland, Hungary, New Zealand, and even Mexico. The airport's traffic peak was in 1991, followed by a rapid decline in 1992 due to the inauguration of the Yamagata Shinkansen. While the airport saw almost 500,000 passengers in 1991, the figures were down to 50,000 in 2002.  Fuji Dream Airlines (Nagoya, Sapporo), J-Air (Osaka), and Japan Airlines (Tokyo) currently serve it.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom ground-poly, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.86, requiring at least 29.20 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
