<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-04T18:21:16.472304+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eglcxp</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces London City Airport (EGLC) for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eglcxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c8e391f415511f7567c927_orbx.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="515869"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier, developer Orbx has announced on their social media platforms that they will be bringing their London City (EGLC) scenery to X-Plane 12.  London City Airport is located 6 miles east of the city of London in the Borough of Newham and sees on average 4 million passengers each year. The airport features just one runway, which also acts as the main taxiway. The short runway, steep approach angles, and strict noise abatement rules mean that the list of aircraft that service the airport is quite limited. Currently, the airport has flights offered by British Airways, ITA Airways, KLM, Loganair, LOT, Lufthansa, Luxair, and Swiss International.  Orbx included preview images of the scenery that highlighted the airport’s terminal and some recognisable buildings that can be seen around the airport. Orbx originally released the current version of EGLC for Microsoft Flight Simulator earlier this year. While no release date has been announced be sure to keep an eye on Threshold for any updates that may come.</summary>
    <published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksmon</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Montréal International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksmon" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c8de05db454aa3f2ad1bb9_montreal1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="167646"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently updated their newly released rendition of Montréal International Airport (CYUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding improvements and fixes based on customer feedback.  Update v1.0.1 includes the removal of wrongly placed objects, night lighting improvements, the addition of missing apron lines, fixes on the spotting area, 3D snow model tweaks, and jetway animation improvements. ‍  They have already revealed their plans for v1.0.2, which will include the removal of HSBC logos, a new logo on the Air Canada hangar, terminal glass opacity and brightness tweaks, the addition of lights on the Montréal sign at night, LOD improvements, and RAM usage reduction. ‍  The full changelog is available on their original update announcement on Facebook. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/razmig</id>
    <title>RAZBAM Show New MiG-23MLA Images for DCS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/razmig" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c8e98338dbe525785fa638_cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="215048"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Renowned DCS World developer, RAZBAM who have recently released their F-15E Strike Eagle has been so focused on providing updates and patches that news on their other projects has gone quiet until recently. Ron Zambrano, the CEO of RAZBAM has recently shared new pictures of their MiG-23MLA. This project has been in development for a while now however not much news has surfaced regarding it. These latest images clearly show that the MiG-23MLA is very much in active development and that great progress is being made. The Images released show the 3D modelling of the cockpit and an external view of the aircraft. As of yet, there is no indication as to when we can expect this aircraft to release, there is also no pricing information however Threshold will keep you updated with all the news to come so stay tuned! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cacrcw</id>
    <title>Cockspur Announces C162 Release in Coming Weeks for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cacrcw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c8ebebd9b2024f75761ac5_coverCockspur.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="183675"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur has taken to Facebook to announce that their Cessna 162 Skycatcher will release within the next few weeks! ‍ This aircraft has been a side project, allowing the developers to experiment and tinker without any predefined commitments. Despite being kept secret, the 162 Skycatcher is now completed, with final packaging underway. The developers have collaborated closely with SparkyPilot86, an experienced real-life pilot who flies the 162, ensuring accurate systems and flight modelling. Additionally, partnerships with Rainier Flight Service will provide the liveries of their entire fleet of 12 162s as defaults within the package. The 162 Skycatcher package will offer two variants - with or without wheel fairings - providing flexibility to pilots. Priced at $19.99, this aircraft will be accessible on both PC and Xbox platforms. Stay tuned for its official release and prepare to embark on a thrilling flight adventure in the 162 Skycatcher! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42rbh</id>
    <title>Parallel42 Released Bluffers Hill Scene for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42rbh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c8ef139a9321239286dcc5_P42-BLUFFERS-HILL-42BH-MSFS-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1821186"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel42 has announced the release of Bluffers Hill after seeing the popularity of Sharktooth Ridge. Bluffers Hill is located near Red Bluff, CA and is completely surrounded by bluffs and nearby sandbars. Parallel42 has used a 3D library of ground assets along with their own custom terraforming which overwrites the default MSFS terrain which in turn produces a better more realistic terrain for pilots. Bluffers Hill dares pilots to attempt its challenging approach, dangerous sloped runway and no safe option for a go-around. This brings a challenge to even the best pilots out there. Bluffers Hill is suited best to STOL aircraft and any bush planes you have in your hangar. Included is a whole host of features which really bring this area to life when you fly here.  As always, Threshold will keep you informed with the latest news in Flight Simulation, stay tuned for more ! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ngmshk</id>
    <title>NMG Simulations Releases King Shaka International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ngmshk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c96c2a63fb0718e10169ba_shaka1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="421143"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  NMG Simulations has recently released their rendition of King Shaka International Airport (FALE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the South African city of Durban with a yearly average of 4.3 million passengers.  The airport was idealized in the 1970s, but its opening only happened in 2010 due to a multitude of reasons. When the original construction work started in the mid-1970s, the project was halted due to economic reasons, with only the earthworks and its drainage system reaching completion. There was a revival attempt in the late 1990s, but new operational challenges appeared, such as its original 2700m runway, which was deemed too short.  After much deliberation and environmental impact studies, the airport’s construction resumed in 2007, with completion achieved by late 2009, when operational testing began.   It ultimately replaces Durban International Airport - now a military-only airport - as Durban’s main airport, served by Airlink, CemAir, Emirates, Eswatini Air, FlySafair, LIFT, Proflight Zambia, Qatar Airways, South African Airways, TAAG Angola Airlines, and Turkish Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail buildings, custom-made lighting, AI traffic compatibility, custom ground textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.84, requiring at least 104.63 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfslan</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Langkawi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfslan" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c970bafaeb8e186e4a4fa0_mfs1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="321285"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Langkawi International Airport (WMKL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Langwaki and Peris in Malaysia with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  It started as an airfield for the Japanese Army in 1945, only becoming a passenger airport in the late 80s after a huge effort by the Malaysian government to develop Langkawi as a major tourist destination.  It was then upgraded to international standards in 1991 and expanded in 2018 to accommodate up to 4 million passengers annually.  AirAsia (Johor Bahru, Kuala Lumpur–International, Penang, Singapore), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Kuala Lumpur–International), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Penang), Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur–International), MYAirline  (Kuala Lumpur–International), and Scoot (Singapore) serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, custom ground textures, a 3D model of the Maha Tower, and custom night lighting.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.68, requiring at least 37.82 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fetdal</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Dallas Love Field for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fetdal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64c98aafa8fe50b3f8f063f1_dal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="246802"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Dallas Love Field (KDAL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Dallas-Fort Worth metropolitan area with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.  It opened 105 years ago as a training camp for World War 1 pilots and then converted into a storage facility for surplus aircraft after the war, with traffic reducing massively through that period.  It was purchased by the city of Dallas in 1928 and opened for civilian use, with its first set of paved runways coming four years after its grand reopening.  The first passenger terminal was built in 1940, serving over 21 weekday departures from American, Braniff, and Delta.  World War 2 saw the airport become a training school for army pilots, returning to its civil applications after the war.  The increased demand for air travel in the 1950s led to an expansion, with a new terminal (T3) designed by Donald S. Nelson, sporting three concourses, 26 gates, and the world’s first moving walkways.  Currently, the airport has a single terminal with 20 gates, with Alaska and Delta Air Lines having one each and Southwest Airlines having full control over the remaining 18. Unsurprisingly, Southwest has 95.3% of the passenger market share, while Delta and Alaska have 2.2% and 1.7%, respectively.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with highly-detailed PBR models, custom ground poly, custom ground textures, custom animated jetways, custom night lighting, and an updated AFCAD.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.11, requiring at least 715.23 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slcrvu</id>
    <title>Self-Loading Cargo Receives version 1.6 update</title>
    <updated>2023-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slcrvu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cacca7ab0820e15e89cc5b_covere02.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="197655"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Popular cabin interaction app Self-Loading Cargo has been updated to version 1.6 or what Lanilogic Technologies is calling "The Interactivity Update". The update comes nearly 3 years after the last update which was released in August of 2020. Self-Loading Cargo aims to add another layer of realism for users who are looking for a more airline-focused experience in their chosen simulator. The name is based on what some pilots jokingly give their passengers. The app was extremely popular when it was first released in August of 2019 and received many updates during its first year of release. Lanilogic stated the reason for the lack of updates or announcements in the last three years is due to personal reasons and was very apologetic while promising to have more open communication about updates to his product moving forward.  Version 1.6 brings a ton of new features including voice commands and ground crew simulation. The ground crew integration includes interaction at both departure and arrival airports, a completely regionalized sound pack, and a completely integrated pushback system that includes support for both 'hotel' and single-engine taxi modes. Ground crew interactions can be initiated by either voice commands or through the updated UI. Along with the update, many existing features have also been updated including a complete rework of the pilot scoring and passenger satisfaction systems. The developer states that now instead of passenger satisfaction being rated by a simple percentage, you'll receive updates both in real-time and as an overall opinion of the flight based on things like the smoothness of the flight as well as the timing of announcements. Additionally, both the flight crew and cabin sound packs have been completely reworked to include new sounds as well as the ability to use different languages. The update also comes with a small price increase from £12.99 to £16.99. The developer states the price increase is the result of rising operational costs as well as the added functionality of the software. This price increase is only applicable to new purchases though and customers with existing licences are free to download version 1.6 without any additional costs.  ‍ Be sure to stay tuned as Threshold brings you the latest in flight sim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cfsnia</id>
    <title>CFSS Releases Niagara District Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cfsnia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cb06f72e6d4dc8ff3cfb27_nia.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="600144"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CanadianFlightSimStudios has recently released their rendition of Niagara District Airport (CYSN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving the town of Niagara-on-the-Lake in Ontario, Canada.  The St. Catharines Flying Club initially established the airport in March 1929, although in a different location (it was relocated in 1935 to its present location). It was then heavily utilized by the RCAF (Royal Canadian Air Force) during World War II for pilot training, where they also built basic infrastructure (hangars, barracks, and a control tower).   It was then returned to civilian use after the war, growing continuously, featuring three runways, a terminal building, multiple hangars, a flight school, and an aircraft maintenance facility.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom models, PBR texturing, HDR lighting, and an interior for the executive terminal.  It’s available in their official shop for roughly $9.74. Shout out to Shenherm for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwyul</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release Montréal-Trudeau International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwyul" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cbfb19b531f5b60676f17d_bmw1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="694189"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim have recently released their rendition of Montréal-Trudeau International Airport (CYUL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving greater Montréal and eastern Ontario with a yearly average of 16 million passengers.  It was opened in 1941 to replace Saint-Hubert Airport  - Montréal’s former main airport -considered inadequately small for the city’s size and needs, on a former race track known for good weather throughout the year, rarely fogging up.  In the 70s, the government made huge plans to replace it with a new, much larger airport - Montréal Mirabel -, which would become the largest airport in the world when built in terms of total land area and fully expansible if there was ever a need to add a new runway or terminals. On the other hand, YUL was repurposed as a domestic airport during that period, while Mirabel’s expected traffic figures never came to fruition, eventually leading to its partial shutdown in the early 2000s (it has ceased passenger operations).  During Mirabel’s final commercial breaths, Montréal-Trudeau saw the resumption of its international traffic in 1997 and charter flights in 2004, while Mirabel saw nothing but the demolition of its passenger terminal in the last 20 years. The maintenance costs were far too high for something not in use, leading the administration to adopt such an extreme measure.  It’s a hub for Air Canada (Barcelona, Bogotá, Brussels, Calgary, Casablanca, Delhi, Denver, Edmonton, Fort-de-France, Frankfurt, Geneva, Halifax, Houston–Intercontinental, Lisbon, London–Heathrow, Los Angeles, Lyon, Mexico City, Miami, Milan–Malpensa, Paris–Charles de Gaulle, Pointe-à-Pitre, Providenciales, Rome–Fiumicino, San Francisco, San José de Costa Rica–Juan Santamaría, São Paulo–Guarulhos, Tampa, Tokyo–Narita, Toronto–Pearson, Toulouse, Vancouver, Winnipeg), Air Transat (Cancún, Cayo Coco, Fort Lauderdale, Holguín, Lisbon, London–Gatwick, Lyon, Málaga, Marseille, Miami, Montego Bay, Orlando, Paris–Charles de Gaulle, Port-au-Prince, Puerto Plata, Puerto Vallarta, Punta Cana, Samaná, Santa Clara, Toronto–Pearson, Varadero), and OWG (Cayo Coco, Holguín, Santa Clara, Varadero), flying passengers all over the globe.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal area, animated jetways, custom ground markings, high-resolution texturing, landside buildings, custom runway guard lights, parallax windows, and more.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.66, requiring at least 2.73 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mksmol</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Montréal-Trudeau International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mksmol" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cbfecbc6174b9107622d68_yul1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="520801"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has recently released another update to their rendition of Montréal-Trudeau International Airport (CYUL), adding features requested by the community and more.  Update v1.0.2 removes the HSBC logos from the jetways (it was also removed in real life), adds the missing logo on the Air Canada hangar, fixes the brightness and opacity on the terminal glass, improves performance with LOD tweaks, and more. The complete changelog follows down below: - Removed HSBC logos (up to date with the real airport), - Added missing logo on Air Canada hangar, - Terminal glass brightness and opacity fix, - Added Montreal sign lights at night, - Better LOD setup to improve performance, - RAM usage reduction, - Static vehicles placement fixes to allow more space for GSX to operate, - General improvements around the airport.  They have also mentioned a potential new update (1.0.3) coming in a week, with more fixes and improvements.  The scenery is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $18.29, requiring at least 3.75 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdukv</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases United Kingdom VORs for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdukv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cc1ee519452178f29cdb92_VOR01.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2875810"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Burning Blue Design has recently released a package with 50 VORs (VHF Omnidirectional Ranges) scattered across the entire United Kingdom for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  A VOR station is a short-range navigation system for aircraft, allowing planes to determine their position by receiving a signal from a fixed ground station. They are being decommissioned as of late thanks to the advent and popularization of GPS units, which are way more accessible now than they once used to be and easily found on all sorts of aircraft these days. While GPSes don’t require maintenance per se, VORs cost money to maintain, which has made some countries start phasing them out as they fail. The United States, for example, went from over 3000 VORs in the early 2000s to less than 1000 nowadays. The UK also plans to phase out their VORs gradually and cut them down to 20.  Burning Blue Design’s package depicts every one of the 50 fixed-ground VOR stations in the United Kingdom, made with PBR texturing and looking as close as possible to their real counterparts. The complete feature list follows below:  It’s available on their official store for roughly $11.38. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/550v2x</id>
    <title>AKD Studios Releases GLF550 V2 for X-Plane 11/12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/550v2x" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd25ea7137f7778fac5371_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3340400"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AKD Studio has recently released version 2 of their popular GLF550 business jet for X-Plane 11/12 almost a year after the release of version 1. The update brings various new features from custom MCDU to FMOD sounds, as well as an array of bug fixes. 	According to the developers, the plane’s modeling has been “completely overhauled”. Accompanying the new model are a brand new custom MCDU, new textures, custom RNAV support, and a FMOD customized by Mango Studios. In addition, the new version also brings improved systems and a tuned flight model. For a full list of new features, tweaks, and bug fixes that come with V2, visit the aircraft’s store page. Currently, the GLF550 V2 can be purchased on X-Plane.org for $41.95 USD, a $10 increase from V1. The developers recommend users to have at least 920 MB of free disk space to install the aircraft.</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbv2rt</id>
    <title>Fenix Begins V2 Rollout</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbv2rt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd3b62a03f0b2cfaf47241_v2header.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="520714"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. This is the first part of a two part announcement by Fenix. You can read the second announcement here. The rollout of the highly anticipated V2 commences. Over the next few days, Fenix plans to initiate this process by pushing a "staging" build. This rollout strategy involves releasing the modules of V2 in two distinct blocks. An exciting milestone has been reached with V2, where certain modules are ready for deployment, independent of any dependencies still under development. In the initial block, referred to as V2 Block 1, the offerings will include FBWv2, FMv2, and the first of the new displays, (ISIS). Additional smaller displays will be introduced later. Users can look forward to all code-side performance optimisations, including the innovative display render technology. Furthermore, a substantial portion of non-dependent avionics improvements across the aircraft, including the brand new VNAV, and a host of bug fixes, will be included. The full changelog will be provided upon rollout. This sets the stage for the second phase of the V2 delivery, projected to conclude by the end of September. Block 2 will comprise the new visual model, IAE and external engine model, further avionics fixes, EFBv2, and any additional revisions or improvements deemed necessary for Block 1.The rationale behind the decision to divide the rollout into two blocks is multifaceted. Block 2 requires additional refinement before it's ready for its prime-time debut. However, Fenix believes that the substantial improvements Block 1 brings to the user experience cannot be held back, especially since the development teams have completed their work on it. Fenix also encourages community feedback on Block 1's features to refine and enhance Block 2, aiming for an optimal overall user experience when V2 is fully delivered. In appreciation for users' patience, Fenix will be releasing some screenshots next week, giving a sneak peek of what they aim to achieve with Block 2, particularly the visual model. The entire aircraft has undergone a painstaking rebuilding process. This endeavor not only raises the bar from what was achieved with the first version but also demonstrates Fenix's commitment to delivering a high-quality product at no additional cost. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/faaams</id>
    <title>Fenix Announces A321 and A319 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/faaams" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64cd3cbd00081cedd6d21b20_fenix_back.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1303835"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. This is the second part of a two part announcement from Fenix, you can see the other announcement here. ‍In the world of flight simulation, secrets are hard to keep. Speculations have been brewing, and the big reveal is finally here. While working on revamping the A320 with V2, Fenix has simultaneously been developing the A321 and A319. The improvements made with the rollout of V2 have laid a robust foundation upon which these new aircraft models have been built. Fenix has announced plans to release these new models by the end of the year as a single expansion package, priced at £39.99. As with the A320, sharklets will follow at no additional cost to the customers. With the release of Block 2 scheduled for September, the end of the year will witness the debut of the A321 and A319. As Fenix moves into 2024, it plans to update all its product lines with sharklets for free. Timelines are often tricky and met with apprehension. Nevertheless, Fenix believes in the importance of transparency with their customers. It is crucial for them to provide a clear roadmap of their plans and timelines, alleviating the anxiety that can come with uncertainty.A question that might arise is why the A321 and A319 are prioritized over the A320 sharklets. Fenix said the simple answer is financial stability. The new aircraft models' release will ensure the company's steady financial standing, crucial to support continued product line development and future offerings. For the time being, customers are encouraged to enjoy the revised displays, enhanced performance, and improved handling and behaviour of the aircraft. While the next month might seem like a long wait, the company assures its customers that they are diligently preparing the rest of V2. Over the weekend, Fenix will share performance benchmarks for V2 Block 1, detailing the improvements over the .146 version. In a few days, they will provide a changelog and a new build, continuing to keep their customers in the loop of this exciting journey. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
