<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-02-05T18:22:56.963522+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsl14</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases Local Legend 14</title>
    <updated>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsl14"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b9c1d10ebc612197cdb080_copter.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Microsoft Flight Simulator team has recently released their fourteenth local legend: the Bell 47J Ranger, the first helicopter to carry a United States president. Introduced in 1956, the 47J Ranger is the executive variant of the Bell 47, which was the first helicopter certified for civilian use and one of the most popular helicopters to exist, with 5,600 built. While the Bell 47 could only seat two people, the 47J could seat four. ‍ Two units were purchased by the American government in 1957 to transport the president, Dwight Eisenhower, to and from the White House. They were eventually removed from presidential duties in 1962 but still handled VIP transports until they were fully retired in 1967. ‍ Three hundred sixty-one units were manufactured over its production period, handling VIP transport, cargo, air ambulance, commuter flights, aerial surveying, and military applications. It was also featured in many popular movies, such as James Bond’s Thunderball from 1965. ‍ Powered by a 260 hp Lycoming VO-540-B1B piston engine, it can cruise at 91 mph, with a service ceiling of 11,000 ft and a range of 260 miles.  ‍ Microsoft Flight Simulator’s rendition features two landing gear types, with seven liveries per variant. ‍ It’s available in the Marketplace for $14.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcoden</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Denver International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcoden"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65b9c742ae9d529c3d3be25b_denis.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr Designs has recently released a major update to their rendition of Denver International Airport (KDEN) for X-Plane 11 and 12, adding new custom ground vehicles, improvements, and various bug fixes. ‍ The complete changelog follows below: ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed terminals, an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, realistic weather effects (X-Plane 12), and more.  ‍ ‍ It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $29.95, requiring at least 7.5 GB of free hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jd76xp</id>
    <title>JustFlight and Thranda Design Releases Duchess Model 76 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jd76xp"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65baa5083fcf1418ad5335a2_duchess-model-76-xplane-12_46_ss_m_240123162145.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After much anticipation, developer JustFlight has released its rendition of the Duchess Model 76 for X-Plane 12. A breath of fresh air for the simulator’s general aviation lover, the aircraft will feature everything from an accurately modeled cockpit and high quality textures to realistic engine performance and a customizable avionics suite. The Duchess, created as a collaboration between JustFlight and Thranda design, is “built using real-world aircraft plans and comprehensive photography of the real aircraft”, with almost every component inside and outside the plane fully animated. In addition, users can expect the plane to be IFR capable. The aircraft will come with a “fully featured” X-Plane native GNS430 with the option for users to purchase the GTN750 separately. 	Furthermore, the product will include an EFB in the form of a tablet. Pilots can use it to plan out their flights, adjust the plane’s weight and balance, and even change the livery of the Duchess on the go. The plane is also VR-compatible. Those interested in the aircraft can purchase it for $42.99 USD from JustFlight’s webstore. For successful installation, the developers are recommending users to have at least 3GB of free space on their hard drives. Shoutout to Luke from the Threshold Discord for the news scoop. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/co42rd</id>
    <title>COWS Announces DA42 Release Date for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/co42rd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65baf4f677d9f1ec85dffdd5_10date.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Developer COWS, has announced that their highly anticipated rendition of the Diamond DA-42 will be released for Microsoft Flight Simulator on February 10th, 2024, just under two weeks from the time of writing. The aircraft will be available for purchase initially on the Orbx Store.  COWS started development of the DA-42 out of their love for the aircraft, and because they fly the aircraft in real life as students of flight schools.  COWS has also announced that they will be including the -TDI variant, which is very popular at many large flight training schools for multi-engine training, along with the -VI variant. The COWS DA-42 will also be coming to the Xbox platform on the Microsoft Marketplace, but they have not confirmed a release date for that.  The aircraft will feature high quality visuals and engine simulation. Additionally, in their pre-release announcement, COWS has said that they will have the DA40-180 XLS out by this year “if time allows.” COWS have not announced a price for the DA-42, but Threshold will keep you updated, so stay tuned for that, and for more high quality flight simulation news, reviews, and more! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rttara</id>
    <title>Rafael Tango Tango Releases Aracaju Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rttara"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65baf99bf2c8c30af3919a70_aracaju.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rafael Tango Tango has recently released their rendition of Aracaju - Santa Maria Airport (SBAR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Aracaju, Sergipe, Brazil, with a yearly average of 960,000 passengers.  ‍ In operation since the early 50s, it was officially inaugurated in 1958 and heavily overhauled three years later with a terminal enlargement and a runway extension. ‍ Under the helm of Infraero since 1975, the runway was further extended in 1993, and a passenger terminal expansion was completed in 1998.  ‍ A new passenger terminal was built in 2012, doubling its passenger handling capabilities. ‍ In March 2019, Aena won a thirty-year concession to operate the airport and handle potential upgrades and modernizations. ‍ Azul, Gol, and LATAM serve it with frequent flights to their hubs. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, PBR, a custom windsock, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $5.42, requiring at least 197.87 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fthont</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Ontario International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fthont"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65bafbbd3af46cec9a451aaa_ontario.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere has recently released their rendition of Ontario International Airport (KONT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of San Bernardino, Riverside, and Greater Los Angeles with a yearly average of 5 million passengers. ‍ The airport was built in 1941 as an Army Air Corps aircraft training and operation base. After the war, it became a large storage, sale, and scrapping center for Army Air Forces aircraft.  ‍ Shortly after, in 1946, the airport was renamed from “Ontario Municipal Airport” to “Ontario International Airport” because of outgoing trans-Pacific cargo flights. The first international passenger flight happened that same year, a Pacific Overseas Airlines flight from Shanghai to Ontario, inaugurating round-trip air passenger service between the United States and the Orient. Western Airlines began operating at the airport three years later, followed by Bonanza Air Lines in 1955. ‍ A new terminal was opened in 1998, discontinuing the old terminals, which now function as the administration and the USO. There are 26 gates total, with 12 on T2 and 14 on T4. Terminal 2 hosts Alaska Airlines, Avianca El Salvador, China Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, United Airlines, and Volaris. Terminal 4 hosts American Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, and Southwest. ‍ It’s a FedEx and UPS Airlines cargo hub, transporting cargo all over North America and Asia (UPS). Amazon Air, Ameriflight, Amerijet International, Asia Pacific Airlines, and Kalitta Air also serve it. Ontario International is the ninth-largest cargo airport in the United States. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with over 60 highly detailed building models with PBR texturing, custom ground poly, custom animated jetways with gate numbering, improved taxiway and runway lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.26, requiring at least 714.80 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssama2</id>
    <title>Synaptic Simulations Announces Move to Payware Model; Partner With iniBuilds</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssama2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65bafd1a76e1e8983c62cfbb_Artboard_12x.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a lengthy announcement in their Discord and on the iniBuilds forum, Synaptic Simulations has announced that they will be moving away from having their rendition of the Airbus A220 for free, to a payware model, with support from iniBuilds, and they will be adding Xbox support as well. ‍ In their post, they elaborate on some of the reasons why they moved away from a freeware to a payware product: “This decision comes out of a realization of the project's potential as well as the ever-growing development demands during often busy and stressful times for our team.” Also in the announcement were more details concerning what will come with the Synaptic A220 on release, which will feature both the -300 and -100 variants, as well as an ACJ220 variant coming in “later as a free upgrade to customers of the base package.”  Synaptic also addresses concerns about this change, saying “We understand any unfavorable feelings you may have toward this decision, as it was a tough one for us to make knowing the support you have all given us with the promise of a free and open-source add-on. We hope that you will remain committed to this project, as our commitment to deliver the best A220 experience remains steady.” The Synaptic team say that they will publish an FAQ in the “very near future,” and that they encourage the community to ask questions in the meantime. ‍ Although nothing about a release window or pricing has been announced yet, Threshold will keep you informed once we know, so stay tuned for that, and for more high quality flight simulation news, reviews, and more!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdgkf</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Kefalonia Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdgkf"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65bc465e983574f661be0137_334219_LGKF_MSFS_12a.jpg.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flight Simulation Design Group has just released their newest foray into the flight simulation scenery space, recreating the island and airport of Kefalonia, Greece, in Microsoft Flight Simulator. Kefalonia is the first in a series of products that FSDG is calling the “Scenic Routes Edition.” Kefalonia, or Cephalonia, is the largest of the Ionian islands in the Adriatic Sea off of the west coast of Greece. It is a popular destination for many European tourists during the summer for its fair weather. Kefalonia’s Airport is served by many low-cost carriers such as easyJet, Ryanair, and TUI, but almost all of its air traffic is seasonal, with only one route to Athens served by Aegean Airways being operated year-round.  FSDG’s rendition of Kefalonia features not only the airport but many landmarks around the island and buildings such as hotels. The airport itself features high-quality texturing and modeling, as well as 3D interiors, and custom night lighting. You can get Kefalonia for €15.69 on SimMarket, and it will take up approximately 3.98GB of disk space.</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mdss15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Dev Stream Recap: SU15, G3X Touch, and More</title>
    <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mdss15"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65bc6b5c0fb401fc9381b3c2_Screenshot%202024-02-01%20at%209.19.50%E2%80%AFPM.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In their most recent developer livestream hosted on Wednesday, Microsoft and Asobo showed off more features for the upcoming Sim Update 15, an overhaul to the default G3X by Working Title, a few more bits on the highly anticipated MSFS 2024, and much more! ‍ Starting off with Sim Update 15, the newest update to the simulator is slated to land on March 12th, with a public beta starting soon. The main focus for this update is improving performance, and especially with memory usage improvements. Working with Working Title Simulations, Microsoft and Asobo have been able to squeeze more performance out of the glass cockpits by reworking the CoherentGT thread, which is the process that renders glass cockpits, and is a common pitfall when it comes to performance with complex glass cockpit aircraft.  As for memory allocation, the Asobo team was able to backport the technology from the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and the most benefit will come to those low in RAM, or have a stutter-filled experience. A new system for handling AI and ATC interaction with airports will also be coming in the update as well, and fixes to the many bugs and quirks that the system has gotten a reputation for. In addition, many highly requested fixes that concern snow coverage, with the sim incorrectly freezing over lakes being one of the many fixes.  Also, Jorg Neumann, Head of Microsoft Flight Simulator has confirmed that Microsoft Flight Simulator will be expanding support for Xbox Cloud Gaming in SU15, adding support for mobile devices and touchscreens. Finally, dual-rotor support has been added, allowing developers to finally be able to correct popular helicopters such as the Chinook, and the V22 Osprey. Another thing revealed during this month’s dev livestream was the reworked Garmin G3X Touch built by Working Title Simulations. It will feature all the goodies we can expect from a Working Title rework, including a faithful recreation of the styling, layout, and symbology of the real G3X unit, as well as having a functioning EIS page, and specific configurations for different aircraft types. When it releases, the new G3X Touch will come installed in the default XCub, NXCub, and VL-3.  Moving on to the iniBuilds A320neo, which is currently still in the development phase, after coming under stability issues during the Sim Update 14 Beta, as well as speculation that it violated the GPL. Jorg Neumann addressed the question of the release date saying, “I’m not 100% sure it’s going to make SU15…it’s tight…[it] won’t be in the first beta for sure.” There was a lot in this month’s dev stream, so here are some of the other points that didn’t make it into the larger categories: ‍ You can watch the whole one and a half hour stream on their Twitch channel. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inignm</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Leeds Bradford Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inignm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65bd6ed1e052cd7a986ea33b_lba.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Leeds Bradford Airport (EGNM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving North and West Yorkshire with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers.  It was opened in 1931 as Leeds and Bradford Municipal Aerodrome (or Yeadon Aerodrome), mostly used for general aviation and training during its initial years, with scheduled flights starting in 1935.  Work on the main terminal started around the late 30s but only reached full completion after WW2.   Avro constructed a shadow factory during that WW2 period called the Leeds Bradford Airport Depot, with over 5,000 aircraft before its closure in December 1946.  In the early 1980s, the runway was extended, allowing it to be classified as a regional airport. After the extension, Wardair commenced international flights to Toronto in a 747 in 1984.  The airport underwent expansion work in the late 90s and early 2000s, allowing it to reach an 88% increase in passenger traffic by 2007 (2.9 million passengers visited the airport that year).  The highest airport in the United Kingdom (681ft!) is an operating base for Jet2.com and Ryanair and is served by Aer Lingus, Aurigny, easyJet, KLM, and WizzAir.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, highly detailed models, an up-to-date layout, custom jetways, PBR texturing, and more.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $12.73, requiring at least 3.65 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini104</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini104"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/659886c209781dbee7f3ce5f_a300update2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing VNAV bugs, save states, missing flags on instruments, and more.  v1.0.4 - the fourth update since its release in December 2023 - brings a list of changes ranging from art to systems. The complete changelog follows below: ‍  The airplane is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbanj</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Banja Luka International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbanj"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65be1d5598d52325b9dcca1c_banja.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Banja Luka International Airport (LQBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Banja Luka in Bosnia and Herzegovina, with a yearly average of 460,719 passengers as of 2023. ‍ Construction started in 1976, and the airport was initially part of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, operating as a strictly domestic airport for many years. After the Bosnian War and the creation of Republika Srpska, Banja Luka was established as the capital, and the airport was granted international status and opened for civilian traffic in 1997. ‍ The airport underwent heavy upgrade work between 2002 and 2003 for Pope John Paul II's visit in June 2003. ‍ Aegean Airlines (seasonal), Air Cairo (seasonal), Air Serbia, Freebird Airlines (seasonal), Nouvelair (seasonal), Ryanair, Tailwind Airlines (seasonal), and WizzAir currently serve it. ‍ Developed by indie Radoslav Tucakov, the scenery features fully custom terminals and buildings, interior details, exquisite perimeter details, a custom village and air base near the airport, PBR texturing, and more. ‍ It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $9.78, requiring at least 1.35 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/146cab</id>
    <title>Just Flight Previews New Passenger Cabins for 146 Professional</title>
    <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/146cab"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65becc38025e68d4897aaa37_flybe.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently previewed their brand-new passenger cabins for the 146 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which will soon be available as a free update for all existing owners. ‍ The cabins feature a high-density 3+3 layout, custom-modeled for each 146 variant, with differences in the rear seating layout because of the fuselage’s curvature and miniature overhead bins on the seat rows below the wing structure.  ‍ The screenshots show the 146-300, the longest variant in the family, and they are currently working on integrating the new cabin into the shortest variants as well. ‍ The galleys will feature a fully functional attendant’s panel with cabin lights, ground power control, and several annunciators for cabin-related items such as seatbelt signs and door locks. ‍ There will also be a panel on the vestibule controlling the communications between the forward and aft galley, the passenger cabin, and the cockpit, as in real life. It will also house the controls for the cabin sound system, allowing the user to play music and manually adjust the volume as desired.  ‍ While all the doors will still be controllable via EFB, users can open and close them by clicking on their handles, as in real life. ‍ The development process had performance in mind, ensuring minimal performance impact. Users who do not wish to have it visible can disable it through the EFB. ‍ There’s no information on the release date for said update yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tff35c</id>
    <title>ToLiss and FlightFactor To Collaborate On Upcoming A350 for XP12</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tff35c"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c03c36901f043063f3b390_426148969_1531166767729977_8576039288246783654_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In an unexpected move during this weekend’s X-Plane Developer Summit in Montréal, Canada, developers ToLiss Simulations and FlightFactor have announced that they are collaborating on developing a rendition of the Airbus A350 for the X-Plane 12 platform.  FlightFactor and ToLiss, are both known well for their simulations of Airbus aircraft. ToLiss has been exclusively developing Airbus aircraft for X-Plane, while FlightFactor have developed both Boeing and Airbus, with their 2nd rendition of the Boeing 777 on the way. FlightFactor released their version of an A350 back during the days of X-Plane 10. Both companies are usually in competition with each other for the Airbus market, but now they have come together to create what will certainly be a very high quality, if not the best rendition of Airbus’ newest airliner for the X-Plane platform to date.  No other information about how this partnership will work, or anything other than just a simple confirmation that joint development is going on has been released yet, but Threshold will keep you informed, so stay tuned for that, and for more high-quality flight simulation news and editorials! </summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/davmal</id>
    <title>David Rosenfeld Previews Milan Malpensa Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/davmal"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65c0be78cc4a845f0e5e8598_malpensa.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. David Rosenfeld has recently previewed his rendition of Milan Malpensa Airport (LIMC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Milan metropolitan area with a yearly average of 26.1 million passengers.  ‍ The site where the airport was built has more than a century of aviation history, with records dating back to 1910 when the Caproni brothers flew their Cal biplane. It became a popular prototype testing site in Italy, eventually leading to its upgrade to an actual airfield.  ‍ During that same period, the Caproni brothers decided to build a factory there, and Giovanni Augusta followed suit. It became the largest aircraft production center in the country.  ‍ In the following decades, the airfield hosted two Royal Italian Air Force squadrons.  ‍ In September 1943, the German Luftwaffe captured the airfield, building its first concrete runway, which didn’t last long: the airfield was heavily bombed during WW2.   ‍ With the retreat of the German forces from Italy and the eventual end of the war, the runway was rebuilt and extended to 1,800 meters. A small terminal was built to shelter passengers and cargo from adverse weather conditions. ‍ Its official inauguration happened in 1948 as Aeroporto Città di Busto Arsizio, with Sabena and TWA being one of the first international carriers to serve it.  ‍ In 1952, now under the control of the municipality of Milan, it was decided that Malpensa would become Milan’s international airport, and Linate (Milan’s other airport) would handle domestic services.   ‍ As Milan’s main airport, it needed a respectable terminal, which was built between 1958 and 1962. The runways were also extended and were the longest in Europe then.   ‍ Even though their original intent was to make Linate domestic-only, major European carriers preferred it over Malpensa because it was closer to the city center, transforming it into a secondary airport for over 20 years.  ‍ Things were only to change in the 1980s when Linate was forcibly downgraded to domestic, and Malpensa underwent heavy upgrade work. Construction started in 1990, and it only reopened eight years later. ‍ ‍ It’s an operating base for AlbaStar, easyJet Europe, Malta Air, Neos, Ryanair, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air France, Air India, AirBaltic, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Etihad Airways, KLM, Korean Air, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom jetways, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ini105</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ini105"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658e3cd4374e2720154dbc55_inia3002.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an emergency update for their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing an LNAV issue introduced in the previous update from a few days ago.  Given its “hotfix-ish” nature, the fifth update’s changelog is relatively small, with only four changes:  ‍ ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $45, requiring at least 8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
