<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-12-31T18:28:40.888103+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jflf71</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes New F70/F100 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jflf71"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6764b1e1ae016d9183fe0f7a_fokka1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight has shared more details on how their upcoming Fokkers (F70 and F100) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 are progressing through the development process, accompanied by images of the flight deck and exterior. They claim to have achieved “some exciting milestones” with the project, with their coders being hard at implementing the F100’s complex systems, which should be entering beta stage soon. “Fortunately we have a great testing team to help us, full of eager real world F70/F100 pilots, engineers, and knowledgeable simmers, ready to pick through every single detail”, they add.  Most of the new screenshots showcase the recently upgraded liveries, now in 8K resolution and built with the utmost attention to detail using high-resolution reference photos.  Regarding MSFS 2024 compatibility, Just Flight claims that it’s still “early days” for the new platform. Core development will remain on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 for now, with an eventual port once the new simulator is more stable. However, they remain committed to supporting both simulators.  The Fokkers will be their next airliner release for MSFS, set to land on the virtual shelves in the first half of 2025.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sexkir</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Kirkwall Airport for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sexkir"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6764c1e654f2be63857ec790_kirk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Kirkwall Airport (EGPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves the Orkney Islands in Scotland and has a yearly average of 143,000 passengers. Built in 1940 as RAF Grimsetter to defend the Scapa Flow Naval base, taking its name from the homonymous farm it was built over.  Three years later, the Royal Navy took over and renamed it Royal Naval Air Station Grimsetter. Control was passed over to the Ministry of Civil Aviation in 1948 and handed over to an administration company in the mid-1980s, ultimately ending its military roles. Nowadays, Kirkwall Airport serves as a vital connection between the Orkney Islands and the mainland, operating services to Aberdeen, Belfast City, Dundee, Ebay, Edinburgh, Glasgow, Inverness, London Heathrow, Manchester, North Ronaldsay, Papa Westray, Sanday, Stronsay, Sumburgh, and Westray through Loganair, which is the only airline serving the airport as of 2024. The airport is home to the Sustainable Aviation Test Environment (SATE), the United Kingdom’s first low-carbon aviation test center. It is helping to pave aviation’s future one test flight at a time. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D-modeled terminal, custom landside buildings and hangars, custom ground textures, custom runway textures, a custom interior, and more. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $11.99 and is currently compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Once the in-sim marketplace is launched, an MSFS 2024 exclusive version will be available. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/300119</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes New A300B4 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/300119"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6764c9ef92e4948c0ccbf80e_pit1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight recently published a new development update on the upcoming Airbus A300B4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, showcasing the night lighting logic in the flight deck and addressing its compatibility with MSFS 2024. The developers are finishing work on the animation and lighting logic for nearly two thousand switches, dials, and annunciator lights. This process required coding each element, verifying its operability within the simulator, and tweaking the animations or artwork further when needed.  Their systems coders have made great progress over the last 18 months. They will soon be able to “bring the aircraft to life” as the cockpit artwork and animations are ready. They look forward to sharing systems previews early next year. The exterior has not been previewed yet because it is undergoing work on refining its overall geometry, adding extra details such as panels, lines, wiring around the landing gear, and a detailed cargo hold, to name a few. The modeling has recently reached completion, and texturing is now underway, with previews to come in 2025. Similarly to their upcoming Fokkers, core development will remain on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 for now while they wait for greater stability. The commitment to support both simulators remains. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/300114</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A300-600R for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/300114"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67662bed8e6f4073bff78846_mj1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 (compatibility and Premium), addressing stability issues, tweaking VNAV, and more. Updates v1.1.4 (Compatibility patch) and v1.0.1 (Premium) are the first to be released since its arrival in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, further improving its compatibility with the new platform and enhancing its overall stability on both platforms. The changelogs follow below:  v1.0.1 Fixed - Rain effects for wheels are showing above the wing not located at the wheels themselves sometimes Fixed - PW Engine covers don't have any text Fixed - Pitch Trim 1 Switch size anomaly Fixed - Missing backlight on CPT/FO Side panel &amp; PW Oil gauges Fixed - Tire rain/snow fx coming from fuse instead of wheels  Fixed - Z-fighting on rear MLG tire textures Fixed - Z-fighting/flickering on left NOSE taxi/landing light bulb emissive Fixed - [GE Pax] Left landing light inop Fixed - OEW Difference between Simbrief profile and Aircraft - 19.4t LBS / 8.8t KG. Note Simbiref profiles have been updated v1.1.4 Fixed - Random Crash - Fuel runs out Fixed - SEC F-Plan crash Fixed - VNAV Issues - Descending too early / capturing speed target too early Fixed - EFB Door Arming Logic / Option Reversed Fixed - APU keeps running if start is aborted Fixed - FMS Progress Page VOR/DME Station behaviour &amp; formatting Fixed - THR and ACCEL altitude logic and behaviour The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $43.92 (compatibility patch) and an additional $12.56 is required to purchase the 2024 upgrade. New owners can get the 2024-only version for approximately $39.52. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350121</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Publishes A350 Trailer &amp; Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350121"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67674183ad3c69b10fa62d67_emi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently launched the trailer for their upcoming Airbus A350 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, along with a comprehensive development update listing some of its features and shedding light on a potential release date. As previously covered, iniBuilds decided to make it compatible with 2020 due to stability and reliability issues with Microsoft’s new flight simulator, thus investing in two development cycles under a single purchase and allowing the freedom of platform choice. “We will do our very best to have parity in feature sets between both versions of the aircraft, but please note this will not be possible all the way, and more details will be shared close to release,” they conclude. The feature list promises a detailed 3D cabin with a cabin announcement system, a comprehensive flight attendant panel, custom terrain radar, detailed systems simulation, Navigraph integration with SimBrief import feature, a situation manager, ABEAM &amp; Offset simulation, intricate 3D model and texturing, GPS jamming, multiple failures, Brake-to-Vacate, and structural vibrations.  They claim to have worked very hard to provide a top-tier simulation of its electrical parts and systems, with a full-fledged electrical bus simulation, dynamic load computation, distinct battery options (NiCad or Lithium, with varying capacities and amperage), and noise-optimized N1 settings for NADP procedures. iniBuilds will be commencing their usual Aircraft showcase series on YouTube within the next few weeks, walking people through some of these new features. While the A350 was originally set to be released in 2024, iniBuilds has made the difficult decision to postpone the release to Q1 2025 to warrant a “fantastic product on launch.” Both variants will be available on day one, and the XLR will come at a later date. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/luu1rd</id>
    <title>LevelUp Announces Update 1 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/luu1rd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67682a79fb34524f95dfb2e6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Ever since the highly anticipated LevelUp released on January 1st, 2022, numerous users are eagerly awaiting the next update for the comprehensive Boeing 737 NG addon. However, a mixture of real-life happenings and internal development issues led to the addon being left alone for two years, until now. Just recently, the LevelUp team announced that after a series of cumulative internal updates, the much-anticipated Update 1 will be released this Christmas Eve, December 24th, 2024. According to the LevelUp team, the team has been hard at work to revamp the flight model, adding several new features, and most importantly, making the addon compatible with X-Plane 12. Snippets of the update were initially teased by streamer SkyMatix just earlier this year, showcasing new features such as openable cockpit windows, and so on. The team thanks the ZiboMod team for their full support on the project, as well as their flight model artist Allan who have revamped the flight model along the way. With Update 1 out of the way, the LevelUp team now will move on to the next phase, which is focusing on a visual update that will lay the foundation for the highly anticipated 737 MAX expansion, which will be dubbed Update 2.For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/klaxv2</id>
    <title>ShortFinal Design KLAX for XP12 Updated to V2</title>
    <updated>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/klaxv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67688e487225e4ae619b357d_1000010296.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ShortFinal Design (SFD) has updated KLAX to V2. This is the first update since 2020, and it includes numerous changes. Los Angeles International Airport (KLAX), with its four runways, served 75 million travellers in 2023. This makes it the second-largest airport in the US and one of the world’s busiest airports in terms of both arrivals and departures. ‍ According to SFD, the most notable update in version 2 is the introduction of native support for X-Plane 12. This allows for a variety of enhancements, such as 3D vegetation, dynamic airport vehicles equipped with FMOD sounds, and native rain effects. Users of X-Plane 11 will also benefit from updated hangars and terminals, as well as significant structures like the SoFi Stadium and the LAX Automated People Mover. Furthermore, the update enhances textures and lighting, improves various structures, and streamlines animations through LST integration. ‍ The full list of changes is as follows: ‍ Version 2.0 (December 20th 2024): The update is free for all current owners of the scenery and is available for $26.95 on the x-plane.org store for those who do not already own it. Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord.</summary>
    <published>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/321290</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321Ceo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/321290"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de45dfff6dd35cf791aa_labsup1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs recently issued a new update to their A321Ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The update addresses core functionality issues that were affecting a subset of users with their Simbrief, Pushover, Printer, and Techlog integrations, fixes several crash-to-desktop issues, provides additional System fixes, and more. Update v11.0.1.290 – the second in rapid succession since the product’s release in early December – is currently only available via the experimental channel, bringing the fixes mentioned above and adding hardware access to the FCU, EFIS, and glareshield, with an expansion planned over the coming weeks. Work with their industry partners to integrate the interface into their software is underway. The update highlights follow below: ‍ FWC (F9C &amp; F3P) ATSU/EFB/Techlog Systems Improvements: Exterior Model Updates: Sound Enhancements: Simconnect Hardware Based on user feedback, FSLabs is working on improving the sounds, which are expected to land in the experimental channel early next week. The add-on is available on their website for $69. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xe134r</id>
    <title>xEnviro Version 1.34 Released</title>
    <updated>2024-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xe134r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6769a110a8ad8347894fbcfe_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. xEnviro has been updated to version 1.34, introducing new and reintroduced features to the environmental plugin. This update includes various new features and fixes, further polishing the plugin for X-Plane. The new update for X-Plane 12 introduces a range of enhancements. It includes adjustments for camera exposure and a bloom slider to improve visuals. Additionally, the update features improved weather effects, realistic lightning strikes, and reflections from city lights on the clouds and atmosphere. Light scattering has been refined for enhanced realism, and NVIDIA graphics cards in X-Plane 12 have received an anti-aliasing update. Enhancements have been made to cloud and shadow rendering, as well as to thunderstorm formation. Airport lights now function correctly at night. Haze effects and the white edges of clouds in mountainous regions have been addressed, and fixes have been implemented for Vulkan crashes. Additionally, a recent update has improved performance when minimizing windows. A full changelog of the new features, fixes and improvements can be found below: ‍ What’s New: -X-Plane 12 Enhancements. -Camera exposure adjustments. -A new bloom slider for fine-tuning visuals. -Improved Weather Effects. -Lightning strikes with cloud-to-cloud and cloud-to-ground variations. -City lights reflecting on both the atmosphere and clouds. ‍ Key Fixes &amp; Improvements: -Light scattering adjustments for better realism. -Anti-aliasing fix for NVIDIA cards in X-Plane 12. -Multiple cloud and shadow rendering enhancements. -Fixed haze effects and cloud white edges in mountainous areas. -Vulkan crash fixes and improved performance when minimizing windows. -Airport lights reappearing properly at night. -Thunderstorm formation improvements. The team behind xEnviro is optimistic about the future, stating that this winter and spring, they expect to restore all the features that were temporarily removed during the transition to X-Plane 12. Additionally, they anticipate the introduction of new features.  ‍ While this update primarily focuses on X-Plane 12, the team confirms that compatibility with X-Plane 11 will still be maintained. They caution, however, that they cannot guarantee 100% compatibility, although it should function as intended for most users.  ‍ When asked about the duration of X-Plane 11 compatibility, Magnus indicated that it will remain partially or fully supported at least until all features currently removed due to the transition to X-Plane 12 are fully restored. The update is now available for download from xEnviro's website. If you do not yet own xEnviro, the team is excited to announce a temporary price reduction from $69.69 to $49.69 while they work on restoring all features. This is a great opportunity for anyone interested in trying xEnviro for the first time, and it can be found in our store. ‍ With the update, the xEnviro team thanks everyone for their support and wishes everyone a happy holiday. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lux12r</id>
    <title>LevelUP 737NG Series for XP12 Released</title>
    <updated>2024-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lux12r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6769e2150cb39ff84be07bda_Available-Now.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. For years the freeware aircraft has been in development, but after two years it is finally ready for X-Plane 12. This release represents Update 1. The package includes all five members of the 737 Next Generation family. According to the LevelUp team, the release features brand new textures, reimagined cabins, and a modular visual architecture. It includes the full power of the ZiboMod, offering incredible visuals, realistic flight dynamics across four different fuselage lengths and an all-new CornUI Tablet interface. Additionally, the LevelUp team has partnered with Laminar Research and FlyJSim developer Daniela Rodriguez Careri to bring a symphonic audio experience. ‍ The aircraft is available for free now on the Threshold forum! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmefou</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Oulu Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmefou"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/676ac2266a510b51e7d9f498_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently launched its version of Oulu Airport (EFOU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This airport, located approximately 6.6 miles from the city center of Oulu, Finland, welcomes around 550.000 passengers each year and handles nearly 6.000 aircraft movements. The airport opened in 1953, following the commencement of construction in 1949. Initially, the airport featured only gravel runways. This changed in 1958 when the runways were paved, and the airport received its terminal and air traffic control (ATC) building. In 1973, the current terminal building replaced the earlier structure, which was later demolished in 2005. The terminal underwent further expansion and renovation in 2002 and 2011. Regarding the runways, the second runway was removed in 2000, shortly after the completion of the current ATC tower in 1998. Today, the airport operates flights from Finnair, Lufthansa, and Aegean Airlines, offering various regular and charter destinations, including Helsinki, Munich, Chania, and Rhodes. The scenery package is filled with features including custom night lighting, custom parking positions, custom surroundings, custom people, PBR materials, and much more. The add-on requires slightly over 1 GB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for $17.16. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcfs24</id>
    <title>X-Codr Updates Sceneries for MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2024-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcfs24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66b8771e662f70ff37689ea4_Screenshot%20(116).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. X-Codr Designs have recently updated all of their MSFS20 sceneries for the MSFS24. The update focuses on compatibility with the newest simulator and will be completely free.  ‍ The Grand Canyon West Airport (1G4) has received many improvements, such as a fully remodelled skywalk bridge, texture improvements for the Skywalk complex, airport ground markings and airport facilities, an updated airport layout, and various other minor enhancements. This update is available for both MSFS20 and MSFS24 on Orbx, and will soon be available on the MSFS marketplace. The development update also mentioned that the West Yellowstone Airport has undergone a lot of changes in the past years: a new hangar, an expanded FBO, as well as a brand-new terminal set to open in 2025. Because of that, a free update containing all the changes will be released in 2025! ‍ As the differences between MSFS24 and MSFS20 are quite considerable, there are still some issues with some sceneries. The list of issues can be found here. The last part of the development update also mentioned an upcoming airport for X-Plane, with a little sneak peek. If you have any ideas about which airport this might be, let us know in the comments down below! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwmcd</id>
    <title>WinWing Launches MCDU/CDU Panels</title>
    <updated>2024-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwmcd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/676de815866d63712d7aba09_Skjermbilde%202024-12-26%20233711.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. We now have more information about the WinWing MCDU and CDU panels announced this spring at FSWeekend and further showcased at FSExpo, thanks to a promotional video shared on their social media. The video showcases their new “MIP Series Airline Panels” lineup, which includes the previously mentioned A320 MCDU and 737 FMC, as well as two new additions: the 747 and 777 FMCs. After being a key player in the military flight simulation market, WinWing entered the commercial flight simulation market earlier this year with the A320 FCU, having big aspirations. WinWing says its new product line will feature a full-scale design aimed at delivering maximum authenticity, with a panel thickness of 28.5 mm. The panels will be fully backlit, and equipped with adjustable lighting and realistic light sensors. Their SimAppPro plug-and-play system will allow users to manually switch positions among captain, co-pilot, and observer roles, making the panels suitable for a variety of cockpit configurations. The video also shows mounting solutions that make the panels ideal for both desk setups and home cockpit builders. Each unit in the lineup costs the same, being priced at $129.95 before tax and shipping, with small price differences depending on currency exchange rates. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl291</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321Ceo for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl291"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de3df1ae2d10ada9d7bc_labsup2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs has released another update to their experimental branch for the newly released Airbus A321Ceo, addressing CTDs, further system fixes, extending hardware support, and more. Update v11.0.1.291 – the third since the product’s rollout in early December – brings improvements to the sound sets in the cockpit, mitigates an issue affecting a subset of users with a lot of add-on products in their community folder, and further refines its overall stability. It also extends hardware access to more EFIS and ECP events. The highlights for the update are below: DMC Systems Improvements: FWC:  ATSU:  Sound Enhancements: Simconnect Hardware FSLabs will continue the sound work through the holidays, as they are aware that some issues still exist. However, they wanted to provide part of the ongoing work with this update to gather feedback and eventually warrant a polished result. The add-on is available on their website for $69.95. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrpvi</id>
    <title>Airwil Sceneries Releases Iloilo International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrpvi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/677134fce3f78e3a0a8f9c6b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Airwil Sceneries has recently launched its latest scenery for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12: Iloilo International Airport (RPVI). As the fifth busiest airport in the Philippines, Iloilo International Airport welcomes over 2.3 million passengers each year. Commercial traffic at the airport began in 2007, serving as a replacement for the former Mandurriao Airport. Although it did not operate as a commercial airport before 2007, the site of the current airport has been involved in various aviation activities since 1942. During World War II, an airfield was constructed in 1942. After the war, this airfield gradually transitioned into a civilian airport, accommodating both military and general aviation traffic. Over the years, the airport underwent several changes and construction projects before commencing commercial operations in 2007. ‍ Today, the airport serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific and PAL Express, offering flights to destinations including Cebu, Manila, Singapore, Hong Kong, and many others. Airwil Sceneries' depiction of the airport boasts numerous features, including hundreds of custom-made objects, a modeled interior of the passenger terminal, a modeled interior of the control tower, and more. The scenery requires 1.99 GB of storage space and is now available at SimMarket for approximately $11.46. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1213</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12.1.3 Released</title>
    <updated>2024-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1213"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/677405a51140e8830db3ab17_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane 12.1.3 has just been fully released, one and a half months after the first beta release. ATC, the user interface, and sounds are among the most improved aspects of this update. ‍ ATC and sounds According to Laminar Research, the ATC system has undergone a significant overhaul. Radio communications have become much more realistic, including features such as radio checks, clearance requests, and VFR and IFR procedures that support SIDs and STARs. Additionally, the default navigation data has been updated to AIRAC 2306. Users can now copy and paste routes from tools like Navigraph and Simbrief directly into their flight plans. They can also request alternative SIDs and STARs, ask for altitude exceptions, and receive per-turn instructions. Furthermore, X-Plane can now be configured to output ATC audio to a separate audio device. Weather A full weather update is planned, but some changes have been made in version 12.1.3. Issues with sudden altitude and pressure changes during mid flight have been resolved. Additionally, improvements have been made to cloud visualization and interpreting METAR information and wind data. Errors related to the NEXRAD display for document number G1000 have also been addressed. User interface The flight configuration menu now provides more detailed information about gates and ramps. Additionally, the map highlights active runways and shows taxi routes. Several smaller improvements have also been made, including fixing rendering stutters that occurred when displaying UI elements and ensuring that VR windows maintain their positions. X-Plane identity In preparation for the X-Plane Store, the X-Plane identity feature has been released in early access. This feature allows you to link your purchase key to your X-Plane identity. Once you complete the migration, your X-Plane key will no longer be necessary; a simple login will grant you access to the simulator. In the future, purchases from the X-Plane Store will be linked to your X-Plane identity. According to Laminar Research, migrating to X-Plane identity is entirely optional. Several other changes have been implemented, including a handcrafted overhaul of The Downtown Manhattan Heliport (KJRB) and enhancements to the default A330, Cirrus SR22, and Cessna Citation X. ‍ The full list of changes can be found on X-Plane.com. ‍ Version 12.1.4, “The Flightlessons Update” is next up. ‍ For more on that, and more, stay tuned to Threshold. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2024-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
