<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-03-15T18:26:19.527492+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xokefl</id>
    <title>Xometry Announces Keflavík International Airport For X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xokefl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6221d768abba3430b0bef817_ok.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="289560"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Xometry has announced their latest project which takes us to the far North, a land that is often missed by flight simmers and overlooked by those who cross the pond. Keflavíkurflugvöllur or commonly referred to as Keflavík International Airport, is an airport many would have encountered but likely not visited. Typically overflown on routes between central europe and the west coast of the United States, this airport would likely feature as an alternative but hardly ever as a destination. Xometry could potentially have a reason to fly here.  The airport was initially established as a USAF base in 1942, later serving as a NATO air station, and as of 1987, becoming the gateway for passengers to the natural wonder that is Iceland. This airport is home to a few 757’s from IcelandAir, presenting us with the opportunity to operate the Flight Factor 757 outside of the USA. Handling almost 10 million passengers at its peak in 2018, it's anyone's guess as to why the flight simulation world has neglected to visit such an intriguing location. The project looks promising, with progress pictures that display an extreme level of attention to detail, which the team has claimed is their priority; mentioning “The airport has been recreated in high accuracy with much attention being put into making sure that we bring you the most up-to-date rendition of BIKF currently available for X-Plane 11/12.” It is important to note that the team is aware, and ready to ensure this scenery is off the bat ready to be compatible with X-Plane 12, especially as we fast approach its release.  Taking a look at their provided feature list below, we see all the usual features we expect from high quality payware scenery developers, however what is particularly interesting and not so common in X-Plane, is the modeled interior, a feature which is often overlooked but a neat detail when implemented. This inadvertently adds to the immersion and is certainly not expected but highly appreciated when done correctly. Check out their full feature list below: For more information stay tuned and we’ll bring you the latest when available. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12du</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Publishes March 4 X-Plane 12 Dev Update</title>
    <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12du" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622313d86cc398f518a65343_Cessna_172SP_seaplane_-_2022-03-04_15.38.53-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="459321"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. As X-Plane 12’s release date slowly encroaches upon our current simulators, it is almost time to say goodbye as we look to the future. One will know it's almost time to fork out and invest in the latest Flight Sim Software, when the time between announcements decreases, and with that our anticipation increases. In this article I want to give a brief breakdown on Laminar’s latest blog entry, detailing the latest progressions on the forthcoming simulator. Let's take a look. Confirming several speculations (and footage/software leaks as of late), X-Plane 12 currently resides within a closed private alpha group where our favorite third party developers have the opportunity to ensure their products are immediately compatible and without major bugs upon release. In the meantime, the team at X-Plane have provided in their announcement a table to give us a general overview on where the project currently stands and what still needs some work. As you will discover below, the announcement mainly addresses components mentioned under the “In Progress'' tab in their table. We will break down these items as we progress through the article. The first item mentioned is rendering low visibility. The team at X-Plane have been hard at work to ensure that the fog visually reacts like fog, with a real focus on how atmospheric conditions will impact its appearance. Sunny days will now illuminate the fog and anything less than sunny will have fog appear slightly darker, with nights obviously having the darkest tone. In addition to this, the team has mentioned that their focus remains on ensuring the simulator represents an accurate environment in which instrument training can be conducted. They are achieving this by using a modeled “monolith” surrounded by runway lights as a calibration target, pictured below: Next, the announcement shifts to water, something we typically tend to avoid an interaction with, unless you’re using a seaplane. Despite this, water has long been an oversight within X-Plane, with default textures looking underwhelming and dull. For version 12, water receives a major makeover in both function and form. In line with most modern titles nowadays, the water will be 3D, finally allowing users to see physical waves; the team has even gone as far as to work with Seaplane pilots during the Alpha phase, to pay particular attention on getting seaplane behavior correct. Lighting is the cornerstone of X-Plane 12’s visual rejuvenation, now utilising a photometric system and running entirely in HDR. The team has updated their methods in which they design night lighting and light sources, such as urban lights and street lights. Precise attention has been given to sources that will impact your flying experience, such as approach, runway, and PAPI lights, which they have done in accordance to FAA specs. Previously, users relied on FlyWithLua scripts to bring life to a number of environment aspects within X-Pane, particularly lighting. We hope to see the new default lighting exceeding that of third party addons.    Anti-Aliasing is next on the agenda. X-Plane in the past has made partial use of a deferred renderer, what we have now learnt from the recent update is that in order to implement the new weather effects and lighting, deferred rendering will have to be and is the exclusive mode at which the X-Plane graphics engine runs. With the deferred rendering, X-Plane 12 will now support MSAA or Multisample Anti-aliasing which it was not able to when X-Plane only partially utilised deferred rendering. This comes with the potential for improved performance as opposed to the use of SSAA which severely impacted Frame Rate. To further improve framerate the team will be implementing AMD’s FidelityFX Resolution, which allows for faster rendering and presents users the opportunity to scale up to 4K and retain their framerate. In terms of third party support, below are some short sweet points, that were mentioned in the announcement: As mentioned in their full official update, which you can find here, the team has indicated that the next step from the current phase will be early access beta, which will be accessible to everyone willing to participate. This can be done through either a demo or full purchase. For more information stay tuned, or check out their full announcement. We will bring you the latest when made available.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kiadxp</id>
    <title>Nimbus Studios Releases Washington Dulles for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kiadxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62231571156e94fb4de96e60_b738%20-%202022-03-02%2022.18.42.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="488904"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After much anticipation from the community, Nimbus Studios has recently released Washington Dulles International Airport (KIAD) for X-Plane 11. The scenery, featuring everything from fully modeled terminals and their interiors to custom HDR lightings and animated ground objects, presents users with an authentic experience when flying to the American capital. Based on the information provided, it can be seen that Nimbus has furnished KIAD with the latest technologies and the airport's most recent layout. A few notable features of the scenery include 4K PBR textures, custom night lighting, Dulles’s unique people movers, and ground traffic. A full list of features can be found on the product’s store page. Washington Dulles Airport, located in the state of Virginia around 40 miles outside of D.C, is one of the three major airports that services the capital. It has four runways and 139 gates. In 2019 alone, the airport saw some 24 million passengers and remains one of the region’s largest hubs for international flights. Currently, the scenery can be purchased on X-Plane.org for $29.99 USD, excluding any sales tax that may incur. Users who purchase the X-Plane 11 version will receive a free upgrade when X-Plane 12 is released. The developers recommend users to have at least 1.2GB of free space available on their hard drives in order to successfully install the products.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ts1112</id>
    <title>TorqueSim X-Plane 11 Updates Released; X-Plane 12 Preparations</title>
    <updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ts1112" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6223275fbb74451768dd3078_sr22.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="78988"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Renowned aircraft developer TorqueSim has retaken to their forums to announce the release of their anticipated X-Plane 11 updates and further outline their X-Plane 12 ambitions. Their SR20 and SR22 received the most attention in this update.  The following updates consist of quality assurance improvements and preparations for X-Plane 12. It's imperative to mention, though, that there is no X-Plane 12 update just yet.  SR20/22 G1000 1.3.0 Release Notes: Bug Fixes: SR20/SR22 Entegra 1.1.0 Release Notes: All of the above "new" features found in the SR20/22 G1000, in addition to: Bug Fixes and Improvements Aspiring TorqueSim pilots can find the SR20/22 on the X-Aviation store. As we optimistically await X-Plane 12, Threshold will continue to report on all new things TorqueSim. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/37fenx</id>
    <title>Fenix Drops Another A320 Preview</title>
    <updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/37fenx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6225c44e92854cb1e04832ec_dattabletho-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1907053"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After entering beta in early February, the Fenix Simulations team has returned to keeping their lips tight. Aamir has since returned from the depths of silence to share a singular new screenshot of the upcoming A320 for MSFS. The screenshot showcases the functionality of the EFB, as well as shows the cockpit in a “turnaround” state. Aamir hasn't mentioned any additional details regarding the aircraft's progress in beta but did claim that an upcoming update will reveal "areas of the products as yet unseen/unheard!." For those who aren't familiar with the current functionality of the aircraft, you should gaze at Fenix's YouTube channel that exhibits the A320's components. The team also has a public Discord server where members can communicate with any inquiries or concerns.  Unfortunately, there isn't much more to share with this update, but Threshold will keep up to date with Fenix as more information is released shortly.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prevwe</id>
    <title>FlightBeam Studios Shares Wellington Airport Previews</title>
    <updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prevwe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6225c764e2560a5bd508b81f_eba5cc_48952dbfae60478ba673a688c58d84bbmv2-2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="290823"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Smooth seas don’t make skillful sailors, Wellington International Airport is testament to this. Located just outside of the world's windiest city, this airport has notoriously had pilots constantly on their toes and challenging their skills. Windy Welly has since its inception, had pilots and seatbelts alike tested everyday, with a relatively short runway not making things any easier. That said, you can’t beat Wellington on a good day! FlightBeam Studios have been hard at work to give us the opportunity to experience this airport first-hand, recently sharing a couple of preview images that evidently suggest that this project is indeed in its late phase of production. The textures are clear and complete with buildings looking true to reality. Unlike most sceneries, surroundings are particularly important here as your nose will almost never be straight down the centerline.  The precise attention to detail in the air bridge texturing in particular, demonstrates the teams capabilities, setting our expectations high as we hope this level of detail remains consistent throughout the scenery as a whole. We can confirm release is imminent as FlightBeam Studios have opened applications for Beta testers whom must meet the following prerequisites, as mentioned on their official application form:  For more information stay tuned. Do feel free to check out their original preview post. Should you be interested in beta testing and meet the above requirements, submit an application here.  </summary>
    <published>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aoda50</id>
    <title>Aerobask Drops DA50 Trailer</title>
    <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aoda50" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622832854e2a9c3365c72385_Screenshot%202022-03-08%20215126.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="113183"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Throughout the years, Aerobask has played a critical role in X-Plane’s 3rd Party Addons. Providing quality, detailed, and outstanding-looking aircraft for the simulator. Today, Aerobask and X-Plane.org have released a trailer for the upcoming DA50 aircraft, coming to XP11 and XP12. Being one of Aerobask’s more highly anticipated General Aviation aircraft, the trailer provides a good look into what will be included in the aircraft when it is released. At first glance, the exterior of the aircraft is modeled correctly to match its real-world counterpart. With all exterior lighting, and features such as the winglets, being modeled as well. The shots of the interior of the aircraft provide us with a look at the G1000 suite that comes with all Aerobask products alongside the standard cockpit of all Diamond aircraft. Interior lighting has been accurately placed, along with seats, air vents, and other miscellaneous aspects of the cockpit being modeled correctly as well. While no feature list has been provided as of yet, Aerobask’s reputation as a developer has reached all ends of the market, both freeware and payware. Users are looking forward to being able to test this product in X-Plane 12, which Aerobask has stated this product along with other products will be compatible with the next-generation simulator. ‍ No official date for release has been brought to light, but Threshold will be sure to keep you updated on any further developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctp22w</id>
    <title>VATSIM Cross The Pond Slots Now Open!</title>
    <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctp22w" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622862ff39bd5c2c4c9b55a0_Vatsim-color-tagline-white.png.97c5c207436092fc1acd7f853ce29e05%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="26539"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VATSIM's team has announced the opening of their slot system for pilots to express their interest in participating in the upcoming event. Those who aren't familiar with the new slot system should note that the new system doesn't allow you to book a specific slot initially, but rather "expressing interest" enters you into a lottery to win a slot.  ‍Cross The Pond is the largest and longest-running event on VATSIM. Its history dates back to almost 20 years ago, and the event takes place biannually in a transatlantic fashion between North America and Europe. The VATSIM team has adapted to the modern media landscape, so pilots can now monitor CTP updates by following the #CTP22W hashtag on Twitter rather than having to scour through the website. They've also created a Discord server for aspiring CTP pilots to communicate and receive news regarding the event.  Lastly, the team wants to thank the community for its dedicated volunteers for making the event possible. Pilots who desire to participate should check out their website to potentially win a spot for the event.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/39pmdg</id>
    <title>PMDG Posts New MSFS 737 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/39pmdg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622866b4e6406a0f5aaa500f_pmdg1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="993757"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has entered its fourth week of testing their upcoming 737-700 for MSFS. As reported in weeks past, the team is making better-than-anticipated progress on the aircraft. Hundreds of "taskings," also known as "bug reports," have been resolved since the beginning of the beta test.  Randazzo reports that the "number of knee-knockers we are hitting that are related to PMDG-platform interface issues is dropping rapidly, and the number of "this system/function is behaving incorrectly" reports is rising as a percentage of the whole." Systems-wise, the airplane is operating at an "expected level" in this development phase.  PMDG is simultaneously working on improving the visuals of the aircraft, such as adding more wear-and-tear to the cockpit and adding some more character to the textures. Randazzo noted some small yet crucial details of their texturing adventures, relating to aluminum being exposed on the backing plate for the right-most dimmer panel, left of the captain's FMS. Aesthetic fingerprints are also being incorporated onto the screens of the digital displays. Last but not least, PMDG will begin working on some other preview videos as some time is freeing up to allow them to do so. No additional information regarding the aircraft was shared, but keep up with Threshold to stay in touch with the latest and greatest from PMDG!</summary>
    <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfopti</id>
    <title>GotFriends Previews the EA7-Optica for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfopti" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622b783064130a5597768ae6_unnamed%20(3).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="155311"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After releasing a multitude of freeware projects, GotFriends have once again decided to venture into the world of payware, with the announcement of the EA7 Optica, their second payware aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This aircraft is a full remaster of the previous freeware version which released last year. The developer has made it clear, however, that this is built completely from the ground up and includes exciting features such as a KAP140 autopilot and full PMS50 (GTN750) support. Included are “several real world liveries the aircraft was most popular for,” an animated cat and dog sitting visibly in the cockpit, and the aforementioned KAP140 autopilot and GTN750 support. It should be noted, however, that currently the TDS GTN750 does not work with this aircraft. Upon its initial release, the aircraft is set to be exclusive to the Flightsim.to store, and will be coming to the MSFS Marketplace (and Xbox) within a month. Furthermore, the aircraft is set to cost $19.99, but will launch with a sale of 50% as a token of appreciation to the community. It was also stated that users should be looking forward to the aircraft releasing sometime next week. For further information make sure to check out the official teaser trailer, as well as the original announcement made on the Flightsim.to website</summary>
    <published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mu-2v2</id>
    <title>X-Scenery Announces Mitsubishi MU-2B-60 Marquise 2.0</title>
    <updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mu-2v2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622c62ce2ad45820988b8327_overall.jpg.df8811fb8799a340c56caac02e4834a3.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="77212"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, X-Plane developer X-Scenery officially announced their latest project - the Mitsubishi MU-2B-60 Marquise 2.0. The aircraft, a completely reinvented version of the developer’s first payware product back in 2008, will serve as nostalgia for longtime X-Plane users while allowing others to enjoy a memorable general aviation experience. According to the developer, the 3D model of the MU-2 has to be redone from the ground up to accommodate for the differences between X-Plane 9, the simulator the first version of the plane was designed for, and X-Plane 11. Improved software technology, hardware capabilities, and workflow have allowed the team to improve the model’s geometric fidelity and “get the challenging shapes and curves more accurate”. To illustrate the differences between the two models, the developers included a comparison between the two where the v2 model clearly has “a higher density 3D model all around”. Additionally, higher 3D details have been utilized in certain areas of the aircraft to “reflect light more realistically as [the user] moves the camera around”, an approach that differs from the traditional method of using texture decals which may result in “fake looking 3D models”. To compliment the new model, the developers are also utilizing PBR textures with a solid implementation of ambient occlusion, “a phenomenon where light loses energy as it bounces around into corners, resulting in darker corners and recesses”. Since ambient occlusion is not provided for aircraft in X-Plane by default, it will be painted, or "baked", into the MU-2's textures. For a full list of improvements in version 2, checkout the developer's post. Finally, the developers teased that additional progress updates that will introduce the users to the MU-2’s cockpit will be published soon, though no specific time frames has been given. Currently, X-Scenery is yet to announce the release date or pricing of the Mitsubishi MU-2. However, the developers did indicate owners of V1 will receive a discount when purchasing MU-2 V2. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gfoptc</id>
    <title>Got Friends Releases the EA-7 Edgley Optica for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gfoptc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622dff0eab20150642006b11_unnamed%20(4).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="145364"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After a recent run of previews, Got Friends has released their second payware aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the EA-7 Edgley Optica. The Optica serves as a complete remaster of their previous freeware version, with the developer calling it a “full redux” built from the ground up. The EA-7 Edgley Optica is a single-engine aircraft originally created by Edgley Aircraft Limited, built primarily for aerial observation and as a low-cost solution for helicopters.  Powered by a Textron Lycoming IO-540-V4A5D at 260 horsepower, the aircraft is able to reach speeds up to 132mph and is limited to its service ceiling of 14,000 feet. The developer's rendition of the EA-7 Optica boasts various exciting features, such as a KAP140 Autopilot, PMS50 GTN750 support with Working Title’s extension framework, as well as attachable skis for winter operations, and much more. The full feature list is viewable below. Currently, the aircraft is available for purchase exclusively from the flightsim.to store for a price of $13.20 CAD, which is 50% cheaper than its original price of $26.40 CAD. However, the aircraft will also be available via the MSFS Marketplace and Xbox in the coming months. For further information, make sure to check out the teaser trailer, or view the aircraft's product page.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xobikf</id>
    <title>Xometry Releases Keflavik International Airport for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xobikf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622e062f53c422e402194dfa_unnamed%20(5)%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="68066"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After the original announcement of Keflavik International Airport (BIKF) earlier this month, Xometry has now released Iceland’s biggest airport for X-Plane 11. Originally serving as a USAF base in 1942, Keflavik has quickly become Iceland’s largest airport after the opening of its main passenger terminal in 1987. Not only does this aerodrome serve as a hub for Icelandair, but it saw nearly 10 million passengers in 2019 while being used by over 20 major airlines. Promised as the “most up-to-date rendition of BIKF currently available for X-Plane 11/12,” the developer claims that the airport has been made with high accuracy. Furthermore, the airport features custom SAM jetways, an interior on the main terminal, high-resolution PBR texturing, and much more. The full feature list is viewable below. Xometry’s rendition of BIKF is available for purchase via the iniBuilds store for a price of £17.99 GBP (excluding VAT). It should also be noted that customers are subject to a 15% discount on other Xometry products when using the code “BIKF-Launch”. Furthermore, users can enjoy a 20% discount on the iniSimulations Airbus Beluga by using the code “BIKF-Beluga” at checkout.  For further information, make sure to check out the official trailer via the iniBuilds YouTube channel.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfcord</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces Release Date for Concorde</title>
    <updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfcord" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622edfd5d9cfeb9ed8c639d8_6220755png.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1506231"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, Just Flight announced that its much anticipated Concorde for Microsoft Flight Simulator will be released on the 30th March. The Concorde, produced by DC Designs to be both “an accessible and yet highly detailed rendition of this iconic aircraft”, will provide the users with unique adventures as one of the world’s first supersonic jetliners. The Concorde, according to the developers, will feature most of the special features found on its real life counterpart, including custom-coded fuel systems, fully operational engineer’s station, nose-droop mechanism, “advanced autopilot system, and fly-by-wire controls”. A full list of features can be found on Just Flight’s website. Additionally, the aircraft has been given a custom-made flight model that accurately reflects its handling in “subsonic, transonic, supersonic and super-cruise” phases of flight, which “will require correct handling of the aircraft in order to achieve her famous high-altitude and high-Mach performance”. Currently, the Concorde is set to be priced at £27.99 / $39.99 / €34.95, excluding sales tax that may incur. To find out more about the DC Designs Concorde, visit their Facebook page.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eschsp</id>
    <title>Emerald Scenery Design Previews Chunilna Cabin Strip for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eschsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622fcd3d4a3e885a397c5221_chunilna_cabin_strip_alaska_msfs_r9%20(1).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="400534"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After releasing a plethora of freeware backcountry airports for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Emerald Design is venturing into the world of payware for MSFS, with the Chunilna Cabin Strip, a remote airfield located 11km to the Northeast of Talkeetna, Alaska. Marking the first payware product created by the developer for Microsoft Flight Simulator, Chunilna Cabin Strip is set to feature a multitude of exciting features not typically seen in other addons. With the airfield being located in Alaska, the scenery will include four native Butterflies and Morel mushrooms only seen during the warm summer months. Furthermore, additional dynamic features were included, such as rain puddles, and a bonfire along with smoke from the cabin that only appears when the temperature drops.  Along with these various immersion-enhancing features, the developer has included hand-placed native vegetation, a sloped runway, custom ground textures, and much more. As well, a shortened feature list is viewable below.  The airport is set to release via the developer's website and store.flightsim.com for a price of USD $9.99. As well, Emerald Scenery Design is hoping to release the airport on flightsim.to and the MSFS marketplace but is still awaiting approval. Furthermore, the developer is currently not planning on an Xbox version due to the maximum 1GB package size on the console. Nevertheless, Threshold will make sure to keep you updated on any developments that arise with this product. In the meantime, make sure to check out the original announcement post on the MSFS Forums and the airport's product page for further information. </summary>
    <published>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gsxpr2</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Drops Second GSX Preview</title>
    <updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gsxpr2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/622fde28313d583c9c1aa9d3_FSDreamteam-GSX-First-Look-in-MSFS-01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="198925"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Umberto Colapicchioni dropped a second preview on his YouTube Channel regarding GSX for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing the product's pushback procedures and animations, whilst the upcoming product is in its alpha build stage of development. This video starts off with Umberto summoning the GSX menu, and from eyeshot, viewers can see a variety of options from the menu. Items such as catering, refueling, boarding, and jetways are all shown in the UI along with other options the plugin is known for in its P3D and FSX counterparts.  After clicking on the pushback option, viewers see a handling operator menu, giving users the option to choose what air carrier operation pushes them back from the gate. The options included in the video are British Airways, Easyjet (both white and orange logos), and Virgin Atlantic. After choosing one of the options, viewers then can see a pushback tug pulling up to the aircraft, involving a ground crew member, fully animated.  After that, the aircraft pushes back, and once again, ground crew animations are fully animated, along with realistic flags and such being animated, and modeled.  FSDreamTeam did add a disclaimer that the product is in its Alpha version with features being subjected to change. Alongside this, no price or release date was announced by the development team.</summary>
    <published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
