<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-04-12T18:18:14.983571+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avdufr</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Publishes Frankfurt Airport Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avdufr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66107971ce8289af59130fe2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Software has shared an update about the development of the Frankfurt International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator. As announced in December, the airport will be available as a free download, and the developer has been working hard to ensure that it meets the highest standards. While the community has been patiently waiting for the release, the developer has now shared further information about the project. The team has been busy adapting to the new simulator, as they are used to working with X-Plane. Although this has slowed down the pace of the project, the team has been working hard on beta testing. The beta testers have been doing an excellent job, and the team has been fixing bugs and adding new features based on their feedback.  They have shared several images that showcase the airport buildings, ground details, interior, and ground equipment. These images give a glimpse into the level of detail that the team has put into the project.  A couple of new features were added to the list, including fully functional VDGSs, fully operational jetways, more land-side vehicles, ground markings, and animations. Their libraries are also constantly being updated. ‍ At the moment, beta testing is ongoing, and the team is working hard to ensure that the airport is as polished as possible. Once the airport is ready, it will be available as a free download for the Microsoft Flight Simulator community. We will let you know once new information is available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777046</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New 737/777 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777046"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6610eb3ab25734dbc3450d08_777apr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published another development update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, covering a new 737 lineup update to mitigate a camera issue and a couple of new 777 flight deck previews. The fixes are related to a mechanism within the 737 that handles the viewpoint when data is entered into the tablet. They found out that under certain conditions, the camera could get stuck during that process, making it seem as if the simulator is frozen, while it is, in fact, just the camera acting up. After a lot of research and replication, their tablet team engineered a fix and pushed the update right away, which is already available via the PMDG Operations Center. The update might take a while to appear on the marketplace as they are still completing their intake process on the previous build.  Randazzo has shared three new images of the upcoming 777-300ER flight deck, emphasizing that it does not represent the final product and is merely a work in progress.  It demonstrates some of the "wear and tear" they mentioned during the previous (Jokeless April Fools) development update, with high-touch areas being "polished" by oily fingertips after twelve years of heavy usage. ‍ While the surveyed airplane is, in fact, relatively old, it was treated with care, meaning the wear isn't as accentuated as one could imagine, being mostly natural wear that inadvertently happens regardless of the nature of the usage. ‍ They have also included dust and crumbs, which accurately represent an airplane that has been actively used for so long.  ‍ PMDG also confirms it will be possible to open the cockpit door and wander around the cabin, with dynamic sounds that will change according to your position in the airplane. Nocturnal screenshots were taken but discarded because they showed slight artifacting upon compression, according to Randazzo, which also drew an interesting parallel with taking night photos of your dog and how the picture doesn't have the same personality as they do in person. "Dark scenes in MSFS are the same way. In person they look spectacular, but in still images they often look artifacted and cloudy", concluded Robert. The movable lights on the flight deck can be moved about and pointed wherever one wants, like their 737s.  The PMDG 737 lineup is available in their store, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $69.99. The upcoming 777-300ER's pricing and release date are yet to be revealed. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/richax</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Richmond International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/richax"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660eaaf2eb399ea2b2870b42_ric4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Axonos has recently released their rendition of Richmond International Airport (KRIC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Sandston, Virginia, and has a yearly average of 4.7 million passengers, making it the busiest in Central Virginia and third-busiest in the state, only behind Washington Reagan and Washington Dulles. Its history dates back to 1927 when it was dedicated as Richard Evelyn Byrd Flying Field in honor of Richard E. Byrd, brother of the governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia.  A terminal building designed by Marcellus Wright and Son was built in 1950. Expansion work, including the current passenger concourses, was conducted between 1968 and 1970. The early 2000s saw impressive growth figures, leading to a complete redesign of the terminal, which added ten gates, extra parking spaces, and a new air control tower. It also included a complete revamp of the terminal building and the construction of a central utility plant. The two-year project was concluded in 2007. It was expanded again in 2018, two years after it recorded its second-highest yearly passenger volume, with the gate count going from 22 to 30. It was concluded three years later, in 2021. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, detailed 3D modeling, static aircraft (optional), custom jetways, custom ground clutter, realistic night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, and a custom GSX profile. ‍ It’s available in their store and OrbxDirect for $14.99 and $16.45, respectively. To install the scenery, you need at least 1.04 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/phehle</id>
    <title>Papa Hotel Releases Lelystad Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/phehle"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6612158bb42c8a2c3c32c4d0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Papa Hotel has recently released Lelystad Airport (EHLE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located in the Dutch province of Flevoland, Lelystad Airport is the second busiest airport in terms of flight movements in the Netherlands with an average of 80,000 aircraft movements per year, which also makes it the busiest General Aviation airport in the country. Lelystad Airport was originally established in 1973 to cater to General Aviation. The runway was paved in 1981 and extended in 1993. In 2015, the airport was given the green light to adapt for holiday and leisure air traffic, with a completion date initially set for 2018. However, the opening of the airport for commercial traffic has been delayed multiple times by the Dutch cabinet in The Hague. Despite not being open for commercial traffic, Lelystad Airport is still being utilized by several flight schools and clubs. Moreover, it is also home to the Luchtvaartmuseum Aviodrome, which hosts the famous FSWeekend. The scenery features a high-quality and accurate rendering of Lelystad Airport, high-resolution PBR textures, ortho imagery, a detailed rendition of Aviodrome and its exhibitions, a custom car pack, custom 3D animated objects, and much more. The airport requires 6.84GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for $16.22USD. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cvdivj</id>
    <title>Colombian Virtual Design Releases Capitán Vicente Almandos Almonacid Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cvdivj"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66121f6326eb03e88c579344_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Colombian Virtual Design has recently released its version of Capitán Vicente Almandos Almonacid Airport (SANL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This airport, located in the Argentinian city of La Rioja, serves around 63,000 people annually. The airport of La Rioja opened in 1948, and its first terminal was built three years later, in 1951. In 1969, the airport's grass runway was replaced with a new asphalt runway, which is still in use today. In 1978, a new passenger terminal and car parking were added, and the terminal had air conditioning installed in 1990. The airport has two domestic destinations, San Fernando del Valle de Catama and the capital of Argentina, Buenos Aires, operated by the airline Aerolineas Argentinas. The scenery includes various features, such as an accurate rendition of the airport, a custom terminal, and a realistic ground layout, and it is performance-friendly for the simulator. The airport requires 55MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for $7.58USD. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsa064</id>
    <title>FSA Releases FlightSimExpo 2024’s Schedule &amp; Activities</title>
    <updated>2024-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsa064"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6613b4df36f307518a6852df_2019_6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Flight Simulation Association (FSA) recently released the schedule and activities for FlightSimExpo 2024, which will take place between June 21 and 23 in Las Vegas. The event will feature developer announcements, panel discussions, community-inspired seminars, and more. The event kicks off on Friday (June 21) with #FSExpoFriday, consisting of a series of announcements and new product reveals, with more than fifteen presentations from developers. Then, the weekend seminar series will cover RNAV approaches, scenery design, online networks, combat and helicopter simulation, a live PC build on stage, and more. The seminars were sourced from the community and selected by the vote of the attendees. They will take place in Rio Las Vegas’ Brasilia room and on the FSElite stage in the exhibit hall. The organizer - Evan Reiter - ensures there’s absolutely something for everyone in their 2024 seminar schedule, regardless of their level of experience with flight simulation. The list of paid and free activities includes a tour of the Las Vegas Air Traffic Control Tower, museum visits, a night out on the town, on-site workshops, and live shows at the Rio. Further information about the activities can be found here. ‍ Twelve new partners were confirmed since the initial reveal in late March: Beta Technologies, The Pilot Club, Hyperion Sim, Thrustmaster, Redbird Flight Simulations, BeyondATC, Vyral LLC, Yawman, National STOL Series, Somnium Space, FlyVirtual.net, and FlyInside. Prospective exhibitors can visit this page for further info. Registration is available online at their official website. Attendees are encouraged to book discounted hotel rooms before they sell out. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/egnt12</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Newcastle International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/egnt12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6615ad1b684c417e6afea258_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released Newcastle International Airport (EGNT) for X-Plane 12. The airport, located in Newcastle, UK, is the 11th busiest airport in the country, serving around 4.8 million passengers per year. Newcastle International Airport, originally Woolsington Aerodrome, was established in 1935. During the Second World War, the airfield played an important role in training RAF aircrew and was occasionally used to operate detachments of the Supermarine Spitfire fighters. In 1967, a new runway, terminal, apron, and air traffic control tower were constructed, leading to a rapid increase in passenger numbers. Since then, the airport has undergone multiple expansions and other projects, becoming the focus city for airlines like Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways. It now offers over 80 direct destinations, ranging from sunny Rhodes to rainy Bergen, or even chilly Reykjavik. ‍ The newly released scenery, updated from the original X-Plane 11 version, features custom PBR ground textures, animated jetways, tower interior, revised lighting, revised orthophoto, reworked autogen, and much more. ‍ The add-on requires 2.6GB of storage space and is available on the Aerosoft Shop for approximately $18.20. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xro500</id>
    <title>X-Rotors Releases AW139 Version 5.00 for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xro500"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6615ae9d4a037ff4739d5d50_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Rotors has recently released an updated version of their AgustaWestland AW139 for X-Plane 11. This latest version, 5.00, comes with a lot of new features and improvements. The helicopter has undergone a major overhaul, with a completely new model built from scratch. It now boasts a new cabin, panels, and landing gear, as well as a new main and tail rotor. The helicopter has also received new textures and liveries that give it a fresh visual look within the simulator. Additionally, it has a steerable winch, wire-cutters, inlet filter, and floats. ‍ Other new features include a new audio panel and FMS screen, among others. Overall, the new version has an impressive changelog that can be found below: ‍ ‍ The newly updated version of the AW139 is now available on the X-Rotors Shop for approximately $43.40. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inprla</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Update for Los Angeles International Airport</title>
    <updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inprla"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6615af819822a01dca3e89b0_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has provided a sneak peek into their next update for Los Angeles International Airport (KLAX). According to the developer, the update will feature performance improvements and will match the current real-life airport layout. ‍ Although further details on the update have yet to be released, iniBuilds has shared a few preview images of the upcoming version of LAX. ‍ The developer has stated that the update will be released soon, while the current version of the airport is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $25.59. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeengm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Oslo Gardermoen for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeengm"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6616547e64ba2985a6cb0fb4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has provided us with several glimpses of the upcoming Oslo Gardermoen Airport (ENGM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Pictures of the Norwegian airport have been shared on the AviationLads Facebook page, while Aerosoft has also posted a video about it on their Facebook page. ‍ ‍ Although the pricing, release date, and features are not yet announced, Aerosoft confirmed on their Facebook post that the airport is coming soon. ‍ We'll keep you updated with more information as it becomes available. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vrfgru</id>
    <title>Vref Simulations Announces Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vrfgru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661763efd36cec2f33c8e941_guarulhos1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Vref Simulations has recently announced the development and imminent release of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves São Paulo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 41.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in the country. The airport's planning started back in 1967, when the government first considered renovating the airport infrastructure in the country and ran some studies to figure out which step to take next, leading to a straightforward conclusion: Congonhas (São Paulo's main airport at the time) was not big enough to sustain the ever-growing demand, nor could it be easily expanded, which led to a plan B: transforming a former Air Force Base into a full-fledged international airport. After decades of planning, construction started in 1980, with three runways and four passenger terminals in mind at first, which turned into two runways and two terminals due to time and cost constraints. It was inaugurated five years later and quickly became the city's primary airport.  Four years after the inauguration, the runways were extended, and the passenger terminals were expanded, bringing the overall capacity from 7.5 million passengers a year to 8.5.  A third terminal, planned for 2001, was built a decade later, along with Terminal 4. The first phase (of Terminal 4's construction) had it holding up to 5.5 million passengers a year, and the second phase brought it to its intended capacity of 8 million passengers, making it so the airport could handle 28.5 million passengers in total. The terminals were renumbered in 2015, with Terminal 4 becoming Terminal 1, Terminals 1 and 2 becoming Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 retaining its numbering. It's a hub for Gol Transportes Aéreos and LATAM Brasil and served by Azul, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and more. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, an up-to-date taxiway layout, dynamic lighting effects, detailed ground markings, and more. It's set to release tomorrow (11/04) for $8.99. Further information can be found on Vref's Discord. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tssgas</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Silvio Pettirossi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tssgas"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6617655d450a9eb335d8c742_asu.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently released its rendition of Silvio Pettirossi International Airport (SGAS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is situated in Paraguay and serves the city of Asunción. It is located just 6 miles (10 km) from the city center and serves around 1.03 million passengers annually. ‍ ‍ The Silvio Pettirossi International Airport was inaugurated in 1938. Its runway was constructed in the 1960s and later refurbished in 1985. Over the years, several international airlines have established routes to this airport. Iberia started flying from Madrid around 1968, and Lufthansa began flying from Frankfurt in 1971. The local airline, Lineas Aereas Paraguayas, also started operations to Frankfurt. Although these airlines have stopped these routes, the airport still has multiple international and domestic destinations. The Silvio Pettirossi International Airport is a hub for LATAM Paraguay and Paranair, and airlines like Air Europa and Avianca offer routes to destinations like Madrid, Bogotá, and Buenos Aires. ‍ ‍ The new scenery features a highly accurate rendition of Silvio Pettirossi International Airport, full night illumination, dynamic lighting, PBR materials, and much more. ‍ ‍ ‍ The add-on requires 440.69MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $18.17. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vefgru</id>
    <title>Vref Simulations Releases Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vefgru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/661763efd36cec2f33c8e941_guarulhos1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Vref Simulations has recently released their rendition of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves São Paulo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 41.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in the country. The airport's planning started back in 1967, when the government first considered renovating the airport infrastructure in the country and ran some studies to figure out which step to take next, leading to a straightforward conclusion: Congonhas (São Paulo's main airport at the time) was not big enough to sustain the ever-growing demand, nor could it be easily expanded, which led to a plan B: transforming a former Air Force Base into a full-fledged international airport. After decades of planning, construction started in 1980, with three runways and four passenger terminals in mind at first, which turned into two runways and two terminals due to time and cost constraints. It was inaugurated five years later and quickly became the city's primary airport.  Four years after the inauguration, the runways were extended, and the passenger terminals were expanded, bringing the overall capacity from 7.5 million passengers a year to 8.5.  A third terminal, planned for 2001, was built a decade later, along with Terminal 4. The first phase (of Terminal 4's construction) had it holding up to 5.5 million passengers a year, and the second phase brought it to its intended capacity of 8 million passengers, making it so the airport could handle 28.5 million passengers in total. The terminals were renumbered in 2015, with Terminal 4 becoming Terminal 1, Terminals 1 and 2 becoming Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 retaining its numbering. It's a hub for Gol Transportes Aéreos and LATAM Brasil and served by Azul, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and more. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, an up-to-date taxiway layout, dynamic lighting effects, detailed ground markings, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $9.22, requiring at least 543.03 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo412</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Publishes New San Francisco International Previews for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo412"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618c5f30f4701d3b78d30e8_ksfo1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam Studios has recently shared new images of their upcoming San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing the progress on the terminals, ground texturing, and custom jetways. San Francisco International is the second-busiest airport in California, with a yearly average of 57 million passengers, only behind Los Angeles International.  It’s a hub for United Airlines (44% of the market share) and Alaska Airlines (10.66% of the market share) and is visited by multiple international carriers such as Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air New Zealand, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, and WestJet. ‍ Mir, the developer, emphasized that it’s still a work-in-progress project, with one of the showcased concourses (United’s Concourse E) not featuring jetways yet. It was previously stated to be their most detailed work yet, sitting high above their previous projects regarding visual complexity, quality, and performance. It’s said to be inching closer to completion, and if things go according to plan, it could be released before summer. Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdogru</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations &amp; db Scenery Announce Guarulhos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdogru"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618c9dead3989329b5a7ebe_gdru1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations and db Scenery have recently announced the development and imminent release of Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves São Paulo, Brazil, and has a yearly average of 41.3 million passengers, making it the busiest airport in the country. The airport's planning started back in 1967, when the government first considered renovating the airport infrastructure in the country and ran some studies to figure out which step to take next, leading to a straightforward conclusion: Congonhas (São Paulo's main airport at the time) was not big enough to sustain the ever-growing demand, nor could it be easily expanded, which led to a plan B: transforming a former Air Force Base into a full-fledged international airport. After decades of planning, construction started in 1980, with three runways and four passenger terminals in mind at first, which turned into two runways and two terminals due to time and cost constraints. It was inaugurated five years later and quickly became the city's primary airport.  ‍ Four years after the inauguration, the runways were extended, and the passenger terminals were expanded, bringing the overall capacity from 7.5 million passengers a year to 8.5.  A third terminal, planned for 2001, was built a decade later, along with Terminal 4. The first phase (of Terminal 4's construction) had it holding up to 5.5 million passengers a year, and the second phase brought it to its intended capacity of 8 million passengers, making it so the airport could handle 28.5 million passengers in total. The terminals were renumbered in 2015, with Terminal 4 becoming Terminal 1, Terminals 1 and 2 becoming Terminal 2, and Terminal 3 retaining its numbering. ‍ It's a hub for Gol Transportes Aéreos and LATAM Brasil and served by Azul, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, American Airlines, Avianca, British Airways, Copa Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Iberia, ITA Airways, KLM, Lufthansa, TAP Air Portugal, United Airlines, and more. The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with 4K PBR textures, an up-to-date taxiway layout, custom landside, custom terrain mesh, custom ambient sounds, dynamic lighting effects, detailed ground markings, and more. It's set to release next Thursday (18/04) for roughly $9. Refer to the product page for further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bs0or8</id>
    <title>Backwood Studios Releases 0OR8 Sutton On Rogue Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bs0or8"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6618cb5b66e52cd9b310c08b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Backwood Studios has recently released their rendition of Sutton On Rogue Airport (0OR8) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located in the U.S. state of Oregon and has a 2,500-foot (762 m) grass runway and a helipad. It is situated approximately 3 nautical miles north of White City and has enough space for small GA aircraft operations. ‍ ‍ Sutton On Rogue Airport is located along the Rogue River, and it is a great destination for those who love water sports and fishing. If you prefer to stay dry, you will still enjoy the stunning panoramic views of the area. The airport has a 24-acre horse ranch in its estate as well. ‍ ‍ ‍ The airport features a grass runway, helipad, helicopter hangar, airplane hangar, and a pilot house for relaxation and entertainment. ‍ Backwood Studios' latest release provides a highly accurate rendition of Sutton On Rogue Airport, custom PBR textures, animated elements, tailored night lighting, custom 3D-modeled buildings, detailed interiors, and more. ‍ ‍ ‍ The add-on requires 1.98GB of storage space and is available on OrbxDirect for approximately $11.25. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
