<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-05-29T18:20:46.834346+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navavi</id>
    <title>Navigraph Releases Avionics Plugin for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navavi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6466a9aa449bd11e4515599e_chart1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="56282"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Navigraph has recently released their Avionics Plugin for Microsoft Flight Simulator, improving the Garmin G3000 and G5000 experience in the simulator with seamlessly displayed charts, SimBrief integration, and more.  The new chart integration aims to reduce workload and enhance situational awareness. It allows the customer to display specific sections of the chart and bring them to multiple displays within the flight deck, with lots of customization.  Although only compatible with the G3000 and G5000 for the time being (TBM 930 and Cessna Citation Longitude, respectively), Navigraph plans to integrate charts into more units in the future, like the G1000 NXi and the CJ4 Pro Line 21. It’s also available for integration by Xbox aircraft developers and soon available on the console and PC versions of the HJet and SF50 Vision Jet from FlightFX.  It’s available right now for Navigraph Ultimate subscribers. Please refer to their blog post for guidance on how to set everything up. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsdxin</id>
    <title>BRsimDesigns Releases Embraer E121A1 - Xingu II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsdxin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6466b0dcec2bb52a947f5e1a_xingu1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3817266"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BRsimDesigns has recently released their rendition of the Embraer E121A1 Xingu II for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an upgraded version of a twin-turboprop fixed-wing aircraft developed and manufactured in Brazil by Embraer in the mid-70s.   The E121 was the “first child” of Embraer’s 12X Project, which aimed to develop cutting-edge pressurized turboprop aircraft for civil and military use.   The Xingu was an upgraded EMB-110 Bandeirante, using the same Pratt &amp; Whitney PT6A engines but with a sleeker fuselage and cutting-edge technology (for the 70s/80s).  BRsimDesigns modeled the upgraded version of the Xingu, named E121A1 Xingu II, introduced in September 1981. It was slightly more silent and a bit more powerful, thanks to the pair of PT6A-135 engines, cruising at 380 km/h, with a service ceiling of 28,000ft and 660 nautical miles of total range.  Their rendition for MSFS brings a detailed model, internally and externally, making use of 4K and 8K texturing, including eight liveries, a KAP140 autopilot, WT GNS530 integration (also compatible with the PNS GTN750, payware), custom NAV/COM/DME/ADF/Transponder panels, a limited weather radar, a custom coded pressurization and AC system, an EFB, and more. The complete feature list follows down below: Visuals:- 8 Liveries (Including two Brazilian Air Force and two French Air Force liveries)- Detailed external model- Detailed cockpit model- Detailed 3D instruments- Detailed 4K and 8K textures- Detailed passenger cabin   Autopilot/Navigation:- KAP140 Autopilot- GSN530 GPS (Working Title GSN530 necessary)- PMS50 GTN750 (Externally Integrated)- Custom NAV/COM/DME/ADF/Transponder panels- Weather Radar (limited by API)   Warning System:- Custom integrated warning system   Anti-Stall system:- Stick Shaker- C.A.A (AOA Control System)   AC/Pressurization:- Custom coded AC system (With auto and manual control)- Custom coded pressurization system (With ventilation and pressurization mode)   EFB:- Controls: Chocks, GPU, doors, weight and fuel   Checklist:- MSFS checklist menu- EFB checklist page- PDF checklist   MSFS Effects:- MSFS icing effects- MSFS particle effects   Customizations (Controlled by EFB):- Airplane Registration (With the exception of Air Force liveries)- 2 glareshield options (New and Old)- 2 panel color options (Blue and Beige)- Fuel Panel Indicator (Magnetic indicator or Lights)- Shades for the cockpit side windows- Baggage objects shown according to the loaded baggage weight-  WT GNS530 and PMS50 GTN750- Save and autoload system for customizable options   Lighting:- Custom cockpit flood light- Custom passenger cabin light- Custom glareshield light- Custom and individual spot lights for every instrument- Custom landing, taxi, nav, beacon and inspection light   Custom Sounds:- Knobs- Switches- Warning- Autopilot- Stick Shaker- Oxygen Test- Fuel Pumps- Engine Ignition   Notes:- For the engine sounds to work, it is necessary to have the Default Asobo KingAir350 installed in your Microsoft Flight Simulator- This add-on is not study level. However, normal operations are simulated.- It is recommended to start the airplane in Cold And Dark state.- It is recommended to load fuel and weight using the EFB.- Not tested for Virtual Reality (VR)  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.49, requiring at least 708.95 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/staphl</id>
    <title>StarSim Releases Philadelphia International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/staphl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6467d7eb1ac45e9f60e82d84_phl.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3942135"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. StarSim has recently released their rendition of Philadelphia International Airport (KPHL) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the 21st busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 19.6 million passengers.  The airport site has been used for aeronautical activities since 1925 when the Pennsylvania National Guard began using it as a training airfield. Two years later, it became “Philadelphia Municipal Airport,” despite not having an actual passenger terminal until 1940, which forced airlines to use the nearby Camden Central Airport instead (they all moved to PHL once they finally built a terminal).  It was heavily used during WW2 by the USAF as a training airfield, organizing and training multiple fighter and bomber groups throughout the war.  It was granted international status in 1945 when American Overseas Airlines started their direct flights to Europe. By 1957, the airport had over 30 weekday departures by the wings of Eastern, TWA, United, American, National, Capital, Allegheny, and Delta.  Nowadays, PHL is dominated by American Airlines (63.75%), the dominance of which dates back to the US Airways days, way before the merger, starting in the 1980s and gaining major strength in 2003, when most of their hub operations were shifted from Pittsburgh to Philadelphia. It was their largest international hub and second-largest overall behind Charlotte and has since shifted hands to American Airlines after the merger in 2015. Frontier (11.02%), Spirit Airlines (6.59%), Delta Air Lines (6.00%), and Southwest Airlines (4.51%) take the remainder of the market share.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a fully modeled interior for all seven terminals, high-resolution PBR texturing for ground and objects, animated custom jetways, realistic custom mesh, custom road network, accurate 2023 airport layout, and optimized for X-Plane 12 and its new features, while also being compatible with X-Plane 11.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $24.00, requiring at least 3.56 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnxav2</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Publishes Long-Awaited Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnxav2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6467e5a8e1ec2e644b4d3ec4_iae.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="78866"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently published a new development update, celebrating their A320's first year of release and teasing some of what will come on the V2 update: new engine model, new fonts, flight model improvements, and more. ‍ They begin by thanking everyone for the support over the first year and explaining why the aircraft hasn't gotten any updates as of late: a strategic decision to prioritize work on a more substantial update that could address more things at once. "While I understand this may be frustrating in the short term, we are also incredibly happy with the results of this painful process - and truly believe that there was no quicker, or better way of producing these necessary upgrades for you", completed Aamir Thacker, Fenix Sim's CEO.  The long-awaited IAE engines are now in beta, featuring their proprietary external engine model technology, built on thousands of man-hours worth of work. "The degree of accuracy we were aiming for required that we have concrete, real life, data points to build the model around", they said. Fenix has made sure to model every aspect of the engine, ensuring it was as close as possible to the real-life data they have covered. To further expand their IAE engine development, they have teased its accuracy with different startup demonstrations, albeit without sounds yet, as they claim to be still working on that.  The next "victim" of the upcoming update was the fonts, which were entirely reworked and built on hundreds of high-resolution imagery sourced from their network of technicians and pilots. "We are very pleased with the result so far - but work continues on this project, with further nips and tucks required to font thickness and bolding amongst other minor details, along with the full completion of the various other display elements," they said, followed by two images showing the before and after. ‍  As if the list of improvements couldn't get any bigger, they have been working hard on lowering the VRAM footprint and improving its performance while also explaining why it used to be so demanding beforehand, dating back to a choice they made in 2020 back when the simulator's SDK did not support the sort of advanced display drawing technology they required to achieve what was envisioned. Things have changed since then, and they have addressed it by switching to a new display rendering method. VRAM-wise, they have performed lots of testing to reduce the memory usage without negatively impacting the visuals, reducing the memory usage by 50% inside the cockpit while also gaining a quality boost.  Lighting is another thing that changed for V2, with shadow-casting lights that have zero performance hit compared to standard/default lights, generating results that, according to the developers, are closer to real life.  The flight model was also not left behind, with fixes targeting crosswind takeoffs, crosswind landings, takeoff pitch input for rotation, and landing issues, followed by a collection of demonstrative videos.  The avionics will also be updated, bringing multiple improvements, including mitigating VNAV bugs, wrong DECEL point calculations, general system behavior errors, hydraulic system improvements, issues with auto flight, FMA improvements, crash fixes, and more. They will expand on that later once the update rolls out.  They finish off with an EFB showcase, which has been rewritten, migrating from a pure Javascript and PHP codebase to a more modern Angular front-end application powered by a C# backend, allowing their developers to work seamlessly on an industry-standard codebase, accelerating the development of new features for the EFB with greater flexibility and extensibility. They mention it's much faster to navigate between "apps," allowing them to remove the transition effects between pages and yield an overall smoother experience. The takeoff performance calculation was moved from the server side to the client side, making everything faster and more accurate on the speeds and landing data.  The Fenix A320 is available on the FenixSim Store for roughly $62.22, requiring at least 3.79 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pu7lim</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pu7lim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6467f3b0b755e5e174557a0e_1250410_20230516005750_1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1537614"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. As previously announced, PMDG has rolled out a new update to their 737 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing bug fixes, structural code improvements, and background preparations for the Universal Flight Tablet.  The new update was also submitted to the Marketplace for approval without a release estimate. They also state the intake process is running slower than usual. The full changelog follows down below:  0012284: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Small hole on VC (vscimone) 0011971: [General - Engines] Handling MSFS inbuilt model for in flight engine restart at high altitudes (emvaos) 0012338: [Main Panel - PFD] Meters Marker remains after deselection (abashkatov) 0011178: [Main Panel - PFD] SINGLE CH Annunciation shown with green frame (abashkatov) 0012358: [FMS/AFDS - LNAV] Custom waypoint off another custom waypoint naming (emvaos) 0011698: [General - Flight Model] AP roll channel revised with emphasis to engine out situations (emvaos) 0012348: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Typo in VC (vscimone) 0012346: [General - Comms/Navs] Aircraft Type Not Used by MSFS ATC (cbpowell)​​ ‍ The Xbox version of the 737-700 and 737-800 was also submitted for marketplace approval, which might release on either May 25th or June 1st, depending on Microsoft themselves, according to PMDG.   Their DC-6 was also updated, bringing the aforementioned UI updates for compatibility with the Xbox version. The update is now live on both PMDG.com and the in-game Marketplace.   The Universal Flight Tablet is scheduled to enter beta by the end of May, with a release timeframe becoming a possibility soon.   The 737 Lineup and the DC-6 are available on the PMDG Shop and the MSFS Marketplace (partially).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mu2upd</id>
    <title>TOGA Simulations Rolls Out v2.1.0 Update for MU-2 Marquise</title>
    <updated>2023-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mu2upd" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6468fb4e6ac3a3f830166873_MU2v2_1v11.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="290279"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Cameron of X-Aviation recently has taken it to the forums to address the updates for TOGA Simulation’s MU-2 Marquise update: “This will serve as an official announcement that we have released the TOGA Simulations MU-2 Marquise version 2.1.0 update. All customers who have purchased the MU-2 Marquise v2 up till now have been sent an e-mail by X-Aviation with complete instructions on how to obtain your update. We have made this a very simple process! For those that purchase the MU-2 Marquise v2 from today forward, your purchased download will already be updated to version 2.1.0 for you.” - Cameron. TOGA Simulation’s MU-2 Marquise update truly amplified its flying experience, setting a new benchmark in the world of flight simulation with its impeccably enhanced performance, and remarkable user-friendly features. The Patch (v2.1.0) notes include:  ‍ Fixes: ‍ Changes: ‍ Additions: ‍ In conclusion, TOGA Simulations has once again shown their commitment to providing an immersive and realistic flight simulation experience with their latest v2.1.0 update for the MU-2 Marquise. Addressing previous issues, this patch brings a host of important fixes to elements such as lighting, gauges, and autopilot functionalities. It also removes certain constraints for a more user-friendly flight experience and introduces synchronised features between the pilot and co-pilot's instruments.  Moreover, the addition of new effects like windshield rain and ice, engine start-up exhaust glow, and new custom commands underscores TOGA's keen attention to detail and dedication to innovation. The seamless process for existing users to access this update and immediate integration for new customers highlights X-Aviation and TOGA Simulation’s customer-oriented approach. With these enhancements, the MU-2 Marquise v2.1.0 is set to offer an even more engaging and dynamic flight simulation experience, reinforcing TOGA Simulation's position at the forefront of this sector. For more information please visit the X-Pilot forums and stay tuned to Threshold for more news.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfl146</id>
    <title>Just Flight Updates 146 Professional for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfl146" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646ca26eb0a8466151def75c_bae1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="91040"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently released an update to their British Aerospace 146 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding SU12 &amp; Xbox Compatibility, flight model and performance (FPS) improvements, failures (and failure control), and more.  The British Aerospace 146 is a regional airliner made in the United Kingdom between 1983 and 2001, featuring four geared turbofan engines mounted underneath the wings, with a retractable tricycle landing gear. With up to 3,600 km of range and a 749 km/h cruise speed, it can tackle short and medium-haul, formerly very popular at airports like London City with its short runway and steep glide path angle.  The new update is now fully compatible with SU12 and Xbox, along with new features, including a random payload button on the EFB, allowing users to set a random amount of passengers for the flight. They have also included a fully customizable failure system, where users can control over 80 different system and component failures, with the possibility to fail them instantly, arming them to fail later, or even randomly, with togglable probabilities. The full changelog follows down below: v0.1.9 - SU12 and Xbox compatibility added - Pushback controls added to the EFB aircraft page - Failure controls added to EFB aircraft page - they can be set to fail instantly (FAIL) or armed to fail after X number of minutes (ARM). There is also a random failures option with selectable probability for those occurring. - Random passenger and cargo load button added to the EFB aircraft page - HF antenna EFB option is now available on all variants - VHF NAV 3 antenna (located on tail) EFB option added - Speed card weights now show in LBs if that unit is selected on the EFB aircraft page - Onscreen keyboard added to EFB aircraft page - Numerous flight model improvements - Performance (FPS) improvements - Weather visible in -300 cockpit and cabin - fixed - Various minor livery fixes - Glass effect added to FMS screen - Rear passenger door button no longer shown when QT variant is being flown - Flight director go-around mode is now correctly commanded by two presses of the AP disconnect switches - ADF 2 test mode fixed - Fast e rection function added to standby ADI - Altitude selector test mode fixed - Tweaks to DME HOLD test - Minor fixes for MWS captions and tests - Elevator trim green band backlighting fixed - Small gap around EFB screens fixed - Higher resolution compass cards added - Runway turnoff lights now illuminate fuselage - Honeycomb hardware compatibility improvements - Additional lighting added to -300 and QC/QT cabins - Outside ambient noise is no longer heard when only the lower cargo doors are open  Just Flight has also added pushback controls to the EFB, allowing for tug connection/disconnection, direction control, and even steering the tug during the pushback with the rudder.  With their effort to ensure Xbox compatibility came a complete redesign of the EFB operability, adding a virtual keyboard for controller users.  They have also previewed their custom UNS-1 Flight Management System, which is undergoing extensive testing to ensure it’s working as it should.  It’s available on the Just Flight Store and Threshold Store for $69.99 and $64.99, respectively. Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winlba</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases Las Brujas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winlba" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646cafd782d5520deef939cb_bruja1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3466649"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of Las Brujas Airport (SKCZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Corozal in Colombia with a yearly average of 46,100 passengers.  It was built on the immediacy of a witch-burning site from the Inquisition days, commonly referred to as “Las Brujas,” meaning “The Witches,” hence the airport’s name.  The airport was inaugurated in July 1939, with a SCADTA (current Avianca) Sikorsky S-38 being the first airplane to land on Las Brujas.   It was recently modernized by its operator, the Grupo Aeroportuario del Sureste, expanding the passenger terminal, extending the runway, constructing a cargo terminal, adding a covered walkway for passengers, improving the sanitary infrastructure, and repaving the apron, along with other minor changes and improvements.  It’s served by EasyFly and Satena, flying to Medellín-Olaya Herrera and Bogotá, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a 3D model of the passenger terminal, custom ground markings, a true-to-life taxiway layout, custom ground clutter, and custom night lighting.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.58, requiring at least 276.52 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfstre</id>
    <title>RFscenerybuilding Releases Treviso Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfstre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646cc05d156077ddade9ba58_liph1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3157607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RFscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Treviso Airport (LIPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Treviso in Italy and the neighboring towns of Venice and Padua, with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  Built in the 1930s to meet the needs of the Treviso Air Club and inaugurated by Benito Mussolini himself, the airport only got its first passenger terminal nearly twenty years later, in 1953, the same year when Treviso got its first international flights (to London and Vienna, operated by BAE and Austrian, respectively).   For a long time until the opening of Tessera (Venice Airport), Treviso was also the airport of choice for passengers visiting Venice.   In 2007, the airport got a new terminal named after Antonio Canova, a famous local sculptor. It expanded its passenger handling capabilities and became Venice's de facto secondary airport, fully embraced by low-cost carriers like Ryanair.   It's served by Ryanair (Alicante, Amman–Queen Alia, Beauvais, Berlin, Billund, Bucharest–Otopeni, Budapest, Charleroi, Cork, Crotone, Eindhoven, Fez, Hahn, Kraków, Málaga, Malta, Marrakesh, Palma de Mallorca, Porto, Poznań, Prague, Riga, Seville, Sibiu, Sofia, Tallinn, Tel Aviv, Tenerife–South, Thessaloniki, Trapani, Valencia, Vilnius, Warsaw–Modlin) and Wizz Air (Bucharest–Otopeni, Cluj-Napoca, Iași, Skopje, Suceava, Timișoara, Tirana), with a significant route network encompassing most of Europe and some of Africa.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom buildings, custom ground textures, a true-to-life taxiway layout, custom ground clutter, and custom airport vehicles.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $16.23, requiring at least 161.53 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lispal</id>
    <title>Lisium Design Releases Palanga International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lispal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646ccff56449cc129fa917f4_pal1-min%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3179474"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Lisium Design has recently released their rendition of Palanga International Airport (EYPA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the town of Palanga in Lithuania with a yearly average of 300,000 passengers. ‍ The airport was built during the post-WW2 period, aiming to replace the former Palanga Airport that sat 7 km east of the new one. It was originally a military airport, controlled by the Soviet Union’s Air Force. The civil airport conversion only came to be nearly twenty years later, in 1963.  ‍ Between 1994 and 1997, the airport underwent substantial renovation work, with a revamped passenger terminal, featuring ICAO-compliant passenger services and luggage handling, a full control center renovation, followed by a runway resurfacing. ‍ With Lithuania joining the European Union in 2004, the passenger figures skyrocketed, a 60% difference compared to the previous year. With extra passengers came the necessity to expand once again, improvement of which happened in 2007, increasing the terminal area by two thousand square meters to comply with the Schengen border crossing regimen. Later that year, the runway was extended to the current 2,280 meters. ‍ It’s served by airBaltic (Riga), Norwegian Air Shuttle (Oslo), Ryanair (Dublin, London-Stansted), and Scandinavian Airlines (Copenhagen, Oslo). ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, PBR, parallax interiors, custom night lighting, a true-to-life ground layout, animated models, GSX and AREX compatibility, and high quality models of the airport and its surrounding buildings. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.23, requiring at least 1.20 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aermar</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Marseille Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aermar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646f6bb808891fdf3f64be1d_mar1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="106505"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of Marseille Provence Airport (LFML) for X-Plane 12, the sixth busiest airport in France with a yearly average of 9,390,491 passengers.  The airport started operations in 1922, on a 230-ha site 2 kilometers from Marignane, with a seaplane station and a 200-meter pier. It was one of France's main points of operation for flying boats, hosting Aeropóstale, Air Union, and even Pan American World Airways, although briefly.   The passenger terminal was rebuilt in 1961, designed by architect Fernand Pouillon (exterior)  and Maxime Old (interior), increasing its passenger handling capabilities. Thirty years later, in 1992, they expanded the terminal even further with the construction of Hall B.  In 2006, they opened a new terminal (MP2) aimed at budget airlines such as Ryanair, one of Marseille's most popular carriers. It's their biggest base in France, with 60 routes and more than 240 weekly departures.  The airport is served by many airlines, including Air France, Aer Lingus, Air Transat, Austrian, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, KLM, Lufthansa, SWISS, Tap, Turkish, Volotea, and Vueling. It offered 132 regular destinations in 2013.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality 3D objects, native weather effects, high-resolution orthophoto, realistic ground textures, accurate dynamic night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, SAM integration, custom animated jetways, and more.  It's available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $22.47, requiring at least 3 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Poptart for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thrbn2</id>
    <title>Thranda Design Announces BN2A Islander for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thrbn2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/646f74f63cb67dfca6839407_thr1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="189943"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Thranda Design has recently announced the next member of their Dynamic Generation Series lineup: the Britten-Norman BN-2 Islander, a British light utility aircraft and regional airliner in production since 1965.  The BN2 took off for the first time in June 1965, initially powered by Rolls-Royce Continental IO-360B, and then later replaced by a set of Lycoming O-540-Es. The first production unit flew for the first time two years later, the year when it got its US certification.  Thranda’s version replicates the BN-2A Islander, which came out in 1969 with aerodynamic and flight equipment improvements, including lower-drag engine cowlings, a bigger rear baggage area, and slightly more powerful engines.  One of its key features is its ability to operate from unprepared airstrips, including grass and gravel runways. It is a popular choice for remote and inaccessible locations where traditional runways may be limited or absent. Its STOL capabilities allow it to take off and land in challenging conditions, such as short runways and rough terrain, making it ideal for island hopping, humanitarian missions, surveillance, and aerial survey work.  It has a seating capacity for up to nine passengers, although it can be easily reconfigured for cargo transportation. Its large cabin provides ample space for passengers or cargo, and the aircraft can be equipped with various interior layouts to suit specific requirements. The cabin can also be modified to accommodate medical equipment for air ambulance operations or fitted with specialized equipment for surveillance and reconnaissance missions.  Powered by two piston engines, usually the Lycoming O-540 or the Textron Lycoming TIO-540, the BN2A Islander has a cruising speed of around 140 knots (160 mph or 260 km/h) and a range of approximately 800 nautical miles (920 miles or 1,480 kilometers). Its fuel efficiency and relatively low operating costs have contributed to its popularity among operators worldwide.  The little airplane has been utilized in various applications, including regional airline operations, charter services, military missions, border patrol, fisheries protection, search and rescue operations, aerial surveying, and environmental monitoring. Its reliability and robustness have made it well-suited for operations in harsh environments and demanding conditions.  As of October 2019, 800 islanders were still flying out of the 1,280 built.  ‍ There’s no information regarding features, pricing, or the release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed. Shout out to Luke for the news scoop! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsscal</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Calgary International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsscal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6470073bbd70cc6cc674035d_cyyc1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="124730"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has recently released their rendition of Calgary International Airport (CYYC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Canada with a yearly average of 14,452,000 passengers.  The airport was built in the late 30s, with a hangar financed by Trans-Canada Airlines and three runways funded by the Department of Transportation. It was initially named McCall Airfield after a Calgarian WW1 hero.  WW2 had Calgary International be repurposed as a fuel and maintenance stop for war aircraft and, later, housing a military flight training school. In the meantime, they continued to get regular passenger flights.  The end of World War 2 saw Calgary getting infrastructure improvements, including additional hangars, a fourth runway, and a passenger terminal, a repurposed hangar.   It turned out the repurposed hangars were not enough for the traffic boom of the 50s, leading to the construction of a new passenger terminal in 1956, designed by then architecture student Ken Bond. It was one of the most modern terminals in Canada back in the day.  Twenty years later, the once brand-new terminal could no longer handle the new passenger volume, forcing the city to spend $130 million on a 600,000 square feet terminal, which exists to this day.  More recently, in 2016, Calgary International got a new terminal, costing 1.6 billion dollars, covering 186,000 square meters of land and adding 24 new aircraft gates and a super modern passenger screening system with sustainability in mind.  It’s a hub for WestJet, flying to multiple destinations in the Americas and Europe. Air Canada and Flair are two other prominent operators with a significant destination list.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, fully detailed terminal interiors, realistic night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and more.  It’s available on Contrail  and FSimStudios' Store for roughly $21.44, requiring at least 7.12 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to Tang0 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdhou</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Releases Houston Intercontinental Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdhou" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/647030a10cb90011f36c86f5_kiah1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="289678"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDreamTeam has recently released their rendition of George Bush Intercontinental Airport (KIAH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 12th busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 41 million passengers.  Inaugurated in 1969, it quickly became Houston’s busiest airport, getting all the scheduled passenger traffic that once flew into William P. Hobby, which remained open but just for general aviation traffic. It wasn’t until 1971 with Southwest Airlines that William P. Hobby Airport would also offer commercial scheduled services again.  The airport has five terminals, 161 gates, and support for jumbo jets such as the A380 and the 747 (terminal D).  It’s a hub for United Airlines, offering multiple global destinations, truly an intercontinental operation. United Express, their regional branch, also provides a significant domestic route network. Spirit Airlines and American Airlines also serve Houston with many domestic destinations.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a realistic airport definition file, a customized GSX Pro integration, full dynamic lights, PBR texturing, Parallax shaders, the new terminal c modeled from scratch with full interiors, and more.  It’s available on FSDT’s website for roughly $9.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtphl</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Philadelphia International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtphl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6473c98f39779002f0090742_phila1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="619208"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DominicDesignTeam has recently released their rendition of Philadelphia International Airport (KPHL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 21st busiest airport in the United States with a yearly average of 19.6 million passengers. ‍ Built as a training field in 1925, PHL got its first terminal building only 15 years later, in 1940, when they got their fair share of passenger traffic that once used to fly into Camden Central Airport instead because Philadelphia lacked the infrastructure. ‍ The military personnel demands of World War 2 converted it into a First Air Force training field, organizing and preparing various fighter and air bomber groups throughout the war. It was handed back to the city as soon as the war was over. It was also when the airport was granted its international status. ‍ In the 1950s, the airport got a new  terminal and underwent heavy expansion work, lasting up until 1970, when the entire structure was modernized. Two new terminals were built in the same decade, starting with Terminal D in 1973, and Terminal E in 1977.  ‍ American Airlines holds the majority of the market share with 63.75%, offering a considerable amount of destinations, domestic and international. Frontier is second with 11.02%, followed by Spirit, Delta, and Southwest, with 6.59%, 6%, and 4.51%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, dynamic lighting, real ground markings, hand-crafted pavement textures, custom jetway, custom object animation, and AI airline parking codes.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.99, requiring at least 704.85 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxikal</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Kalamata International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxikal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6474a687fa73925d4e31dc4f_kal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2647351"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has recently released their rendition of Kalamata International Airport (LGKL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the second most populous city of the Peloponnese Peninsula, Kalamata (Greece).   It was opened in 1959 as a military airfield, primarily serving as a base for the Hellenic Air Force. After nearly a decade of charter traffic, it converted into a dual-use facility in the 90s. A new passenger terminal was built in 1991.  The 2000s saw continuous work to upgrade and expand the airport, keeping up with the ever-rising passenger numbers, although on a seasonal basis.   It’s visited by multiple airlines during the summer, including the Greek carrier Aegean Airlines, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Condor, easyJet, Edelweiss, Eurowings, Jet2.com, Lufthansa, Neos, Olympic Air, Ryanair, Smartwings, Swiss, Transavia, and Volotea.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with up-to-date ground markings, detailed models with PBR texturing, a basic interior on both terminals, custom taxiway signs, 3D passengers, and custom vegetation.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.02, requiring at least 1.40 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
