<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-28T18:25:15.483206+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftsy12</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Sydney Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftsy12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664b1619ce19b15c0760cea7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlyTampa has recently released its version of Sydney Kingsford Smith Airport (YSSY) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Australian city of Sydney and is situated approximately 5 miles (8 kilometres) from the city. As the biggest and busiest airport in Australia, it welcomes around 42 million passengers annually. In 1919, Nigel Love leased and established an airfield on grassy paddocks in the suburb of Mascot. The first flight from the airfield was with Love in 1919, and the official opening took place in 1920. After the lease ended in 1923, the Commonwealth Government acquired the airfield, just before the first regular flights began in 1924. The first gravel runway was built in 1933, and by 1949, the number of runways had tripled. Construction for a new terminal started in 1966 and was officially opened in 1970. Over the years, the airport has undergone several upgrades and constructions. Today, the airport serves numerous cities worldwide and is a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia, as well as many other airlines, with a yearly total of over 300,000 aircraft movements. The newly released version of Sydney Airport includes many features such as a fully custom rendition of Sydney Kingsford Smith Airport, custom mesh, custom night lighting, SAM and LST integration, Ortho4XP patch, and much more. The newly released add-on is now available on Orbx for approximately $32.50. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxipvk</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Preveza Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxipvk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664c98df90484b4f72ebc8d0_340412_M1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has released their rendition of Preveza Aktion Airport (LGPZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the city of Preveza and Lefkada Island, with an average of 773,000 passenger operations per year. Opened in 1968, Preveza Airport is a popular airport during the summer season, with charter flights arriving from all over Europe, but it is also used by NATO and the Hellenic Air Force. In 2015, 14 airports in Greece, including Aktion Airport, were privatised by Fraport AG. Aktion Airport was presented with an investment plan to modernise the terminal and improve customer service. Along with the terminal renovation and extension, reorganisation of the apron and refurbishment of airside pavement were also planned. Outside of the summer season, Preveza Airport only receives domestic flights from Zakynthos, Corfu and Sitia. During the summer, more than 28 air carriers perform charter flights from Preveza to numerous cities in Europe, mostly in Germany, the UK and Sweden. MXI Design’s LGPZ features accurately modelled terminal and airport buildings, up-to-date ground markings, terminal interior, PBR textures, and custom static planes. Preveza Aktion Airport is available for purchase on SimMarket, for approximately 10.83$, requiring at least 1.52GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned for more flight sim news to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/c3dsfa</id>
    <title>CAT3DUAL Releases Sfax Thyna Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/c3dsfa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664c9ba136bd356fb26802e4_340377_DTTX-01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CAT3DUAL has released their rendition of Sfax-Thyna Airport (DTTX) for MSFS. The airport serves the city of Sfax in Tunisia and has a yearly average of 200.000 passengers. It is located 6 kilometres outside the city of Sfax. During WWII, the airport was used by the USAF during the North African campaign and was known as Sfax Airfield. Two bombardment groups used this airfield - the 12th and 340th Bombardment Group, both using the B-25 Mitchell. After the war, Sfax Airport received many extensions and improvements, with the most important one being the construction of the new terminal in 1988 and the extension of the runway. In the following years, a cargo terminal was added, along with a warehouse, taxiways and the airport apron reconstruction. The latest expansion was finished in 2007, when a new terminal, consisting of three buildings, and a new control tower were built. Today, Sfax-Thyna Airport serves 6 airlines to 7 destinations, and many charter flights from Germany and UK during the summer season. CAT3DUAL’s rendition of DTTX features custom buildings on the airfield, main apron including an eastern expansion, accurate airfield way finders: taxiway signs and markings, airfield lighting placement and colours per Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP), custom perimeter wall and more. This scenery can be purchased on SimMarket for approximately 8.68$ and requires at least 135MB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftegnj</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Humberside Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftegnj"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664c9e11e0e434082ff8c68b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has released their rendition of Humberside Airport (EGNJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving Lincolnshire, Kingston upon Hull and the East Riding of Yorkshire, this airport welcomes around 90.000 passengers per year. Opened in 1941 as an RAF air base, RAF Kirmington housed the 166th RAF Squadron that operated Avro Lancasters. After 1945, the airport was abandoned for 30 years, until the local council decided to activate the airfield again. After the local area was renamed, the airport was renamed to Humberside Airport. Due to the proximity of other airports, Humberside faces competition from East Midlands and Leeds Bradford Airport. This is because competitive airports have a wider range of passenger flights. The airport serves only two airlines with scheduled passenger flights, KLM to Amsterdam and Eastern Airways to Aberdeen, while during the summer season, TUI has charter flights to Palma de Mallorca, and BH Air to Burgas. FlyTampa’s version of Humberside Airport features Hi-res modelling and PBR textures, a modelled terminal interior with animated passengers, a GSX profile, and LOD performance modelling. This scenery can be purchased on FlyTampa’s website for 12.99$. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jetgen</id>
    <title>Jetstream Designs Announces Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jetgen"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664ce3761ae36b5b1651cb09_lsgg1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Jetstream Designs has recently announced the development of Geneva Airport (LSGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This international Airport serves Grand Genève (Geneva’s metropolitan area) and has a yearly average of 14 million passengers. ‍ It was first established as an airfield in Cointrin, near Geneva (which explains the airport still being informally known as Cointrin Airport), in October 1919. It wasn’t until the late 1920s that the airport would get appropriately structured, with concrete hangars instead of makeshift wooden sheds.  ‍ The first concrete runway was built in 1937, with a total length of 405 meters.  ‍ The airport was heavily expanded during World War 2, as the Swiss authorities banned any departures for safety reasons. The runway was extended to 1200 meters near the end of the war, and provisions were made to ensure further expansion capabilities in the future. The first passenger terminal was built in 1946, costing 2.3 Swiss Francs to the authorities, along with a runway expansion to 2000 meters.  The runway was expanded for the last time in 1960, with jet traffic in mind, taking it from 2000 meters to 3900 meters. This is an unusually long runway for an airport of that size, and a territorial exchange had to be made between Switzerland and France to ensure that there would be enough room for it.  ‍ In the late 1980s, a new passenger terminal was built, with 12 jet bridges and two ground-floor gates. It ultimately replaced the old one from 1946, which now only opens during winter charter season.  ‍ It’s a hub for Swiss International Air Lines and an operating base for EasyJet Switzerland. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, easyJet, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, ITA, Jet2.com, KLM, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, TUI Airways, United Airlines, Vueling, and Wizz Air also serve it. While a feature list has not been provided, the many screenshots shared on their social media platforms reveal some of it: custom ground textures, custom jetways, terminal interiors, and custom runway textures. Jetstream also proudly announces that Marcus Nyberg, a scenery developer from Orbx, has joined them to help with Geneva and future projects. There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bmwsfo</id>
    <title>BMWorld &amp; AmSim Release San Francisco International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bmwsfo"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664d1a72ae2567b1c98e7351_sanfra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BMWorld and AmSim recently released their rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the San Francisco Bay Area and has a yearly average of 50.1 million passengers. ‍ Initially meant to be a temporary and experimental airport project when the city of San Francisco leased 61 hectares of land in 1927 from the Mills Estate (owned by Ogden L. Mills), it quickly became a permanent commitment with the purchase of the land and its surroundings, totaling up to 450 hectares of area.  It was briefly used as a Coast Guard base and an Army Air Corps training and staging base during World War 2. Following the war, international air travel boomed, prompting the airport's final name change to San Francisco International Airport in 1945. The jet age ushered in a new chapter for SFO. In the 1950s, longer runways were constructed to accommodate larger jetliners and new terminals were built to handle the increased passenger volume and the demands of international travel. ‍ SFO's commitment to innovation continued throughout the latter half of the 20th century. The airport embraced new technologies, such as jet bridges and baggage carousel systems, to improve passenger experience. In 1971, SFO became the first airport in the United States to have an automated people mover system, the AirTrain. ‍ It's a hub for United Airlines (44% of the market share) and Alaska Airlines (10.66% of the market share) and is visited by multiple international carriers such as Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air New Zealand, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, and WestJet. The scenery features an accurate airport rendition, with high-resolution ground textures, custom ground markings, animated jetways, a detailed terminal area, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $22.50, requiring at least 1.84GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lut102</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates London Luton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lut102"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6606f1e634e0e854c2a43a96_luton2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their rendition of London Luton Airport (EGGW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing small bugs and missing items. Update v1.0.2 addresses an issue with flashing lights on runway 25, blurry logos on the National Sameday building, floating ropes, a misplaced crosswalk on stand 2/3, missing ground services at some gates, and more. The full changelog follows below:  - No flashing lights on runway 25 - Blurry logos on National Sameday building - Interior windows floating with interiors disabled - Floating ropes - Sequenced flashers - Stand 1-5 + 9L stop markers - Misplaced crosswalk on stand 2/3 - Missing ground services at some gates - Fixed issue with main terminal optimization.  ‍ They have also updated the GSX profile to accommodate the changes to the modified gates. ‍ The scenery is available at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.91, requiring at least 5.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avacon</id>
    <title>AviaSim Designs Releases Conington Aerodrome for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avacon"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664d2b256e3725a4da07744c_coni1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AviaSim Designs recently released their rendition of Conington Aerodrome / Peterborough Business Airport (EGSF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This privately owned airfield is 13 kilometers south of Peterborough in the English county of Cambridgeshire. Originally built as RAF Glatton in 1942-1943 by the 809th United States Army Corps of Engineers to house B-17 bombers of the 457th Bomb Group, it was passed to the Royal Air Force after the end of the war. A year later, it was mothballed, and most of the structure vanished over the following years, leaving just a hangar and a water tower. The airfield saw some use in the 1960s from two local companies, which used its runway and hangar to store their aircraft. A ground engineer provided basic maintenance facilities.  Aerolease Ltd. currently operates it, and aviation fuel is available on-site. Hangarage and parking must be arranged beforehand. The current layout consists of two runways: runway 16/34, which isn’t AIP or NAPS listed, is approximately 800 meters long and in worse condition than the listed one (10/28), which is slightly longer at 987 meters. The scenery features an up-to-date layout, custom aerial imagery, 4K PBR textures, custom ground poly, sloped runway profile, dynamic lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.86, requiring at least 335.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfdsjc</id>
    <title>ShortFinal Design Releases San Jose International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfdsjc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664e72e0e768f2cf78b60c09_sjc1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ShortFinal Design recently released its rendition of San Jose International Airport (KSJC) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves Santa Clara Valley and the San Francisco Bay Area and has a yearly average of 12 million passengers. ‍ Officially opened in 1939, its first proper runway was only built six years later on land leased by test pilot James M. Nissen and his partners. A hangar and an office building for a flight school were also built.  The city took over shortly after, with James Nissen becoming the airport's first manager, considerably instrumental in its infrastructural development. ‍ The increased demand for air travel in the 1960s led to constructing the first proper terminal building, which later became Terminal C. Throughout the late 20th and early 21st centuries, SJC witnessed continued growth. Terminal A opened in 1990, followed by the city council's approval of a new master plan for long-term expansion in 1997. The airport has seen the introduction of international flights, including the first trans-Pacific service to Tokyo launched by American Airlines in 1991. ‍ Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, Hawaiian Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, Volaris, and Zipair Tokyo serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, detailed models for all buildings, terminals with fully modeled interiors, PBR materials, custom dynamic night lighting, high-resolution photo imagery, 3D vegetation, and more. ‍ It's available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $22.95, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shsvsa</id>
    <title>SkyHigh Studios Previews Växjö Småland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shsvsa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664f624f4d4a62a033efc120_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SkyHigh Studios has announced and previewed their new scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new scenery will be Växjö Småland Airport (ESMX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Pictures of the Swedish airport have been shared on the SkyHigh Studios Facebook page, the Orbx page for the airport is also up. Although the pricing has not yet been announced, SkyHigh Studios confirmed on their Facebook post that the airport is coming next week. Features for the airport have also been shared, which include PBR 4K ground polygon, custom AFCAD, a fully modelled interior, authentic assets, dynamic night lighting, and more. We'll keep you updated with more information as it becomes available. For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsu15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 15 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsu15"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664f8271c3ac491e60d0b2d1_update15.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released the long-awaited Sim Update 5 for Microsoft Flight Simulator after a series of delays and controversies. The new update brings performance improvements, faster loading times, airport fixes, and the A320neo V2 by iniBuilds. ‍ Focusing on performance gains and stability, Sim Update 15 claims to bring significant framerate gains where it was otherwise low, fewer stutters, especially on long sessions, and substantially faster loading times. The performance figures on glass cockpit heavy airplanes, such as the 747, have also been greatly improved thanks to their work optimizing the Coherent/JS tech stack. On the stability front, Microsoft has devised a way to stop the console version from crashing when it runs out of memory by detecting the issue before it happens and temporarily reallocating the memory, causing a brief loss of detail quality while preventing a hard crash. ‍ The physics front has also seen changes, with a new high-accuracy physics system to enable vibrations and micro-movements, a more accurate ground contact model, and an optional soft ground collision model for tires and flexible gears.  ‍ The A320neo V2 by iniBuilds is now available, featuring a high-quality 3D model, improved system fidelity, high-resolution textures, and a high-detail cabin for PC users. Microsoft has shared a video introducing us to the brand-new aircraft: ‍ The complete changelog follows below: ‍ The update is available right now on all compatible platforms. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fadsrs</id>
    <title>Final Approach Design Studios Releases Sylhet Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fadsrs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6650edf8a96d290c6005f2d8_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Final Approach Design Studios recently released their version of Sylhet Airport (VGSY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Officially known as Osmani International Airport, the airport serves the Bangladeshi city of Sylhet. The airport is the third busiest in the country and is located around 5 miles from the city centre. It serves an average of just under 650.000 passengers annually. Osmani International Airport was built during the period of 1944-1945. It was constructed during World War II with the purpose of controlling Japanese aggression from Burma. Initially opened as Sylhet Civil Airport, it started as a domestic airport. In 1986, a terminal building, navigational aids, new runway pavement, taxiways, and aprons were constructed. The airport saw its first international flight in 2002 and has since undergone further expansion and upgrades. Today, the airport is operated by airlines such as Biman Bangladesh Airlines and Novoair, offering flights to destinations such as Dhaka, London, and Dubai. The recently released version of Sylhet Airport features 4K PBR textures, highly detailed ground poly, detailed 3D buildings, ground service equipment, animated jetways, terminal interiors, and more. The add-on requires a total of 1.40GB of storage space and is available on iniBuilds for roughly $14.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/denm24</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Announces Denver International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/denm24"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6651c99d344734cfdb5f9191_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. X-Codr Designs has announced the development of Denver International Airport (KDEN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This comes after the successful creation of the airport for X-Plane. The team is currently in the final stages of development and testing for the Microsoft Flight Simulator version. The scenery package will include highly detailed models, high-resolution textures, custom jetways, an accurate and up-to-date layout, performance optimisation, ortho imagery, and more. The announcement was made on the developer's website, and as the airport is nearing completion, the release of the scenery might be right around the corn ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stsmaa</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Announces Maastricht-Aachen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stsmaa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66526f799454c6a0685fbedf_maa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently announced the development and imminent release of Maastricht-Aachen Airport (EHBK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Maastricht, in the Netherlands, and Aachen, in Germany, with a yearly average of 97.000 passengers. It was built by the Allies as a temporary airfield during World War 2, later transferred to the Dutch government and named Beek Airfield. It saw lots of traffic during its initial months because most roads in the country had been bombed and/or heavily damaged. As the repairs progressed, the traffic figures died down. The first semi-permanent terminal was built in 1947, followed by runway paving work in 1949 and 1950. Further expansion work was carried on from 1951 and beyond after an agreement between the airport and the Dutch Air Force. The airport underwent expansion work in the early 1970s to handle bigger aircraft, which included runway lengthening, taxiway widening, and apron enlargement. A decade later, a new passenger terminal was built, replacing the old one from the 40s. Corendon Dutch Airlines, Pegasus Airlines, and Ryanair serve it. ‍ The scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom ground textures, custom taxiway signage, custom objects, PBR texturing, a realistic runway profile, and more. Refer to their website for further information. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msesmx</id>
    <title>SkyHigh Studios Releases Växjö Småland Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msesmx"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/665450683649913b944ef8c4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SkyHigh Studios has just released their rendition of Växjö Småland Airport (ESMX) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Swedish city of Växjö and sees just under 150.000 passengers yearly. It offers both regional and international destinations for the city. The city of Växjö received its first scheduled flights in 1960, operating to and from the Uråsa airbase at that time. With increasing demand, a larger airport, Växjö Småland Airport, was constructed and opened in 1975. Initially, the airport only offered flights to Stockholm, but in 2007, international flights began. Airlines such as Ryanair and Wizzair began operating out of the airport, and over the years, the popularity of charter flights to the Canary Islands and Southern Europe increased. Presently, the airport offers year-round flights to Stockholm Bromma Airport through Braathens Regional Airlines. Additionally, airlines like Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Sunclass Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic operate seasonal routes to destinations such as Alicante, Rhodes, and Gran Canaria. The airport sees around 4000 aircraft movements annually. The scenery package is filled with features, such as PBR 4K ground polygons, custom AFCAD, fully modelled interior, authentic assets, dynamic night lighting, and more. The newly released Växjö Småland Airport is now available on Orbx for approximately $14.10 and requires 2.64 GB of storage space. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carplc</id>
    <title>Cloudsurf Asia Releases Clark International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carplc"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6654974903838761a186deb1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cloudsurf Asia has recently released its version of Clark International Airport (RPLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located 50 miles northwest of Manila and serves both the Central Luzon and Northern Luzon regions, welcoming just under 1.9 million passengers annually. In 1902, after the United States Cavalry established Fort Stotsenberg, part of it was converted into an airfield, which was later renamed Clark Air Field in 1919. In 1991, the Philippine government took over Clark Air Field, and it wasn't until 1996 that the airport opened for commercial operations. Over the years, the airport has undergone various expansions and developments. Today, the airport features an 889.000 square feet terminal, opened in 2022, and one runway after the former second runway was decommissioned due to its proximity to the other one. The airport handles both passenger and cargo operations and serves airlines such as Cebu Pacific, Sunlight Air, Emirates, and Qatar, offering a variety of destinations such as Cebu, Dubai, and more. The airport sees around 5.500 aircraft movements annually. The newly released version of Clark International Airport for MSFS includes many features such as fully custom objects, terminal interior, PBR textures, custom animated jetways, and much more. The add-on requires a total of 1.63 GB of storage space and is now available on Orbx for approximately $23.82. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
