<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-01-15T18:22:05.011329+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssead</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Announces Release Date for Embraer 175 Add-on</title>
    <updated>2023-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssead" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b760722457ab24cdb681db_emb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="538011"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG has recently previewed their upcoming Embraer 175 in a three-hour long live stream where they have shown the current state of the product, planned features, and pricing, along with a development roadmap.   The E175 is a narrow-body, twin-engine jet airliner produced by Brazilian aerospace manufacturer Embraer, designed to seat up to 78 passengers in a typical two-class configuration or a maximum of 88 passengers in a high-density layout. It has a range of up to 2,400 nautical miles, making it suitable for regional and medium-haul flights.   The add-on is coming out five days from now under an early access program, where users will be able to test the aircraft during its development process and provide feedback. The complete feature list follows down below:  ‍ It’s going to be available next Tuesday for 33 euros. Threshold will keep you updated. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lepaqp</id>
    <title>Low-End PC Studios Releases Rodríguez Ballón International Airport v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lepaqp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b9ae5be1149b0fbb739931_aqp1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="826795"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Low-End PC Studios has recently released their updated rendition of Rodríguez Ballón International Airport (SPQU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Arequipa, Peru’s second-largest city. With nearly 2 million passengers yearly, it’s the third busiest airport in the country.   It’s the main gateway to the Colca Canyon, among the deepest canyons in the world (3270 meters deep) and 70 kilometers in total length. The region had pre-Inca rooted folk, and many old towns founded during the Spanish colonial era, still inhabited to this day and with their ancestral traditions still going strong. The stepped terraces - their pre-Inca agricultural heritage - are still actively cultivated.   The airport is a hub for JetSmart Perú, with domestic legs to Cuzco, Lima, Piura, and Trujillo, also regularly visited by JetSmart Chile (Santiago de Chile), LATAM Perú (Cuzco, Lima), and Sky Airline Peru (Lima).  The scenery features default jetways, projected mesh for ground textures, PBR materials on some objects, a custom runway elevation profile, 3D objects, and two landmarks.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.80, requiring at least 545 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blgpoa</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Previews Salgado Filho International Airport Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blgpoa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63b9ebe0c156e97d3573a702_poa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="422329"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Brazil Land Games has recently teased the progress on the upcoming update for their Porto Alegre Salgado Filho International Airport (SBPA) scenery, serving the city of Porto Alegre in Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil. It is the ninth busiest airport in the country, with nearly 8 million passengers yearly (pre-pandemic).  Originally called São João Federal Airport, it was just an air club, with its first flights dating back to 1923. It saw commercial action for the first time in 1932, when VARIG (the oldest Brazilian airline) replaced their seaplanes with land airplanes, adopting Porto Alegre as their hub. It took eight years for the commission of an actual passenger terminal. Its current name was adopted in 1952, after Joaquim Pedro Salgado Filho, a local politician who had died a year prior (air crash).  It’s a focus city for Azul Brazilian Airlines, with a significant domestic network (fifteen destinations) and international legs to Punta del Este and Montevideo (Uruguay). The other two Brazilian giants, GOL Linhas Aéreas (thirteen domestic destinations) and LATAM Brasil (5 domestic destinations), are also regularly seen around POA. TAP Air Portugal is the sole European visitor, coming from Lisbon.  Not much was said other than the pictures themselves and the fact it’s still undergoing development. Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simnak</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Sakon Nakhon Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simnak" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63bb5646c3ef98e90dc4df99_vtui1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3669503"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Sakon Nakhon Airport (VTUI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a civil-military airport serving the city of Sakon Nakhon in Thailand. It’s visited by Nok Air and Thai AirAsia with flights to Bangkok (Don Mueang).  The airport was established in the 1970s as a small, regional airport serving the local area. In the 1980s, the airport underwent a Major expansion and upgrade, which included the construction of a new terminal building and the lengthening of the runway to accommodate larger aircraft. In the 1990s, the airport was further expanded to accommodate an increase in passenger traffic. Today, Sakon Nakhon Airport is an important transportation hub for the region, and it is used by both domestic and international travelers.  The scenery features a custom 3D model of the airport terminal with its interior, realistic taxiways and parking positions, true-to-life apron markings, custom runway with accurate markings, and taxiway lights.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.45, requiring at least 1 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42flu</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Updates Flow for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42flu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63a17e9f6a09671055752c6a_flwbig2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="496765"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently released an update to Flow, their customizable interface for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding new features requested by the Community, and a fix for an issue brought by the latest MSFS beta update.  They have listed five key features added with the new update, which are:   ‍  In addition to the updates included in this release, Parallel 42 has also added several APIs for script creators, allowing them to access and customize a range of features in Flow. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ NEW ‍ ‍ IMPROVED ‍ ‍ FIXED ‍ ‍ Overall, the update to Flow aims at improving the user experience, and the company is confident that the tool will continue to evolve and improve with the input and creations of their community.  Parallel 42’s Flow is available on Orbx Direct, requiring at least 10.26 MB of free disk space to install. Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilh3</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases London Heathrow Airport V3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilh3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63bdf5022b7a8bd57f6d035f_v31-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1535098"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their updated rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding new features and improving the overall performance within the simulator.   London Heathrow is the eight-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 80 million passengers, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprehending international travel, and the remaining 6% is strictly domestic. It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within the United Kingdom and all over the world, with more legs set to begin in mid-2023.  The V3 update adds features such as parallax interiors to all terminals, a groundpoly overhaul, an ATC tower interior, clutter on the ATC tower roof, static people added to some terminals, additional model details added to stillages and substations, barless tugs and belt loaders updated with new models, new marking details around all terminals, and the addition of airport-wide optimization and lodding. The complete changelog follows down below:  ‍ ‍ The update is available right now on iniManager to all current owners. New owners can find the scenery on the iniBuilds Store with a 30% discount (until 17.01.23) at roughly $15.34, requiring at least 5.67 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpber</id>
    <title>RDPresets Updates Bergen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpber" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63bdfab7ea5503823ad5ad3e_ber1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="991128"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently released an update to their rendition of Bergen Flesland Airport (ENBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including improvements and bug fixes. The additions include animated jetways on both terminals, parallax on buildings, an animated tram on the new terminal, an animated helicopter, and more.   Bergen Flesland Airport is the second busiest airport in Norway, with a yearly average of 6 million passengers. It features a wide intra-European route network, by the wings of Scandinavian Airlines, Wideroe, Norwegian Air Shuttle (all from Scandinavia), and several visitors from around Europe such as Air France, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, and WizzAir.   Along with the new additions to the scenery, RDPresets has also changed the runway slope, removed cruise ships, and fixed the jetway colors on the old terminal. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ ‍ It’s available on the RDPresets Store for roughly $21.47 or on SimMarket for $19.00, requiring at least 1 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/t320ne</id>
    <title> ToLiss Announces A320 NEO as the Next Product for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/t320ne" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63be502dbcbd79129dfe824c_Screenshot%202023-01-11%20at%2012.59.06%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="640273"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, developer ToLiss announced the A320 NEO as their next product for X-Plane. The aircraft will mark yet another addition to the already impressive ToLiss Airbus fleet that includes the A319, A321, and A340. ‍ From the teaser picture that accompanied the announcement, it can be seen that the exterior modeling of the aircraft has already been completed, including the brand new engines that distinguishes the NEO from the other A320 variants.  ToLiss has only released limited information regarding the NEO. Therefore, it is unclear whether the A320 NEO will receive a cockpit completely modeled from the ground up or one that’s derived from that of the A321 and A319. It is also not known if Tolise’s NEO will feature both the CFM Leap and the PW1000G engine options. ‍ Currently, a firm release date is yet to be disclosed but the A320 is expected to come out sometime in March of this year. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/acspar</id>
    <title>AC Scenery Releases Pardubice Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/acspar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63bedf2fba56ff753f7c2747_pardu1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1905290"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AC Scenery has recently released their rendition of Pardubice Airport (LKPD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a civil-military international airport serving the city of Pardubice in Czech Republic. It’s the fourth busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 140 thousand passengers.   The airport sees most of its commercial traffic during the summer season, when Ryanair and Smartwings offer four destinations in total. Military traffic makes up most of the year-long traffic, with a NATO A332 constantly visiting from Eindhoven in the Netherlands.   Pardubice got a new terminal and apron expansion in 2017, increasing its passenger capacity and handling larger aircraft such as the Airbus A320 and the Boeing 737. It was named after Jan Kaspar, an icon of Czech aviation.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of Pardubice Airport, with orthoimagery around the whole area, optimized dynamic lighting, and performance friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.87, requiring at least 522 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aero10</id>
    <title>Aerobask Celebrates 10 Years of Innovative Flight Simulation Add-Ons</title>
    <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aero10" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63bf26415a30e2c380bf5a2f_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1179983"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerobask, a leading developer of aircraft add-ons for the popular flight sim platform X-Plane, is celebrating its 10th anniversary in the industry. In the last ten years, Aerobask has established a reputation for creating high-quality, accurate, and realistic aircraft models that have been widely praised by flight simulation enthusiasts. To mark the occasion, Aerobask will be releasing an all-new Diamond DA42 aircraft for X-Plane.  In a Forum post earlier today, a member of the Aerobask team revealed “ On this occasion, we are adding a brand new DA42 to our catalogue” followed by a video teaser promoting the team's 10th anniversary and the new DA42 aircraft.  ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cows42</id>
    <title>Experienced developers collaborate on ambitious DA42 project to advance flight simulation</title>
    <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cows42" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c01b0d807635a5cb4e424f_DA42-VI_-_2022-10-26_00.10.23_Original.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2409126"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The flight simulation community has seen the emergence of a new developer group, CreatorOfWorldS (COWS). The team has generated significant interest with their first product in production, the Diamond DA42 aircraft, a highly detailed and accurate replica of the aircraft. Early previews of the product have generated excitement among enthusiasts and professionals alike when shared on social media. Their first public appearance was under another name. We covered the quartet of developers "Simmy Aircraft" for their first debut in an earlier article. COWS has stated that their primary goal is to provide products that will aid in training and simulation opportunities for students and consumers. They have put a lot of effort into replicating the flight behaviour and systems through real aircraft testing and feedback. The development team comprises four members, one of which is Mitchell, who is in charge of creating the meticulously crafted 3D model of the plane. He had direct access to a DA42 throughout the development process, which means that everything about the model has been created based on manuals, pictures, first-hand experience, and a lot of passion for the project. Another team member, Jacob, is responsible for everything under the hood. He has carefully recreated the flight model, electrics, fuel, engine control units, and de-ice system based on the aircraft's manuals and first-hand experience flying the real-life counterparts. The flight model has been tuned to match performance tables accurately, and the result is so close to the real plane that it can be handled just as it would in the real world. Boris is in charge of creating the sounds for the aircraft. He is known for his work in the flight simulation community, being in charge of audio at FlyByWire, the FlightFX Vision Jet and having created sound packs for the Cirrus SR-22 in Microsoft Flight Simulator. To create realistic sounds for the COWS' DA42, Boris has recorded real aircraft sounds and incorporated them into the simulator to ensure a truly immersive user experience. With Peter at the helms of reason, administrative tasks, branding and 3D work assistance, the four members sum up the current team. The COWS DA42 is equipped with a fully custom Garmin G1000NXi avionics system. This system has been created using a combination of manuals, first-hand experience, and Garmin software in order to make it as accurate as possible to the real-world version of the system. The system includes simulation of many of the features of the real Garmin, such as the GPS satellite constellation, profile saving and copying, persistent settings, and system statuses. The system also includes simulations of other systems, such as the PFD, AHRS, ADC, GTX335R, and GMU. Currently, the only features that remain to be added to the simulation are custom flight planning with custom LNAV/VNAV and maps. The system also has the capability to remember user settings. It allows for per-livery, and per-aircraft configurations, giving users the ability to customise their avionics package to their preferences.  The video is a demonstration of the fully custom G1000NXi from COWS own press release. ‍ ‍ The development is still ongoing, and the team is working hard to bring the DA42s to the flight simulation community. No timeline is given, but they are dedicated to ensuring no stone is left unturned and bringing the best DA42s they can offer their users. However, as the team put it, it will take them a little more time to finish everything and ensure everything is perfect. In their press release, COWS mention that their next project will be the DA40-180 XLS, after their DA42 series.  To follow their progress, you can join their discord.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jff100</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes First Fokker 70 &amp; 100 Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jff100" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c0a13f264b5f15d518ee71_f100-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="649302"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently published the first development update on the Fokker 70 &amp;  100 project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, announced last year. It’s composed of some information on the current state of things and fourteen screenshots.   Their Fokker 100’s cockpit, exterior models, and textures are undergoing extensive testing, with dynamic lighting in the cockpit and externally being the latest addition. Work is yet to begin on the 70 variant and a detailed passenger cabin for both. Just Flight plans to keep everyone updated with further development updates.   The product will feature (once finished) native models with 4K and 8K textures, realistic animations including dynamic wing-flex, all doors (including cargo), lift-dumpers, and the tail-mounted airbrake. The cockpit will feature hundreds of functional switches, knobs, controls, and high-resolution displays, driven by complex custom-coded systems based on real-world FCOMs, including hydraulic, electrical, fuel, pressurization, and a custom navigation system with an FMS.   The Fokker 70 &amp; 100 are twin-turbofan regional aircraft, developed by the Dutch aircraft manufacturer Fokker. The Fokker 70 is a shorter version of the 100, seating up to 86 passengers. The F100 variant can fit up to 110 passengers. They were introduced in the late 1980s and early 1990s, rapidly gaining popularity among regional airlines due to their cost-effectiveness and reliability. However, due to financial difficulties, Fokker went bankrupt in 1996, with a permanent halting of the production line. Despite it all, there are many F70s and F100s around to this day, especially in Australia.  There’s no information regarding the price or release date yet. Stay tuned to Threshold for more information on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerda4</id>
    <title>Aerobask Releases the Diamond DA42 NG for X-Plane 12 </title>
    <updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerda4" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c30f4f65a10a0513f01ce3_thumbnail%20(3).jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="28228"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. To celebrate their ten-year anniversary, X-Plane aircraft developer, Aerobask, has released the DA42 NG for X-Plane 12. This release comes ten years after their first-ever payware release, the DA42, in 2013. The release of the DA42 NG comes just after their ViperJet, which was released in September of 2022. The aircraft adds to Aerobasks' ever-growing list of Diamond aircraft, with the developer previously having released the Diamond DA50 and DA62 for X-Plane. As is expected with Aerobask products nowadays, the DA42 NG comes with a host of custom systems, such as synthetic vision, a simulated oxygen system, fully functional breakers, and much more. A complete feature list is viewable below. Feature List: Aerobask Systems Suite Advanced Flight Model and Flight Experience Superb 3D Model Custom Sounds Other features and docs Auto-Updater For those looking to purchase the aircraft, Aerobasks’ rendition of the Diamond DA42 NG is available on the X-Plane.org Store for $39.95. A trailer for the aircraft was also made available via the developer’s YouTube Channel, where the DA42 NG can be seen in action.</summary>
    <published>2023-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stsegi</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Egilsstadir Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stsegi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c343b07151358eecb9b697_egil1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="616381"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations has recently released their rendition of Egilsstadir Airport (BIEG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-runway international airport serving the city of Egilsstadir in Iceland, owned by Isavia. With a yearly average of 100000 passengers, it’s one of the busiest airports in the country.   It’s currently served by Icelandair with daily flights to Reykjavik on a DH8B, totaling up to 17 flights a week. It’s the only commercial airline that operates in Egilsstadir as of 2022.  Built in the 1940s as a USAF base, it was repurposed into a civilian airport after the war, with several expansions in the following decades to accommodate larger aircraft and higher passenger numbers. Today, it’s a hub for regional air travel and a popular tourist destination in the eastern part of Iceland. It’s used as a diversion airport for flights originally headed to Keflavik, the busiest airport in Iceland.  The scenery features an accurate replica of the terminal, with custom hangars and buildings, typical Icelandic houses, the Fellabaer Bridge, realistic markings on the runway, apron and taxiways, custom objects and environment details, and high-detail textures with PBR.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.80, requiring at least 221 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffaxwb</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases New A350 Beta Update for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffaxwb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c37858aabe58274adca310_a350-2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="303520"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently updated their A350 beta branch to version 1.7.02, fixing a sim crash on replay, the reverser animation, and graphical bugs on X-Plane 12.  The FlightFactor A350 XWB Advanced provides realism in its depiction of the Airbus A350, featuring a highly detailed virtual cockpit, ground equipment, an advanced systems simulation with SIDs and STARS, customizable failures, and a fully integrated Airbus electronic checklist system. The ECAM monitoring system is fully customized, and the fly-by-wire simulation includes a realistic implementation of normal laws. All Airbus autopilot modes are included, except for a few non-precision approach modes, and the option for independent autopilots is also available. Additionally, it features a custom 3D stereo engine sound system and an interactive flight attendant helper.  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $64.95, requiring at least 800 MB of free disk space to install. Shout out to Poptart in our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxbr</id>
    <title>ORBX Release Landmarks Brisbane For XP12</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxbr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c3fd3e668c5b7c461a89a7_3.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3271922"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ORBX, a leading developer of flight simulation software, has announced the release of "Landmarks Brisbane" for X-Plane 12. This highly detailed add-on package brings the Australian city of Brisbane to life in stunning realism, allowing virtual pilots to explore the city's landmarks and iconic locations in incredible detail. The package features highly detailed models of over 100 of Brisbane's most famous buildings and landmarks, including the Story Bridge, the Wheel of Brisbane, and the Queensland Cultural Centre. Additionally, the package includes high-resolution textures, custom-designed autogen, and accurate night lighting, all of which combine to create a truly immersive flying experience. According to ORBX, the package has been developed using the latest in 3D modelling and texturing techniques, ensuring that the city of Brisbane is depicted as accurately and realistically as possible. The package also includes a range of custom-designed Heliports. The package is now available for purchase on ORBX's website and is compatible with X-Plane 12. Virtual pilots can purchase the package for AUD$19.34 ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
