<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-03-18T18:33:01.141201+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/m24mar</id>
    <title>Microsoft Rolls Out Marketplace for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/m24mar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d07d293d738725a21c989f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Not long after the release of Sim Update 1, the team at Microsoft has launched the in-sim Marketplace for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This Marketplace has been highly anticipated by the community and is now accessible within the simulator. Many items from the Marketplace in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 have been ported to the new simulator. These items should be available in the library and need to be activated. However, content created by Microsoft and Asobo is automatically activated. The Marketplace offers a variety of options. Ported content from the 2020 version to 2024 is marked with a small logo indicating that it is ported. Content upgraded to the 2024 version may have a new price or be available as a free upgrade, and it is also indicated with a logo showing that it has been upgraded. Users can purchase content using Simverse Coins, which is an in-sim currency that can be bought either in the Marketplace or at select retailers. Currently, the Marketplace does not support rentals or gifting, but these features are expected to be introduced with Sim Update 2 in April. Additionally, there are a few known issues with the Marketplace. For the full release notes and details on these issues, please check the official release announcement. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfxix</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases World Update XIX for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfxix"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d081b40d6ccf1f34811fdc_xix1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft recently released a new World Update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which enhances half the landmass of South America with detailed coverage of Brazil, Guyana, Suriname, and French Guiana.  They partnered with Bing Maps, Maxar, and Vexcel to craft the update, which features sights ranging from vast dune fields to bustling metropolises. Fusing several types of recent geospatial data, including aerial photographs, satellite imagery, DEM (digital elevation model) data, and DTM (digital terrain model), they managed to concoct a very realistic rendition in real-time. It captures 75 Points of Interest in total, including Fort Diamant in French Guiana, Monte Roraima in Guyana and Brazil, and Brazil’s Christ the Redeemer statue in Rio de Janeiro. It also includes four TIN cities, all in Brazil: Brasilia, Ouro Preto, Rio de Janeiro, and Sao Paulo.  Gaya Simulations – one of their partners – crafted seven airports: Foz do Iguaçu International Airport (SBFI), Fernando de Noronha Airport (SBFN), Santos Dumont (SBRJ), and Santarem - Maestro Wilson Fonseca International Airport (SBSN); Guyana’s Kaieteur International Airport (SYKA), Suriname’s Zorg en Hoop Airport (SMZO), and French Guiana’s Saint-Laurent-du-Maroni Airport (SOOM). The update also includes three discovery flights, three landing challenges, and three bush trips.  New MSFS 2024-only content will be added on March 17th, including a helicopter landing challenge at Mirante Dona Marta (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil), a rally race through Rio in an F/A-18, and a low-altitude challenge in an L-39 through the Serra do Corvo Branco, a rugged mountain range in southern Brazil. The update is free for all Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 owners. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/halzhu</id>
    <title>HALUA6683 Releases Zhuhai Jinwan Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/halzhu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d08af596da9f2a04b8a36a_zhu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. HALUA6683 recently released their updated rendition of Zhuhai Jinwan Airport (ZGSD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves Zhuhai, Guangdong, China, and has a yearly average of 11.4 million passengers. Construction work started in December 1992, and it opened three years later in 1995. It went on to host China’s first International Aviation and Aerospace Exhibition in 1996, which it still does to this date. The airport was expanded in 2017 to accommodate the predicted passenger figures, gaining an expanded eastern corridor, two new floors on the terminal, and a western VIP lounge, totaling over 122,000 square meters of area. It’s a focus city for China Southern Airlines and served by Air China, Air Guilin, Chengdu Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China United Airlines, Donghai Airlines, Juneyao Air, Loong Air, Lucky Air, Shandong Airlines, Shanghai Airlines, Shenzhen Airlines, Sichuan Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tianjin Airlines, West Air, and Xiamen Air. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a highly detailed replica of the terminals, custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, custom objects, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.22, requiring at least 304.37 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asoemb</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator and Embraer Announce Partnership</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asoemb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d0a325e2695cc0b421150b_embraer.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. In conjunction with their newly released World Update XIX: Brazil, Suriname, Guyana, and French Guiana, the Microsoft Flight Simulator team is happy to announce a strategic partnership with Embraer, one of the largest aircraft manufacturers in the world. ‍ "We are thrilled to announce our partnership with Embraer, one of the global aerospace industry leaders," said Jorg Neumann, Microsoft Flight Simulator's lead developer. "Embraer's latest generation fleet and their innovation-driven focus make them a perfect partner for Microsoft Flight Simulator, and our objective is to bring many Embraer aircraft over to the simulator as part of our Expert Series. We are happy to announce that we are starting this collaboration with the widely popular Embraer Praetor 600, which will be released in MSFS sometime this year", he added. ‍ "We are thrilled to share the Praetor 600 with the Microsoft Flight Simulator community.  The most innovative executive jet from the Super Midsize category and the most technologically advanced in the world", said Embraer's Marketing Director, Felipe Alfaia, to which he added, "It's a pleasure to see our industry-leading jet landing on the most popular consumer flight simulator of the world near the end of 2025".  ‍ The Praetor 600 is a super-midsize jet with the biggest range in the world so far, being able to fly from London to New York or Sao Paulo to Miami. Aside from the superb range, it also brings full fly-by-wire, a highly advanced avionics suite, and an insane degree of connectivity, making it one of the most technologically advanced airplanes in its class. Its interior fully uses the cabin's dimensions, ensuring no space is wasted with six foldable seats, custom tiles, and a vacuum-operated lavatory system. ‍ Furthermore, the Praetor 600 also brings a turbulence reduction system, a highly silent cabin, a large cargo capacity for baggage, and a comprehensively sized wardrobe in the rear bathroom. ‍ There is no further information regarding pricing or features, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozale</id>
    <title>Moza Teases Launch Event for Flight Sim and Sim Racing Products </title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozale"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d0ab27e4875ca5bdeec471_2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Moza has recently announced the launch of their next-generation lineup of products for both flight simulation and sim racing, scheduled for March 18th at 9 AM EDT. They emphasized that this is an event you won't want to miss. Originally known for their sim racing equipment, Moza has expanded into the flight simulation hardware market. They now offer a variety of products, including a force feedback base, which our very own Magnus had the chance to review last year. The announcement included an image that appears to depict an airliner alongside what looks like a Formula-style car. Moza has described this launch as a groundbreaking moment, and we are eager to see what they have in store. We will keep you updated as soon as we have more information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/meri25</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Announces Brand; Product Announcement</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/meri25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d1913052f024653fd52772_meridian%20banner.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The world of flight simulation hardware welcomes a significant new player today - Meridian GMT. At the helm is Nicki Repenning, a name long familiar to the simulation community through his former role as founder and public face of Honeycomb Aeronautical. While Repenning’s earlier work helped establish some of the most widely adopted peripherals in the sector, Meridian GMT is attempting a distinct break from the past - a clean-slate approach grounded in new principles, or rather, on their terms. Repenning played a central role in bringing to life the Honeycomb Alpha Flight Controls, Bravo Throttle Quadrant, and Charlie Rudder Pedals - devices that saw widespread acclaim for their feature set and accessibility. However, Honeycomb’s legacy is not without complications. Despite its disruptive design, price point, and popularity, the Bravo Throttle faced recurring quality concerns, such as cable issues and mechanical wear, which were highlighted in long-term user experiences. Furthermore, the very protracted delivery timeline for the Charlie Rudder Pedals and the outright conflict between Repenning and his former business partner Mike Steup from Snakebyte Group, a German product development company, over the ownership and direction of Honeycomb, left a permanent mark on the brand’s reputation. That conflict was central to the community's growing distrust towards Repenning and the Honeycomb name. These challenges were not unnoticed. Community discourse and critical media coverage, including our own reporting at Threshold, explored the implications of Honeycomb’s faltering transparency and logistical setbacks. Our piece "Into the Hive: Updates on Honeycomb's Journey", we provided a deep dive into the frustrations voiced by customers and the broader lessons for hardware developers in the flight sim industry. It should be noted that while Honeycomb eventually fulfilled the Charlie pre-orders, the extended wait, poor support, and surrounding controversy left the brand tainted in the eyes of many. Today, however, marks a turning point. Meridian GMT positions itself not as a continuation of Honeycomb but as a new venture with its own values, structure, and trajectory. While Repenning’s experience is undeniable, Meridian is shaped by a conscious intent to move beyond prior missteps. A more modular design philosophy, increased repairability, a tighter internal team, and strategic outsourcing of non-core competencies reflect this new direction. The company’s first product presentation will take place this coming weekend. Repenning will take the stage at FSWeekend and reveal three hardware products that aim to set new standards across their respective categories. Until then, the full product lineup remains under wraps. As stated in Meridian GMT’s official press release today on their website. "Meridian GMT is more than just a brand; it's a commitment to the flight simulation community", said Repenning. “Our core values - innovation, precision, durability, and affordability - are at the heart of everything we do. Our mission is to deliver hardware that not only exceeds the expectations of the community but also makes products for the casual flight simmer, embarking on their first solo flight, and bring immersion and fun to their experience too". The brand’s identity is also symbolically constructed. Meridian says the logo reflects its mission: three diamonds representing Community, Industry Partnerships, and Innovation, set within a golden hexagon signifying Legacy. The inverted Y in the logo nods to aviation roots, with a subtle aircraft silhouette formed by the space between the diamonds. While the past casts a long shadow, Meridian GMT is determined to navigate new horizons - without relying on nostalgia or name recognition to carry its message.  Instead, they hope to enter the market with clear eyes, tempered expectations, and a commitment to better serve the simulation community. The brand’s story begins here—and what follows will be watched with interest. </summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350103</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350103"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d1d3360d1288fc525c3463_v103NowAvailSocials.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently rolled out a new update to their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, aiming to mitigate WASM crash issues and aid overall stability. Update 1.0.3 focuses on making the product more stable and less vulnerable to WASM crashes that have plagued the product since its release, sparking a lot of controversy around many online flight sim communities. They have discovered that the update rates between third-party services and the A350’s systems sometimes don’t align, inducing issues, and specific data exchanges may cause unexpected increases in memory usage, leading to potential crashes.  To further illustrate what has been going on with their A350, iniBuilds decided to provide an in-depth explanation of how the WASM system works and why it may, at times, stop working: it needs memory to run the avionics, custom systems, and other third-party add-ons, which isn’t random access memory, but its very own virtual memory running separately inside the simulator, which is allocated according to the demand, and allocation issues may happen, leading to a WASM crash (that either entirely kills the simulator or freezes the airplane’s system). They have switched their method of handling that by going from manually managing memory to smart pointers, which helps prevent memory leaks and automatically handles freeing up memory when it’s no longer needed. Furthermore, they have taken steps to avoid using unnecessary copy constructors, which lead to high memory usage and performance issues.  iniBuilds has also implemented a delay to third-party data requests. Previously, they requested data at 30 fps, which overwhelmed the WASM environment. Now, it only polls it once every second, reducing the memory and processing overhead. The expected benefits of the above measures are fewer crashes due to bad memory management, more efficient memory use in the WASM environment, and better performance and smoothness.  The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/midx12</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Chicago Midway International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/midx12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d1dc724732690bcb80c4de_chi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Drzewiecki Design recently released their rendition of Chicago Midway International Airport (KMDW) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Chicago Metropolitan Area and has a yearly average of 22 million passengers. Established in 1927, Midway was Chicago’s main airport until the advent of O’Hare International in 1944. This did not stop it from being one of the busiest airports in the nation.  It is an operating base for Frontier Airlines and Southwest Airlines. Allegiant Air, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Porter Airlines, and Volaris also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-quality 3D models, PBR materials, custom animated jetways, VDGS, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.64, requiring at least 1.73 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f28two</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases F28 Professional V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f28two"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324880615470b16ee888a_fuk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently released the Fokker F28 Professional Version 2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This version brings many significant upgrades over the first version, such as a new flight management system (UNS-1), new cockpit equipment, boarding/refueling simulation, and more. The Fokker F28 Fellowship is a twin-engined regional jet developed in the late 60s. Its first flight was in 1967 and its introduction happened in 1969, with 241 units built after a 20-year run (production ended in 1987). Multiple variants were developed, with the F28-1000 seating up to 70 passengers, the F28-2000 housing 79 people, and the later revision, the F28-4000, featuring quieter engines (Rolls-Royce Spey 555-15H), a redesigned cockpit and modified wings, and increased seating (up to 85 passengers). It was then superseded by the Fokker 70 and 100.  As of 2019, there are no current operators of the F28 around, with Fly-SAX being the last to operate it commercially. Garuda Indonesia was the largest former operator, with 62 of them. Other Major operators include the Ansett Group (13), AirQuarius Aviation (4), and Biman Bangladesh Airlines (4). The Ansett Group was also responsible for the longest nonstop F28 route in the world, between Perth and Kununurra, roughly 2300 km apart.  Version two of the F28 ensures compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. It adds many new features to the product, further enriching its realism, such as the new UNS-1 flight management system, new cockpit equipment, boarding and refueling simulation, and more. Please refer to this page for further information on all the features included.  It’s available in their store for $50.39 (a promotional price to celebrate the new update). V1 owners are entitled to a free upgrade. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atekos</id>
    <title>Atelic Releases Kos International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atekos"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d4a1380e553fb3265e9e27_kos1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Atelic has recently released their rendition of Kos International Airport (LGKO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Kos Island, Greece, and has a yearly average of 2.8 million passengers. It opened in early 1964, and the first expansion work was carried out within a decade, bringing the runway to 2,400m and thus enabling it to accommodate larger jet aircraft. The ever-increasing passenger traffic figures led to the construction of a new passenger terminal in 1980, which underwent renovation and expansion seventeen years later. Upon winning the airport’s concession in late 2015, Fraport was heavily committed to improving the infrastructure through heavy maintenance and upgrades and ensuring it was within the safety regulations. It’s a focus airport for Aegean Airlines and seasonally served by Aer Lingus, airBaltic, Air Serbia, Austrian Airways, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Condor, Discover Airlines, easyJet, Enter Air, Eurowings, Lufthansa, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Smartwings, Swiss, Transavia, TUI (multiple), and Wizz Air. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality PBR textures, realistic night lighting, an up-to-date ground layout, detailed terminal and tower interiors, realistic terrain profile, custom vegetation, custom roads, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.32, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsw251</id>
    <title>FSWeekend 2025 Day 1 Roundup</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsw251"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f763c683db81aefe3e38ca_DSC00657.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. It was quite the day in Lelystad, Netherlands, today, with FSWeekend kicking off a jam-packed weekend of announcements, presentations, and more flight sim news. Saturday saw five hours of presentations, and we’re here to round today’s big announcements up for you right in one place! Threshold is also on the ground, covering the event in person, so if you see any of us around, feel free to say hi and chat! ‍ First up was Sayintentions.ai, CEO Brian Shellabarger making three big announcements regarding their AI ATC add-on: AI Living World, OpenSky Beta, and SkyNet. AI Living World is Sayintentions’ new traffic injection and sequencing feature, connecting AI traffic to their existing AI ATC. According to Shellabarger, each injected aircraft is an individual AI entity, following real-world schedules, with the AI ATC sequencing every aircraft according to actual weather conditions. AI Living World is set to launch for partner customers on April 15 for MSFS 2020 and 24, with X-Plane support coming later this year. SkyNet, Sayintentions’ basic AI ATC service currently in closed beta, is now free. It will boast features such as premium neural voices, authentic phraseology, radio chatter, and more, all fully cloud-based. However, the service will be ATC only, limited to IFR gate-to-gate operations with little flexibility. Wrapping up their presentation was the announcement of the release of SkyNet, which is now available to all Sayintentions.ai customers for MSFS 2020 and 24. SkyNet is a real-time multiplayer network featuring model matching, cross-platform support, and the ability to create/join private groups. It will be available for the whole community early this summer, with AI sequencing and X-Plane support planned for the future. Navigraph was next, having announced a new feature for their popular Charts software called Scratchpads. Scratchpads will give users templates to write notes, such as ATIS, CRAFT clearances, and takeoff performance. No exact release date has been provided, but Navigraph CEO Magnus Axholt says it will come “very soon”. Swiss developers FlightSim Studio have announced the 727 Passenger for MSFS 2020, coming next month in April 2025. It features a fully modelled cabin and more. Along with that, they announced the Super 27 Expansion, which includes more powerful JT8D-217 or JT8D-219 engines and a modern avionics package with a new autopilot, FMS, EFIS, GPS, and more. According to FSS, the Super 27 Expansion will come later this year. FSS also announced progress for their E-Jets series for MSFS, which will soon include a new MCDU with support for custom nav data importing, performance improvements, new MFD modes, weather radar, enhanced LNAV, and more. However, FSS did not mention a release date for this update. Finally, there was WinWing, who announced a slew of new hardware products. On the roadmap for 2025 are additions to the Ursa Minor lineup, the MIP series, and the new Cyber Taurus joystick bases. The very popular Ursa Minor lineup will be getting an Airbus A320-style throttle quadrant and pedestal controls, priced at $127.95 and $107.95 respectively, will boast metal construction and detents, authentic backlighting, and the ability to switch between detent and detentless modes with one button. Following their highly successful MIP panel releases, WinWing announced the MIP Airline PAP 3 Panel, this time styled after the Boeing 737 MCP, which will feature full backlighting, realistic knobs, and more, for $149.95. The PAP 3 Panel can be upgraded with the MIP MAG Switch, a magnetic switch for the autothrottle function, which will be available for purchase either separately for $49.95 or pre-installed to the PAP 3 panel for $199.99. Along with the PAP 3 Panel will be the MIP Airline PDC 3N Panel, modelled after the 737 EFIS Panel, and will be available for $84.95. Concluding the MIP series additions is the MIP Combat 13 CNI-MU Panel, styled like the 737 FMC, but with combat-focused functions, priced at $129.95. Lastly, WinWing announced additions to the Cyber Taurus series, with three new joystick bases and a rudder pedal set, all being force-feedback driven. The base tier Cyber Taurus joystick base will include electronic load control, belt-driven construction, and a rated output of more than 20 NM, priced at $414.95. The higher tier, the Cyber Taurus (D) joystick base, will have two versions: a gear-reduced model and a direct drive model. The gear-reduced model will have a rated output of more than 60 NM, and the direct drive model will have a rated output of more than 16 NM. Both will be available for $699.95. Closing out their presentation, they showcased the Cyber Taurus Electronic Load Control Rudder Pedals, which will have a rated output of more than 170 NM, and a pricetag of $799.95. ‍ That closes a very packed day at Europe’s largest flight simulation convention! But there’s still another day, so stay tuned to Threshold for coverage of Day 2! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcfswa</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Aeronautical Announces Four New Products</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcfswa"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d6b3d94ea99fe5393dbb07_Flight_Path_2025_All_products_Runway_1_54aa1021-ce9d-4950-8258-975801eb9927.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Starting off the announcements today at FSWeekend, Honeycomb Aeronautical announced four new products. These new products come in two different ranges, the Flagship range, and the all new Lite range.  Firstly, they announced the Sierra TPM module. Following on the success of the Bravo Throttle Quadrant, the Sierra TPM module focuses on general aviation, with Cessna-style knobs instead of levers. Along with the knobs, it will come with an integrated trim wheel, parking brake, flap, and gear controls. Once available, the Sierra TPM will be priced at $249.99. Next, Honeycomb announced their entry into the joystick market with the Foxtrot Aviation Stick. Honeycomb previously had announced a similar stick in 2020, but that was back before their management debacle. This new Foxtrot stick will include a linear resistance system with adjustable tension, five two-way switches, four programmable action buttons, along with three rotary switches. However, unlike its previous iteration, the new Foxtrot Aviation Stick will not include an integrated gear lever or throttle lever. No pricing information has been released yet for the Foxtrot. Honeycomb then introduced their new Lite product lineup, featuring two new products, the Alpha Lite, and Bravo Lite. The Alpha Lite, like its more premium counterpart, features the same popular yoke design, but does not include the switch panel. When it becomes available for purchase, the Alpha Lite will be priced at $199.99. Finally, the Bravo Lite will feature four axes, an integrated trim wheel, interchangeable flap detents, and a parking brake control. It will be priced exactly the same as the Alpha Lite at $199.99 when available. Honeycomb says that all of these products will be available for purchase by Christmas this year. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mgfswa</id>
    <title>Meridian GMT Announces Initial Product Line</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mgfswa"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d6fd7ebbef2a2020524978_Screenshot%202025-03-16%20at%2010.31.54%E2%80%AFAM.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Meridian GMT announced its initial product line during today's final presentation at FSWeekend. Founded by Honeycomb Aeronautical founder and former CEO Nicki Repenning, Meridian GMT hopes to break into an increasingly competitive hardware market. ‍ Their initial lineup consists of three new products: The Sierra Plus Flight Controls, the Tango Plus Throttle Quadrant, and the X-Ray Flight Controller. Meridian’s focus for these products is a multi-purpose and modular approach. ‍ Repenning started the presentation by showcasing the Sierra Plus (not to be confused with the Honeycomb Sierra TPM), which he says includes many improvements over his previous designs, chiefly the Honeycomb Alpha. The Sierra Plus will boast features such as swappable button and switch panels, quick-release yoke, vibration motors, and under-table mounting. Multiple panel configurations will be available for the Sierra Plus, including a commercial configuration based on the Boeing 737 and a general aviation configuration complete with a chronometer. On release, the Sierra Plus will be priced at approximately $325 (€299.99). Next, Repenning moved to what he says is “the product that I am most excited about”, the Tango Plus Throttle Quadrant. Like the Sierra Plus, the Tango Plus builds on previous designs' success, adding modularity, among other features. Meridian has packed the Tango Plus with features, including an annunciator panel, trim wheel, exterior light switches, auto brake knob, and more. The flagship feature of the Tango Plus is the swappable avionics and throttle configurations. Users can customize their quadrant based on the type of aircraft they are flying, with Repenning mentioning configurations for single and multi-engine general aviation, as well as configs for Airbus and Boeing, which will include detents. The avionics receive the same treatment, the general aviation config receiving a Garmin-style radio and autopilot panel, the Boeing panel styled after the 737 MCP, and the Airbus panel made to represent the FCU. Meridian’s final product is the X-Ray Flight Controller, which Repenning says is “the product that will launch first into the market”. The X-Ray Flight Controller is Meridian’s answer to the increasingly popular console market, being an Xbox controller with various features specific to flight simulation. No pricing information has been announced for the Tango Plus or the X-Ray controller, but Threshold will keep you informed, so stay tuned! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350104</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350104"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d74ca627ae5eebe484b673_104.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing system depth improvements, art tweaks, and more. Update v1.0.4 aims to increase the systems simulation further, bringing extra depth and more overall fidelity. Following customer feedback and further investigation, the art was also tweaked on the long-winglet model for the A350-900, improving its shape and profile.  ini has also done extra optimization work for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 version by tweaking node counts and refining the system for swapping cockpits. These changes significantly reduce CPU load and bring smoother performance and fewer stutters, especially on lower-end systems. As the update changes the 3D model to some extent, all liveries will need to be redownloaded or updated to work with the new version in both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. They claim this was necessary to ensure the key fixes in the patch could be carried out at once. More WASM fixes were also introduced to enhance the product’s stability further, resolving multiple crashes related to TCAS activation, flight plan imports, and Navigraph integration.  The developers claim to remain dedicated to continuous improvement and deeper simulation accuracy, with ongoing refinements across all areas of the A350’s systems.  The complete changelog for the update follows below: v1.0.4Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️Fixed - WASM*** EFIS_Gauge_Update crash fixed Fixed - WASM*** Crash on CPNY F-PLN IMPORT after changing data source crash Fixed - WASM*** Exception c000005 in gauge SND on SB ImportFixed - 2020 ***WASM*** MFD exception while editing SEC planFixed – WASM - Repeatable WASM crash, closest airports&gt;DATAFixed- WASM - Exception in Gauge MFD – TCASFixed - Navigraph_FunctionResult WASM crash Fixed - Navigraph commbus/function WASM crashFixed - WASM crash when selecting FIX INFO and inserting runwayImprovement - Dynamic fuel temp simulation Fixed - HDG bar missing on the PFD in Raw DataFixed - Incorrect GD, S, F speeds in APPR page in some situations Fixed - Unable to DTO custom wptFixed - Insert to next waypoint causing navigraph function to dieFixed - NAV ACCUR UPGRADED should be white instead of amberFixed - SEC copy active did not copy the flight numberFixed - Incorrect landing weight being displayed in some situations Fixed - Changing approach (but not inserting it) clears the minima in some casesFixed - Able to have 2 menus open in FPLN pageFixed - THS trim "wheel" moving in opposite direction in some cases Fixed - Wind Data KNOT spd limit too smallFixed - Turning SPD knob while on managed speed issue bug Fixed - MFD Local Time issue bug Fixed - Swap active not carrying over the CRZ ALT bug Fixed - ENG SD COOLING text alignmentFixed - Incorrect colour coding in SEC plansFixed - MFD Cancel noise missing *Fixed - SD Page formatting - CAB V/SFixed - Unable to reselect SLSFixed - No STEP DELETED message bug Fixed - Step Alt persistence after climbing to new altFixed - HSP = too far right bug Fixed - Fuel over waypoints when LB selected shows T bugFixed -  TMPY UNDO* prompt bug Fixed - PFD Vls line issue bug Fixed - DESCENT SPD LIM and the respective SPD LIM vertical revision entry is missingFixed - Decel Point in F-PLAN - Does not activate approach mode/phaseFixed - FMA change box behaviourFixed - FIX INFO pge not fully clearing dataFixed - FMS F-PLN/AIRWAYS page - if you enter a wrong WPT, there is no way to "reset" the fieldFixed - LEG RNP visible in FPLN at the topFixed - SEC PLAN TMPY syncing with active plan on insert prior to swap Fixed - Wind Page CRZ waypoint logic doesn't match IRL Fixed - A/THR failure, thrust not lockedFixed - ARPTs being limitedFixed - Small zone in THR lever without FMA indicationFixed - Anti-skid logic incorrect -1000Fixed - EFOB on F-LPN being calculated in KG regardless of simbrief and aircraft being set to LBS.Fixed - Copy active SEC has magenta dotsFixed - Deleting STEP Climbs erases F-PLN in some cases Fixed - The SEC F-PLN PERF APPR GA Page does not consider the SEC F-PLN Destination.Fixed - bracket behind aircraft while in offset on max zoom in bug Fixed - Min DEST EFOB disappears after engine bug Fixed - Incorrect IGNITION memo during startFixed - PFD: Altitude indication issueFixed - PFD: altitude value not centered vertically Fixed - FUEL&amp;LOAD, extra on ground errorFixed - MFD CLB incorrect display when no noiseFixed - FO unable to capture alt constraint and not transferring to planFixed - CPLDC scroll HL missingFixed - Cannot select CSTR,ARPT + WPT/VORD/NDB at onceFixed - ENG FF value alignmentFixed - FO MFD changes automatically to GO AROUND pageFixed - GPWS 50 and 40 callouts play too earlyFixed - CPDLC cursor flash rate is too fastFixed - Trip wind not working in some cases Fixed - CPDLC normal messages should have a 10second aural delayFixed - Turnaround state, block fuel not clearedFixed - 2nd flight remembered noise values from 1stFixed - Polar: No SELECT TRUE NORTH REF msgFixed - No auto switch over to TRUEFixed - Step climb info crz page showing first step onlyFixed – RA faults bug Fixed – Extensive ECAMS review for double ECAMS bug Fixed - SUGT: Add sidestick AP on engage soundFixed - There are duplicate ECAM messages left and right side when the TO and LDG MEMO's are displayed.Fixed - ACFT STATUS page review model/engine formatFixed - All variable probes outside are at incorrect angles (and excessive)Fixed - Add limit to OFP Text size buttonsFixed - OFP page - Text size not saved bug Fixed - Landing Calculator using Live gross weight bug Fixed - OIS OFP page - add zoom feature bug Fixed - OIS TO Perf, MTOW perf needs to change depending on conditions/optionsFixed - OIS TO perf SYNC current WT not TOWFixed - OIS Maintenance: opening fueling panel and hyd refill panel opens door 1L in flightFixed - AFK mode to not be exclusive to time acceleration when option is onFixed - Can't use default ATC optionsFixed - [FS20] ENROUTE CHARTS BLACK / POSITION DESYNCFixed - FS20]  Report - Performance Degradation due to Enroute Map over long flights in VRImprovement – Interactive points reviewFixed - aircraft still getting airborne before Vr or with minimal inputFixed - ECAM Memo - Missing "SURV TCAS STBY" ECAM alertFixed - IR in align memo messageFixed -  Green/Yellow HYD fault ECAM issuesFixed - T.O INHIBIT memo disappears at rotationFixed - Excessive Hoppie/SayIntentions server loadFixed - The TO SHIFT field is not calculating when manually entering TORA and other valuesFixed - OIS OFP Page - Shortcuts not working properly if using format other than LIDO | WKGFixed – [FS20] UPDATE NAVDATA does not clear FMS same as swapping navdata sourcesFixed - SB profile taxi amount != FMS taxi fuel 3D Art 🎨🖌️Fixed - Long winglet model updated for -900 variant - We've listened to your concerns and concluded our investigations. The shape and profile of the long-winglet type featured on the A350-900 has been improved as per new technical and image reference data we been able to obtain.Fixed - Rain wiper mask added to windshields in FS24.Fixed - Various animation and alignment fixes on gear door mechanisms, hatches and panels.Fixed - FS20 click spot inaccuracy issues resolved - system for swapping cockpits between variants in FS20 changed to increase clickspot accuracy issues several users were experiencing.Fixed - FS24: Integral light difference in brightnessFixed - APU flap not animated Fixed - Split up cockpits/cbays between 900 and 1000 export FS2020Fixed - Bleed doors reflecting sunlight when in "IN" configFixed - FS24: Ice indicator light not workingFixed - FS24: Avionics bay lights not working (red/green flashing lights)Fixed - EFIS Mode and Range Selector lights are not tied to the ANN LT TEST SwitchFixed - FS24: Small see through gaps on inside of engine cowlingsFixed - FS24: No cabin variants lack physical windows from the interior - no rain drops on windowsFixed - FS20 performance improvements - node counts optimized and system for swapping cockpits in FS20 has been changed to be more optimal resulting in less of an impact for CPU-limited users. Users on lower end system specifications have noticed a decrease in stutters and smoother frame rates when this optimization was carried out. Sounds 🔊Fixed - no sound for evac selector switchFixed - no sound for evac horn off squibFixed - no sound for several smooth rotary knobsFixed - no sound for ecam checklist buttonsFixed - no sound on some isis buttons Fixed - no sound on engine man start buttonsFixed - no sound for baro selector Fixed - fms keys virtually inaudible Fixed - some duplicate manip sound events Fixed - Improved apu start/loop blending ‍ The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddssyd</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Announces Western Sydney International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddssyd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d75244a47f8ad7c024a98c_syd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design recently announced the development of Western Sydney International Airport (YSWS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport is set to begin operating in late 2026 and supplement Sydney’s Kingsford Smith International, which has been operating at capacity due to a legislated curfew. After a more than decade-long debate on the location, the government officially designated the site in April 2014. It was conceived to operate 24 hours a day, with no curfews whatsoever, helping mitigate the fact Sydney’s main airport is already operating at capacity and with limited slots. The administration has decided to build the airport in multiple phases, starting with a smaller terminal and a single runway and eventually building up as required. Phase one – which is nearing completion – consists of that one “small” terminal, able to handle up to 10 million passengers a year, and a single 3700m runway. As of June 2024, the terminal was 80% ready and set to reach total completion by January 2026. It’s going to be Australia’s first fully digital air traffic control system, using a 45-meter-tall mast with over twenty high-definition cameras instead of a traditional control tower. The developer plans to fully utilize Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s capabilities, aiming to deliver highly detailed visuals, optimized performance, and an immersive flight simulation experience. For that, they seek reference materials, including airport documentation, high-quality images, charts, blueprints, and operational insights. If you fit the criteria, feel free to contact the developer here.  There’s no information on pricing or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdsszc</id>
    <title>Papa Delta Studio Releases Szczecin-Goleniów Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdsszc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d9aa154505b7b8b1fce749_scz1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Papa Delta Studio recently released their rendition of Szczecin-Goleniów Airport (EPSC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Szczecin, Poland, and has a yearly average of 600,000 passengers. It was built as a standard military airport between 1953 and 1956 during the Cold War, with a 1,800-meter runway and basic infrastructure. It wasn’t until eleven years later that it became a civilian airport. In the late 1970s, the runway was extended to 2,500 meters, and a new passenger terminal was built. Extra effort was made in the late 1990s to improve the runway and the main apron, followed by the opening of a new passenger terminal in 2001.  Four years after its inauguration, the new terminal underwent expansion to accommodate the predicted passenger figures for the decade. Completion was achieved a year later, in 2006. LOT Polish Airlines, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Smartwings Poland, and Wizz Air serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-quality terminal model, custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, custom static aircraft, custom 3D people models, custom ground service equipment, custom clutter, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.31, requiring at least 87.55 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
