<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-03-11T18:32:36.426032+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsnuuk</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Nuuk International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsnuuk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c5ba3095aaccab33cf3340_19_476353f1-ba64-4aa7-83dc-2856bfcb2b5f_1600x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Originally built in 1979, the airport was part of a network the newly formed home rule government created to connect Greenland’s residents domestically. International flights from Nuuk Airport began in 1981 when Air Greenland introduced a route to Iqaluit, Canada. This service operated for 13 years before it was discontinued in 1994. It was briefly reinstated from 2012 to 2015 but was closed once again. In 2024, the route reopened as a summer service. The challenges faced by Nuuk Airport for international travel highlighted the need for a new and improved airport. The airport reopened in November of last year following an extensive transformation. It features a 2,200-meter runway as well as a new passenger terminal and control tower, making it one of Greenland’s largest construction projects. Nuuk is the main hub for Air Greenland, which operates a fleet of Dash 8 aircraft, an Airbus A330-800, a Beechcraft King Air, and various helicopters. In the coming months, United, SAS, and Icelandair will also operate into Greenland’s capital. The developer states that the scenery features meticulously crafted interior and exterior models, accurate lighting, signage, and layout. It also includes hand-made terrain around the airport, several points of interest in the city of Nuuk, and runway lighting and Navigation Aids modelled as per recent charts. It is available on the FSimStudios website, Contrail and Orbx for $14.99, requiring at least 2.79 GB to install. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for all of your flight simulation news!  ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon</summary>
    <published>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brisv2</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Brisbane Airport V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brisv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c603e0456d4da18a440513_binge1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently announced the development of a new Brisbane Airport (YBBN) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, which will significantly enhance the previous version.  It is the largest airport in Australia by land area and the third busiest in passenger traffic, with a yearly average of 23.2 million passengers. The airport’s construction started in 1980. Built by Leighton Contractors, it cost 400 million dollars and opened eight years later. It initially had a domestic terminal and two runways. Nearly a decade later, in September 1995, the international terminal was inaugurated, bringing in further passenger traffic. In 2007, the government approved the construction of a new parallel runway, which was expected to take eight years to build on swamp land 2 kilometers west of the terminal area. The unexpectedly long construction time was due to the settling period of the 13,000,000 cubic meters of sand gathered from Moreton Bay to cover the swamp. Work was completed in 2020, costing $1 billion and taking precisely eight years from start to finish. It’s a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia. Air Canada, Air Niugini, Alliance Airlines, American Airlines, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, EVA Air, Fiji Airways, FlyPelican, Jetstar, Korean Air, Link Airways, National Jet Express, Nauru Airlines, Philippine Airlines, Qantas, QantasLink, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Skytrans Airlines, Solomon Airlines, United Airlines, VietJet Air, and Virgin Australia also serve it. The new rendition features an up-to-date layout, a high-resolution orthophoto of the surroundings, improved landside detail, better ground polygons, realistic lighting, and enhanced airside clutter.  An upgrade path will be available for V1 owners to access all the new features.  There’s no release date and pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support us, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777200</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes Progress Update on Upcoming Products for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777200"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6680374cecbae34096a84c9f_1250410_20240628183738_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG recently published a new development update covering their progress on the upcoming 777-200ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the compatibility of the 77W and 77F with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and more. Randazzo begins with good news on the 777-200ER’s testing program’s process, which is said to be running well. They have spent most of this week ensuring the engine performance metrics are accurate, including EPR, N2, fuel flows, resulting thrust values, etc.  It has also been simultaneously tested in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with an MSFS 2020/2024 release in mind, all from a single purchase.  ‍ They have also confirmed it will come with over 30 liveries, which will be managed via the new operations center, which is set to be released shortly before the 777-200ER. They already have a set date on the calendar for the upcoming bird, but they want to clear a few things up before committing to a specific date. ‍ The 777-300ER and the 77F will also be updated in concurrency with the 777-200ER, including numerous fixes, adjustments, adaptations, and improvements.  ‍ PMDG has also been working on improving the sound environment with the help of some development partners (surely with the MSFS 2024 update in mind). ‍ As part of their commitment to the customers, the 77W/77F owners will receive the MSFS 2024 update for free. ‍ The PMDG DC-6, initially rather disastrous in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 due to laggy animations, has been mostly fixed, and they are working fast to get it out as soon as possible. Changes include lighting adjustments, surface tweaks, and more. ‍ Similarly, as with the 777 lineup, the DC-6 update will be free for current owners. ‍ The 737 is still being worked on, and they have not evaluated the effort thoroughly yet due to being busy with the 777 fleet and the DC-6, but the new cabin model is being merged in, and they are well underway with re-engineering the sound environment.  ‍ The MAX project is still on hold due to the need to maintain professional separation between retail simming work and work on enterprise-level projects. Once they are clear of that obligation, work will resume. ‍ Work on their 747 is also said to be coming along nicely. Systems integration for the flight engineer’s panel and sound sourcing from a real unit are their current priorities.   They have also started mapping out the behaviors that will be needed to give the user a reliable flight engineer and first officer, ensuring unparalleled ease of use for the more casual demographic while also allowing you to get no hand-holding whatsoever if so desired. ‍ In unusual fashion for PMDG, a few images of the landing gear—albeit without textures on—were also shared: PMDG anticipates it being their most visually detailed product yet, built from the ground up with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 in mind. Randazzo anticipated that this could potentially lead to questions regarding a potential MSFS 2020 availability, and the answer for now is “I don’t know.”  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mku78x</id>
    <title>Magknight 787: Aviator's Edition Updated to V1.11.5</title>
    <updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mku78x"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c6cb626d041ac1ee463202_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Magknight has released an update for the Magknight 787: Aviator's Edition, now at version V1.11.5. While the changelog is brief, this update introduces the final variant of the aircraft, the Boeing 787-10, to the add-on. Additionally, it includes several fixes. The most noticeable feature of the latest update is the introduction of the Boeing 787-10 variant, which is the longest version of the 787 series now available for virtual pilots. It’s important to note that the 787-10 is only compatible with X-Plane 12, whereas the 787-9 and 787-8 variants can be used with both X-Plane 12 and X-Plane 11. In addition to the new variant, the update includes improvements in pitch sensitivity and the FMA pitch limiter, as well as ensuring that the aileron lockout returns at high speed. The newly updated Magknight 787: Aviator's Edition is now available on X-Plane.Org Software Store for $44.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f70f1k</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Fokker 70/100 Development Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f70f1k"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c89321fa9e45fab494fead_fok1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight recently published a new development update for their upcoming Fokker 70/100 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which provides information on the overall status, new features, and more. They have been busy recently working on basic aircraft systems such as lift dumpers, airbrake, external and internal (flight deck) lighting, and polished LCD backlights.  Some time has also been spent on the more complex aircraft systems, mostly related to the EFIS (Electronic Flight Information System), which includes implementing the FWS (Flight Warning System), monitoring aircraft systems for both normal and abnormal situations, and displaying various memos, alerts, messages, and procedures on the MFDUs. The autopilot has undergone in-depth testing to ensure everything works across all areas of the envelope without throwing any surprises like a nose-dive into the ground.  With the systems starting to come together, they have stepped up the testing with the involvement of F100 pilots and engineers. Said process is said to take a while due to the inherently complex nature of a modern airliner. As the F100 systems reach maturity, they will soon turn their attention to the F70, which will require some changes to the cockpit panels and tweaks to the flight model to account for its shorter fuselage length, lower weight, and different engine performance. The next step—which is set to start next month—is integrating the sounds from Sim Acoustics. Their team “cannot wait” to get their hands on it and share footage of the new sounds in action when possible.  Just Flight will delve deeper into the systems when the time comes.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/727108</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studios Updates B727 to v1.0.8</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/727108"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c9ec32b84d4f45af442a5f_FSS-B727F-Official-Web-25.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightSim Studios has recently updated the B727 to version 1.0.8, which brings the new Sperry-150 Autopilot, reworked forward pedestal and the Flightplan clipboard. One of the biggest features of this update is the new Sperry-150 autopilot. Produced by the Sperry Flight Dynamics in the 1960s, this rather antique specimen of the autopilot system was capable of following simple tasks such as altitude hold, heading select, IAS/pitch hold, and approach modes. The developers have also included key bindings for the autopilot functions, allowing users to set up the controls to their liking. Another new feature is the update to the GNS-XLS, which now allows the manual entry of airways. The forward pedestal panel also has a new addition - a dummy weather and terrain radar screen. The first update of the year has also brought improved sounds and sound positioning, fuel system overhaul, and the Flightplan clipboard, where you can import your SimBrief flight-plan, and move it between the Flight Engineer station or the forward pedestal, right next to the navigational computer of your choice. The full changelog of bug fixes and new features can be found below:  ‍ Improvements: Features: The B727 Freighter can be purchased on the Aerosoft store or the Contrail for roughly $36.20 and requires at least 3.5GB of free disk space ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eddb24</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Updates Berlin Brandenburg Airport to Version V3</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eddb24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67c9fe40eda54c3ecd88e933_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has recently released an update for its rendition of Berlin Brandenburg Airport (EDDB), now available in version V3. This new version is exclusively for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, while the previous version, V2.3, can still be downloaded for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The update introduces a range of new features aimed at making the scenery as realistic as possible. The latest update takes full advantage of the 2024 simulator capabilities, featuring a completely remodeled terminal, new jetway models, and much more. See the full changelog below: ‍ Version 3.0 (MSFS 2024): The updated version of Berlin Brandenburg Airport is now available, and can be purchased from Aerosoft for $18.12. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo024</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Updates San Francisco International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ca27a25d89df6bdc0ab71b_amogus1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flightbeam Studios recently updated their rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO), ensuring compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 and introducing enhanced ground textures, performance-optimized assets, built-in native VDGS, and more. The update takes advantage of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024’s modern SDK to further improve their rendition of San Francisco International, now without barriers imposed by the previous platform’s limitations: it would enforce, for example, a default detail map on all aprons, which is no longer the case, allowing Flightbeam to further increase the quality on the ground textures with higher resolution samples, more oil stains, tire marks and gunk, accurately matching the real counterpart. Furthermore, every single asset in the scenery was re-optimized and re-exported for the best possible performance. It also brings a native VDGS system on A, B, E, and G gates, completely custom taxiway lights with correct runway entry/exit colors, diverse fauna and flora around the airport, and new scanned assets from their multiple visits to SFO in real life. The update is completely free for previous owners, and new purchasers can find it on Contrail for roughly $13.29 (promotional price), requiring at least 2.44 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/su1m24</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 1 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/su1m24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ca2f5c3abc46e6eee8d9a9_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has just released the first Sim Update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, Sim Update 1. This update has transitioned from beta to full release and is filled with various fixes and improvements aimed at enhancing the simulator further. The update prioritizes stability and performance, while also addressing general bug fixes and implementing changes across a variety of aircraft. Additionally, the Software Development Kit (SDK) has received numerous fixes, along with updates in several other areas of the simulator, making this a significant update. As with previous Sim Updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, the changelog is extensive, featuring numerous fixes, enhancements, and new features. For those interested, the full changelog is available here.  Moreover, the Microsoft team has announced that the highly anticipated Marketplace will be coming soon. They are currently making final adjustments to ensure it's readiness upon launch. Sim Update 1 is now available for download. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nv2024</id>
    <title>Navigraph Launches Community Survey 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nv2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cb46b8f96abf8d6d17e6cc_survey2024.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has just launched the seventh edition of their FlightSim Community Survey. The Survey asks various questions about preferred platforms, add-ons, use cases, preferences, etc. It provides great insight into the modern flight sim demographic, thus making it easier for the industry to understand what the simmers really want. Unusually, the Survey was delayed until early 2025 so Navigraph could more comprehensively and accurately capture the community's sentiment due to the large number of major releases near the end of last year. Averaging more than 20,000 respondents since the 2020 edition, the Survey has become the go-to reference for hardware metrics, given it differs massively compared to mainstream reference data such as the Steam Hardware Survey, which takes their entire user base into account. Focusing exclusively on flight simmers, it provides a more accurate image of the most popular hardware among virtual pilots.  It also sheds light on the most popular flight sim platform, intent (whether simulating just for fun or training for a pilot's license), simulation proficiency, and how many of us are real-life pilots.  The Survey will run for ten days starting today (March 7), and the results will be published shortly after. It is entirely GDPR compliant and fully anonymous, with no personally identifiable data being collected and no redirects.  Click here to participate in the world's most comprehensive flight simulation survey! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhr024</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases London Heathrow Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhr024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cb4ee60b8603e71fc9b1f5_innit1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently released the Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 Edition of their London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) rendition, which features a complete rebuild designed for maximum detail and performance. London Heathrow is the eighth-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprising international travel and the remaining 6% strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom landside, custom night lighting, a walkable terminal 5A interior, high-quality terminals, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, and more. It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $28.30, and owners of the 2020 version can upgrade for $12.90.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350102</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350102"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67bf1797199e80fda0eaa13a_fitty1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their newly released A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing further WASM stability, bug fixes, and two new features. Marked by a controversial launch—with a creator even asking for a refund—update v1.0.2 aims to get their ultimate airliner experience back on track with enhanced WASM stability, a substantial amount of bug fixes, and two new features: the A350 MORA (Minimum Off-Route Altitude) implementation and the Secondary Navigation Display, which provides backup navigation should the primary flight management system be unavailable or degraded. They have also made a note on the many community mods that supposedly improve the A350’s flight model: “Comments and updates from the community regarding flight model cfgs are mostly irrelevant, or a placebo effect, as they have little to no effect on how the aircraft performs in sim. We have tuned the plane to fly as closely to real life with the support of our technical working group and A350 pilots team”, concluded iniBuilds, while also addressing one of the mod files and their direct impact – or lack thereof – on the flight model: Mod File Feature List: ‍ Major Flight Stability Increases (aircraft should feel much heavier on the controls, will be improved on) iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Corrected Reference Speeds (Overspeed Limits increased, set to real values) Overspeed and Cruise Mach iniBuilds: Fixed in v1.01    Reduced Thrust Multiplier (lower overall thrust output). iniBuilds: Only effects total thrust. Reducing it as indicated will have a negative/unrealistic impact on SRS   Increased Ground Friction (initial roll requires thrust increase) iniBuilds: Unrealistic modification as this was tuned as per IRL references and pilot feedback.    Reduced Elevator Trim Speed (slightly) iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Slower Spoiler-on Deploy timing (mostly in-flight, the spoilers seem unaffected) iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.  Can be adjusted slightly in cfg’s but this is not realistic.    Custom Flight Dynamics Overhaul. iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Improved Flare and Rotation Behavior (looking into this). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Slower Spoiler Deployment (looking into this, may not be needed after V1.0.1). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Improved Fuel Flow Scalar (looking into this). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.    Improved Climb-Lift Ratios. iniBuilds: Unrealistic modification as this was tuned as per IRL references and pilot feedback.   Brake Changes (higher priority, looking into this also). iniBuilds: This is not possible or true as its controlled via our WASM.  ‍ The complete changelog for the update is available here.  The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cpl143</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes Launch Details for ChasePlane</title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cpl143"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cf2f51feebfd0936b69459_chaseplane2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 recently published another blog post providing further details on their upcoming physics-based camera add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, including its full price, release date, and new pre-release content. For the unaware, ChasePlane is a highly versatile physics-based camera system that allows you to quickly create and share custom views for any airplane. It gives you seamless control over views, be it from within the flight deck, cabin, wing, or even landing gear bay, if you so fancy. ‍ The user feedback on their many pre-launch videos allowed Parallel 42 to take extra time to fine-tune the experience, polish features, and refine the onboarding process for newcomers.  ‍ As far as platform compatibility goes, ChasePlane will debut on Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 first, but a 2024 version is in the works. Eventually, it will be made available for free for all ChasePlane 2020 owners for a limited time period after release. ‍ The add-on will be available to Club 42 members on Friday (14/03) at 11:42 CST for $30 (including cloud backups and community). The limited rollout will allow the developers to stress test the community features and backup infrastructure, ensuring everything works well enough before opening the floodgates. ‍ If you are wondering what “Club 42” is and how to become a member, it is Parallel 42’s way of giving something back to its supporters, providing them with early access to products, permanent discounts, exclusive sales, and personalized recommendations. Click here for further information. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simwee</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Weeze Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simwee"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cf36e162e29a7edc64ebe1_weeze1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimPixel has recently released their rendition of Weeze Airport (EDLV) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Kreis Kleve (Germany) and Nijmegen (Netherlands) with a yearly average of a million passengers. It was built on top of a preexisting military facility (RAF Laarbruch) and started operating as a civilian airport in 2003. The airport’s name was supposed to be after the city of Düsseldorf, but it was ruled out due to the distance (83 km) and the fact Düsseldorf already had two international airports in close proximity (Düsseldorf Airport and Cologne-Bonn). The name idea was eventually ruled out by the court in 2016 due to the huge potential to mislead passengers. Ryanair still refers to it as Düsseldorf-Weeze, though. It’s an operating base for Ryanair, and Sky Express serves it seasonally. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution textures, custom 3d models, dynamic night lighting, detailed interiors, performance-friendly optimization, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.02, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmsnuu</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Nuuk Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmsnuu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67cf3dc1a1b70d124f258a84_nuuk1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently released their rendition of Nuuk Airport (BGGH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The airport serves Nuuk, Greenland, and has a yearly average of 69,324 passengers. The airport was built in 1979 when the government decided to create a network of STOL-capable domestic airports. It originally featured a 950-meter-long asphalt runway located 86 meters above sea level. The terminal and apron were built on a leveled platform on an undulating slope under a mountain.  After many years of expansion proposals, the administration decided to expand the runway to 2,200 meters, build a new terminal to accommodate the expected passenger traffic figures, and expand the apron and service buildings. Construction started in 2019 and reached partial completion in 2022. The new terminal was only inaugurated two years later, in 2024. The scenery accurately depicts the airport, including its new terminal, the 2,200-meter-long runway, handcrafted terrain elevation, detailed 3D terminal with a custom interior, animated objects, custom ground service equipment, up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.82, requiring at least 747.95 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/m24mar</id>
    <title>Microsoft Rolls Out Marketplace for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/m24mar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d07d293d738725a21c989f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Not long after the release of Sim Update 1, the team at Microsoft has launched the in-sim Marketplace for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This Marketplace has been highly anticipated by the community and is now accessible within the simulator. Many items from the Marketplace in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 have been ported to the new simulator. These items should be available in the library and need to be activated. However, content created by Microsoft and Asobo is automatically activated. The Marketplace offers a variety of options. Ported content from the 2020 version to 2024 is marked with a small logo indicating that it is ported. Content upgraded to the 2024 version may have a new price or be available as a free upgrade, and it is also indicated with a logo showing that it has been upgraded. Users can purchase content using Simverse Coins, which is an in-sim currency that can be bought either in the Marketplace or at select retailers. Currently, the Marketplace does not support rentals or gifting, but these features are expected to be introduced with Sim Update 2 in April. Additionally, there are a few known issues with the Marketplace. For the full release notes and details on these issues, please check the official release announcement. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
