<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-09-16T18:34:00.704525+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx2260</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx2260"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c0d971eebdac2d330f27f5_1250410_20250908232701_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations recently issued a small update to their A320 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, addressing an issue where certain liveries were not loading correctly, mitigating a few EFB bugs, and a couple of art &amp; sound fixes. Update 2.4.0.2260 is the second update post-BFU, further trimming the edges through a few quality of life changes and minor fixes. The complete changelog follows below: ‍Avionics and Systems ‍ Art and Sound EFB Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (complete bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbjwarchi24</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Jurassic World Archipelago for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbjwarchi24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c0fdae28208133d69e56c1_archi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their virtual rendition of the Jurassic World Park for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a partly fictional archipelago off the coast of Costa Rica with six islands. The developers bring a complete recreation of the Jurassic World archipelago, set just before the events of the 2015 movie, when the park was operational yet not entirely under control.  Besides the islands, custom airfields and helipads, highly detailed theme park structures, animated dinosaurs and reptiles roaming the land, ruins, and unique animations and visual effects, the package includes guided tours, missions, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: Featured Islands and Mainland Locations (Costa Rica): ‍ ‍ Featured Dinosaurs and Prehistoric Reptiles: ‍ ‍ Other Features: ‍ Furthermore, the Jurassic World pack integrates with Volanta’s MSFS 2024-only avatar tracking, allowing players to explore the islands in a never-before-seen manner and collect a special type of aerocache, only accessible via foot. There are multiple spread across the archipelago. The add-on is available for purchase through 4 different bundles. The cheapest bundle - retailing for $24.99 - only includes the scenery and missions. The second cheapest offers 6 months of Volanta Premium on top of the scenery for $39.99. Alternatively, you can get the PAC 750 instead of Volanta Premium for the same price. Then there’s an ultimate package, with the scenery, Volanta Premium (6 months), and the PAC 750 for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vfrgci</id>
    <title>RealVFR Releases Guernsey Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vfrgci"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c189d95af38985a5d770b5_482055989_634403019339691_4503206361353260357_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. RealVFR has recently released its rendition of Guernsey Airport (EGJB), for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Known for bringing smaller airfields like the Isles of Scilly and Bolt Head to life, the developer has now turned its attention to one of the busiest island gateways in the region. Perched on the picturesque island of Guernsey, Guernsey combines challenging approaches with breathtaking scenery, often featuring crosswind and low visibility components. Home to Aurigny Airlines, Blue Islands, and a steady flow of visiting general aviation traffic, the airport is a hive of activity. RealVFR’s version captures that atmosphere, with a host of carefully crafted features. Expect faithfully sloped taxiways and aprons, immersive night lighting, a fully modelled ATC tower interior, and extensive use of high-quality PBR textures across every building and surface. Even the island’s iconic hedgerows have been recreated in 3D. The add-on has been designed natively for MSFS 2024, making full use of the sim’s enhanced height maps and updated lighting engine. Beyond the airport boundary, RealVFR has gone the extra mile, replacing default housing with handcrafted cottages, bungalows, churches, and more. RealVFR’s Guernsey Airport for MSFS 2024 is now available on the developer’s website, priced at $20.34. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xtpglj</id>
    <title>Xtreme Prototypes Releases Gates Learjet 25 for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xtpglj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c1a6df9f09e39ba62d1233_GLJ25_MSFS2020_01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Xtreme Prototypes, also known as XTPRO from the Prepar3D world, has released their debut aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the GLJ Model 25 Classic SE, replicating the classic Gates Learjet 20 series. Aiming to capture the jet’s “fighter in civilian clothing” characteristics, the team brings deep systems fidelity and plenty of polish. The cockpit is a retro-fitted fit-out, built around the GNS 530, with steam gauges modelled in full 3D, hundreds of animations, and comprehensive lighting with independent dimmers. Under the hood, custom systems cover electrics, hydraulics, pressurisation, anti-ice, fuel (including cross-feed and wingtip jettison), the CJ610 powerplants, and a fully modelled AFCS, with speed hold, yaw damper, and GPS/NAV modes. Sounds are authored in Wwise, and the aircraft features visual effects as well, ranging from exhaust heat and contrails to icing and rain. On the art side, XTPRO notes high-resolution PBR textures, detailed interior and exterior models, and 14 liveries. A 300-page manual (English or French) ships with the aircraft, also including a paint kit. Owners can even add their own custom GPS/radar or tweak aircraft behaviour, using the customisation kit. Note that such third-party avionics are supported, but not included. Xtreme Prototypes notes that the aircraft is built natively for MSFS 2020, though it can also be flown in MSFS 2024, using a compatible version. However, this version is not fully native, so you should expect potential bugs and quirks, and fly at your own discretion. A native 2024 version is coming soon, the team stated. You can find the aircraft manual here. For the full feature list, visit the official product page. For a classic and old-school Learjet experience, you can find the GLJ Model 25 Classic SE on Xtreme Prototypes’ website, for $36,06 USD. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtabq</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Albuquerque International Sunport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtabq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c32a26f4d032cc952801c5_4KSeq.00_01_29_49.Still022_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. DominicDesignTeam has released a detailed rendition of Albuquerque International Sunport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing the well-known desert city a new angle in the sim. The package features high-quality PBR textures, dynamic lighting, and realistic ground markings, custom jetways, bespoke taxiway signage, and hand-crafted pavement, dirt, wear, and surface variation. You also get custom objects, passenger and bus animations, for extra life on the apron, plus tuned LODs, to keep performance smooth across a range of systems. As a quick refresher, Albuquerque Sunport is the primary gateway to New Mexico, sitting between the Rio Grande and the Sandia Mountains. With a 4,800-plus foot elevation and frequent crosswinds, the Sunport serves up lively departures and arrivals. DominicDesignTeam’s Albuquerque is available now via the iniBuilds Store for $18.94 USD. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/e19172</id>
    <title>Echo19 Releases Cessna 172 Precision Audio Pack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/e19172"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4659447cf8f96345c081c_FlightSimulator2024_2025-08-05_15-04-26_400.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Echo 19 has launched its Cessna 172 Precision Audio Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing a rich, reactive soundscape to the world’s most-flown GA aircraft.  Built on the developer’s new EchoFX system, the pack layers sounds that respond to airspeed, angle of attack, weather, and pilot inputs. Expect ground and cabin life cues like fuel slosh, seat and interior creaks, and airframe squeaks in the wind; exterior touches, such as refined control-surface stops, battery contactor clicks, and heat exchange; plus aircraft-specific details, including an accurate N-model flap motor, prop flutter in high winds, and a stall horn that varies pitch with angle of attack. Inside the cockpit, 96 kHz ambisonic captures place every switch, knob, and lever in true 3D space, for headphone and Spatial Sound users. Engine behaviour shifts with mixture and temperature, and there is also airflow noise once the air is moving, with wind layers built naturally as you accelerate. In addition, there are some handy customisation switches, such as toggling vintage-style gyro sounds via the Marker Sensitivity switch. You can also enable an alternator whine, if you fancy a little retro buzz. As a small bonus, Echo 19 also includes five liveries: four for MSFS 2024 (Classic “Ruby”, USAF Academy, Echo 19 House, and House Alt), and one for MSFS 2020 (Echo 19 House Alt). You can read the full feature list below: ‍ 🔉 ECHOFX Immersive Features 🌎Real-World Ground &amp; Cabin Life • Dirt swirl FX for grass, gravel, and paved surfaces • Airframe squeaks when parked in wind • Fuel slosh that reacts to movement and fuel quantity • Seat and interior creaks synced to cockpit motion 🛩️ Deeply Modeled 172 Characteristics  • Accurate N-model flap motor position • Prop flutter when stationary in high wind • Stall horn with pitch variation based on AOA • Dynamic wind layering based on airspeed and angle of attack 🌬️Rich Exterior Ambience • Audible air/heat exchange and battery contactor clicks from outside the aircraft • Reworked control surface stop sounds (rudder, elevator, aileron) 🎚️Smart Customization Controls • Toggle vintage-style gyro sounds via the Marker Sensitivity switch • Choose your soundscape and personalize your flight experience 🎙️Full-3D Cockpit Interactivity • 96kHz ambisonic captures for a complete 360° spatial soundstage • All switches, knobs, dials, and levers placed in true 3D space • Yoke hide/show SFX and optional alternator whine toggle via SPKR • Designed for best results with Spatial Sound enabled 🔥Engine Behavior That Reacts to You • Rough-running effects when mixture is pulled or temps are cold • Internal engine layers change dynamically with airspeed and flight phase 🌡️Environmental Control Audio • Cabin air/heat knobs bring in realistic airflow sounds once airspeed is alive 🎨Bonus Content:  • 4 MSFS 2024 Liveries — Including a Classic “Ruby,” USAF Academy, Echo 19 House, and House Alt • 1 MSFS 2020 Livery — Echo 19 House (Alt) Echo19’s Cessna 172 Precision Audio Pack is available now on the Echo 19 shop for $12.23, as well as the in-sim Marketplace, Contrail, iniBuilds, and Orbx. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flow24</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Provides Update on Flow Pro for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flow24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c48460d39acfd7cc375ad6_545730685_1197698989059534_2706326631889373788_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has taken to Facebook and announced that they’ve pushed Flow Pro for MSFS 2024 into its internal beta testing phase, inching the utility closer to release. The team says they are putting every feature through its paces and will launch once satisfied. No timeframe has been announced. For newcomers, Flow for MSFS 2020 replaced the default toolbar with a sleek, in-sim radial wheel that you can summon with a key or controller button. It lets you access default and third-party panels, arrange custom wheels per aircraft, and resize interface elements for clarity, handy for accessibility on various devices. We have reason to believe similar functionality will be included for the upcoming 2024 version. Looking ahead, Flow Essentials and Flow Pro are planned for MSFS 2024, while the free edition remains on MSFS 2020. Existing Flow Pro customers can expect a small upgrade fee for the MSFS 2024 version. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slhsbh</id>
    <title>SLHSimDesign Releases Saint Barthélemy Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slhsbh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4b407432344dac6769342_TFFJ11_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SLHSimDesign has recently released their new St. Barthélemy scenery, also known as St. Barts, bringing a new rendition of the famous Gustaf III Airport (TFFJ) for MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Well known for its “Saddle” approach, SLHSimDesigns brings accurate hill terraforming, so you can properly hug the slope on short final. Included is a populated RWY28 beach scene, as well as dynamic pedestrians by RWY10, who duck, wave, and film your landing, as well as animated road traffic that turns the hilltop into a living obstacle, just as in the real world. The package has custom 3D modelling throughout, with 4K PBR textures, fully modelled terminal and tower interiors, a working lift between floors, corrected terrain elevations, bespoke ground texturing and grunge, dynamic lighting, and performance-minded optimisation. The island gets attention beyond the runway as well, with animated jet skis and speedboats around Eden Rock and beaches, an uplifted Gustavia Bay, nearby shopping areas, and various points of interest. A quick heads-up before you fly: Disable the Asobo default TFFJ to avoid conflicts.  SLHSimDesign’s St. Barts is available now on the iniBuilds store for $18.97. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a0912</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a0912"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4e305e7104aacb1bc8bf9_aerostarnew.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing new refinements, fixes, additions, and more. Update v0.9.12 of their Aerostar 600 is nicknamed “Little Bits Part 2”, bringing many fixes, further refinements, new additions such as noise-canceling headphones and a functional Hobbs meter, among many other things. The complete changelog follows below: Change log v0.9.12: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ubbb12</id>
    <title>Azrsim Releases Heydar Aliyev International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ubbb12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c565b01ab5b66a4fc40f63_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After releasing their Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 versions of Heydar Aliyev International Airport (UBBB) a few weeks ago, Azrsim has now launched the X-Plane 12 version of the airport. Located in Baku, the capital of Azerbaijan, the airport serves over 7.5 million passengers each year. The airport began operations in 1933. In 1964, a new passenger terminal complex opened, increasing the facility's capacity. A new runway was inaugurated in 1998, followed by the opening of Terminal 2 in 1999. The following year, a new air traffic control (ATC) tower was constructed. In 2004, a new domestic passenger terminal was introduced, and the Baku Cargo Terminal (BCT) was launched in 2005. Additionally, an extra runway was built in 2012, and Terminal 1 was inaugurated in 2014. ‍ The airport accommodates numerous airlines that operate both domestically and internationally, including Azerbaijan Airlines, IrAero, Pegasus Airlines, and Utair, among others. Consequently, the airport facilitates the movement of over 7.5 million passengers annually and manages nearly 60,000 flights each year. The scenery package includes features like accurately recreated terminals, hangars, and additional buildings, detailed interiors, high-resolution ground textures, detailed apron layouts, and much more. The newly released version of Heydar Aliyev International Airport for X-Plane 12 is now available on SimMarket for approximately $23.47. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssmok</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Molokai &amp; Kalaupapa Airports for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssmok"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c5e01b23f35de1cd89d99b_43.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Northern Sky Studio has released a twin-pack for X-Plane 12, featuring Molokai Airport (PHMK) and Kalaupapa Airport (PHLU), giving island-hoppers two richly crafted airports in one go.  Both airfields feature custom ground textures, detailed airport objects and vehicles, weather effects, new lighting, PBR materials, and 3D vegetation. For night operations, you can tune COM1 to 125.7 to switch on the runway lighting, like at a real pilot-controlled field. The package integrates with new X-Plane 12 features, supports World Traffic 3, and is compatible with Ortho4XP and the default mesh, ensuring it should fit into most Hawaii setups without issue. Molokai’s two asphalt runways and central-plateau sets the contrast nicely with Kalaupapa’s coastal strip, making this a versatile pair for commuter, air taxi, or GA flying. Expect high-resolution building and ground textures, realistic reflections on glass, shaded and baked details, plus animated ground traffic, courtesy of the LST plugin. As always, you can read the full feature list below: Features: The Molokai &amp; Kalaupapa Airports pack is now available from Orbx, priced at about $19.20.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vdlebb</id>
    <title>Virtual Design 3D Releases Bilbao Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vdlebb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c7e354f792befcb6d5731c_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Virtual Design 3D has just launched its rendition of Bilbao Airport (LEBB) for X-Plane 12. Situated just 5.6 miles from the city of Bilbao, this international airport serves over 6.3 million passengers annually, facilitating travel to and from the Basque Country in northern Spain. The airport opened its doors in 1948, with the terminal beginning operations two years later in 1950. At that time, the airport featured one asphalt runway, one earth runway, a passenger terminal, an air traffic control tower, and a taxiway. In 1955, a taxiway was added to connect the runway to the parking stands and terminal. Between 1964 and 1965, an Instrument Landing System (ILS) was installed, along with an extension to the runway and apron.  ‍ In 1977, the airport underwent several expansions, including an extended parking stand, a link road, an upgraded ILS, and a new runway. During the 1980s, further improvements were made, including the expansion of the passenger terminal and parking facilities, as well as the addition of a cargo terminal and a fire service building.  ‍ Since the 1990s, the airport has continued to grow, acquiring a new taxiway, a new aircraft parking apron, a new air traffic control tower, and a newly designed terminal area featuring a new terminal building and a north apron. In 2009, an expansion of the terminal building was announced, originally expected to be completed in 2014; however, it has faced delays of at least five years. ‍ Today, the airport serves a wide range of destinations through various airlines, accommodating over 6.3 million passengers and nearly 50,000 aircraft movements annually. The scenery features highly detailed terminals and buildings, custom animated jetways, custom runways, HDR lighting, customized 3D vegetation, detailed surrounding areas, and much more. The newly released Bilbao Airport for X-Plane 12 is now available at the X-Plane.Org Software Store and is currently on sale for $14.93. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cowsep</id>
    <title>COWS Updates Diamond Aircraft, Introduces DA40-NG for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cowsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c89364aeda392855e269a1_DA40DA42_Update%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. COWS has recently rolled out a major update across its Diamond line of products, bringing the entirely new DA40-NG, alongside refinements to the DA40-XLS and DA42 TDI/VI. These changes arrive as two distinct product updates, each with its own feature set and improvements. The Diamond family of aircraft is a familiar sight at many flight schools and academies around the globe. The DA40 XLS, being the oldest of the three variants, offers a traditional Lycoming piston setup, while the newer DA40 NG introduces a more modern, AE300 engine. Stepping up, the DA42 takes the DA40’s platform, adding twin turbodiesel engines, retractable gear, and enhanced stability, making it a popular bridge into multi-engine training. The DA40-series has been updated to version 1.1.0, with the headline addition of the new NG variant. Built on the XLS platform, the NG comes with a reworked flight model, designed to replicate training manoeuvres with more accuracy. On the systems side, the aircraft now features a fully custom electrical system, that models bus voltage, alternators, and battery behaviour down to details, such as overnight discharge, if the cabin light is left on.  Other highlights include refinements to engine dynamics, autopilot, priming assist, as well as an expanded G1000 feature set, with wide flight plan view, nearest airport auto-set, endurance calculations, and additional reset options. The DA42 also sees a significant refresh, now at version 1.2.2. Developed in parallel with the DA40 update, it benefits from the same electrical system overhaul and G1000 improvements. Changes extend into the powerplant model, with FADEC adjustments, turbo response tuning, and cooling airflow simulation. Other systems, such as de-ice and auxiliary fuel tanks, are now also influenced by aircraft acceleration. A long list of fixes touches on lighting, visuals, state saving, and failures, rounding out the update. As always, you can read the full changelog(s), for both updates, in the following section: ‍ V1.1.0 15/09/25 Powerplant/Flightmodel Engine friction changes and tuning Oil and CHT warm up a little faster New cooling airflow simulation (More natural behaviour with winds and prop discing) Automixture: Mixture lever now sets a target mixture like a conventional FS mixture lever Increased oil pressure drop from propeller governor Fixed engine alternate air bug Added rudder deflection from trim tab Systems Autopilot tweaks RPM sensor is now simulated Added temperature offsets to gauges Fixed stall horn on the ground in high winds Standby gyro reacts to system voltage Fully custom electric system: - Simulated electrical buses, diodes, component power draw, circuit breakers, batteries and alternators - Simulated alternator field voltage, voltage regulators - Simulated battery voltage, resistance and temperature - Battery charge is statesaved and battery will self discharge over time - Leaving the cabin light on will discharge the battery - Battery can be recharged in the G1000 engine page menu and emergency reset procedure (check tips in checklist) G1000 Updated Navigraph plugin Added wide Flightplan view Added Priming assist Added nearest airport being set as the origin Updated the MFD data fields to use the totalizer for fuel and endurance calculations (FOB, FOD, END) Updated the Engine Page Menu with more reset failure options Updated the fuel calculator range and endurance to use the avionics computer state Fixed the endurance field showing as failed when toggling the electric master Fixed the PFD bottom info data styling to be compatible with the HSI map and other configs Added "timer expired" voice alert Added a delay to displaying the CAS Reversionary mode fixes Total Time in Service is now activated when the aircraft becomes airborne Other: Separated package into FS20 and FS24 specific versions (G1000v2 mod no longer required, currently Orbx only) Fixed Parking brake on/off commands Tweaks to: Lighting, Visuals, Sounds, Statesaving, Failures, Standby instruments Added some new tips to checklist FS24: Fixed lighting bloom Added DA40NG ‍ V1.2.2 15/09/25 Powerplant/Flightmodel FADEC improvements Increased turbo response New cooling airflow simulation Oil cooling improvements Improved fuel system behaviour Ecu error detection is paused shortly after slewing Reduced steering angle at high speeds Systems Autopilot tweaks De-ice fluid is now affected by aircraft acceleration Removed unusable de-ice fluid Aux tanks are now affected by aircraft acceleration Added temperature offsets to gauges Standby gyro reacts to system voltage Fully custom electric system: - Simulated electrical buses, diodes, component power draw, circuit breakers, batteries and alternators - Simulated alternator field voltage, voltage regulators and temperature - Simulated battery voltage, resistance and temperature - Battery charge is statesaved and battery will self discharge over time - Leaving the cabin light on will discharge the battery - Battery can be recharged in the G1000 engine page menu and emergency reset procedure (check tips in checklist) G1000 Updated Navigraph plugin Added wide Flightplan view Added nearest airport being set as the origin Updated the MFD data fields to use the totalizer for fuel and endurance calculations (FOB, FOD, END) Updated the Engine Page Menu with more reset failure options Updated the fuel calculator range and endurance to use the avionics computer state Fixed the endurance field showing as failed when toggling the electric master Fixed the PFD bottom info data styling to be compatible with the HSI map and other configs Added Blue and Red line airspeed markers Added "timer expired" voice alert Added a delay to displaying the CAS Reversionary mode fixes Total Time in Service is now activated when the aircraft becomes airborne Other: Separated package into FS20 and FS24 specific versions (G1000v2 mod no longer required, currently Orbx only) Set fuel tank priority, main tanks are refilled first Fixed Parking brake on/off commands Tweaks to: Lighting, Visuals, Gear physics, Sounds, Statesaving, Failures, Feathering, Deice system, Fuel selectors, Xfer pumps, Standby instruments Added some new tips to checklist FS24: Blocked prop lever inputs triggering ECU errors FS24: Fixed lighting bloom Both the DA40 and 42 are offered as separate purchases, priced at $26.85 and $30.85 respectively. You can find them both on OrbxDirect. Owners of the DA40-XLS receive the NG variant as part of the package, at no extra cost. Updates are available now through Orbx Central, with Marketplace releases to follow. Be aware, COWS has noted that neither aircraft is currently compatible with the new SU4 beta. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aflsep</id>
    <title>Airfoillabs Shares 737 MAX 8 Systems Update for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aflsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c8a834f77a283762009dfc_AFL737MAX8-2025-08-1600_01_41.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After a string of progress reports, Airfoillabs has taken to social media, sharing the latest on its 737 MAX for X-Plane 12. The update focuses on systems work, cockpit modelling, and the steps toward a custom Autopilot and Autothrottle, providing insight into how the ambitious project is shaping up. Starting off, the FMS has seen a round of quality-of-life tweaks since the last update. The Arrivals page now streamlines STAR and transition selection, while constraint checks have been refined to be more straightforward and less error-prone.  We also saw previews of the Vertical Situation Display, adding various practical cues, such as destination runway on profile, approach glideslope and minimum-altitude gates, plus a cleaner terrain picture, to support descent planning. Meanwhile, the PFD/HSI are reported to be close to feature-complete. Airfoillabs says the suite now renders the core symbology used in normal ops, including validity flags and annunciators, with edge cases tuned. Hence, the flags appear, and clear, in a more predictable way. The 737 MAX will also support third-party navigation data, with Airfoillabs noting ongoing work with Navigraph. This integration brings worldwide procedures and navaids into X-Plane 12, updated with each AIRAC cycle. This means cleaner routing, with fewer gaps, particularly on complex SIDs and STARs. Ultimately, this work should ensure consistency with other Navigraph-enabled tools, and a more predictable experience, when flying published procedures. Two cockpit art milestones are also in place. The aft overhead panel now has all animations and manipulators implemented, with guards, detents, and backlighting, tuned for consistent interaction, in 2D and VR.  Animations and UI logic for the Mode Control Panel are also complete, including a custom-built font, with this work serving as the front-end for the custom AFDS, currently underway. That AFDS, the Autopilot and Flight Director System, is currently moving through intensive development. Airfoillabs explains that they are developing a custom system, complete with an integrated autothrottle.  Planned functions include LNAV, VNAV, Level Change, V/S, localiser and glideslope capture, dual-channel autoland, speed protections, and go-around logic. The team describes this process as iterative, with captures, transitions, and reversions being expanded over multiple passes, with the eventual goal of offering study-level realism. Looking ahead, Airfoillabs plans to refine the AFDS further, focusing on smoother LNAV and VNAV captures, approach handling, and system protections. Work is also underway on expanding the autothrottle, adding mode safeguards, and improving throttle lever behaviour.  Alongside this, the team continues quality checks on navigational data, as well as polishing cockpit details, such as backlighting and switch feel, to ensure consistency across both 2D and VR. For the full details, you can read Airfoillab’s numerous blog posts on the X-Plane.Org Forum, and visit the product page here. No release date has been announced, however progress seems to be moving along nicely.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barreirinhas</id>
    <title>flyt Simulations Releases Barreirinhas Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barreirinhas"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c8d3993c6b84b8d8850327_maranhao1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. flyt Simulations has recently released their rendition of Barreirinhas Lençóis Maranhenses Regional Airport (SSRB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Barreirinhas, Maranhão, Brazil. It opened only four years ago, replacing the older facility, which has been closed since then.  Easaero operates it, and there are no scheduled flights to Barreirinhas as of yet. It's mainly used for panoramic flights of the Lençóis Maranhenses National Park, one of the UNESCO World Heritage sites due to its exceptional beauty and overall uniqueness. There's nothing quite like it anywhere else in the world. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, high-quality 3D buildings, custom clutter, and much more. It's available in the Marketplace for $5.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol113</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates Volanta Flight Tracker to v1.13.0 </title>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol113"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c9870ee32b1aa1f00cdeb2_social.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated its popular Volanta Flight Tracker to v1.13.0, introducing a mix of new features, quality-of-life tweaks, and perhaps some rather unexpected additions.  At the centre of this update is support for MSFS 2024’s walk-around mode, which allows player movement outside of the cockpit to be tracked by Volanta, just like in the air. When stepping out of the cockpit to explore, you will now see your path logged as blue lines, recorded alongside your flights in purple. A new kind of aerocache has also been introduced, available only in walk-around mode. These hidden collectables are marked by orange circles on the map and, for now, are exclusive to Orbx’s new Jurassic World: Archipelago scenery, off the coast of Costa Rica.  That pack adds nine airfields, 12 helipads, and more than 550 square miles of terrain to explore, and yes, dinosaurs are included. Read more about it here. Elsewhere, Volanta gains a new map layer for points of interest (POIs), designed to highlight locations worth visiting, with more detailed map data. Flight cards have also been given themed styles, when departing or arriving at Jurassic World airports. Behind the scenes, Orbx has released an entirely new plugin for MSFS users. The installer has been simplified, bugs such as auto-selecting aircraft have been ironed out, and overall performance impact has been reduced. This plugin supports all the latest features of v.1.13.0, including the new avatar tracking. For those who would prefer to keep things strictly realistic, the fictional Jurassic content can be disabled via a toggle, available for all Volanta users, as of the latest patch. You can read the full changelog of v1.13.0 here: Enhancements (As of version 1.13.2, Premium is no longer required to disable fictional content) Volanta v1.13.0 is available now as a free update. The program can be downloaded free of charge from the Volanta website, supporting virtually every simulator out there, from DCS and Aerofly, to Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
