<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-02-23T18:23:47.586217+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctpw22</id>
    <title>Vote for VATSIM’s Cross The Pond Westbound Airports!</title>
    <updated>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctpw22" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620b2ae92872738f29dd88e3_banner_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="838369"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. VATSIM’s team is maintaining its biannual tradition of Cross the Pond. The event will take place on April 2nd, in the westbound fashion. For those unfamiliar with the event, VATSIM hosts a transatlantic event where hundreds of pilots and full ATC coverage come together to participate in long-haul operations. Nearly 12 hours of full Air Traffic Control services will be in use for the entirety of the event. The team has opened up a vote for pilots to give feedback as to which airports they’d like to operate out of during the event.  As always, there’s a plethora of airports to choose from. Pilot’s are given the opportunity to choose three of their preferred airports from the lists below.  It’s critical to mention that aspiring CTP pilots must book a flight slot to ensure participation in the event. Whilst bookings are currently not available, the VATSIM team will keep the community updated regarding the results and booking availability later this month. Due to the large swarms of aircraft during the event, pilots can potentially expect delays to their slot times. Another small piece of information to add, is that Concordes are not permitted within the event and supersonic aircraft will not be recognized as event participating aircraft. Stay tuned with VATSIM’s Cross the Pond website to ensure up to date information regarding slot bookings, and event updates.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md11tf</id>
    <title>TFDi Announces MD-11 Pricing Details</title>
    <updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md11tf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620dbacd1a16115d5de2d91a_ext3.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1844197"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TFDi has updated their product page for their MD-11 to include pricing information. The team seems to follow the same a-la-carte pricing model of the forthcoming PMDG NG3 which lets users purchase a single aircraft variant of their choice, unlike previous pricing models which includes two or more main variants within the base package. TFDi stated that the pricing model was adopted to allow users to “select the exact features and options you want.” The base package comes in two flavours, the freighter to passenger variant, purchasing one of them will discount the other base package. For example, if you purchase the passenger variant, you don’t need to shell out another $89.99 for the Freighter base package, but $14.99. TFDi aims to also expand the breadth of the simulation with an add-on package labeled “Extended Simulation Package”, this package introduces operational failures, an advanced custom failures menu, and some circuit breaker functionality.Here is the original breakdown of the pricing: Other information on the product page promises a well rounded digital replica of the trijet, with support for all the modern ESP (namely, Prepar3D v4 and v5) platforms including MSFS. The team opened the possibility of adapting the aircraft for use on older ESP simulators such as FSX and Prepar3D v1 to 3. The supplied feature list is short but covers what you’d normally expect in a high end aircraft simulation, with a fully bespoke visual model that includes highly accurate 3D and textures, with support for PBR on simulators that support it. On the technical side, accurate flight dynamics, a full fledged onboard simulation system that features a completely simulated FMS and autopilot system simulation are promised. Lastly, the team partnered with Turbine Sound Studios for the soundpack. TFDi is still accepting suggestions in their forum for features people like to see included in the aircraft. Head over to their wishlist to contribute. That’s all for TFDi’s MD-11. We’ll be sure to keep you in the loop. For now, do visit their product page for the original source.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mag787</id>
    <title>Magknight Updates Boeing 787</title>
    <updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mag787" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620dcbdfb40718395f756bb5_Cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="53848"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The developers over at Magknight have updated their rendition of the Boeing 787 Dreamliner for X-Plane 11, bringing the aircraft version to 1.7.21. This update features many bug fixes and minor feature additions to help prepare the aircraft for its next major update. This is the latest major update to come out, the first in 2022 since August of last year. Since then, the team has been pushing frequent updates in smaller form, through their Cygnus and development-highlights channel. On the coding end, the team has been hard at work preparing for the custom FMC, and Mitchell has been reworking several of the exterior visuals which includes newly modellied wings and wingbox and a fresh set of landing gears - the former which are said to be featured in the next update for the aircraft. The Magknight team has been the sole developer to venture into the world of the Dreamliner in XP11, with FlightFactor shortly becoming their competitor with their 787 currently in development. This update mainly features various bug fixes and minor additions. The CDU help box and NAV RAD page have been added, along with a custom radio simulation. MFD screen pop-ups have been added also with an N1 prediction addition to the EICAS. New Avitab textures, ND graphics,  and CDU graphics have been implemented into the aircraft as well. Moving on to items that have been changed, the CDU will now display times in “real” UTC. Multiple changes have been made to the MFD, such as keyboard entries, mouse entry code, and movement code, which have all been changed. The PFD artificial horizon colors have been improved alongside screen dimming in the flight deck. Legacy panel art and BetterPushback buttons when the plugin is not installed have been removed in this version. If you are interested in further learning about this update, you can view the full changelog at Magknight’s Official Discord Server. If you are interested in purchasing this aircraft, you can find it on the X-Plane.org Store for $44.95. Threshold will keep you posted on any further updates from Magknight.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbwsup</id>
    <title>FlyByWire A32NX Systems Update Progress</title>
    <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbwsup" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620f770095ca8029bf264ee7_fbw.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="763276"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Freeware aircraft developer FlyByWire has published a new community update outlining its future systems development endeavors. Ranging from the Fly-By-Wire systems to the Air Condition system, there’s a plethora of updates incoming for the A32NX. The team has provided the community with multiple videos to visualize these future updates, and to help pilots understand the functions of these systems.  Many system improvements have been made, such as adjustments to the pitch law, alongside confirming that yaw and roll laws are already realistic. Pitches at lower speeds have also been tweaked making the pitch law more sensitive. Pitch law has also been improved to help compensate for speedbreak deployment and speed changes. With these changes, brings adjustments to the joystick recommended configuration. FBW recommends users to adjust their +/- 30%, which will in turn, help better mimic the increased force needed to go full back or full forward. ‍ In correlation with the Fly-By-Wire system improvements, the autopilot has also received some tweaking. Conditions with arming the ALT and engaging the mechanisms have received several changes. Target load factors to help guide the AP are now seperated for every law that has been previously mentioned and situations. Speed/Mach laws have been improved with what the team refers to as “further edge cases''. Vertical speed limitations have also been tweaked for Open Descent and Climb modes. Autoland systems have also been tweaked to include a brand new filter to help recognize the flare law, which will measure vertical speed relative to the ground via radio altimeter. ‍ Moving forward, the Autothrust has received minor tweaking with the involvement of improved transitions between climb, descent, open descent, and open climb modes, which will help keep speeds at -5 or +10 knots on vertical approach. Thrust limits have been improved to help itself and its interaction with CLB limits during flex temp takeoffs.  SRS engagement and ATHR arming have been discord to be related, i.e. if SRS does not engage on takeoff, the ATHR will not arm. Lastly, speed control for acceleration and deceleration have been improved to achieve better speed control.  Whilst all of these updates have occurred, FBW has been hard at work developing a new warning system for the aircraft. When released, the Flight Warning Computer (FWC) will help trigger callouts such as GPWS at more accurate heights than before. Other features will include the famous “cricket” stall noise, and intermediate callouts. ‍ Work on a new AC system has begun. When finished, the cabin will be able to warm and cool with the outside temperatures. Air flow delivery systems have been overhauled to fit into the shoes of its real world counterpart. Users are currently able to try out and are invited to play around these new building blocks for the new AC system. If you’re interested in picking this aircraft up for yourself, you can download it over on FlyByWire’s Website.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vc10no</id>
    <title>Just Flight's VC10 for X-Plane is Potentially Cancelled</title>
    <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vc10no" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/620fa8be8e8ffe73defbe475_VC10XP_040820_10_cNNC0cvYC.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="230965"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. New evidence supports the claim that the Just Flight VC10 for XPlane has been cancelled. In May 2020, Just Flight announced their intentions to port their VC10 from the ESP platform into X-Plane. This was followed by previews uploaded to their Facebook Page: Despite promising images of the team’s progress, a long radio silence ensued, until XPlane users started to express their concerns online. On February 4th 2022, a user of the XPlane.Org Forums posted an email claimed to have been sent to them by Just Flight’s customer service in response to a query as to the whereabouts of the VC10. The email cites that the main reason for the cancellation of the project was the team’s inability to assure the quality of the product. This claim is corroborated by the fact that clicking the link to the progress blog on Just Flight’s website yields a ‘Page not found’ error. Whilst Just Flight have not yet formally made a public announcement, the evidence points toward the VC-10 port for X-Plane no longer being in development.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/da50ab</id>
    <title>Aerobask Teases DA50 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/da50ab" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62101fe63de5ac130e570d94_chrome_1802_2237.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2516263"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The team at Aerobask has uploaded a teaser trailer of their upcoming Diamond DA50 RG for X-Plane 11. Aerobask’s DA50 features a Garmin avionics suite, PBR textures, and accurate modelling. The new aircraft will join the existing DA62 in the developer’s Diamond catalogue.  The Diamond DA50 is a five seat, single engine, composite aircraft designed and manufactured by Diamond Aircraft. Originating out of Austria, the aircraft first flew in April of 2007, but is not in active production awaiting certification from EASA and the FAA. The RG variant of the DA50 has a useful load of 559kg (1,232 lbs), a maximum speed of 181 knots, and a range of 750nm (1,389km). Currently, only two prototypes of the aircraft exist in the entire world, with production expected to resume once its certification process is complete.  Unfortunately, Aerobask has not revealed any additional information regarding the whereabouts of the project, but keep an eye out for future teasers and trailers on our website. Pilots who are unfamiliar with Aerobask should take a quick look at this article showcasing Aerobask's rendition of their previous Diamond Aircraft project, the DA62.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inihea</id>
    <title>iniScene Premieres Heathrow Trailer</title>
    <updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inihea" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621064dbb0efea420ca3a990_neue.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="957243"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The highly awaited trailer for iniScene’s rendition of London Heathrow Airport has premiered on their YouTube Channel. This trailer comes just after the team announced the project for Microsoft Flight Simulator just a week ago, alongside releasing a teaser trailer the same day. London’s Heathrow Airport is often referred to as one of the main International hubs in Europe, alongside airports like Amsterdam Schiphol and Charles De Gualle. It is the hub for the countries residing Flag Carrier, British Airways, while also being a focus airport for Virgin Atlantic. The airport also sees many other well-known carriers such as Delta, KLM, American Airlines, and Emirates to name a few. This project by iniScene has been one of the most ambitious projects for the developer. Not only has the team focused on the main terminals, runways/taxiways, and airport facilities, but they have also focused on many different airport landmarks such as the airport's distinctive looking ATC Control Tower, to construction vehicles on the airport grounds, ending with hotels outside the airport grounds. The team has said that this project will be the team's “most detailed and feature-rich scenery to date.” No feature list or product page has not been released to the public at this time. Though we do expect to see an intense feature list when it has been made readily available to the public. If you are interested in learning more about this project, check out our previous coverage when this project was first announced!Threshold will keep you updated on further developments regarding this project.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stu24f</id>
    <title>MK Studios Hints at Rome News on February 24th</title>
    <updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stu24f" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62108ee9540aff2b45c70979_tinypng_1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="267725"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just posted a new update on their Facebook hinting at some potentially crucial news on February 24th. Alongside their message, they’ve also posted some additional previews of their up and coming Rome Fiumicino Airport (LIRF) for MSFS. First announced in their 2020 roadmap, the airport is now on its final approach.  Rome Fiumicino International Airport “Leonardo Da Vinci” serves the capital city of Italy, Rome. The airport is the busiest in the country, and also breaks the top 15 most busy airports in Europe. Serving as a hub for ITA Airways, Vueling, Ryanair and Wizz Air, the airport sees over 40 million annual passengers. Three runways call Fiumicino home: 07/25, 16R/34L and 16L/34R.  Stay tuned with Threshold as the upcoming news may include the airports release! If you’re interested in keeping up with MK Studios other projects, take a peek at their Facebook. They also updated their website recently, to take a look at their current products, look here.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdtra</id>
    <title> PMDG Publishes 737 For MSFS Preview Trailer</title>
    <updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdtra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6210aea5ca55b36682bd327b_tr.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="484361"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG Simulations has posted a new preview trailer of their 737 for MSFS in action on their YouTube channel. The highly anticipated aircraft has seen some major progress as of late, most recently having entered the beta stage of testing. Similar to its counterpart in Prepar3D, the aircraft will come delivered with every feature as is possible to simulate in MSFS. No release date has been set yet, but the community will be notified of the team's release intentions once the details are concrete.  The preview trailer showcases the many views the 737 possesses, presenting the exterior, cockpit, cargo operations, as well as passenger views. Viewers are also able to witness all of the systems in action, as well as the aircraft in a flying state. It’s imperative to mention, though, that the aircraft is still in active development, therefore systems may be altered from their state in the video. Another subtle but important detail is PMDG’s acknowledgement of MAX development for MSFS. In the description of the video, the author mentions that the product line will “include the entire third and fourth generation 737 series from the 737-600 to the 737-10”. No additional details were given as to the development status of the MAX, so ensure that you keep up to date with future articles entailing information about their future products.  ‍Another Dev Update! Robert Randazzo added to the trailer by posting a new development update. At this point in time, the team is cleaning up the aircraft, bugs are being attended to, and the beta is in full swing. Beta testers are still bound to their Non Disclosure Agreement for the time being, but PMDG expects the testers to be able to share media of the plane in the coming weeks. Luckily, the aircraft is in a better state than expected, which infers a more imminent release.  If you’re not caught up with PMDG’s 737 development for MSFS, take a look at this previous article here outlining its beta testing and future progress.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777rcp</id>
    <title>A Recap of Flight Factor’s latest 777V2 previews</title>
    <updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777rcp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6210dcef7048187164424ef4_FLWXwyUXsAUWBtr.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="85056"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has been chipping away at several projects, their front-running project being the 777, kickstarting 2022, the team went on a tour with 777v2 updates these past few weeks, dropping several previews and showcasing different aspects and areas of the aircraft. Their latest update takes us to the seat of the cabin, with a rendition that will certainly have you live the exciting moments in a 777: For the bourgeoisie sitting in the forward cabin, FlightFactor has reproduced a highly impressive business class cabin: Emirates undoubtedly has one of the most distinctive and luxurious cabin interiors in the skies; their wooden lacquer window frames and chic cream upholstery serves as a basis for their standard interior modelling amongst a few other options users will be able to choose from. Flight Factor has additionally began modelling some mood lighting across the cabin, shown below: A common argument that frequently appears across all simulation platforms is the idea that cabins are not necessary, and while they don't impact the actual piloting aspect, many enjoy the depth and immersiveness it brings - modern X-Plane airliners all feature a modelled cabin to various degrees of detail. It’s great to see FlightFactor continue the increasingly popular “cabin culture” within X-Plane; no longer will users feel their calming boarding music will be played in vain, now with a cabin to match. On the exterior, FlightFactor has taken a page out of CaptainSim by modelling in operable hatches and service doors across the plane, their most recent example being fully functioning engine cowlings. To date, no other airliner in X-Plane has implemented such a detailed visual model for an airliner. This alone will certainly be a selling point for FlightFactor as it's this type of attention to detail that really touches the buyer's stimulus: Complementing pre-flight inspections, the team has posted a short clip demonstrating animated workers scattered on the apron - bringing some life to the beginning of your flight: Needless to say, this aircraft is generating a lot of noise within the X-Plane community, as it replicates one of the most popular twinjet airliners Boeing has ever made, and is a much-needed replacement to their original product that dates back in X-Plane 9’s final days. For more updates, check out Flight Factor’s Twitter page and be sure to stay tuned, as we will bring you the latest news and updates when available.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simcub</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Previews the Piper J3 Cub for X-Plane 11</title>
    <updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simcub" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6211a971b02b10a5f701f65c_unnamed%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="54984"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After the recent release of their DA40NG for X-Plane 11, SimSolutions has once again taken to the iniBuilds Youtube Channel to announce their newest aircraft for the simulator, this time with the Piper J3 Cub. With the developer claiming the aircraft as a “ faithful rendition of the real aircraft,” the single-engine Piper is set to boast “high-resolution textures, accurate flight characteristics, and an accurately modelled airframe.” Furthermore, to cover the J3 Cub’s diverse flying capabilities, the piston airplane will release with three different configurations, including standard tires, tundra tires, and floats. Lastly, an extensive feature list was provided, which is viewable below. Unfortunately, no release date was provided for the aircraft. However, it’s been confirmed that it will cost £12.99 GBP (plus tax). Lastly, make sure to check out the aircraft's product page via the iniBuilds store for further information. As well, Threshold will make sure to keep you updated on any potential developments that arise with the J3 Cub.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/madbet</id>
    <title>Leonardo Maddog for MSFS is in Beta</title>
    <updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/madbet" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6211c94bfba3194aa85cdb1e_maddog.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="286296"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. First announced in November of 2020, Leonardo has undergone active development of it’s incredible McDonnell Douglas MD-80 for the new simulator. It’s been a couple months since we’ve last heard from the team, but recently, Stefan subtly commented on the Maddog X forum that the aircraft is currently in it’s beta stage, and the software is progressing well.  Leonardo’s MD-80 was originally developed for Prepar3Dv4 and FSX. It’s widely considered by the flight simulation community to be one of the best airliners available for any simulator platform, and arguably the best MD-80 available, period. The aircraft delivers fully simulated failures, accurate systems, superb modeling, and a proactive development team.  Reverting back to the MSFS compatible MD-80, the team has shared a few videos on its YouTube channel, showcasing the aircraft in action. Other than their videos and promising comments regarding the aircraft’s development progress, though, we haven’t received any additional information surrounding its release.  Stefano mentioned that more details will follow this announcement, make sure to keep up to date with Leonardo’s progress on their forums, as well as with us here at Threshold. </summary>
    <published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blue75</id>
    <title>BlueBird Simulations Announces 757 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blue75" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621236468c749afce981d8b3_Screenshot-9040-Logo-2048x1152.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1466645"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Up-and-coming aircraft developer BlueBird Simulations has announced their first project for flight simulation, the Boeing 757. The team contains four dedicated members, including a programmer with a plethora of experience, two model designers, and an airline pilot. Just Flight will be supporting the 757 development efforts. BlueBird informed the community that “this will be a mid-level complexity aircraft which will be several layers more complex than default airliners.” ‍ BlueBird Simulations intends for the 757 to be an MSFS-native aircraft to fully utilize the SDK. As of now, the aircraft is still in the early stages of systems development, but more information will be disclosed later, when the team has more progress to share. It’s important to contextualize the recurrent theme of “assuming release dates” by pointing out that development times may change over the course of time if the developer feels its necessary, but BlueBird is confident that the 757 will find itself on the market in the first half of 2023.  Head over to the BlueBird Simulations website to visit the original update post, additionally check Just Flight's Facebook post for more images of the 757’s current exterior, and to keep current with the “flying pencils” progress. </summary>
    <published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tdsgtn</id>
    <title>TDS Sim Announces GTNXi VC Integration MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tdsgtn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621331db750bf90c7e2f7d12_cpic02-2.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="289971"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. As the addons list for MSFS continues to grow, it has been refreshing to see a utility product amongst all the scenery and aircraft hype. With TDS Sim’s flagship product, it’s a simulated fourth generation Garmin GTNXI: an answer to the complaints and concerns over MSFS native navigation systems that have, according to the community, long been one the simulators short falls - its latest update is certainly arriving with much anticipation. Recently, TDS Sim announced that their product for MSFS can now be experienced through Virtual Cockpits with added VC and VR support.  Now armed with these new capabilities and an expanding list of compatible aircraft, the product's future developments appear promising. The aircraft that will initially support this added VR and VC ability will be the Just Flight PA28 collection, followed by the upcoming SimWorks Studios RV-14, as well as the FlySimWare C414. Integration of the product and the added functionality will be dependent on external aircraft developers and their willingness to adopt TDS Sim’s SDK.  In true Garmin fashion, the GTNXi is packed with some really impressive features that will give the pilots who utilize it the upper hand. This experience is now heightened with the recently added capabilities; if you are not a current user of the GTNXi, and are a VR user or simply someone who prefers complete VC integration, then maybe the prospect of this product now working for you may spark some interest. Luckily we’re here to give you a quick insight on what this product entails. It is evident that the team has really gone to great lengths to ensure no function has been forgotten. What we have seen from the team recently proves their willingness to constantly build on their existing products, meaning we can be sure to see future updates. Take a look at some of their more interesting features amongst many, that we thought are worth highlighting: Some noteworthy mentions: the product contains both the 650Xi and the 750Xi so there’s no need to purchase them individually. Should you decide to go ahead and purchase the product, the team has expressed their focus in keeping the product optimized so that performance of the flight simulator remains unimpacted, we know this is important. The installation of similar products in the past have always notoriously been tricky, however TDS claims their installation process is as simple as running a standalone exe file. Should you require further information check out the product page for an extensive breakdown, potential users can expect all the usual Garmin functions and much more. The product is currently on sale at 39.95 EUR, typically costing 49.95 EUR and can be purchased on TDS Sim’s website.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sspj3c</id>
    <title>SimSolution’s releases Piper J3 Cub</title>
    <updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sspj3c" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/621356088dd56d981010e9b1_1_53993699-dd72-4bc5-9a32-164de9db6e02-2-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="580850"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Piper J3 Cub is aviation’s old trusty steed, and SimSolution’s rendition of the iconic aircraft is now available to live on within X-Plane 11. SimSolution’s appears to have done a great job in recreating one of aviation's most adored aircraft, this STOL aircraft has long been known for its versatility and agility, capable of unthinkable maneuvers. For pilots looking for an aircraft to just have fun with, this was and still is it. SimSolutions claims to have modeled this aircraft with high resolution textures, which is demonstrated in their provided images. Accurate flight characteristics is another promise made by the developers, meaning you can do all the same crazy low speed maneuvers you've seen these aircraft do in those viral videos. The Product comes with three configurations, namely: Standard Tires, Tundra Tires and Floats. With this, the aircraft includes a number of quirky features such as a custom hand held radio, hand propping ability, and toggleable covers. See below their full Feature list: In addition to all this, what could be considered a minor yet appreciated feature is the provided CSL model for Vatsim use. The great news is this neat little product can be enjoyed by all, as the aircraft works with X-Plane 11.50+  across Windows, MacOS and Linux.  It's worth mentioning, with Vatsim Velocity being released not too long ago, could we see this Aircraft leading an STOL challenge perhaps? Do let us know! Priced at a reasonable 12.99GBP the aircraft can be purchased from the product page on the iniBuilds Store.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/2nc0ms</id>
    <title>Pilot’s Releases Mountain Air Airport For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/2nc0ms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6215c1bdb39ec357e8edab78_Cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="159701"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mountain Air Airport (2NC0), is North Carolina’s well recognized general aviation favorite. Known around the world for its unique breathtaking views and scenic approaches. Topped with a slight element of danger, given the runway is sloped, while simultaneously nestled high in the Slickrock Mountains. Surrounded by neighboring Black Mountains, Blue Ridge Mountains, and the Appalachian Mountains, it's needless to say, pilots here typically won't be able to truly take in the natural beauty on their way in, given the evident obstacle issue that tends to require full effort and attention.   Pilot’s GesmbH has attempted to capture this beautiful location in a way that could offer everyone sitting at home the opportunity to experience operations in and out of the airport. Looking at their provided images, it appears they have done a brilliant job in doing so, with consistently crisp, clear textures. Below is a list of features they have implemented into the scenery, while the list is quite limited the images do speak for themselves.  If you enjoy short-haul tourist charter flights, this scenery may be ideal for you. Currently, the product can only be purchased exclusively on the MSFS Marketplace and is priced at a reasonable $12.49 USD. This scenery is available on PC and XBOX. For more information check out their Facebook page.</summary>
    <published>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
