<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-04-13T18:30:20.726123+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ufkasc</id>
    <title>UFK Announces Airbus Steering Console</title>
    <updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ufkasc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e59ffe599fef467f7f3067_3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Universal Flight Kit, one of the new players in the world of flight sim hardware producers, has just announced their first product - the Airbus Steering Console. As the name suggests, the console is a 1:1 replica of the A320 steering console, with a 12-bit plug-and-play steering tiller with a metal base, 5V console/floor light, and attachment templates for various sidesticks (some of them being VKB, VIRPIL, Thrustmaster). As mentioned earlier, the console features an aluminum steering tiller, along with a functional PEDAL DISC button with a metal base, realistic amber built-in backlit panel (BIBL - one of their upcoming products), aluminum trash tray with a lid, and comes with screws, hardware and instruction manual. The console is made out of an MDF frame and has realistic vent grills. UKF’s newest product can be bough from their website for $299.95 during the pre-order period, and $399.99 as a standard price.The shipment begins on 2nd April, and it is also possible to order the F/O side version. It is compatible with all FS20 and FS24 aircrafts (including the most popular ones coming from developers like Fenix, PMDG, iniBuilds, Aerosoft, FBW, FSLabs, ProSim etc.), and with X-Plane 12 and ToLiss products.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fx320n</id>
    <title>Fenix Announces A320NEO family for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fx320n"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e6e1610162be660eaedf2e_neo-leap-hero.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix has just posted its 2025 roadmap, detailing planned updates for the current A320 CEO family, compatibility improvements for MSFS 2024, and a new NEO variant. A320 and A321 NEO Announcement The major highlight of the roadmap is the announcement of an all-new A320 and A321 NEO. After extensive research and development, Fenix has created a completely new “NEO” standard ECAM system from the ground up, which is independent of ProSim. This advancement allows for even deeper system modeling. This is not merely an updated A320 CEO with new engines; it is a fully developed A320 NEO simulation. According to Fenix, the entire aircraft has been rewired, encompassing every sensor and generator. They have also developed a fully functional DRAIMS panel, although visuals are not yet available for display. Both the CFM LEAP engine and the Pratt and Whitney Geared Turbofan will be fully represented in the simulation. Additionally, the Fenix A320 NEO will be a standalone product, meaning that prior ownership of the A320 CEO family is not a requirement. Upcoming Big Fenix Update Fenix has announced that a major update for the A320 CEO family will be released in a couple of weeks. This update will include the addition of A139 sharklets, the implementation of the Weather Radar, and new landing dynamics that enhance flare and ground effect behavior. Several upgrades to the Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) will also be introduced, such as support for Lido charts and a improvedV-Speeds calculations. Additionally, there will be audio improvements, including a new 3D AEVC soundscape for the flight deck and a redesigned IAAE V2500 soundset. Fenix says they will provide a full changelog shortly. ‍ For more details on the Fenix A320 NEO and A321 NEO, along with the upcoming big Fenix update, refer to Fenix’s website. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/305106</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/305106"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67e1b6ddb846c49b9cce2201_filly.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued another update to their A350 Airliner add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, introducing an autosave system, bug fixes, major system refinements, and more. Update v1.0.6 is the most significant update yet, bringing a powerful and flexible autosave system with user-configurable time intervals, saving the full state of the aircraft, including system variables and position data. It bypasses the default save/load system, warranting full control and fidelity of all systems. Furthermore, the update also brings a wealth of bug fixes, further refinements on many departments (systems, art, etc), and much more. The complete changelog follows below: v1.0.6Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️Fixed - During an Autoland the RETARD callout should play at 10ft, not any higherFixed - Issue with swapping SEC in edge casesFixed - SEC PERF missing some computed valuesFixed – Tweaked LDA approaches logicFixed – LS button logic adjustmentsFixed – Tweaking Manual ENG startFixed - FPLN formatting incorrect in TRK/DIST sectionFixed - Editing RNP accuracy doesn't saveFixed - Taxi camera light linked to main taxi lightFixed - Issue with NEXT WPT input nbr 2Fixed - F-PLN INFO btn on the active fplan logicFixed - Route summary  formatting incorrectFixed - OIS screen movement feedback 2Fixed - Issue with NEXT WPT input nbr 1Fixed - Route summaries in the SEC flight plan bugFixed - FCU MACH PRESEL is not workingFixed - WASM Crash - EFIS Exception - Undo on TMPYFixed - Undoing more than one action causes a blank TMPY f-plnFixed - Up and down double chevrons on sec f-plan aren't working correctlyFixed - Clearing top line in MFD behaviourFixed - Turning SPD knob while on managed speed issueFixed - Signs in auto show as on in cabinFixed - CABIN READY message does not reset after landing. If doing a second leg it will still display even though the passengers have not boarded etc.Fixed - Swap DB confirmation box issueFixed - Pull speed knob selects managed instead of current speedFixed - VD bracket behaviour incorrect when reaching destinationFixed - TRAF button should turn on when ADIRS line upFixed - Major: MLG sinks too much into the ground during touch downFixed - A359/K Bogie animation on landing gear sinks into ground on touch-downFixed - Gravity feeding and balancing bugFixed - Can't turn on Display Fix anymoreFixed - GSX/Push back causing damage to tires in FS24 meaning user is unable to taxiFixed - F-PLN INTERCEPT time on FIX INFO page incorrectFixed - Incorrect MORA range shown in NDFixed - Ability to type using your keyboard on the RH side display.Fixed - FADEC powering up timings adjusted per further dataFixed - Checklist typoFixed - Allow scrolling in dropdown using scroll handleFixed - Not sensed ABN list issueFixed - 1 window missing inside paneFixed - FAP screen texturesFixed - CAB PRESS indicator in door lights up depending on distanceFixed - Cathay livery, forward bulkhead low res textFixed - Incorrect SLIDE ARMED door indication by the doorFixed - Add Gear Bay Light to both 900 and 1000Fixed - Doors armed in EFB bugAddition – More technical ECAMS (HYD)Fixed - STATUS page items should update while a failure is activeFixed - PRIM 3 should fail if DC1 failsFixed - GREEND HYD LO PRESS doesn't have the LDG GRVTY EXTEND deferred itemFixed - the STATUS page should show deferred itemsFixed - FO Side OIS GSX menu disappearing mid-flightFixed-  reset NG code buttonFixed - Options page for CalloutsFixed - ZFWCG with GSX fuelingFixed- -1000 variant maintenance page to include correct number of tiresFixed - OIS Maintenance: disable options in flight or with engines runningFixed - Added mouse position cursors to OISFixed - Added GND SPLRs FAULT logic to failureFixed - FUEL R(L) MAIN+STBY PMP FAULT failures items now differentiate correctly between pumps abnormal off or failedFixed - PRIMs/SECs should show fail only in flight or on ground with engines on (verified from real aircraft)Fixed - FAP not functionalFixed - FAP - Cabin Lighting levels not changing w/ FAPFixed -  Add "Set Default Panel State" optionFixed - FAP not working for cabin lights?Fixed - FAP: Avionics bay and cargo bay lights not workingFixed- OIS full load pax numbers per class does not add up 3D Art 🎨🖌️Fixed -  Brake Fans Spinning Texture ImprovedFixed - APU Cowling AnimationFixed -  Slat Positions IncorrectFixed- RAT Animation adjustmentsFixed- APU stairs characterFixed - window missing paneFixed - White livery business class seat numberingFixed - cab press and arming indicatorsFixed - door press and arming logicFixed - engine cowling not being lit up by landing lightFixed - wing lights disappearing before fx takes overFixed -  FS24 added cabin rainAdded - MLG lights (minor)Added: APU manNote: Chocks may not appear visually in some instances. Under review. Sounds 🔊Improvement - Hydraulic sound overhaulFixed - No hyd yellow noiseFixed -  external hydraulic sound distancingFixed - Exterior engine shutdown sound improvedFixed - Improved exterior sound leaking insideFixed - Rain sounds more noticeable in various situationsFixed - Increased levels of spoiler dragFixed - Improved faders of various system soundsFixed - Wiper volume increaseFixed - more ambient sound to respective volume slidersFixed - Increased vol of both low and higher type AP discFixed -  distancing of exterior ambient soundsFixed - event coning of some exterior sounds (were going mute aft of aircraft)Fixed - 90-60 altitude callouts added ‍ They have also recently shared a roadmap for the A350’s development, promising a bunch of new features, more ECAM logic, geo-specific GPS jamming, new features, etc, as per the image below: The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/stsbov</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Bovec Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/stsbov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67eb0d3ca829f44b5b577767_bovec1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. ST Simulations recently released their rendition of Bovec Airport (LJBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which serves the municipality of Tolmin in Slovenia. Built in 1962, Bovec is an important airfield in the country. It is located in the Slovenian Julian Alps at an elevation of nearly 1450 feet, which makes it perfect for parachuting events (which are held yearly) and general aviation. Its single 900x40-meter asphalt runway and slightly high elevation make it a great challenge regardless of the size of the airplane. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models and an up-to-date ground layout. It also offers performance-friendly optimization with MSFS 2024’s new LOD system, a custom hangar with an interior, landside buildings, custom objects, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.79, requiring at least 349.29 MB of free hard disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crj041</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases CRJ V2 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crj041"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ec63171d5d53f777a4e4e1_crj1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has recently issued a major update to their CRJ 550/700/900/1000 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing a list of improvements, compatibility with MSFS 2024, and much more. Version 2 features a fully remodeled cabin (on a per-variant basis), a revised flight model based on the simulator’s new aerodynamics, full Navigraph charts implementation, partial GSX integration, weather radar, a landing distance calculator, extensive customization options for knob acceleration, sounds, autopilot configuration, throttle calibration, etc. The full changelog follows below: The update is free for V1 owners, and new customers can acquire it directly from the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $50.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vol111</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta Tracking Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vol111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ede84006d2282d11f6d3c5_social.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx recently updated Volanta with a real-time tracking feature for premium members, polling the aircraft’s position locally every second. The new update also brings several bug fixes and new enhancements. Update 1.11 is one of Volanta’s most significant updates yet, featuring real-time tracking for premium members, improved map performance, ultra-low hardware usage when minimized, 3D mode tweaks, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Volanta can be downloaded for free on their website. Certain features require a premium membership.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp1222</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.2.0 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp1222"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67ef0ee9572b607093dd0c18_lgt1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research recently released a major update to X-Plane 12, which brings massive improvements to cloud rendering, lighting, environmental effects, and graphics performance. Their graphics team has been working to mitigate the famed dark cockpit issue, bringing significantly improved interior rendering quality. The light coming into the cockpit correctly follows the aircraft's contours and structural details. Furthermore, the graphics engine's exposure handling has also been improved, bringing exposure fusion—a familiar feature on most modern smartphones—to the virtual realm of X-Plane 12. It consists of taking multiple photos at various levels of exposure and then automatically stitching them together, yielding a potentially impressive-looking result.  The sky brightness has also been tweaked to ensure it's more natural and doesn't burn people's retinas. Ground object brightness values have also been tweaked to ensure they are not overly bright. Their graphics engine as a whole has also undergone changes, with an upgrade to their shader compiler, which manages resources more efficiently and thus brings smoother performance figures. Texture handling has also been tweaked to ensure faster loading times and more efficient rendering. Their VRAM management method has also been tweaked, ensuring it prioritizes smaller memory requests before large ones, aiding total memory allocation. Additionally, it makes multiple attempts to allocate memory before giving up, allowing the system to free up space when needed and ultimately reduce the chances of blurry textures or slow performance overall. The cloud rendering system has also been changed, with a small radius surrounding the camera's viewport sporting high-quality clouds, nearly eliminating cloud pixelation effects around the airplane. They hint at it being a stepping stone to other cool rendering effects in the future. Last but not least, they have also changed how their light rendering system works by breaking them into tiles, yielding better performance in demanding environments such as large airports and cities. In addition, they have also made minor changes to colors, bringing more realistic color accuracy, improved sky rendering, better cloud shadows, cloud shadows on clouds, cloud-aware ambient light, and more realistic shadows overall. Detail has also been enhanced on surface textures around airports, and weather effects now also show outside of the airport's area, accumulating on main roads, as suggested by the community. ‍ The complete changelog follows below: ‍ Known Issues ‍ Fixes and Enhancements General ‍ Graphics ‍ ‍ Scenery ‍ The update is currently available on the public_beta branch on Steam. Laminar customers can get the update by toggling “Check for new betas as well as updates”. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350107</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350107"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f3036d228ee951d79aa105_stairs1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds recently issued a new update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This is their last weekly build for the foreseeable future as they work on a longer-term—and more substantial—patch. Update v1.0.7 brings enhanced SimBrief integration (you can now plan your flight directly from the EFB), integrated air stairs for people without GSX (only available with GSX disabled for the same reason), and reintroduced engine and pitot cover logic using MSFS 2024’s SDK. The airplane’s FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator) bug was wholly mitigated, with no issues on the flare, land, and rollout modes.  The complete changelog follows below: v1.0.7 Systems &amp; EFB ⚙️🖥️ Fixed – FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator) bug: We’ve fully resolved issues related to the Flare, Land, and Rollout modes. A logic bug previously caused the Flare mode to not display correctly on the FMA, even though it was functioning in the background. This is now fixed and displayed correctly in all landing scenarios.  ‍ Fixed – Flex Temp  Output: We’ve corrected an issue where incorrect Flex Temperature values were affecting the engine power rating. The system now provides accurate thrust settings based on the entered Flex Temp.Fixed - No confirmation box when deleting pilot stored elementsFixed - SEC/Wind data bug fixedFixed - CRZ temp range on INIT page bug ranges fixed Fixed - Add door variables to autosaves Fixed - ETA box overlapping on oceanic requestFixed - Route uplink FMS message missing bug fixed Fixed - Up and down double chevrons on sec f-plan aren't working correctly fixed Fixed - PFD ALT flashing box feedbackFixed - Step alt revision menu bug Fixed - Selecting TERR off in SURV still have terrain visible on NDFixed - Manual time selection memo missing on WDFixed - SD Position/Time date format Fixed - D-ATIS unread message behaviour Fixed - Callsign not imported properlyFixed - Glideslope aural alert being triggered prematurelyFixed - D-ATIS envelope behaviour when message is readFixed - FMA logic with FD from cold and dark stateAdded - GRID heading display on ND for polar flightsFixed - CRZ TEMP format issue at INIT pageFixed - Direct to a waypoint with approach armed logic wrongFixed -  Strobe light/beacon sync timing not using correct logicAdded – FMS Store route ability added Fixed – GA soft mode bugs Fixed - ENG fire test feedback implemented Fixed - Heatblur excessive in some cases Fixed - Check "toggle autopilot" logicFixed - OIS cursor behind keyboardFixed -  Parking brake ECAM bug Fixed – TORA value changing bug fixed for TO PERF (previously not working)Fixed - Chocks not always visible when selectedFixed - Fuel panel does not open during GSX refuellingFixed - GSX Loadsheet page integration updated and improveFixed - Added new ECAMs and CategorisationFixed - Removed some excessive debugging to improve perfPartial Fix - Introducing some key adjustments for early rotation in some cases. (WIP and will be refined further).Added - GROUND page submenu will flash yellow when GSX requires user input 3D Art 🎨🖌️Added -  Engine coversFixed -  Collision mesh in FS2024 not workingFixed -  Add 3D models of pilots in cockpit from outside viewFixed - Pilot model in Drone/Showcase camera - sunk in cockpit Sounds 🔊Fixed - Hydraulic sound to sys slider / volume/positioning adjustFixed - Fixed cockpit rain event cue not workingFixed - Rain base level adjustImprovement - Improved sys and engine faders on shutdownFixed - Fixed glareshield knob rotary soundsFixed - Fire test sound adjustmentsFixed - Fixed ECP ALL pb making a double click soundFixed - Fixed engine light off sound timing when coolingAdded - Fixed MX call tone missingFixed - Fixed call button interaction too quietImprovement - Edits to cabin announcement clipsFixed - FS24 A359 Cabin announcement distancing tweak in business classFixed - Reduced audio ducking of cabin and packs ambience at higher N1Fixed - Fixed wiper sound inconsistency at fast settingFixed - Fixed wiper sound positioningFixed - Fixed wiper sound doubling on fast modeFixed  - Fixed oxy test sound would play from interacting with oxy percentage buttonFixed - Excessive wait for AP disconnect CRC and warning Improvement – Overhauled engine start soundsFixed - ENG Fire test sound feedbackFixed - Flap sounds overpower interior engine soundsFixed – Ground roll (taxi) sample repetitiveness. The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbgpl</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Global Power Lines for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbgpl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f30b0e7e45b39b5eaa9034_power1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released a realistic pack of Power Lines for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The pack replaces the generic power tower models in the simulator with highly detailed, handcrafted 3D models, aiding VFR navigation and low-level flying. The package features 19 unique tower types for realistic regional variation, with an extended draw distance for improved visibility, performance-friendly optimization (no performance impact), and the promise of ongoing updates with additional towers and refinements. Furthermore, it comes with a management tool for adjusting specific settings, such as wire omission in certain cases.  Microsoft Flight Simulator’s data set still controls their placement and orientation, as placing them manually would require over 100 GB of additional data and significantly impact the overall performance.  The add-on is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $8.38, requiring at least 103.38 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeedlw</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Dortmund Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeedlw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f4e4183593a99a5d0b7617_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has recently released its rendition of Dortmund Airport (EDLW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Located only 6.2 miles east of Dortmund, this international airport serves over 3 million passengers each year. The airport began its first commercial flights in 1925, and service continued to expand until the Second World War, during which it served as a German airbase. After the war, commercial service to the airport was not reinstated until 1979. Construction of a new terminal started in 1998 and was completed in 2000. Since then, the airport has experienced rapid growth in traffic. Today, airlines such as Condor, Eurowings, Wizz Air, and many others provide a variety of year-round and seasonal destinations, resulting in over 3 million passengers traveling through the airport each year. The scenery includes various features such as terminal interiors, animated passengers, custom jetways, functional VDGS, a custom GSX profile, and much more. The newly released rendition of Dortmund Airport is now available from Aerosoft for approximately $13.75. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aeeddl</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Düsseldorf Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aeeddl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f79a478fc41918dd7ee9bc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has just released its latest scenery: Düsseldorf Airport (EDDL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. As the fourth busiest airport in Germany, it welcomes over 19 million passengers each year, thanks to more than 150,000 annual aircraft movements. The airport opened in 1927 and welcomed its first international flights two years later, in 1929. As World War II approached, the airport ceased operations for civil aviation in 1939. However, it reopened for civilian use in 1948. From 1969 to 1986, the airport underwent significant developments, including a runway extension and the addition of three new terminals, reflecting the rapid increase in air traffic. In subsequent years, the airport has continued to expand and improve, with the construction of a new parking garage, railway station, and more. Today, it serves as a base for airlines such as Condor, Corendon Airlines, Eurowings, SunExpress, and TUI fly Deutschland, among others, offering numerous destinations around the globe. The scenery features a detailed recreation of Düsseldorf Airport, including accurate airport buildings and facilities, an updated airport layout, custom terrain elevation mesh, custom aerial imagery, custom jetway models, and more. The newly released version of Düsseldorf Airport is now available from Aerosoft for approximately $18.53. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pfs600</id>
    <title>Propair Flight Releases Shark 600 for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pfs600"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f7a44f8ae921fb2be68cb1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Propair Flight has released its Shark 600 add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. The ultralight aircraft, produced by Shark.Aero, is now available for flight simulation enthusiasts in the virtual sky. The Shark 600 is a two-seat aircraft manufactured by Shark.Aero. As a lightweight aircraft, it is designed for efficiency, high speed, and comfort. The Shark 600 also incorporates modern technology, ensuring it meets the latest standards in aviation. The add-on includes a 3D model based on the real aircraft, detailed textures, animations, a custom Dynon SkyView HDX avionics suite, a custom flap system, and more. The new Shark 600 from Propair Flight is now available on the Propair Flight website for $5.53. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/imkdfw</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Releases Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/imkdfw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67f9662923c500293d805c4a_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Imaginesim has just released its version of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. It is the third busiest airport in the world in terms of passenger traffic and aircraft movements. Last year, nearly 88 million passengers travelled through the airport. Planning for the airport began in 1927, but the plans underwent numerous revisions over the years, delaying construction until 1969. After several years of discussions, planning, and construction, the airport finally opened in 1974. At the time of its opening, it was the largest airport in the world by land area. Since then, the airport has experienced significant growth in traffic, and various expansion projects are currently underway or planned for the future. Today, the airport serves a variety of airlines, accommodating nearly 88 million passengers annually through just over 743,000 aircraft movements. The scenery package includes a variety of features, such as highly detailed terminals, high-definition texturing, custom SafeGate™ Visual Docking Guidance, and custom jetways, among many others. A version for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is also in development, and it will be available as a free upgrade for current owners. Additionally, animations for the Skylink train are in progress. The newly released Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 is now available from Imaginesim for approximately $32.64. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdoc3</id>
    <title>PMDG Unveils Operations Center 3.0</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdoc3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67536d0cda476a2b5d5c3f25_frei5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. PMDG recently unveiled its new Operations Center 3.0, a complete overhaul of their product management application, which has been roughly the same since 2017. The new application features a fresh design, additional diagnostic tools, in-software add-on installation, streamlined livery handling, and much more. The rollout from OC2 to OC3 will be gradual, with the 777F being the first product to transition to the new suite. People who might be interested in checking the new Operations Center are instructed to uninstall their 777F, download OC3 from here, install it, enter their PMDG credentials, and then install the 777F from there. The 777-300ER will follow shortly (within the next few days), and once it is available, the procedure is expected to be the same as the one listed above. ‍ PMDG will also provide full documentation on operating the new Operations Center, which is said to be available “in time for the weekend.” ‍ As they move their entire product line to OC3, installers will no longer be available once the rollout is complete, as they want people managing their product line straight from OC3. ‍ They also hint at making a new 777 available soon, with “more news on that on the next update.” If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsesae</id>
    <title>FlightSimExpo 2025 Schedule and Addon Experiences Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsesae"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67faceea35be38addd774d5d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The schedule for the upcoming FlightSimExpo 2025 has been announced, along with various addon experiences that will soon be available for booking. New information about the three-day event has just been revealed. A seminar schedule has been shared, outlining what to expect on each day of the event. On Friday, attendees can look forward to a range of product reveals, announcements, and updates covering various software and hardware developments. Saturday and Sunday will feature exhibits, seminars, and workshops. The schedule for the Community Stage is available now available online, while the schedules for the FSElite Stage and the SayIntensions.AI Stage will be announced closer to the event. In addition, several different addon experiences have been announced. These activities are available alongside the main event and include options such as tours at the local airport, workshops, and more. Registration for these experiences will open on April 19th at 12 PM ET. You can find more information about the various experiences here. As we look forward to all that the FlightSimExpo 2025 has to offer, more information about the event is available on the official website.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pd2024</id>
    <title>PMDG Shares Development Update for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pd2024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67fad7245aa3ed1bc5dbd717_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG has recently released another development update regarding nearly all of its products for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. Key highlights from the update include the announcement of a release window for the upcoming PMDG 777-200ER for both MSFS 2020 and 2024, as well as a rollout sequence for the product line tailored for MSFS 2024. The development team has announced that the 777-200ER will be released simultaneously for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, with the launch expected between April 16th and April 29th. The add-on will feature different engine types, including the GE90-92 and the Rolls Royce Trent 892. Additionally, it will include a new generation of sound packages. There will be only one package available, which will include versions for both simulators. With the release of the first PMDG product for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 approaching, the team has announced a rollout schedule for their product lineup. The expected release dates are as follows:  ‍ - The 777-200ER is anticipated between April 16th and April 29th. - The DC-6 is scheduled for early May. - The 777F and 777-300ER are expected to be released between mid and late May. - The 777-200LR will be available from late May to early June. - The 737NGs do not yet have an estimated arrival time, as their conversion to 2024 has not yet begun. The team has announced that the 747 product lines will only be developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and not for 2020. Additionally, the PMDG Operations Center 3 has been expanded to include the 777F and 777-300ER. The DC-6 and all 737NG variants will be added very soon. Once these aircraft are added to OC3, they will be removed from OC2. We will inform you if we receive any further details about upcoming updates and releases. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
