<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-02-09T18:26:52.827477+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avapia</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces Release Date for Upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avapia"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c91d63c4ee07a49406e99_pia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightFX recently announced a release date for their upcoming Piaggio Avanti II for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, along with the release of a launch trailer and pricing information. The Piaggio Avanti II is an evolution of the Piaggio Avanti, originally introduced in late 1990 after four years of flight testing. The original concept goes even further back to 1979, when engineering studies started, and design choices were tested in wind tunnels in the subsequent years by Professor Jan Roskam from the University of Kansas and Professor Gerald Gregorek from Ohio State University. The final design choice was finally made in 1982, with the fuselage development starting a year later. The first prototype only took off in 1986, with the Italian certification to come in early 1990. The Avanti II got certified in late 2005, featuring an uprated Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-66B turboprop engines, flying faster and more economically, and a new Rockwell Collins glass cockpit set. With 70 planes ordered in the first few months after the certification, the fastest civilian turboprop twin (according to Flying Magazine) was rather successful. The add-on promises a faithful recreation of the Piaggio Avanti II. It will be available in the MSFS Marketplace for $24.99 next Thursday (06/02).‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2uni</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases University of Illinois Willard Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2uni"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c96d1974e436502d15024_uni1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. UK2000 Scenery recently released their rendition of the University of Illinois Willard Airport (KCMI), serving the Urbana metropolitan area, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020.  While it was dedicated in late 1945, airline flights were to start nearly a decade later, in 1954, albeit in a very barebones manner, as the passenger terminal was only erected in 1960. By the late 1960s, Willard was the second-busiest airport in the state. However, it crumbled within a decade after the Airline Deregulation Act of 1978. Airlines found service to smaller airports inefficient and expensive. Airfares went up, whereas they went down at bigger airports like Chicago O’Hare, quickly killing the demand and leading many airlines to leave the airport altogether. A new passenger terminal was built in the late 1980s and remains used today. Until eleven years ago, the airport was home to the University of Illinois Institute of Aviation, which was voted by trustees to be closed in 2011, and everything was transferred over to Parkland College in 2013 so that the enrolled students could complete their courses.  Parkland College still operates the airport, providing an annual subsidy of $433,000. It’s currently served by a single airline, American Eagle, which flies passengers to Chicago O’Hare and Dallas/Fort Worth.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with full-detail buildings, realistic ground markings, performance-friendly optimization, custom vegetation, PBR materials, custom static aircraft, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.84, requiring at least 70.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mci224</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Kansas City International Airport V2 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mci224"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679c9bb1bd800d775e97af72_kanser1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. TropicalSim has recently released an updated version of their Kansas City International Airport (KMCI) V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The airport is the second busiest in Missouri after St. Louis, with a yearly average of 9 million passengers. The newly released version brings the airport layout up to current standards, with the new single terminal opened in 2023 that replaces Terminals B and C, with 40 gates in total. It also uses new SDK features such as the new LOD system, night lighting improvements, and ground layout edits to match the latest satellite imagery, excludes, and vegetation.  Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier, JetBlue, Southwest, Spirit, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express currently serve it. SWA has the majority of the market share, with 45.43% of the traffic figures, followed by American and Delta, which have 14.27% and 14.08%, respectively. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the new airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, native MSFS24 night lighting, PBR texturing, custom jetways, and a custom interior. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.91 and requires at least 457.73 MB of free hard disk space to install. V2 for MSFS 2020 owners are entitled to a free upgrade, and V1 owners can purchase the new scenery for a discounted price of $17.28. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rafhon</id>
    <title>IM Scenery Releases RAF Honington for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rafhon"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/679ca2f0e51d1bb0e7efbc6f_hon1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IM Scenery recently released their rendition of RAF Honington (EGXH), a Royal Air Force station in Suffolk, England, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024.  Construction started in 1935 and was undertaken by John Laing &amp; Son, an investment group now known as John Laing Group, which boasts 177 years of history. The opening occurred two years later, nearly right in time for the beginning of World War 2. Based in Honington at the start of the war, the IX Squadron ran the first British bombing raid of the Second World War, attacking the Kriegsmarine in the Baltic. In 1942, the airfield was transferred to the United States Army Air Forces and upgraded to a class A Bomber base. It was eventually transferred back to the RAF once the war was over, primarily utilized by the RAF Transport Command and later by the RAF Bomber Command in 1949. In the 1950s, a 9,000 ft concrete runway was built and completed in 1956. In the 1980s, it was selected to become a base for the RAF’s Panavia Tornado fleet, with the IX Squadron being reformed there and becoming the world’s first operational Tornado squadron. ‍ In mid-1992, it was decided that Honington would become an RAF Regiment Depot, with the Tornado fleet wholly leaving the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully custom objects with PBR textures, custom night lighting, custom ground poly, custom terraforming, and custom static aircraft. It’s available on Contrail for roughly $8.30, requiring at least 712.1 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42cpm</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Publishes Introduction to ChasePlane for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42cpm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a03568493d826e0a991328_cp1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Parallel 42 has recently published a blog article providing more information on their recently announced ChasePlane plugin for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, covering its features, MSFS 2024 compatibility info, and lots of in-game footage. They start by mentioning that their teaser was only teasing the cinematics system, which is one of the possibilities offered by their new product: switching effortlessly between cockpit view, external angles, and even airport cameras if you so desire. Custom presets can be easily created and shared online with seamless bind controls. ‍ For the unfamiliar, ChasePlane was originally released in 2016 for Microsoft Flight Simulator X, later being made compatible with Prepar3d and rapidly becoming the de facto camera application for ESP-based simulators at the time. It would only be natural for them to develop it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 when that came about, but technical limitations have made that impossible until very recently, which is why it’s only a thing now, almost five years after the simulator’s release.  ‍ ChasePlane will initially be released for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 only, but they do have Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 in mind and already have a working build, albeit unstable due to the simulator’s very early nature. That makes it hard for them to commit to a public release, as an update could break everything. “We can’t afford to waste time chasing a moving target,” concluded Edson Soriano, Parallel 42’s Managing Director. Due to platform limitations, ChasePlane will not be compatible with Xbox.  ‍ The add-on will feature a highly realistic physics-based camera behavior based on extensive research and real-world pilot footage, warranting realistic motion that dynamically responds to the environment, embracing the flight model rather than altering it. Pilots can feel the vibration during the take-off roll, the rush of turbulence, and the fluid shifts during maneuvers. They have embedded videos demonstrating the camera system on the “realistic” preset with different aircraft and conditions. Users can adjust the settings regarding intensities, etc., with sliders. The complete feature list for the product follows below: ‍ They have not yet been able to provide information on a potential release date or pricing, but it’s said to be coming soon.  ‍ Parallel 42 is ensuring the software is stable through extensive beta testing, ensuring it’s launched in a relatively solid state, thus creating a smooth sailing experience for the customers. They are currently working on refining the user interface, polishing features, and ensuring overall smoothness on a wide range of hardware. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfhav2</id>
    <title>Just Flight Announces V2 Update for Hawk T1/A</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfhav2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a0e6befa9df6d7d57b7c1a_image1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has announced a significant update, version 2, for its Hawk T1/A advanced trainer. This update introduces a variety of changes, the most notable being the addition of MSFS 2024 support. ‍ New and improved flight model According to Just Flight, the original flight model was no longer working as well as it used to, prompting the team to completely redesign it from the ground up. The team emphasises that the Hawk still must be flown in a realistic manner, just as it was before. New weapons functionality You can now fire Sidewinder missiles, drop practice bombs, and jettison payloads. The static weapons are also included in the PC and Xbox Marketplace versions, though they won't have animation. ‍ New liveries The following liveries have been added to the Hawk T1/A Advanced Trainer: Green smoke is now available with the Saudi Falcons livery. There are limits on the amount of smoke that can be produced per flight, just as in real life. Options to refill or enable unlimited smoke are also included. ‍EFB improvements ‍Version 3 of Just Flight’s EFB now includes a redesigned interface and features such as Navigraph enroute charts. ‍ ‍MSFS 2024 compatibility ‍Just Flight states that the aircraft will be available from third-party retailers as well as through the MSFS 2020 marketplace. It will also be offered in the MSFS 2024 marketplace once that becomes available. Current owners can download the updated aircraft for free from the Just Flight website, with the update soon to be available from third parties. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asrwi2</id>
    <title>Astralis Studios Previews Region of Waterloo International for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asrwi2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a0ec4443dfbc3c35f6cf94_Screenshot_2025-02-02_204543.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Astralis Studios has recently showcased their upcoming Region of Waterloo International Airport (CYKF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This airport serves Kitchener-Waterloo and surrounding areas seeing 118,541 aircraft movements in 2018. The airport was opened in 1930 and was used mainly for flight instruction. At the end of World War 2 there was a push for a larger and more appropriate place for private and commercial aviation in the area. In 1948, the Waterloo-Wellington Airport Commission acquired a larger site in the Breslau area and a new airfield was completed there in 1950. The then K-W Municipal Airport became a general aviation facility in 1969. Today, it is served by airlines such as WestJet, Sunwing, and Flair Airlines. Non-stop commercial flights from Waterloo include destinations such as Calgary, Vancouver, Cancun, Halifax and more. In addition to commercial traffic, the airport is a popular general aviation hub and is home to the second largest flight training centre in Canada, Waterloo Wellington Flight Centre, as well as a plethora of privately owned hangars. This scenery includes over 60 custom objects, custom ground markings, enhanced night lighting as well as PBR texturing. It will be released on February 6th and will be available for $15.99 on all platforms. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for all of your flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kra024</id>
    <title>FlyDesign Releases Krakow-Balice Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kra024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a1d90118932095932e524d_kra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FlyDesign has recently released their rendition of John Paul International Krakow-Balice Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving Kraków, Poland, with a yearly average of 11 million passengers.  Its construction started in 1964, opening for civil aviation three years later, in 1967. A passenger terminal was only built four years after its civil opening. The 1970s brought further development work to accommodate larger aircraft: a longer runway, new taxiways, and high-intensity runway lights. A new terminal was inaugurated in the late 1980s after the authorities deemed the actual capacity to be subpar compared to the projected traffic figures for the upcoming decade. Thus, it was inaugurated in 1993, followed by apron upgrades in 1995. New modernization work was carried out in 2002, focusing on improving the international passenger experience. Such effort was not in vain, and international routes increased in the following years. A separate domestic terminal (Terminal 2) was opened in 2007, and at the time, plans were underway to build an entirely new terminal in addition to Terminal 2. Ryanair opened their second Polish base in Kraków in 2012, basing two 737-800 aircraft there and connecting Kraków to many destinations across Europe.  Krakow-Balice became the first regional airport in Poland to reach over 9 million passengers yearly in 2023.  ‍ ‍ Due to the recent increase in traffic, the authorities have announced an upgrade plan to build a new terminal. The current terminal is not large enough to meet the projected demand for the future. ‍ It’s a focus city for Buzz Air (Ryanair Poland), Wizz Air, and LOT Polish Airlines. Aegean Airlines, airBaltic, Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, Swiss, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, hand-placed vegetation, fully dynamic lighting, high-definition buildings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.00, requiring at least 924.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sflphu</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Phuket International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sflphu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a1df1c67b05e122e6a0820_phu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SiamFlight recently released their rendition of Phuket International Airport (VTSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves the island of Phuket, Thailand, and has a yearly average of 17.2 million passengers, making it the third busiest airport in Thailand. Built in 1988 to accommodate only 6.5 million passengers yearly, it operated nearly at capacity for almost 30 years, until a new expansion project brought the figures to 20 million passengers per year (12.5 million passengers on the new terminal, 6.5 on the old one). It currently has three terminals: Terminal 2 handles international flights, Terminal 3 handles domestic operations, and Terminal X exclusively handles charters. Due to space constraints, Phuket has reached its capacity limit, which led the authorities to consider a rail link to Krabi International Airport for traffic alleviation in the near – or distant – future. In addition to the link, there’s a plan to build an entirely new airport elsewhere to serve Phang Nga, Phuket, and Krabi. It was supposed to be a multi-phase project, with phase one to start in 2022 and reach completion by 2025, but everything was indefinitely put on hold.  It’s a focus city for Thai Airways International and an operating base for Bangkok Airways, Thai Lion Air, and Thai AirAsia. Aeroflot, Air Arabia,  Air China, Air India, Azur Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Condor, Emirates, HK Express, IndiGo, Jetstar, Korean Air, Mahan Air, Nok Air, Qatar Airways, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, TUI, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terminals with an interior, custom ground textures, custom jetways, landside buildings, hand-placed taxiway guidance signs, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.38, requiring at least 196.68 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rwa350</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces the Release Window and Price Range for their A350</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rwa350"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a4dbf809e49f35e64e9429_471422468_1095337999269447_6998084516673360667_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IniBuilds recently announced the release window and price range for their highly anticipated A350, during a recent livestream event. While a replay of the stream is not available, highlights will be uploaded to their YouTube channel. IniBuilds aims to release the product by the end of February, with a price set at under $83 (Excl. VAT). Both the -900 and -1000 variants will be available at launch for MSFS 2020 and 2024. Customers will receive both variants through a single purchase.  ‍ Initially, the aircraft will be available on PC through the IniManager software, with a marketplace release planned for a later date. IniBuilds also emphasized that MSFS 2024 for PC is their primary development platform, which may result in some features being unavailable on MSFS 2020 or the Xbox versions. The iniBuilds A350 has been one of the most anticipated addon aircraft for MSFS, since its announcement in late 2023, with iniBuilds aiming to develop the first study-level A350 aircraft for MSFS. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxerj</id>
    <title>FlightFX Announces Embraer 145 as Next Project</title>
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxerj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a5282ddeffbd513d5f49da_0E145_flyer.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlightFX has announced their next project to be the Embraer E145 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This announcement coincides with the release of their long-awaited Piaggio P180. The Embraer E145 is the largest member in the Embraer ERJ family. It first flew in August of 1995 and entered service two years later with Continental Express. The aircraft seats 50 passengers, has a maximum range of 1,550 nautical miles, and has a service ceiling of 37,000 feet. The aircraft is most commonly seen in North America with airlines such as American Eagle and JSX being prolific operators of the type. FlightFX announced their new project on the same day that they released their long-awaited Piaggio P180 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The developer is currently working on the Bombardier Challenger 350 and the Cessna 750 Citation. According to FlightFX CEO Nick Sdoucos, during a stream with flight simulation streamer twotonemurphyt, the Cessna 750 Citation is expected to be released in late March or early April, and its price will be $29.99. The aircraft is set to be the first high-fidelity regional jet for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The team at FlightFX currently plan to release the E145 and the E145XR. Its release is expected in the fourth quarter of 2025. Stay tuned to Threshold for all of the latest flight simulation news and updates!  ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbatl</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Atlanta International Airport for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbatl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a5bdb3d847fb25daeab4e2_jac1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx recently announced the development of Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport (KATL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The airport serves the Atlanta metropolitan area and has a yearly average of 104.6 million passengers, making it the world’s busiest airport. Developed by Matteo Veneziani, the creator of Sacramento Airport (KSMF)—previously reviewed on Threshold –, Burbank, and Olbia (also reviewed by us), Orbx’s Atlanta promises a highly detailed and fully up-to-date rendition of the airport, including the very recent Concourse T extension. Due to its single-creator nature, it claims to boast remarkable consistency across the board, with top-tier optimization and unparalleled realism. The unveiled feature list includes a fully up-to-date ground layout as of 2025, accurate ground elevation, detailed interior modeling, high-quality photorealistic textures, custom ground service equipment vehicles, and more. There is no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon. ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/afsc25</id>
    <title>Date and Location for the FS Conference 2025 Announced</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/afsc25"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a6206487d2fefed3f23e15_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The FS Conference 2025 will be the 20th edition of the event. The date and location have just been announced: it will take place on November 15th at the terminal of Paderborn Lippstadt Airport in Germany. The German flight simulator event aims to showcase the latest developments in the flight simulation community, including both hardware and software. This event also provides visitors with the opportunity to meet and interact with industry professionals. The very first FS Conference took place in 2002, and since then, the event has been held at various airports across Germany. Last year, our very own Magnus attended the FS Conference. If you are interested in learning about his experience at the event, be sure to check out his travelogue. For more information about the upcoming event, visit the official website.  ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/c/thresholdx</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl293</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl293"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6768de3df1ae2d10ada9d7bc_labsup2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FSLabs recently issued a new experimental update to their A321ceo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, which includes a series of fixes and improvements. Update v11.0.1.293 –  the fifth since its release – includes a fix for a memory leak issue when the weather radar is active, a new way to set up Thrust Lever detents via their MCDU options page, and several other fixes which were observed and thoroughly reported by the community. The full changelog follows below: The add-on is available on their website for $69.95. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon.</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/omdb24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Enhanced 2024 Version of Dubai Scenery</title>
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/omdb24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a66d895be20c00df82a27d_KDyHgLtf9WQ-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released a trailer for the Enhanced 2024 version of their Dubai Airport (OMDB) scenery, and its surrounding area, for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. IniBuilds stated “The new scenery brings a host of changes to the already impressive scenery”. These changes include an integrated Dubai landmarks pack, with the ability to be toggled on and off, a new terminal interior for Concourse A, and optimized Level of Detail (LOD) work for smoother performance.  The new version will build upon the previous MSFS 2020 version of iniBuilds' Dubai scenery. It currently features detailed ground textures, realistic airport landside elements, accurate dynamic lighting, intricately designed airport building models, and custom taxi signage. Dubai International Airport (OMDB) is one of the largest airports in the world, offering connections to over 260 destinations as of January 2024. It serves as the primary hub for Emirates, opening up for numerous routes to be flown with the upcoming iniBuilds A350. Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbemd</id>
    <title>Orbx Release Emerald Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbemd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67a7ca88e52dd7ce05062a2a_Skjermbilde%202025-02-08%20221803.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has released Emerald Airport (YEML), developed by Rob Byrne, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. Emerald Airport is situated in the Central Highlands region of Queensland, Australia, approximately 6 km south of Emerald, the main town it serves. QantasLink, Virgin Australia Regional, and Alliance Airlines operate an average of 54 return flights to Brisbane every week. The area is sparsely populated, with fewer than two inhabitants per square kilometre. Additionally, it experiences very little rainfall, averaging around 830 millimetres of precipitation per year. Orbx says Emerald Airport for MSFS offers detailed exteriors and interiors of its terminals. The airport features subtle terraforming, with night lighting for both the terminal and aprons, as well as custom ground markings. There is also custom lighting on the runway, taxiway, and aprons. ‍ In addition, the airport includes a detailed helicopter hangar, general aviation hangars, fuel facilities, and functioning anemometers that respond to changes in wind speed. ‍ A full feature list follows: The scenery can be purchased for $16.36 at the Orbx store and is compatible with both MSFS 2020 and 2024. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for news, reviews, and more. Additionally, join our vibrant community on Discord! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon</summary>
    <published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
