<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-09-14T18:29:02.354232+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bstbm4</id>
    <title>Black Square Updates TBM 850, Now Native for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bstbm4"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bc49f7fc4f8d2f46ae50bf_black-square-tbm-850-msfs-04_1600x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Black Square has released v0.1.4 of their TBM 850, introducing native MSFS 2024 support and a comprehensive list of upgrades, fixes, and quality-of-life enhancements. In the MSFS 2024 version, the new walk-around feature is fully supported, letting you interact with chocks, pitot and engine covers, door handles, baggage doors, and more. The aircraft now also has a proper collision model, allowing the walk-arounds to feel more authentic. Avionics get attention too. The Bendix/King KAS 297B now supports vertical speed arming, while new GTNxi 750 and 650 bezels are included, alongside an improved model-switching method. Black Square has also introduced Magnetic Compass Effects, with physics filtering and realistic interference from onboard fields, so your whiskey compass behaves like the real thing. Inside the cabin, interior lighting has been retooled for MSFS 2024, and the EFB tablet has received upgrades. This includes an Ear Discomfort Index on the visualiser page, payload unit selection that persists between sessions, and an option to enable exterior registration meshes, as a workaround for a known MSFS 2024 dynamic registration bug. There is also a fix for 2024’s light-flare bleed-through. V0.1.4 also adds engine-driven fuel pump failure modelling, with corresponding visualiser behaviour. It also introduces custom toe-brake animations and sounds to stop jitter, along with a revised torque source, for faster indication changes. Black Square has corrected cases where a complete electrical failure would inhibit essential variables from updating, restored air conditioning operation on ground power, and tied the cooling turbine to proper bleed-air logic. Fuel pressure and pump cycling now behave correctly when tanks are empty or the selector is off. The TBM 850 v0.1.4 update is available now for all existing customers. You can pick up the aircraft on Contrail for $42.14, including taxes, and it is also offered through other stores, such as Just Flight. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhhems</id>
    <title>LHSimulations Releases HEMSOB Pack Hungary for MSFS 2020, 2024 to follow</title>
    <updated>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhhems"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bc51d02f2a7ee49b2ff46e_lh20_7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. LHSimulations has released its HEMSOB Pack Hungary for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020, adding three authentic emergency medical bases to the sim.  Designed for realistic scenarios, the pack gives a look into air ambulance operations across Hungary. Support for MSFS 2024 is planned, though the team says a technical issue has caused a short delay. The acronym HEMSOB stands for Helicopter Emergency Medical Service Operational Base, facilities designed for air ambulance crews to launch rapid-response missions from. The pack, developed in close cooperation with the Hungarian Air Ambulance Nonprofit Ltd., recreates three real-world bases used by EC135 crews in Hungary. These include Budaörs (LH10), the country’s main HEMS base, located just west of Budapest, Balatonfüred (LH20), which covers the busy Lake Balaton region, and Marcali (LH30), providing coverage for the southwest of the country. Each base features accurate buildings, hangars, ground textures, and realistic helipads, complete with ambient details, such as fencing, lighting, and parked vehicles. For added immersion, you can even open the hangar doors yourself, using COM1 set to 128.15.. Beyond the visuals, LHSimulations has leaned on authentic references, to create a faithful representation of Hungarian HEMS operations. The bases were built with input from active crews, in pursuit of also making the scenery a tribute to the Hungarian Air Ambulance.  Each base is equipped with an animated heliport transfer platform, a movable dolly, often running on tracks, that allows the helicopter to land outside, and then be transferred into the hangar. For sim pilots, this means a perfect environment to practise medevac scenarios and low-level VFR, or simply explore Hungary with a helicopter.  The HEMSOB Pack Hungary is available exclusively through the in-sim Marketplace for $19.50, including taxes. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/milsep</id>
    <title>Miltech Simulations Releases September Dev Blog, UH-60 Announced, MH-60 Update</title>
    <updated>2025-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/milsep"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68be009ad9272b476bf4e9ad_A1H1%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Miltech Simulations has recently shared their September developer update, covering everything from Marketplace and bug fixes to brand-new aircraft announcements.  The MH-60 continues to be Miltech’s most successful release, being one of the highest-rated helicopters in the in-sim Marketplace, alongside the CH-47. Its next update will tackle a number of outstanding issues, including APU fuel valve bugs, autopilot and trim behaviour, model-matching, and stability improvements for the MFDs. PC users can also expect new explosion effects for Hellfire impacts, and engine values, such as torque and Ng, will be further fine-tuned. However, there’s a small snag with MSFS 2024 Marketplace distribution. The MH-60 has run into errors during Microsoft’s testing process, which has delayed its release on the new 2024 sim. Miltech says the Marketplace engineering team is actively investigating, and they hope to move forward soon. By popular demand, Miltech has confirmed it is working on the UH-60 Black Hawk, developed in partnership with Blackbird Simulations. The initial release will include the Alpha and Lima variants, with cockpit differences catering to different preferences. Other S-70 derivatives are not planned. While the UH-60 shares DNA with the MH-60, it comes with enough unique features to warrant a separate, standalone product. The team is currently targeting an early 2026 release, with potential discounts, for existing MH-60 owners. The first major update for Miltech’s Mission Hub is on the way, addressing bugs and stability issues while adding new assets and functionality. The tool is also heading to the Microsoft Marketplace this month. Optimisations have been made to meet Xbox’s strict performance requirements; however, Xbox users will not be able to share or download community missions at launch. Miltech is working on a cloud-based solution to bring this feature in a future update. Rounding out the blog is a detailed look at Miltech’s upcoming A-1H Skyraider, developed once again with Blackbird Simulations. Known for its ruggedness and versatility during the Korean and Vietnam Wars, the Skyraider is being faithfully recreated with an “ultra-detailed” 3D model, a flight model validated by subject matter experts, and a new soundset by Echo 19. The Skyraider will feature full weapons capability, including bombs, rockets, cannons, and even the infamous “Toilet Bomb”, as well as two Vietnam-era carriers (CV-11 Intrepid and CV-10 Yorktown), bundled at no extra cost. Mission Hub users will also get a mission pack with over 10 scenarios to fly. The Skyraider is now in its final development stages, with sound integration and documentation underway, before beta testing. The release is “not far off,” with pricing set at $24.99 via the Miltech Simulations Store, iniBuilds, Blackbird Simulations Store, and the in-sim Marketplace, for both PC and Xbox. Looking ahead, Miltech also left us with a hint that the next developer blog will bring fresh news on the CH-53, U-2, and another unannounced project. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inileedsv2</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Leeds Bradford Enhanced for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inileedsv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bf983b610f7c6111190cac_brad1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their enhanced rendition of Leeds Bradford Airport (EGNM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving North and West Yorkshire with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers. It opened in 1931 as Leeds and Bradford Municipal Aerodrome (or Yeadon Aerodrome). During its initial years, it was mostly used for general aviation and training, with scheduled flights starting in 1935. Work on the main terminal started around the late 30s but only reached full completion after WW2.  Avro constructed a shadow factory during that WW2 period called the Leeds Bradford Airport Depot, with over 5,000 aircraft before its closure in December 1946. The runway was extended in the early 1980s, allowing it to be classified as a regional airport. After the extension, Wardair commenced international flights to Toronto in a 747 in 1984. The airport underwent expansion work in the late 90s and early 2000s, allowing it to reach an 88% increase in passenger traffic by 2007 (2.9 million passengers visited the airport that year). ‍ The highest airport in the United Kingdom (681ft!) is an operating base for Jet2.com and Ryanair and is served by Aer Lingus, Aurigny, easyJet, KLM, and WizzAir. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, highly detailed models, an up-to-date layout, custom jetways, PBR texturing, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.21, requiring at least 2.68 GB of free hard disk space to install. 2020 owners who use the code EGNM-UG at checkout are eligible for a $5.49 upgrade path.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/su4m24</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 4 Beta for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/su4m24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c061390422b706c39b6de7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft has just released the first beta version of Sim Update 4 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This follows the release of Sim Update 3 just a few weeks ago. The new beta version, identified as 1.6.3.0, aims to enhance stability and performance while addressing general bug fixes and implementing various other improvements. The beta update enhances stability and performance with several key improvements. It includes optimised grass rendering and performance enhancements for airports, air traffic control (ATC), aircraft, and scenery. Additionally, it optimises the main CPU thread and includes various fixes. Overall, these changes contribute to improving simulator performance. Similar to other Sim Updates and Sim Update Betas, the team has provided comprehensive release notes. For those interested in reviewing all the changes, the complete release notes can be found here.  The Sim Update 4 Beta is now available for download to those who are signed up for the beta. If you are not signed up, you can register to try the beta yourself. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx2260</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Lineup for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx2260"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c0d971eebdac2d330f27f5_1250410_20250908232701_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fenix Simulations recently issued a small update to their A320 lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, addressing an issue where certain liveries were not loading correctly, mitigating a few EFB bugs, and a couple of art &amp; sound fixes. Update 2.4.0.2260 is the second update post-BFU, further trimming the edges through a few quality of life changes and minor fixes. The complete changelog follows below: ‍Avionics and Systems ‍ Art and Sound EFB Fenix’s A320 lineup is available on their website for $120.90 (complete bundle), or $67.17 (A320 only) + $53.73 (A319+A321).  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbjwarchi24</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Jurassic World Archipelago for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbjwarchi24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c0fdae28208133d69e56c1_archi1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx recently released their virtual rendition of the Jurassic World Park for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, a partly fictional archipelago off the coast of Costa Rica with six islands. The developers bring a complete recreation of the Jurassic World archipelago, set just before the events of the 2015 movie, when the park was operational yet not entirely under control.  Besides the islands, custom airfields and helipads, highly detailed theme park structures, animated dinosaurs and reptiles roaming the land, ruins, and unique animations and visual effects, the package includes guided tours, missions, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: Featured Islands and Mainland Locations (Costa Rica): ‍ ‍ Featured Dinosaurs and Prehistoric Reptiles: ‍ ‍ Other Features: ‍ Furthermore, the Jurassic World pack integrates with Volanta’s MSFS 2024-only avatar tracking, allowing players to explore the islands in a never-before-seen manner and collect a special type of aerocache, only accessible via foot. There are multiple spread across the archipelago. The add-on is available for purchase through 4 different bundles. The cheapest bundle - retailing for $24.99 - only includes the scenery and missions. The second cheapest offers 6 months of Volanta Premium on top of the scenery for $39.99. Alternatively, you can get the PAC 750 instead of Volanta Premium for the same price. Then there’s an ultimate package, with the scenery, Volanta Premium (6 months), and the PAC 750 for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vfrgci</id>
    <title>RealVFR Releases Guernsey Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vfrgci"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c189d95af38985a5d770b5_482055989_634403019339691_4503206361353260357_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. RealVFR has recently released its rendition of Guernsey Airport (EGJB), for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. Known for bringing smaller airfields like the Isles of Scilly and Bolt Head to life, the developer has now turned its attention to one of the busiest island gateways in the region. Perched on the picturesque island of Guernsey, Guernsey combines challenging approaches with breathtaking scenery, often featuring crosswind and low visibility components. Home to Aurigny Airlines, Blue Islands, and a steady flow of visiting general aviation traffic, the airport is a hive of activity. RealVFR’s version captures that atmosphere, with a host of carefully crafted features. Expect faithfully sloped taxiways and aprons, immersive night lighting, a fully modelled ATC tower interior, and extensive use of high-quality PBR textures across every building and surface. Even the island’s iconic hedgerows have been recreated in 3D. The add-on has been designed natively for MSFS 2024, making full use of the sim’s enhanced height maps and updated lighting engine. Beyond the airport boundary, RealVFR has gone the extra mile, replacing default housing with handcrafted cottages, bungalows, churches, and more. RealVFR’s Guernsey Airport for MSFS 2024 is now available on the developer’s website, priced at $20.34. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xtpglj</id>
    <title>Xtreme Prototypes Releases Gates Learjet 25 for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xtpglj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c1a6df9f09e39ba62d1233_GLJ25_MSFS2020_01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Xtreme Prototypes, also known as XTPRO from the Prepar3D world, has released their debut aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the GLJ Model 25 Classic SE, replicating the classic Gates Learjet 20 series. Aiming to capture the jet’s “fighter in civilian clothing” characteristics, the team brings deep systems fidelity and plenty of polish. The cockpit is a retro-fitted fit-out, built around the GNS 530, with steam gauges modelled in full 3D, hundreds of animations, and comprehensive lighting with independent dimmers. Under the hood, custom systems cover electrics, hydraulics, pressurisation, anti-ice, fuel (including cross-feed and wingtip jettison), the CJ610 powerplants, and a fully modelled AFCS, with speed hold, yaw damper, and GPS/NAV modes. Sounds are authored in Wwise, and the aircraft features visual effects as well, ranging from exhaust heat and contrails to icing and rain. On the art side, XTPRO notes high-resolution PBR textures, detailed interior and exterior models, and 14 liveries. A 300-page manual (English or French) ships with the aircraft, also including a paint kit. Owners can even add their own custom GPS/radar or tweak aircraft behaviour, using the customisation kit. Note that such third-party avionics are supported, but not included. Xtreme Prototypes notes that the aircraft is built natively for MSFS 2020, though it can also be flown in MSFS 2024, using a compatible version. However, this version is not fully native, so you should expect potential bugs and quirks, and fly at your own discretion. A native 2024 version is coming soon, the team stated. You can find the aircraft manual here. For the full feature list, visit the official product page. For a classic and old-school Learjet experience, you can find the GLJ Model 25 Classic SE on Xtreme Prototypes’ website, for $36,06 USD. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddtabq</id>
    <title>DominicDesignTeam Releases Albuquerque International Sunport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddtabq"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c32a26f4d032cc952801c5_4KSeq.00_01_29_49.Still022_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. DominicDesignTeam has released a detailed rendition of Albuquerque International Sunport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing the well-known desert city a new angle in the sim. The package features high-quality PBR textures, dynamic lighting, and realistic ground markings, custom jetways, bespoke taxiway signage, and hand-crafted pavement, dirt, wear, and surface variation. You also get custom objects, passenger and bus animations, for extra life on the apron, plus tuned LODs, to keep performance smooth across a range of systems. As a quick refresher, Albuquerque Sunport is the primary gateway to New Mexico, sitting between the Rio Grande and the Sandia Mountains. With a 4,800-plus foot elevation and frequent crosswinds, the Sunport serves up lively departures and arrivals. DominicDesignTeam’s Albuquerque is available now via the iniBuilds Store for $18.94 USD. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/e19172</id>
    <title>Echo19 Releases Cessna 172 Precision Audio Pack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/e19172"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4659447cf8f96345c081c_FlightSimulator2024_2025-08-05_15-04-26_400.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Echo 19 has launched its Cessna 172 Precision Audio Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing a rich, reactive soundscape to the world’s most-flown GA aircraft.  Built on the developer’s new EchoFX system, the pack layers sounds that respond to airspeed, angle of attack, weather, and pilot inputs. Expect ground and cabin life cues like fuel slosh, seat and interior creaks, and airframe squeaks in the wind; exterior touches, such as refined control-surface stops, battery contactor clicks, and heat exchange; plus aircraft-specific details, including an accurate N-model flap motor, prop flutter in high winds, and a stall horn that varies pitch with angle of attack. Inside the cockpit, 96 kHz ambisonic captures place every switch, knob, and lever in true 3D space, for headphone and Spatial Sound users. Engine behaviour shifts with mixture and temperature, and there is also airflow noise once the air is moving, with wind layers built naturally as you accelerate. In addition, there are some handy customisation switches, such as toggling vintage-style gyro sounds via the Marker Sensitivity switch. You can also enable an alternator whine, if you fancy a little retro buzz. As a small bonus, Echo 19 also includes five liveries: four for MSFS 2024 (Classic “Ruby”, USAF Academy, Echo 19 House, and House Alt), and one for MSFS 2020 (Echo 19 House Alt). You can read the full feature list below: ‍ 🔉 ECHOFX Immersive Features 🌎Real-World Ground &amp; Cabin Life • Dirt swirl FX for grass, gravel, and paved surfaces • Airframe squeaks when parked in wind • Fuel slosh that reacts to movement and fuel quantity • Seat and interior creaks synced to cockpit motion 🛩️ Deeply Modeled 172 Characteristics  • Accurate N-model flap motor position • Prop flutter when stationary in high wind • Stall horn with pitch variation based on AOA • Dynamic wind layering based on airspeed and angle of attack 🌬️Rich Exterior Ambience • Audible air/heat exchange and battery contactor clicks from outside the aircraft • Reworked control surface stop sounds (rudder, elevator, aileron) 🎚️Smart Customization Controls • Toggle vintage-style gyro sounds via the Marker Sensitivity switch • Choose your soundscape and personalize your flight experience 🎙️Full-3D Cockpit Interactivity • 96kHz ambisonic captures for a complete 360° spatial soundstage • All switches, knobs, dials, and levers placed in true 3D space • Yoke hide/show SFX and optional alternator whine toggle via SPKR • Designed for best results with Spatial Sound enabled 🔥Engine Behavior That Reacts to You • Rough-running effects when mixture is pulled or temps are cold • Internal engine layers change dynamically with airspeed and flight phase 🌡️Environmental Control Audio • Cabin air/heat knobs bring in realistic airflow sounds once airspeed is alive 🎨Bonus Content:  • 4 MSFS 2024 Liveries — Including a Classic “Ruby,” USAF Academy, Echo 19 House, and House Alt • 1 MSFS 2020 Livery — Echo 19 House (Alt) Echo19’s Cessna 172 Precision Audio Pack is available now on the Echo 19 shop for $12.23, as well as the in-sim Marketplace, Contrail, iniBuilds, and Orbx. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flow24</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Provides Update on Flow Pro for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flow24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c48460d39acfd7cc375ad6_545730685_1197698989059534_2706326631889373788_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Parallel 42 has taken to Facebook and announced that they’ve pushed Flow Pro for MSFS 2024 into its internal beta testing phase, inching the utility closer to release. The team says they are putting every feature through its paces and will launch once satisfied. No timeframe has been announced. For newcomers, Flow for MSFS 2020 replaced the default toolbar with a sleek, in-sim radial wheel that you can summon with a key or controller button. It lets you access default and third-party panels, arrange custom wheels per aircraft, and resize interface elements for clarity, handy for accessibility on various devices. We have reason to believe similar functionality will be included for the upcoming 2024 version. Looking ahead, Flow Essentials and Flow Pro are planned for MSFS 2024, while the free edition remains on MSFS 2020. Existing Flow Pro customers can expect a small upgrade fee for the MSFS 2024 version. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/slhsbh</id>
    <title>SLHSimDesign Releases Saint Barthélemy Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/slhsbh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4b407432344dac6769342_TFFJ11_4472x%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SLHSimDesign has recently released their new St. Barthélemy scenery, also known as St. Barts, bringing a new rendition of the famous Gustaf III Airport (TFFJ) for MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024. Well known for its “Saddle” approach, SLHSimDesigns brings accurate hill terraforming, so you can properly hug the slope on short final. Included is a populated RWY28 beach scene, as well as dynamic pedestrians by RWY10, who duck, wave, and film your landing, as well as animated road traffic that turns the hilltop into a living obstacle, just as in the real world. The package has custom 3D modelling throughout, with 4K PBR textures, fully modelled terminal and tower interiors, a working lift between floors, corrected terrain elevations, bespoke ground texturing and grunge, dynamic lighting, and performance-minded optimisation. The island gets attention beyond the runway as well, with animated jet skis and speedboats around Eden Rock and beaches, an uplifted Gustavia Bay, nearby shopping areas, and various points of interest. A quick heads-up before you fly: Disable the Asobo default TFFJ to avoid conflicts.  SLHSimDesign’s St. Barts is available now on the iniBuilds store for $18.97. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a0912</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a0912"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c4e305e7104aacb1bc8bf9_aerostarnew.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently updated their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing new refinements, fixes, additions, and more. Update v0.9.12 of their Aerostar 600 is nicknamed “Little Bits Part 2”, bringing many fixes, further refinements, new additions such as noise-canceling headphones and a functional Hobbs meter, among many other things. The complete changelog follows below: Change log v0.9.12: The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ubbb12</id>
    <title>Azrsim Releases Heydar Aliyev International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ubbb12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c565b01ab5b66a4fc40f63_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. After releasing their Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 versions of Heydar Aliyev International Airport (UBBB) a few weeks ago, Azrsim has now launched the X-Plane 12 version of the airport. Located in Baku, the capital of Azerbaijan, the airport serves over 7.5 million passengers each year. The airport began operations in 1933. In 1964, a new passenger terminal complex opened, increasing the facility's capacity. A new runway was inaugurated in 1998, followed by the opening of Terminal 2 in 1999. The following year, a new air traffic control (ATC) tower was constructed. In 2004, a new domestic passenger terminal was introduced, and the Baku Cargo Terminal (BCT) was launched in 2005. Additionally, an extra runway was built in 2012, and Terminal 1 was inaugurated in 2014. ‍ The airport accommodates numerous airlines that operate both domestically and internationally, including Azerbaijan Airlines, IrAero, Pegasus Airlines, and Utair, among others. Consequently, the airport facilitates the movement of over 7.5 million passengers annually and manages nearly 60,000 flights each year. The scenery package includes features like accurately recreated terminals, hangars, and additional buildings, detailed interiors, high-resolution ground textures, detailed apron layouts, and much more. The newly released version of Heydar Aliyev International Airport for X-Plane 12 is now available on SimMarket for approximately $23.47. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nssmok</id>
    <title>Northern Sky Studio Releases Molokai &amp; Kalaupapa Airports for XP12</title>
    <updated>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nssmok"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68c5e01b23f35de1cd89d99b_43.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Northern Sky Studio has released a twin-pack for X-Plane 12, featuring Molokai Airport (PHMK) and Kalaupapa Airport (PHLU), giving island-hoppers two richly crafted airports in one go.  Both airfields feature custom ground textures, detailed airport objects and vehicles, weather effects, new lighting, PBR materials, and 3D vegetation. For night operations, you can tune COM1 to 125.7 to switch on the runway lighting, like at a real pilot-controlled field. The package integrates with new X-Plane 12 features, supports World Traffic 3, and is compatible with Ortho4XP and the default mesh, ensuring it should fit into most Hawaii setups without issue. Molokai’s two asphalt runways and central-plateau sets the contrast nicely with Kalaupapa’s coastal strip, making this a versatile pair for commuter, air taxi, or GA flying. Expect high-resolution building and ground textures, realistic reflections on glass, shaded and baked details, plus animated ground traffic, courtesy of the LST plugin. As always, you can read the full feature list below: Features: The Molokai &amp; Kalaupapa Airports pack is now available from Orbx, priced at about $19.20.  For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
