<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-06-30T18:35:55.791465+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsl306</id>
    <title>FSLabs Updates A321ceo and A321neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsl306"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685e7451454fab1b0a43e8b9_neow1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. FSLabs has recently issued an update to their A321ceo and newly released A321neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing system improvements, model updates, sound enhancements, and more. Update v11.0.1.306 improves logging and error reporting, brings several improvements to the systems, adds wingflex in interior views, removes rubber marks from the flap textures, brings a complete rework of the ground roll, landing, and take-off sounds, and much more. The full changelog follows below: AOC Service: Systems Improvements: Model Updates: Sound Enhancements: ATSU Updates: Furthermore, FSLabs has added a free hardware interface for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing seamless integration between their two products and selected high-end hardware, starting with full support for the Skalarki product line. From the mini overhead panel to the DCDU, the interface allows plug-and-play functionality, aiming to deliver an immersive and highly authentic experience. It can be seen live and in action at FlightSimExpo 2025 at Skalarki’s booth (stand 116). They conclude the blog post on the update with a brief progress update on the PWs, which is said to be coming soon, and they have been hard at work at properly integrating it, from its very unique “whale-like” sound to how it performs and flies, being more than just a different 3D model. The update is only available on their experimental channel for the time being. Users can switch to the experimental branch by heading over to the settings page of their Control Center (in right corner of the settings page).  ‍ Their A321ceo and neo are available for $69.95 each + VAT on their website. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mozafe</id>
    <title>MOZA Releases New Flight Sim Equipment at the FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mozafe"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ebc8bb89cd73a97bdc143_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. MOZA has recently launched a range of new products at FlightSimExpo 2025, further expanding its flight simulation ecosystem. Among these new products are a new force feedback flight base, a throttle quadrant, a pair of rudder pedals, and more. The first new release is the AB6 FFB Flight Base, accompanied by the MHG Flightstick. The AB6 Flight Base delivers 6 Nm of torque, providing realistic torque feedback due to its high-performance outrunner motor. It also includes dual throttle sliders. The MHG Flightstick, designed for high-performance control in conjunction with the AB6, is ergonomically crafted and features programmable buttons, hat switches, adjustable resistance, and more. Next, MOZA introduces the MTQ Throttle Quadrant. This new throttle quadrant is designed to be modular, ensuring compatibility for flying both commercial jets and fighter jets. It features swappable grips, allowing users to choose between fighter jet style levers, Airbus style levers, and Boeing style levers. The team has introduced a new pair of rudder pedals known as the MRP Rudder Pedals. These pedals are constructed entirely from metal and feature metal brake pedals as well. They come equipped with non-slip rubber pads for added stability. Designed for high performance, the pedals include a precision swing-arm design, customizable centering force, and an optional adjustable damper. The final release is the FMP18 Front Panel System. Inspired by legacy naval jet cockpits, this system offers a full-scale, cockpit-grade replica. It features authentic 7.1-inch square displays, universal VESA mount compatibility, and an angle adjustment clamp. This system is a must-have for anyone who enjoys these kinds of aircraft. MOZA has not yet announced pricing for its various products, but we will keep you updated once new information is available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ta320c</id>
    <title>ToLiss Announces Upcoming Airbus A320ceo for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ta320c"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ebc0a1567fd5f4a5401d1_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ToLiss has announced they are developing the A320ceo for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. Following the release of the A320neo in 2023, the team is now focusing on the predecessor of the newer A320neo. Although the team has not yet provided additional details, they have announced that the A320ceo will be released as an addon for the current A320neo. They also mentioned that the release of this addon is planned for before the end of 2025. ToLiss has not announced pricing yet or shared any previews, but the team mentioned that more news will be coming tomorrow. It is unclear whether this news is related to the upcoming A320ceo. We will keep you informed as more information becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42fse</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Announce New Aircraft, Updates, at FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42fse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ee455eb8235f480cf4b2e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. The team at Parallel 42 recently made several announcements during #FSExpoFriday at FlightSimExpo 2025. Among these are an upcoming ChasePlane update, a new aircraft reveal, and more. The team began by discussing ChasePlane, which is celebrating its 8th anniversary this year, having first appeared during the FSX and P3D era. They shared several exciting new features that will be included in the next update for ChasePlane for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. These features include major refactoring, spot view adjustments, support for Tobii Eye Tracker, named shortcuts, custom cinematics, and much more. The upcoming update will be released through both a stable channel and an experimental channel, with the launch scheduled for next week. ‍ Regarding compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, the team mentioned that they have an internal build that is currently functioning. Although the build requires some fine-tuning, it will be ready in due time. Once it is polished, it will be available through the experimental channel. The team has announced that they are currently working on making Flow compatible with Microsoft Flight Simulator  2024. Additionally, they are bringing sceneries from Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 to 2024, including Bush Plane Campout and Mexican Mountain, which will be available in the coming weeks. Lastly, the team discussed the Super Patriot Mark II, FreedomFox, and Fox2 aircraft. The 3D design of the Super Patriot Mark II is entering its final stages, and this aircraft is being developed in partnership with Patriot Aircraft. Initially, the FreedomFox and Fox2 were intended to be compatible with the 2024 version, but they will now be developed natively for 2024 to some extent. While a complete overhaul is not planned, a significant update will be implemented. Additionally, the team announced a collaboration with Trent Palmer to bring the Legend Nomad to the simulator. We will keep you updated as soon as the team shares new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/naafse</id>
    <title>Navigraph Announcing Three New Features at the FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/naafse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685eeb63c03a2e8a9db76d16_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph recently took the stage during #FSExpoFriday at FlightSimExpo 2025. The team announced three exciting new features, including an agreement with Rogers Data, Taxiway Routing, and Simlink v2. Stephen announced that Navigraph has partnered with Rogers Data to provide VFR ICAO charts for all of Europe, free for all subscribers. In the second feature presentation, Alex took the stage to introduce Taxiway Routing. This new functionality enables users to select gates and intersections to plan a taxi route. Users have the option to either choose a route manually or allow the system to generate one automatically. Additionally, users can specify turns while navigating. There are also plans to introduce a variety of other features related to Taxiway Routing in the future. In the final feature announcement, Alex introduced Simlink V2. This new version will allow users to inject AI traffic into the Navigraph Charts App, providing native support for Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS), X-Plane (XP), and Prepar3D (P3D). Additionally, support for third-party integration with BeyondATC will be included. Furthermore, the update rate for aircraft position in the Navigraph Chart App will be quadrupled. We will keep you updated as soon as the team shares new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidoh</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Hamad International Airport and Doha Landmarks for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidoh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ef5be39f7e87bbe6d8c90_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just launched its version of Hamad International Airport (OTHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. In addition, the team has also released a Doha Landmarks package for the simulator. Each year, Hamad International Airport welcomes nearly 53 million passengers, making it one of the busiest airports in the Middle East. Opened in 2014, Hamad International Airport is still a relatively new facility, built to replace the over 70-year-old Doha International Airport. Since its inauguration, air traffic to and from Hamad International has steadily increased. Today, it serves as a hub for Qatar Airways, Qatar Airways Cargo, and Qatar Executive, while also accommodating a variety of other airlines, allowing for destinations around the globe. Last year, the airport recorded 279,000 aircraft movements and welcomed a total of 52.7 million passengers. The airport scenery features hand-made ground textures, true-to-life airport landside recreation, dynamic airport lighting, handcrafted HD jetways, and much more. The landmarks package includes over 30 iconic landmarks across Doha. The newly released Hamad International Airport is now available from iniBuilds for approximately $27.23. Additionally, the Doha Landmarks package is available from iniBuilds for approximately $13.61. Until July 4th, you can receive the Doha Landmarks package for free with the purchase of the Hamad International Airport. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssfse</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Announcement and Development Update at the FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssfse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685efb90ab53a3c6cebb9d65_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. During the #FSExpoFriday at FlightSimExpo 2025, the FlightSim Studio team announced a new expansion and provided a development update on several of their current projects. The team has announced a new expansion for its Boeing 727 series called the Super 27 Expansion. This expansion will introduce new engines, a digital vertical speed indicator (VSI), automatic spoilers, a moving map display, dual distance measuring equipment (DMEs), and more for both the freighter and passenger versions of the Boeing 727. The release is scheduled for late 2025. Additionally, the team mentioned that after launching the Super 27 Expansion, they will begin working on the Boeing 727-100 variant. The next item on the agenda was a development update for the E-Jets. The team presented a preview of the ongoing development, which includes a custom Flight Management System (FMS) featuring LNAV autopilot, vertical path calculation, and route drawing capabilities. This preview is anticipated to be released in 2025. Additionally, the team expects to begin VNAV testing later this year. To finish up, the team announced that a native version of the Tecnam for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is expected in late 2025 or early 2026. We will keep you updated as soon as the team shares new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cofa50</id>
    <title>Contrail Announces FA50 for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cofa50"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685eff94f85025739cfe5999_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. At the #FSExpoFriday event during FlightSimExpo 2025, Contrail founder Lars Pinkenburg announced that the team is currently developing the FA50 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This aircraft will be the first one developed in-house by Contrail. The Dassault Falcon 50, known for its tri-engine design, has been utilised by both private and military operators globally. This aircraft is certified to reach altitudes of up to 49,000 feet and is capable of flying both transcontinental and transoceanic routes. The addon will be equipped with fully customised avionics systems, including the GNSXLS Flight Management System, the Apollo MX20 MFD, the Collins Electronic Flight Information System suite, and a dedicated custom autopilot. Currently, the aircraft is set to feature 18 different liveries. While the price has not yet been determined, it is expected to be released in 2025. We will keep you updated as soon as the team shares new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wwafse</id>
    <title>WinWing Announces New Products at the FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wwafse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685f1171b5ef75b835a73591_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. WinWing has announced a variety of new products at the #FSExpoFriday event during FlightSimExpo 2025, following their announcements at FSWeekend 2025. This latest release includes flight simulation hardware designed for both the commercial and combat sectors. The team began by announcing a variety of new products for the commercial sector. First, they introduced the ATC 32, ACP 32, and RMP 32. The prices for the ATC 32 and RMP 32 are set at $77.50 each, while the ACP 32 is priced at $133.85. Next, they unveiled the AGP 32, which is a landing gear and autobrake panel, also priced at $133.85. They also released the ECAM 32, an ECAM panel, priced at $77.50.  Following that was the NWS L 32, a left-sided Airbus tiller, priced at $82.30. Finally, they introduced the N32 rudder pedals, which are priced at $328.69. Additionally, there will be two Force Feedback (FFB) variants of these rudder pedals, designated as EB140 32 and EB400 32, available for $499.95 and $599.95, respectively. The next announcement highlighted new products in the combat sector. Two new rudder pedals have been introduced: the EB140 N and the EB400 N. These are combat variants of the original EB140 32 and EB400 32 models, priced at $499.95 and $599.95, respectively. The previously announced FFB Boeing Yoke was also on display; however, the price has not yet been determined. Lastly, the Met 29 Grips were showcased. The Joystick Grip R Met 29 is priced at $222.45, while the Throttle Grip R Met 29 is priced at $141.06. We will keep you updated as soon as the team shares new information. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350113</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024 with ULR Variant, Teases A340</title>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350113"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ff6aa92facdea724e95c8_MainA3501100.png.d25037075f3a1ebbb1c762aee159d12e_optimized_1600%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released version 1.1.0 of its A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing a raft of improvements and additions, including the long-awaited A350 ULR variant. The A350 ULR, or Ultra Long Range, features an increased maximum takeoff weight and fuel capacity, with a range of up to 9,700 nautical miles. Designed for non-stop, ultra-long-haul flights, it supports operations lasting over 19 hours, with Singapore Airlines operating the type exclusively, in a two-class, premium-heavy configuration. iniBuilds has adapted this layout for their ULR variant in MSFS 2024, bringing a reworked cabin and compatibility with FS24’s career mode, including interactive boarding procedures. Further additions include the integration of functional emergency evacuation slides and the PDOS (Power Door Opening System) for opening the engine cowlings. Performance has seen additional improvements, with reduced CPU load and a streamlined WASM structure. Furthermore, iniBuilds has overhauled the ECAM, refined the fly-by-wire system, and introduced several new FMS features, including Conditional Descent Advisory and Estimated Time to Target. The update also introduces support for iniBuilds' new modular cabin packs, a separately sold line of swappable, airline-specific interiors, providing realistic cabin layouts from carriers like Air France, Virgin Atlantic and Lufthansa. Artwork updates include refined nose cone shading, reworked cockpit sidesticks, adjusted camera positions, and cockpit storm lighting. iniBuilds has also integrated event-driven scenarios and confirmed upcoming support for a 3D HUD with dynamic projection and crosswind adaptation. Despite popular demand, 8x time compression remains unsupported, due to instability in the autopilot logic at high speeds. iniBuilds also affirmed their confidence in the aircraft’s flight model, citing validation through full-motion simulators, while noting user experience may vary depending on hardware. The developer recommends users apply a 1:1 axis curve for the most accurate control feel.  ‍ iniBuilds closed their post with a single teaser image of what appears to be an Airbus A340-300, possibly hinting at their next big project. As the A350 Airliner enters a more mature development phase, iniBuilds plans to space out future updates, while continuing work on feature enhancements and long-term refinements. ‍ You can find the complete changelog for the update below: ‍ v1.1.0 Systems⚙️FIXED: Incorrect STBY pump off when feeding only from the wing tanksFIXED: VD - missing magenta areaFIXED: VD - vertical alignment with empty FMSFIXED: Aborting an ENG start leads to the EGT rising to +400°CFIXED: VD is missing RADIO HEIGHTFIXED: OEI - Auto rudder trim keeps going in/out, oscillating aircraftFIXED: Incorrect order of memos on ECAMFIXED: RTA page feedbackFIXED: Optimum step field logicFIXED: ALT or OP CLB flashing consistently on groundFIXED: No TAWS messages on PFDFIXED: HAAB arrival descent calculationFIXED: MAGVAR issue for AFS/PFD/NDFIXED: Sec Index logic incorrectFIXED: Navdata Swap not clearing SEC plansFIXED: "T/D REACHED" displayed in amber instead of white on MFDFIXED: Destination data FMS message logicFIXED: ATC Comm menu not populating when calling D-ATISFIXED: SEC F-PLN prompting airport on second NEW DEST attemptFIXED: Speed constraint behavior limitationsFIXED: Position time page tweaksFIXED: POSITION/NAVAIDs syncFIXED: Dual armed modes in FMA not rendering in smaller fontFIXED: Cruise page CAB ALT and CAB V/S remain in auto despite manual changeFIXED: TO Waypoint Range/Bearing shown on ND before IRS alignmentFIXED: Incorrect landing elevation on Cruise SD pageFIXED: LS distance overlap with NMFIXED: FO ND missing ADS-B Traffic IDFIXED: NAV LS lower course pointer lacked double linesFIXED: ETA clock appearing on RTA pageFIXED: ND ROSE mode drawing issuesFIXED: RMP functionality issuesFIXED: ANF onwards flight not resettingFIXED: ANF airport database flickerFIXED: PLAN ZOOM not defaulting to DEST airportFIXED: ND airport direction missing runway codeFIXED: PLAN ZOOM missing DEST airportFIXED: LDA incorrectly showing runway length in ANFFIXED: PLAN ZOOM display logic broken during climbFIXED: NAV/ARC mode missing DEST name next to arrowFIXED: SET PLAN MODE not displaying when clicking ICAOsFIXED: BTV disarming on same runway exit changeFIXED: BTV logic inconsistenciesFIXED: SET PLAN MODE text/behavior in ANFFIXED: Missing SET PLAN MODE message in ARC/ROSE modeFIXED: No prompt when selecting BTV while AUTO BRAKE MED activeFIXED: Turnaround tick color in BTV incorrectFIXED: ANF heading mismatchFIXED: Floating NAV ZOOM box in ANFFIXED: A350-1000 cabin not loading properlyFIXED: WASM EFIS crash on BTV exit selectionFIXED: BLEED SD line incorrect with ENG fail, PACK offFIXED: ECAM APU BLEED fault drawing errorFIXED: ECAM SLAT/FLAP fault missing AUTOLAND INOP indicatorFIXED: APU BLEED fault light not removed in transit stateFIXED: Missing VLS indicationFIXED: Restarting engine in flight reset FOB/FU, falsely triggered fuel leakFIXED: No ECAM or warning for idle ATHR disconnectFIXED: No highlight on WD for failed/fire engineFIXED: Added REMOTE C/B CTL ON memo to EWDFIXED: ELEC GEN2A+2B fault lines overlapping in ELEC ACFIXED: LDG inhibit disappearing too earlyFIXED: AUTO SD failure post system faultFIXED: ECAM flashes when WING or ENG ANTI is selectedFIXED: WHEEL ECP button not removing braking matrixFIXED: Braking action knob didn’t light wheel SD ECP buttonFIXED: RWY braking matrix logicFIXED: Minor EWD color formattingFIXED: ECAM warning missing on flap cruise baulkFIXED: TAWS system issues in SURVFIXED: ADIRS OFF not properly disabling WXR/TAWS/XPDRFIXED: Engine relight ECAM logicFIXED: ELEC faults reporting LDG PERF instead of LGD DISTFIXED: TCAS STBY with MODE C and RMP ONFIXED: Missing wheel numbers on WHEEL SD page (-900)FIXED: ECAM logic for relight with incorrect XBLEED AUTO stateFIXED: RELIGHT IN FLT should show ECAM ENG pageFIXED: A/THR OFF not indicated on voluntary disconnectFIXED: WASM EFIS exception on SEC3 modificationFIXED: Multiple WASM MFD exceptionsFIXED: Step alt logic revisionsFIXED: SUGT optimum step fieldFIXED: Incorrect high speed protectionFIXED: VNAV logic for RJAA RUTAS T STAR not honoring 220kt/FL110 restrictionFIXED: Sim default navdata logic – arrival runway incorrectly part of missed approachFIXED: Secondary nav database failing to update with downloaded navdataFIXED: Importing company route into SEC FPLN incorrectly overrides active FLT NBRFIXED: Flight number parity no longer incorrectly changes ADS-B systemFIXED: PRIMs and SECs not failing properly when powered elec bus is offFIXED: RNAV approach behavior falsely triggering ILS cuesFIXED: Checklist contracting ECAM issueFIXED: ECAM showing incorrect SURV WXR fault when ADIRS offFIXED: ECAM showing incorrect SURV TCAS fault when ADIRS offFIXED: ECAM SURV TAWS feedback when ADIRS is OFFFIXED: SURV CONTROLS page default settings button not syncing ADS-B optionsFIXED: Unable to modify time in POSITION/TIMEFIXED: Automatic arming AED feedbackFIXED: Engine thrust does not follow cursor when set to idle reverseFIXED: FCU switch from MACH to SPD mode below FL250FIXED: LDA should show in ANF, not runway lengthFIXED: Fuel prediction discrepancyFIXED: Cannot reset GPS Jamming status after aircraft power cycleFIXED: Cross-bleed logic improved to maintain pressure in both systemsFIXED: APU fuel usage (FU) shown in KG despite LBS being selectedFIXED: Outflow valve animations corrected per ECAMFIXED: GPWS callouts no longer overlap or cut offFIXED: Traffic info page overflow resolvedFIXED: FIX rings showing invalid FL/Distance now fixedFIXED: ECAM SD light always lit bug resolvedFIXED: Cabin and cargo temp tooltips now display °C/°F not %FIXED: Sidestick logic adjusted based on preferred seat optionFIXED: Sidestick decoupling implementedFIXED: Cargo doors open handle angle correctedFIXED: Snow FX artifacts resolvedFIXED: Fuel jettison active state now shows ON and OPEN correctlyFIXED: Fuel jettison visual effect addedFIXED: MLG tires sink corrected on landingFIXED: Landing gear ground sink behavior improvedFIXED: ULR fuel loading logic updatedFIXED: APU panel state tracking added for Career modeFIXED: Spoiler behavior in flight improvedFIXED: Spoilers extend too far during roll (both AP and manual)FIXED: Spoiler 7 extends too far on flap full configurationFIXED: Time marker synchronization and feedbackFIXED: ANF set plan mode text/behavior correctedFIXED: EFIS Mode/Range Selector lights tied to ANN LT TEST SwitchFIXED: Activating EFIS backup now turns switch lights offFIXED: Uncommanded nose up pitch on landingFIXED: RNAV approach incorrectly shows LS as ILSFIXED: Loop in flight plan after existing offsetFIXED: RMP issuesFIXED: Sidestick not angled correctlyFIXED: Sidestick behavior now aligns with preferred seat optionFIXED: ISIS BARO UNIT knob plays double click with single rotationFIXED: Overhead and pedestal light brightness mismatchFIXED: 3-way switch logic inverted for taxi light controlFIXED: Crash damage prevents spawn; spawn logic correctedFIXED: Engine shutdown mid-flight causing spinner and blades to disappearFIXED: Engine fan animation corrected for startup/shutdownFIXED: PERF mode visibility corrected for both engine cowlingsFIXED: LGAV ILS Z 03R KEA transition - corrected bad drawingFIXED: SALA4B Departure (RWY 08 LLBG) now draws correctlyFIXED: Surveillance systems now switch automatically based on flight number digitFIXED: NAV - Inserting next waypoint from ND no longer causes blank FPLNFIXED: No refueling ECAM warning displayed during refuel sequenceFIXED: Slides can no longer remain deployed past 3 knots; reset messaging logic addedFIXED: GSX now disarms slides automatically prior to auto-deboardingFIXED: Smoke in Cabin situation audio cue logic now resets properly when toggledUPDATED: FS24 career mode support for pax logic and compatibilityFIXED: APU BLEED now only opens below FL250FIXED: RAT now deploys automatically when GEN 1–4 are offFIXED: EMER DES heading offset no longer exceeds valid range near HDG 360FIXED: No refueling ECAM now shows as expected during refuelingFIXED: Overlapping text on RNP approach resolvedFIXED: T.O Perf page in OIS importing correct values and performing accurate calculationsFIXED: Incorrect TORA displayed on OISFIXED: FLT OPS CLEAR/TURNAROUND delay resolvedUPDATED: Weights revised on OIS and SB Profiles (ULR and -900 variants) EFB/OIS🖥️FIXED: Printer - T.O Data page typo ("RUWNAY" → "RUNWAY")FIXED: OIS charts not wiping pinned terminals after FLT OPS CLEAR/TURNAROUNDFIXED: Dynamic seating logic for passengersFIXED: Added printer options page to OISFIXED: OIS stairs not displayingFIXED: RESET ZOOM button added to OIS chartsFIXED: Reworded active pause warning in OISFIXED: OIS loadsheet not updating with GSX progressive boarding/refuelingFIXED: GSX ZFW mismatch caused fuel weight disagreementFIXED: FLT OPS CLEAR/TURNAROUND does not reset loadsheet or payload diagramFIXED: GSX ZFWCG discrepancy vs ACARS loadsheetFIXED: OIS ACARS loadsheet max pax value mismatchFIXED: GSX deboarding not unloading payload stationsFIXED: ACARS loadsheet ZFCG incorrect/out of band vs GWCGFIXED: FO OIS GROUND tab flashing induced by GSXFIXED: AOC Zulu time field display issueFIXED: When CAPT OIS ON CENTER is ON, F/O OIS ON CENTER should not show INOPFIXED: ULR variant OIS label still showed v1.0.11fFIXED: Improved GSX integration logicFIXED: FX performance mode toggle addedFIXED: Remote parking issue: GSX left L2 door openFIXED: OIS brightness now matches other DUsFIXED: OIS "View Offside" behavior clarifiedFIXED: FLT OPS CLEAR/TURNAROUND now wipes pinned chartsFIXED: Option added to disable auto de-rotate in OISADDED: Condensation FX control added to OISFIXED: Option added to manually open/close fuel panel if GSX buggedFIXED: Click spot added to remove printout from clipboardFIXED: Ability added to attach printout to CPT/FO sideFIXED: Takeoff performance page importing incorrect values and calculationsFIXED: OIS Situations page ENABLED/DISABLED toggle now visually matches other menu elementsFIXED: Printouts no longer appear blank when clipped to sideUPDATED: Weights revised on OIS and SB Profiles for ULR and -900 variantsADDED: Realistic "Cabin Ready" option to settingsFIXED: CAPS LOCK not functioning on OIS keyboard (XBOX)FIXED: AOC not loading properly without HOPPIE code (XBOX)FIXED: No-cabin configuration option added to ULR ART🎨FIXED: Missing compass dotsFIXED: ACVS door not functioningFIXED: Avionics bay door accessible on no-cabin variantsFIXED: RAT animation does not display upon deploymentFIXED: Cargo bay lights illuminating cockpitFIXED: Missing co-pilot modelFIXED: LED TYPE configuration missing runway turnoff lightFIXED: VV button letter spacingFIXED: FO EFIS green light not updatingFIXED: FO POV alignment correctedFIXED: Avionics bay decal orientation correctedFIXED: Windshield scratch layer reducedFIXED: Touchdown effects reinstatedFIXED: Nose cone mesh precision improvedFIXED: NW light box rendering issue resolvedFIXED: NW amber lights remain lit in C&amp;D fixedFIXED: Rotating elements incorrectly attached to static parts correctedFIXED: Emergency Escape Slides texture/model addedFIXED: 3-way switch visuals corrected to reflect sim click directionFIXED: Door slide animations restoredFIXED: Xbox: cart and catering truck connection points fixedFIXED: Heavy snow clipping into fuselage resolvedFIXED: 2020 ground vehicles restoredFIXED: Wing light switch not animating (Legacy/Lock)FIXED: Snow FX floating without satcom toggleFIXED: Engine cowling strut clippingFIXED: Edelweiss -900 wing registration and winglets decals missingFIXED: Door decals flickering on EDW liveryFIXED: Storm light function works on Dome LT controlFIXED: AOA and Wiper lights glow issue resolvedFIXED: Snow floating without satcom toggled removedFIXED: Performance drop from condensation reducedFIXED: Strobe light flash timing adjustedFIXED: Lufthansa livery now includes taxi camsFIXED: Cathay B-LXP floor exit sign visibilityFIXED: D-AIXQ nose registration correctedFIXED: Qatar -1000 logo flicker removedFIXED: Swiss livery visual updatesFIXED: A6-EXD main gear door decal parenting issueFIXED: N502DN main door layer parenting issueFIXED: Cabin packs and ULR cabin no longer conflict with iniManager liveriesFIXED: -1000 variant LOD1/2 interior models now presentFIXED: Livery issues with D-AIXY nose probes and Iberia missing wing registrationFIXED: Cathay B-LRL winglet geometry correctedFIXED: 2020 Qatar Livery flags updatedFIXED: Engine cowling decal issuesUPDATED: Cabin textures removed or resized for optimization SOUNDS🔊FIXED: Added “2000” RA callout optionFIXED: PA knob did not allow announcements in cockpitFIXED: Reverse thrust sound lacked volume modulationFIXED: Slat sound inaudible in cockpitFIXED: Inconsistent wing sound volumesFIXED: BARO UNIT knob in ISIS plays double click on single rotationFIXED: Missing cockpit soundsFIXED: Added gear door open soundsFIXED: ECP ALL pb playing double click soundFIXED: Rolling noise disappearing at taxi speedsFIXED: Cabin ambience mix and loop improvementsFIXED: Various sound inconsistenciesFIXED: Parking brake sound audible outsideFIXED: A359 slat sound inaudible in cockpitFIXED: Cleaned up slats sound loopFIXED: Cabin ambient improvements - fixed up some sample loops and general mixing improvementsFIXED: ISIS knobs missing std clickFIXED: Several RMP missing buttonsFIXED: RMP numpad buttons events doubling (four quick clicks)FIXED: Reverse thrust sound - reverse is now volume modulated based on how much thrust is used rather than being staticFIXED: PB sound incorrectly triggered after IR alignmentFIXED: Random button press sounds mid-flightFIXED: SURV screen MFD buttons playing physical key press soundsFIXED: INS alignment triggers extraneous cockpit button soundFIXED: Switch click sound during first ENG start when NW STEER DISC goes amberFIXED: Click sound when WXR radar turns off post-landingFIXED: Cabin announcement trigger now randomized to avoid immediate startFIXED: OIS on/off buttons had no audible differenceFIXED: ISIS standard pressure knob sound volume reducedFIXED: Pushbutton sound playing during IR alignmentFIXED: SURV MFD click sounds playing incorrectly on button interactions ‍ The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for roughly $76.16, requiring at least 10.63 GB of free hard disk space to install. ‍ Be sure to follow Threshold for all the latest updates! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrafse</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Showcases X-Plane 12.3 Update at the FSExpo 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrafse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685ff9f0ef9859a7530846a6_513827559_1272702787583253_5803343644365079472_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar has during during #FSExpoFriday 2025 given an update on the future of X-Plane 12, with performance improvements, art upgrades, and major simulation system enhancements all in active development. The team confirmed that version 12.2.1 will enter public beta next Friday, while the highly anticipated 12.3.0 release will begin private beta testing the same day. ‍ The presentation began with a recap of version 12.2, which is now publicly available. Key fixes and visual improvements include updated ground textures, revised lighting and atmospheric rendering, new aircraft braking effects, and a resolution to the long-standing dark cockpit issue, significantly improving visibility across default aircraft. Laminar also previewed upcoming additions to the X-Plane Gateway, with new community-driven assets currently in development. These include various fire trucks, police cars, construction vehicles, enhanced ramp lighting, and improved ground markings. Much of this work is being led by newly joined scenery artist Justin, also known as Mr. X, and the team highlighted the ability to customise ramps with new compass roses, labels, and colours. The upcoming 12.3.0 version will introduce a foundational shift in how X-Plane uses CPU resources. Laminar has confirmed that multi-core rendering is now in development, with a new job system already built to handle AI traffic, texture paging, and network synchronisation. Internal testing has demonstrated performance gains of up to 30% at graphically intensive airports, such as Frankfurt. Additional optimisation targets GPU and VRAM usage. Laminar is currently refining cloud rendering and night lighting processes, which should result in greater efficiency and reduced GPU workload, particularly beneficial for users running in 4K. Laminar is adopting new virtual memory techniques, to speed up texture loading and safely offload unused graphical assets. The default Airbus A330 is set for a major update, with reworked metallic surfaces, improved textures, detailed weathering and glare shield fixes.  Furthermore, brake fire simulations, refined lighting and cabin ambience, dynamic passenger lighting, and altitude-aware illumination modes were also shown off. A major technical addition is a fully GPU-bound weather radar, integrated by default on the default Boeing 737-800, A330-300, MD-82, Cirrus Visionjet, Baron B58 and Citation X.  The default weather radar includes manual tilt, ground clutter filtering, sector scanning, and predictive wind shear alerts. An API has been made available for third-party developers to integrate the feature into their products. ‍ The G1000 avionics suite has also been upgraded, now featuring synthetic vision, rendered entirely on the GPU. This allows terrain, obstacle, and traffic overlays, including support for online networks like VATSIM and IVAO, without adding CPU overhead or impacting performance. Beyond the simulator core, Laminar reaffirmed progress on its new X-Plane Store. The backend now supports account-based logins and is integrating modern payment systems. ‍ More details are expected as development on the 12.3.0 update continues. ‍ For all the latest updates, be sure to follow Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atafse</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Reveal Partnership for A340-600 in Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atafse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6860307b9e445c2be8ba6c68_videoframe_8556.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft and ToLiss have announced a new partnership at this year's FlightSimExpo, confirming development of an Airbus A340-600 for MSFS. The upcoming release will mark ToLiss’ first entry into the MSFS platform, having already built a reputation for high-fidelity Airbus aircraft in X-Plane. In a statement published on Facebook, ToLiss said the aircraft will feature their proprietary systems suite adapted from X-Plane. It will also include a custom-built flight model, designed specifically for MSFS.  The aircraft is being jointly developed, with Aerosoft handling modelling and visual assets, and ToLiss the flight and systems modelling. While no release timeline has been shared, a recently published video on the Aerosoft Flight YouTube channel showcases the A340 handling three different technical scenarios, including an engine failure after takeoff, and sections of an RNAV approach.  A standout feature is a seemingly working taxi camera, rarely seen in MSFS due to simulator limitations. ToLiss has long been recognised in the X-Plane community for its attention to detail and system accuracy, notably in the A319, A321, A340 and A330neo series. Their upcoming A340-600 for MSFS aims to bring the same level of depth to a new audience. ‍ Further details on the project, including pricing and release platforms, are expected as development continues. ‍ Be sure to follow Threshold for the latest updates! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gf33me</id>
    <title>Got Friends Announces the imminent Release of the AS 33 Me Motor Glider for Microsoft Flight Simulator, with Discus 2c also receiving Upgrades.</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gf33me"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68604640f038e89a617fc225_A33_EXTERIOR.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Got Friends is about to release their AS 33 Me Motor glider for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. It will include both 15-meter and 18-meter variants and has been developed in collaboration with three-time World Gliding Champion, Stefan Langer. According to Got Friends, the avionics suite is highly advanced and will support task-based navigation, thermal tracking, customizable instrument layouts, and more. The aircraft is designed to provide a flexible experience for both experienced and casual players, allowing for a reduction in complexity as needed. The AS 33 Me will also include a new LXNav gliding computer and a variety of liveries. ‍ Got Friends states that this will be their most advanced aircraft to date. It is set to release on July 1st for both Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024 at a price of $19.99. Discus 2C upgrades In addition to releasing the AS 33 Me, Got Friends has also launched a significant upgrade for both the Freeware and Premium versions of the Discus 2c, showcasing features found in the new AS 33 Me. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddysws</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Western Sydney International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddysws"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68604ff0ae79e282f9604cab_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Drzewiecki Design has recently released its rendition of Western Sydney International Airport (YSWS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This airport is situated approximately 38 miles from the center of Sydney and is currently under construction, with a projected completion date at the end of 2026. Once finished, it will serve as a supplement to the existing Sydney Kingsford Smith Airport (YSSY). Construction of the new Western Sydney International Airport began in 2018 and is expected to be completed by late 2026. This airport will be notable for using a remote and virtual control tower rather than the traditional air traffic control tower, making it the first airport in Australia to feature this technology. The new airport is being built to supplement the existing Sydney Kingsford Smith Airport (YSSY), which has limited space for expansion. As of now, airlines including Qantas, Jetstar, and Singapore Airlines have announced plans to operate flights to the new airport. The new scenery includes an up-to-date and high-quality model of the airport, advanced night lighting, custom jetways, and many additional features. The newly released Western Sydney International Airport is now available from SimMarket for approximately $23.44. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asafse</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews A330neo for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asafse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6860549cb73663dcdb2afb28_videoframe_141670.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has shared a fresh look at their upcoming Airbus A330-900neo for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, suggesting that development of the wide-body airliner is nearing its final stages. The announcement was made during FlightSimExpo 2025, through an official release trailer, published on the Aerosoft Flight YouTube channel. The trailer showcases the A330neo in action, featuring in-flight sequences and various system previews. Featured is the Onboard Airport Navigation System (OANS), aswell as a demonstration of the electronic flight bag. The landing gear is displayed in motion, with tilt animations and suspension compression during touchdown. The aircraft’s soundscape is also previewed, highlighting the brake fan ambience and the distinctive spool-up of the Rolls-Royce Trent 7000 engines.  Featured throughout are multiple real-world liveries, such as Condor, Virgin Atlantic, and Delta Air Lines. We also get a glimpse of the cabin. Although a release date has not yet been confirmed, Aerosoft has stated the aircraft is “soon to be released”. Further details regarding pricing are expected soon. Stay tuned to Threshold for more updates, news, and coverage of upcoming releases! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar24</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Shares Screenshots of Upcoming Accu-Sim Aerostar for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68607b0d9c93c1a9f5add741_star1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently shared a batch of Aerostar 600 screenshots provided by their beta testers. These screenshots showcase many aspects of the 3D model, cockpit features, and feature-rich electronic flight bag. A few days ago, A2A finally announced a release date for the Aerostar, albeit in an early access program, allowing the community to experience the airplane as it undergoes its final polishing processes.  While not much was shared regarding features or images, the developers have now satiated everyone’s curiosity with a substantial batch of screenshots, showcasing its internals and externals under different weather and lighting conditions and multiple hints on features.  The airplane’s autopilot is a custom-simulated two-axis Century IV from the late 1970s, not relying on MSFS’s default systems. Furthermore, the EFB – despite looking similar – was fully rewritten and works as a native MSFS 2024 app, meaning it can also display other MSFS 2024 apps such as their flight planner, charts, SimBrief, Navigraph, and so on. Like their Comanche 250, the Aerostar will be compatible with multiple GPS options, including the PMS GTN750, the TDS GTN750Xi, and the KLN90B. Additionally, they have simulated two digital engine monitors this time: the JPI EDM 790 and the EDM 760.  There’s no pricing or a date for the release yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
