<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-10-01T18:32:33.203893+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffnuxp</id>
    <title>Flight Factor Releases Update for Boeing 767 and 757</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffnuxp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6328c52c2caaa41d3a49581e_o5s3nao.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="217267"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has updated their current Boeing 757 and 767, including many fixes and improvements ‍ ‍ Aircraft Developer FlightFactor have further developed on their Boeing fleet to improve any imperfections during its new beta stage for X-Plane 12. The team at FlightFactor are working hard to complete other tasks which will enhance your experience when flying these wonderful machines. ‍ Sadly, no further news on the Airbus fleet or the Boeing 787 they have announced. ‍ The updates are available now to use with the current standing Boeing fleet of 767 and 757 aircraft. This update is free to the current owners of the 757 V2 Professional and 767 ER Professional. ‍ ‍ Below, you will find the Changelog for the current update: ‍ FlightFactor 757 - 2.6.2 - added glow effect to the FPDS displays (xp12) - fixed camera position for 753 (xp12) - fixed 3d reflections in displays (xp12) - fixed various issues with lamps (xp12) - fixed hovering gear (xp12) - fixed possible steering issue (xp12) - improved AT SPD mode behaviour (xp12) - updated billboard effect for external lights (xp12) ‍ FlightFactor 767 - 1.6.2 - added glow effect to the FPDS displays (xp12) - fixed 3d reflections in displays (xp12) - fixed various issues with lamps (xp12) - fixed tiller animation (xp12) - fixed possible steering issue (xp12) - fixed dome light issue in cold&amp;dark - improved AT SPD mode behaviour (xp12) - updated billboard effect for external lights (xp12) - made chart light knob as override knob (400) ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mtnfly</id>
    <title>MtnFly Simulations freeware Learjet-35A progress Update </title>
    <updated>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mtnfly" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632a05b9889cd711b0e93059_Screenshot_2021-09-29_170109.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="278400"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MtnFly Simulations have been developing a freeware Learjet-25A and have recently released a substantial progress update, outlining what has to be done, what is complete and even showcasing a full flight of the aircraft on their youtube channel.  Their update log outlining what has been done is as follows:  - NAV and COM radios are fully functional and will now work with the Garmin GPS even though there is no concept of a true standby frequency in the early model 35's radios. - The yaw damper has been modelled and is now functioning. - The three AC to DC power inverters are now modelled and functioning. - The FC-200 autopilot is now working as expected. - Improvements have been made to the side audio panels. - All four batteries are now connected to their respective power busses and function  - The captain's flight instruments are close to being fully functional. - The emergency brake lever has been modelled and now functions. - The cabin temperature indicator will now display a "cold-soaked" temperature on start-up. It will react to the user's set temperature setting once the engines are running and the passenger air conditioning system is turned on. - Improvements have been made to tying electrical circuits to their respective circuit breakers. - The RCA WXD weather radar has been modelled for those that prefer to fly "old school" without any GPS. - Panel lighting has been added. - Exterior Lighting has been added. - There have been many improvements to emissive lighting throughout the aircraft. - The wing to fuselage fairing has been added. - There have been numerous modelling updates. ‍ At Threshold we will keep you updated while this project progresses. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfs10</id>
    <title>MSFS Sim Update 10 Launches Sept 21st</title>
    <updated>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfs10" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632a08295954ea3cea5b3bd2_FdHkgcKX0AAK9h4.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="199970"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator have just confirmed that the long-awaited Sim Update 10 will be released tomorrow, September 21st 2022. The update will release at 8:00 AM PDT which is 1500 zulu time.  To see the official announcement you can head over to the MSFS Twitter account. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxor</id>
    <title>Orbx Introduces New Reward System</title>
    <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxor" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632b4b1a2011e902f3364e3f_5NH7H7a.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1194465"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently announced the introduction of Orbs, their brand new in-game currency that is earnable through purchases on the Orbx Store or Volanta (by purchasing a subscription, exploring aerocaches, or completing challenges). Users can spend their coins on the Orbs Store, which offers a list of redeemable sceneries for X-Plane 11, Prepar3d, FSX, and Microsoft Flight Simulator.  It’s important to highlight that Orbx has added a temporary multiplier to the Orbs reward system, granting twice as many coins for purchases on Orbx Direct and Volanta. The offer ends on the 3rd of October, at 01:00 UTC.  Read more about the Orbs here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a35012</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases A350 Beta for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a35012" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6330002416fb7f29f7644cc7_Screenshot%202022-09-25%20at%202.15.42%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3492074"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular aircraft developer FlightFactor has recently announced a compatibility update for the beloved, highly in-depth A350 Advanced for X-Plane 12. Not much has been updated on the aircraft overall though the plane now works with the SimBrief flight plan downloader. It must also be mentioned that this aircraft is now in Beta for X-Plane 12. The lack of any exciting new features in this Beta update and any news for the A350’s future is expected after the recent updates of the 767 and 757. Unfortunately there is still no news on their 787 that is still in the works but keep your eyes peeled for possible sneak peaks in the future. Currently, the A350 beta can be obtained from the X-Updater for current owners of the A350. Make sure to check the BETA box to allow the aircraft to work in X-Plane 12. If you have not yet bought this A350 you can find it on the X-Plane Store. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs2023</id>
    <title>Flight Simulation Association Publishes Travel Details on FlightSimExpo 2023</title>
    <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs2023" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633008aa7846f12a25604181_2019_15.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="401796"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, Flight Simulation Association published the travel details for FlightSimExpo 2023. The 3-day event is currently set to take place between June 23 - 25 in the city of Houston. Different from previous expos, FlightSImExpo 2023 will be held in two different locations. On Friday the 23rd, the event will be hosted in DoubleTree Houston Hobby where guests can participate in a reception and welcome seminars. On Saturday and Sunday, the event will move to Lone Star Flight Museum which is around a 15 minutes drive away from the hotel. Those who attend the event will receive free access to the museum for the weekend. Apart from the official events, the organizers are also working with NASA, the FAA, and other parties to arrange off-site excursions. The organizers have once again negotiated discounted prices at two hotels for attendees for FlightSimExpo. They encourage anyone who wishes to attend the event to book their hotel rooms as soon as possible in order to enjoy a special rate of $109/night at the DoubleTree and $89/night at Houston Marriott South at Hobby Airport. Guests at these two hotels will enjoy free transportation to/from Houston Hobby Airport, as well as free parking for those who are driving. Finally, the organizers have also obtained a 10% discount for those looking to purchase tickets to Houston from Delta or Southwest Airlines. More details on travel discounts can be found here. Registration for the expo will open in December; a 3-day pass can be purchased for only $50 USD. Currently, a final list of developers who will participate in the event has not been released; Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrmau</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases Major A320 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrmau" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633079f174586d275b894b32_fenix.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="659789"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations released a major update to their Airbus A320 add-on, which ensures compatibility with the newly released SU10 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with several other fixes and improvements that were long wished for by the customer base. Aamir Thacker, Fenix’s CEO, published an announcement on their Discord server where he describes the several things that were added and improved. A “too long, didn’t read” list with some of the most important changes can be found down below:   Check out the full changelog here. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/terstu</id>
    <title>Terrainy Studios Release Vans RV-8</title>
    <updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/terstu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633099fbf857a017e833fd61_54b8e8_d746d85cbe574e3284490bd43001af28_mv2.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="317782"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Terrainy Studios have released their all-new Vans RV-8 for Microsoft flight simulator.  The Vans RV-8 was first introduced and flown in 1995 and has since proved to be one of Vans' most popular aircraft build packages. Those who are familiar with the Vans fleet will understand that the aircraft are experimental and often built by the owners. The American aircraft designer and Vans Aircraft founder Richard VanGrunsven’s beautifully designed RV-8 is now available for MSFS thanks to the development team at Terrainy Studios!  The Aircraft includes the following features: ‍ ‍ The Terrainy Studios RV-8 is available now from ORBX for approximately  £18.00 ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fdream</id>
    <title>Footage Designs Releases Empuriabrava Aerodrome for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fdream" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63349f1f28957df9af9a3539_leap1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="233171"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Footage Designs has released their rendition of Empuriabrava Aerodrome (LEAP)  for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Very popular among skydivers and with a privileged location (150km from Barcelona), it’s often busy with student and private pilots landing left and right all day long, all coordinated via air-to-air frequency. The scenery was built from scratch, with custom-made buildings, dynamic lighting, and optimized for performance on all sorts of hardware. The full feature list can be  found down below: ‍ The scenery can be purchased on flightsim.to for $7.00 and requires at least 445 MB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerovj</id>
    <title>Aerobask Release ViperJet For XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerovj" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6334ab59349254af721e331f_viperjet3.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="144016"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular X-Plane aircraft developers Aerobask, best known for their Phenom 300 and upcoming Falcon 8X have just released an all-new aircraft! The ViperJet. The ViperJet is a home-built Jet aircraft which first flew toward the end of 1999. It then made its public debut at AirVenture in the year 2000. The base kit retails for around $200,000 but most complete aircraft end up being finished closer to the $350,000 range. Figures from April 2020 show that there are currently 7 ViperJet aircraft registered in the USA.  Thanks to Aerobask, you can now have your very own ViperJet!  The aircraft features include:  To read a complete feature list or pick up your own ViperJet, visit the X-plane.org store where you can get it for $34.95</summary>
    <published>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrnah</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases New A320 Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrnah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6335d703e818b60e18eabac2_fnx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="588509"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has just released a new hotfix to their recent A320 update, addressing issues with the rudders and landing behavior (it was prone to bouncing even with smooth touchdowns, introduced with the first hotfix that addressed the drag coefficient of the flaps). The update is available on their website for registered customers. ‍ ‍ A320 v1.0.3.134 [SYSTEM]  - Adjusted custom low speed friction model to be slightly more fluid  - Fixed incorrect air/ground mix factor causing irrecoverable nose down elevator after a bounced landing  - Removed alpha-buffer pseudo-prot, causing issues with flare authority in certain conditions [FM]  - Adjusted spoiler efficacy  - Improved suspension geometry and setup to reduce bouncing, absorbing more energy on touchdown and subsequently sitting lower on the ground  - Added lift dumping to spoilers so the aircraft is more stable after touchdown in a crosswind  - Improved aircraft's crosswind and weathervaning characteristics  - Adjusted lateral tyre friction to prevent weight on wheels sideslip and/or unintended ice skating ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/c510mu</id>
    <title>Cockspur C510 Mustang Released </title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/c510mu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63373766a015491a7a531238_C510_Promo_1-600x312.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="167576"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSFS aircraft developers Cockspur have released their all-new C510 Mustang for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release may come as a surprise to some in the community who have not been following development too closely, as initially it was due to release a little further down the road.  The C510 is a very light business jet developed and built by the Cessna aircraft company. The mustang is approved for single pilot operations and seats 4 passengers in the standard configuration. It is also used by various operators throughout the world as an air-ambulance which has been recreated by the Cockspur team! The aircraft offers the following features;  -3 different variants; Standard, High Sierra, and air ambulance -Multiple liveries -Different static elements depending on variant -Accurate flight model -Accurate systems modelling -Built from scratch for MSFS -Interactive Cabin -Visible passengers -Custom engine sounds -Extensive documentation -Developed with help from real Mustang Pilots -G1000 NXi integration The Cockspur C510 can be purchased from the Cockspur website for Euro 24.99 ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfscn</id>
    <title>MSFS World Update XI Canada Is Now Available</title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfscn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63373970708fb006caf3d578_MSFS_WU11_Canada_NoSnipe_Logo_NoText.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="931127"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSFS have released their all-new world update XI which focuses on Canada. One of the most stunning countries in the world, Canada is renowned for its incredible wildlife, lake districts, mountain ranges and of course Tim Hortons coffee! The new update from the team behind MSFS brings more focus and detail to Canada than ever seen before in a flight sim.  Asobo revealed: "In creating World Update XI: Canada, the Microsoft Flight Simulator team processed troves of its latest geospatial data, including digital elevation models, satellite imagery, and aerial photography. Complementing the data, models and imagery, the update highlights 12 urban regions enhanced with the latest photogrammetry data and features 87 hand-crafted points of interest" Just some of the new cities which have received an overhaul in this latest update are:  The update also brings 5 brand new handcrafted airports to MSFS, these are:  ‍ Best of all, this new world update is completely  free! to read a full changelog view the MSFS website. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/urbcms</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Belfast City for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/urbcms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63374a011c29c2396cf6850d_egac1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="451303"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has recently released their rendition of George Best Belfast City Airport (EGAC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second airport serving the city of Belfast, located right in the heart of it and with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. Unlike Belfast Aldergrove, most of their routes are within the United Kingdom, with one international leg to Amsterdam with KLM, with seasonal charters to Barcelona and Bologna to begin in 2023, operated by EasyJet. The scenery uses PBR materials, including realistic ground markings, modeled interiors for both tower and pier, animated jetways, custom vegetation, and optimized for high performance. The feature list follows down below: The product is available on UK2000’s webpage for £14.99 or Flightsim.to for $14.99 and requires at least 121 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asdrka</id>
    <title>Aviation-Sim-Design Releases Kyritz Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asdrka" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63374b591167780c714abe9e_edbk.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437983"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviation-Sim-Design has just released their rendition of Kyritz Airfield (EDBK)for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a commercial airfield in a district near Berlin and close to the Baltic Sea. With two runways of one kilometer each (asphalt and grass), it’s the ideal environment for general aviation airplanes and gliders. With a modern lighting infrastructure, nocturnal flight operations are allowed, making it a jack-of-all-trades for small aircraft. The feature list follows down below: The product can be purchased on flightsim.to for $10.49 and requires at least 1.26 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msrsam</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Shannon Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msrsam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63387c0c0ebc1cf35e918f33_shannon1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="353094"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just released their rendition of Shannon Airport (EINN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Ireland, with plenty of aviation history on its back (first transatlantic proving flight, first duty-free airport shop, Europe’s first United States border preclearance facility, the list goes on). Back in the 1960s, it was a busy refueling stop for international carriers crossing the Atlantic. Nowadays, it averages around 1.7 million passengers every year (pre-pandemic). It’s a focus city for Ryanair, with over 16 routes. The scenery features an updated ground layout, realistic night lighting, satellite coverage around the airport and a detailed mesh. It can be purchased for $12.78 on Orbx Direct and requires at least 2.13 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
