<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-07-09T18:26:18.968179+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpar3</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Piper PA-28R Arrow III for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpar3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667edde7ee0551d22a850899_piper1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. In partnership with Thranda Design, Just Flight has developed a rendition of the Piper PA-28R for X-Plane 12, featuring a highly detailed simulation of the popular four-seater first introduced in 1976. As the name suggests, the PA-28R Arrow III is the third iteration of the Piper Arrow lineup. It was launched in 1967 with the PA-28R-180, followed by the Arrow II. Five years later, it was majorly upgraded with a semi-tapered wing, larger fuel tanks (meaning increased range), and several other improvements and commercialized under the Arrow III moniker.  The add-on features high-quality 8K texturing throughout, reworked PBR materials, a brand new EFB tablet with aircraft configuration states, checklists, and customization options, a dynamic livery feature with color, design, and dirt level change on the fly, a high-quality FMOD sound set, and much more.  It’s available on Just Flight’s website for roughly $42.99, requiring at least 2.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777034</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates Boeing 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777034"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6680370f026bdbb7a3de9eb8_1250410_20240626232724_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued an update to their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing some WASM crashes, FMC bugs, and geometry fixes.  They also anticipate a series of updates in the next 14 days, aiming to mitigate user experience-disrupting issues (primarily), and the other teams (model, art, and sound) will also push their fixes. What hasn’t been fixed yet is an SU15-induced issue plaguing their 737 and 777, causing both to freeze entirely and stop responding. They have been working with Asobo to find out the root cause, and “victims” are encouraged to file a support ticket with PMDG so they can be surveyed.  Update 2.00.0034, issued via Operations Center, addresses the CLR bug that plagued many day one 777 pilots; hitting cancel on the EICAS no longer freezes the aircraft, and many model adjustments were made. The changelog follows below: ‍ The next update is already being tested and will fix long directory names preventing the installation process from working altogether.  The Triple Seven is available on PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ifly29</id>
    <title>iFly Previews Upcoming 737 Max 8 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ifly29"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66807e97309d17b67d3695b2_ifly1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iFly has recently published a new development update for their upcoming Boeing 737 Max 8 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring a gallery with over 30 preview images. Other than the images (which say more than a thousand words, one could argue), iFly claims the development is moving along nicely. They have been considering creating a Discord channel to keep everyone updated on the project as it progresses. The 737Max is Boeing’s response to the A320Neo. It has bigger, high-tech, and very efficient engines, a different wing, and a completely new glass cockpit while operating in a similar fashion to its previous iteration, the 737NG. With that, airlines save money in training costs as the commonality is retained.  There’s no pricing or release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tfdimd</id>
    <title>TFDi Releases MD-11 Trailer</title>
    <updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tfdimd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6683267f4cf56bfe16819c37_ext_5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TFDi, a development group well-known for their products such as B717 and PACX, have just released the trailer for the long-awaited MD-11. Unveiled yesterday on TFDi’s YouTube channel, it showcased the progress through years of development, with an interesting song choice in the background.  The trailer previewed mostly internal and external visuals, unfortunately, we couldn’t hear any sounds. We could see that significant effort has been made by the developer team in modelling and texturing. At the very end of the video, we could see the release date - 2nd July! TFDi’s MD-11 Base Pack will cost $69.99 (cargo or passenger), while the Expansion pack (conveniently named The One You Did Not Purchase Already), is priced at $9.99. Later in 2024, the Extended Simulation Package will also be available for purchase. The package will include operational failures, an advanced custom failures menu, and circuit breaker functionality. The MD-11 will be compatible with MSFS, P3Dv4/v5/v6, although support for MSFS2024 still hasn’t been officially confirmed until the developers receive more information about the upcoming simulator. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flightsim news and high-quality reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42vic</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Victoria Falls Scenery Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42vic"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6683e9d40a71c203a10f0034_Banner_Image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After appointing Jeppeson2001 as the new Head of Scenery Design, Parallel 42 has re-released the Victoria Falls Scenery Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator with some updates. The new pack allows users to explore the iconic Victoria Falls and enjoy its beauty. The updated scenery pack includes waterfalls, heliports, and bush strips located near Victoria Falls. It features 6 heliports, 4 bush strips, an animated Victoria Falls with sound and mist effects, 30 landable helipads, and various animations such as boats and rapids. You can purchase the add-on for $15.00 from the Parallel 42 Store, as well as from Orbx and Contrail. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/md1027</id>
    <title>TFDi Releases MD-11 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/md1027"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/668458d15be9fb7c3b057a59_md1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TFDi has recently released their rendition of the passenger and cargo variants of the McDonnell Douglas MD-11 for Microsoft Flight Simulator (and Prepar3d), an ETOPS-capable trijet introduced in 1990 and still in use by many cargo airlines around the World.  The original idea behind the MD-11 development was to take the DC-10 as a baseline and modernize it with the latest and greatest in technology from the early 90s, albeit without going overboard given McDonnell’s financial situation, which led to suboptimal fuel efficiency in comparison with the soon-to-be rivals at the time (Airbus A330/A340, Boeing 777), but with greater maximum range, even if briefly (which made it a relatively short-lived airplane, with only 200 units built).  The timing couldn’t have been worse for a brand-new trijet, as airlines were already prioritizing fuel-efficient twin-engine airplanes and slowly phasing out their fuel-guzzling three, four-engine jets. Unsurprisingly enough, the MD-11 didn’t take off in orders. TFDI’s rendition brings the General Electric engines (Pratt &amp; Whitney option to come later), with custom modeled systems, a custom-built flight management computer, high-resolution texturing, high-detail cabins (pax and cargo), and an onboard EFB allowing you to control payload and change specific settings.  Their “a la carte” pricing model allows you to pick only the variant(s) you want: both cost $69.99 (cargo or passenger), and the other variant can be obtained for an extra $9.99, making it $80 for both. An “ extended simulation package” is set to be released in late 2024, adding failures and circuit breakers. The base packages can be found on TFDi’s website. Shout out to SCOTSGOD for the screenshots! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mcunus</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update 9: Northeastern United States for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mcunus"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66856c682906a6dd1f022d97_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released its latest city update, City Update 9: Northeastern United States. The new update includes a variety of different locations within the northeastern part of the United States. The update includes places such as Washington, D.C., Buffalo, New York, Allentown, Pennsylvania, and the East End of Long Island, New York. Through the utilization of updated aerial imagery and TIN surface modeling, significant enhancements have been made to the various urban areas. This latest update enables users to explore various locations, ranging from the capital city to the shores of Lake Erie. The new city update is available now for free on the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msll17</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Local Legend 17: Curtiss C-46 Commando for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msll17"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/668572b21fd9982687f36309_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft recently released the Curtiss C-46 Commando for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the latest Local Legend at number 17. The aircraft has been impressively developed for the simulator. The C-46 Commando is an American twin-engine aircraft built for military transport. The airplane was manufactured by the company Curtiss-Wright. It had its first flight in 1940 and entered service in 1941 with the United States Army Air Forces. Throughout its lifespan, the aircraft has been used for various purposes including freight operations, medical evacuation, and glider towing. The aircraft has a range of 3.150 miles with a cruising speed of 173 miles per hour at 24.500 feet. The new add-on includes four liveries: Japanese Air Self Defense Force, Olive Drab (Fictional), Blue (U.S. Navy), and USMIL. The aircraft is packed with various features to explore. The newly released add-on is now available on the in-sim Marketplace for $14.99. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxiaok</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Karpathos Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxiaok"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/668590eae25367bdfcc15abb_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design recently released its version of Karpathos Airport (LGKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Located on the Greek island of Karpathos, the airport serves approximately 270.000 passengers annually, who are seeking sun and fun in the Greek islands. Karpathos Airport opened in 1970 as a small airport with limited facilities. Initially, it had only a 500 square meter building. Construction for new airport facilities began in 2005, and the new airport terminal was completed in 2009. The new airport buildings covers a total of 12.500 square meters, a significant increase from the original 500. Today, the airport is a crucial hub for the island, connecting it with destinations both within the country and around the world. The airport serves a variety of seasonal and year-round destinations, including Athens, Amsterdam, Rome, and more, welcoming around 270.000 passengers annually. The scenery package includes accurately modeled terminal and airport buildings, up-to-date ground layouts, PBR implementation, custom CGL aerial imagery, a detailed handmade terrain model, and more. The newly released Karpathos Airport requires 1.81 GB of storage space, and it is available on both SimMarket and Orbx for approximately $10.76. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777036</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777036"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6685d4f8cac256d1fa8d9ddf_klm.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG recently issued the second update (2.00.0036) to their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, aiming to improve the add-on’s performance and stability. As previously mentioned, the second update focuses primarily on stability and performance gains, aiming to mitigate the random WASM crashes, low framerate on lower-end systems, and getting rid of the infamous TA/RA bug inducing freezes on final approach. The full changelog follows below: ‍ Randazzo also mentions it’s not usual practice to add every little change to the checklist, but they want to emphasize how many faults are being corrected in pursuit of optimal stability.  They say the next update is already being worked on and is anticipated to follow sometime this weekend unless they make a breakthrough in the areas affecting user experience (like fully mitigating the WASM lockups).  The add-on is available on PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsegpk</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Glasgow Prestwick Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsegpk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6686bcada17eb2b333997824_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently launched its latest scenery for both X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. This time, they have introduced Glasgow Prestwick Airport (EGPK) for the flight simulator. Situated in Prestwick, Scotland, this international airport serves as a focus city for the airline Ryanair. Glasgow Prestwick Airport has been in operation as an airport since 1935. In 1938, passenger facilities were added to the airport. Over the years, the airport has seen commercial growth, resulting in various facility improvements. It has also served military purposes, with the RAF controlling transatlantic flights during World War II. Today, Ryanair operates the majority of flights from the airport, traveling to destinations like Alicante, Barcelona, and Malaga. Additionally, the airport hosts cargo operations for airlines such as Air France Cargo and Cargolux. Last year, the airport served 525,000 passengers, making it the fifth busiest airport in Scotland. It is also worth noting that Glasgow Prestwick Airport is the largest airport in Scotland in terms of land area. The recently released scenery includes a range of features such as up-to-date HD ortho imagery, 4K PBR terminal and airport buildings, 3D volumetric grass, HD custom clutter objects, realistic GSE, and much more. The recently released Glasgow Prestwick Airport scenery requires 2.6 GB of storage space, and is available on Boundless for approximately $24.24. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rkadcs</id>
    <title>rkApps Releases DCRealistic</title>
    <updated>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rkadcs"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66870936d9f5bb68aa5539cf_Screenshot%202024-07-04%20215109.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. After a long period of silence from rkApps, the developers behind XPRealistic and FSRealistic, have surprised everyone with the release of DCRealistic. The release of DCR marks the third addon from the Realistic series. The goal of DCRealistic is the same as with the other addons from this developer - add immersion to the sim experience. Using camera shaking and sound effects, this addon increases the level of immersion. There are 21 effects inside the app, some of them being: Afterburner, Airbrake Drag, Brakes Canopy Shut, Canopy Jettison, Ground Roll, Over G, Wind ambience, G force, touchdown and many more. Each one of these effects can be manually edited to the user’s liking.  It is also compatible with SimHaptic, another rkApps’ addon that synchronises the Bass shaker with the simulator effects. All mods in DCS are supported, both official and community ones. VR and TrackIR enthusiasts will also be able to enjoy this addon, as both are compatible with DCR. DCRealistic is available for purchase on the rkApps website for $19.99, and the 7-day trial version can also be found on the same page.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tstfff</id>
    <title>TropicalSim Releases Martinique Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tstfff"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/668802960cf517ff5ec927c2_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TropicalSim has recently launched the V2 version of its Martinique Aimé Césaire International Airport (TFFF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Situated close to Fort-de-France, the capital city of Martinique, the airport is about 6 miles away from the city center. It serves just under 1.9 million passengers annually. The airport opened in 1950 and initially had limited traffic due to the island's reliance on maritime transport for its economy. However, after a decade, air traffic increased, leading to the CCIM being awarded the contract for managing and developing the airport in 1965. Further upgrades were completed in 1995 after construction began in 1991. The airport was renamed in 2007 and is currently a focus city for Air Caraïbes and Air Antilles Express. Together with other airlines, the airport offers destinations such as Miami, Paris, and Frankfurt, with an average yearly passenger count of just under 1.9 million. The V2 scenery of the airport includes a highly detailed rendition of the airport, full night illumination, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, use of PBR, and more.  The new V2 of Martinique Airport is available on SimMarket for around $17.84. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ina350</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Previews Upcoming Airbus A350 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ina350"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6689511babff28b4c6f36de6_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has provided a preview of its upcoming flagship iniBuilds A350 Airliner project for Microsoft Flight Simulator. After announcing the project in December, the team has recently shared a few screenshots of the upcoming airliner. iniBuilds posted the previews together with the announcement of its iniBuilds Summer Surprises Event. From July 15th to July 28th, iniBuilds plans to make some new product announcements as well as provide some development updates on iniBuilds aircraft and scenery. The team will host its first iniBuilds Developer Livestream on the 22nd of July. As part of the announcement, the team has previewed the upcoming Airbus A350. While iniBuilds has not yet announced a release date or pricing, the team has stated that they will provide a formal, comprehensive showcase and development update during the announced event. We will keep you informed once more information about the project is announced. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vst38a</id>
    <title>Veco Simulations Releases Trailer for T-38A</title>
    <updated>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vst38a"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6689b05840328720f286ca10_Screenshot%20(81).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Veco Simulations have recently released the trailer for their first community mod for DCS - T-38A Talon.  T-38 Talon is a two-seat, twinjet supersonic jet trainer produced by Northrop Corporation between 1961 and 1972. It was the first supersonic jet trainer, as well as the most produced jet trainer. After more than 63 years since its introduction, it has trained over 72,000 pilots in USAF and other NATO nations air forces, during the joint-training programs. Due to SDK limitations, the development group decided to focus on the 1970s avionic configuration, which will allow them to add every functionality, without the need for other modules or sacrificing fidelity. The mentioned configuration features a functional UHF radio, intercom for communication between pilot and instructor in the back seat, TACAN, ILS, and a mechanical Flight Director system. Veco Simulations’ rendition of T-38 will be released as a free standalone, full-fidelity, community mod. The trailer provided us with amazing shots of the aircraft's exterior and short sneak peeks of the untextured model of the cockpit.  Currently, we have no feature list as of now, but we do however have an estimated release date! At the very end of the trailer, we could see 2025, which could be the possible release year. As of now, no more information about the release date has been released, however, as always, Threshold will keep you updated!  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42777</id>
    <title>Parallel 42’s 777 Immersion Releasing on Friday</title>
    <updated>2024-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42777"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/668b107a1cd3cc1c51cdfc81_simfx1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently announced a release date for their upcoming 777 Immersion package for Microsoft Flight Simulator - part of their SimFX add-on - aiming to improve the overall realism of the effects within the simulator, including condensation, new particle effects, and more. Available as a single package for all major renditions of the triple seven airframe regardless of the livery used, bringing immersive effects for the PMDG and CaptainSim (at a later date) and customized for each with performance as their top priority.  Built on the SimFx framework, it offers the best combination of effects and customizability via the SimFx interface. For the unaware, Parallel 42’s SimFX is a visual effects utility covering a range of immersive scenarios. Every particle on the screen is authentically governed by environmental variables and formulas, and dynamic effects appear under the right conditions, creating unique moments in the virtual skies. The effects include contrails, heat blurs, wing wash, rotor wash, and more. Their immersion package for the 777 builds on top of what SimFx already offers, bringing nineteen custom effects for the mighty triple seven, including swirling contrails, condensation effects, waste water drain every hour, engine cold start effects, fuel jettison, cloud illumination, hot brakes smoke, carbon brake dust, and water droplets. The APU heat blur and the St. Elmo’s fire are not supported because of a development choice by PMDG, using a deprecated technique preventing SimFX or 777 Immersion from injecting their version of those effects. The package will be available for $15.00 on Friday (July 12). Club 42 members are eligible to purchase an early access version of the product.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
