<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-09-08T18:27:15.527329+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rexatm</id>
    <title>REX Simulations Announce REX Atmos</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rexatm"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d32f6a576a46d8e93a759f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The popular plugin developers REX Simulations have announced their latest project, REX Atmos, a shader plugin for MSFS. The plugin will allow users to custom-tweak the weather, environment and atmosphere. Once tweaked they can generate a preset and will be able to share it with other REX Atmos users.  ‍ A picture was shared to show the effects that can be expected on release. The shot showcased the difference between default MSFS and REX Weather Force with REX Atmos. Changes seen include sky colour changes, added true rayleigh scattering, altered environment colouring, and corrected cloud lighting and ozone.  At this point, we do not know any more information about the product, release date or price. However, make sure to keep tuned to Threshold for any further updates and join our Discord server.</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmeddg</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Münster Osnabrück Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmeddg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d340e08b5356f704fffa23_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MM Simulations has recently released Münster Osnabrück Airport (EDDG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the two German cities of Münster and Osnabrück and is considered a minor international airport. It welcomed just under 1 million passengers last year and offers flights to various leisure destinations and European cities. The airport was established in 1966 and has since undergone various developments, including upgrades and new constructions. Currently, it serves airlines like Eurowings, Ryanair, and Sundair, offering flights to destinations such as Palma de Mallorca, Rhodes, and Tenerife, among others. The airport accommodates nearly 1 million passengers annually and consists of one terminal building, which is divided into separate sections for arrivals and departures. The latest release of Münster Osnabrück Airport includes several features such as custom night lighting, parking positions, surroundings, people and animated objects, PBR materials, and more. The add-on requires 2.28 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx for $18.94. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ukbear</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Big Bear Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ukbear"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d396a4ca30c3b7fe75706b_bear1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Big Bear City Airport (L35) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Big Bear City and San Bernardino, California, and has an average of 30,000 aircraft operations per year. The first airstrip in the area was established in the early 1920s. It was mainly utilized for private pilots and airmail service. The overall structure was precarious for its first two decades, and the runway was not paved.  The US Army Corps of Engineers constructed a new runway at the airport in the 1940s, allowing it to be used as a training airfield during World War 2. Following the war, Big Bear City Airport continued to expand. New hangars were built, and the airport's facilities were upgraded to accommodate the growing number of private aircraft and commercial flights. The airport's strategic location in the mountains made it a popular destination for pilots seeking scenic flights and challenging flying conditions. The region's ever-increasing popularity led to increased growth in traffic figures, which forced the administration to implement measures to manage the congestion in a safe - and less disruptive to the residents - manner: specific arrival and departure procedures and noise abatement rules.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, custom ground textures, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR materials, custom static aircraft, and more. It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.29, requiring at least 23.45 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftmcca</id>
    <title>FOX TWO MODELS Releases Cherry Capital Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftmcca"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d3a10dcc95ecdebc75d83a_fox1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FOX TWO MODELS has recently released their rendition of Cherry Capital Airport (KTVC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Traverse City, Michigan, with a yearly average of 602,000 passengers, making it the third busiest in the state. It was opened in 1936 as Traverse City Airport, replacing Ransom Field. A decade later, it was moved to the Coast Guard Air Station and has been operational since. In 2004, a new terminal was opened, wholly replacing the old one, which had been demolished. The runways were also reconfigured, with the third diagonal runway removed. It won the Balchen/Post awards for three seasons in a row for outstanding snow and ice control achievement in the small commercial airport category.  The east-west runway was extended in 2017 to accommodate larger aircraft, attempting an international status promotion (not granted yet). Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Avelo Airlines, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom night lighting, handcrafted models, custom taxi lines and ground markings, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.30, requiring at least 70.63 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsskar</id>
    <title>VueloSimple Releases Skardu International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsskar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d5068ffd6f966d1f9a058e_skardu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. VueloSimple has recently released their rendition of Skardu International Airport (OPSD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a civilian/military airport serving Skardu in Pakistan, with a yearly average of 127,124 passengers. Initially built as a Pakistani Air Force airbase in 1949, following their independence, it was later converted into a domestic airport for civilian use, albeit still serving as a forward operating base for the Pakistani Air Force.  In late 2021, the airport was designated and re-inaugurated as an international airport after undergoing several upgrades to its infrastructure to comply with the required standards. It’s served by airblue (Islamabad) and Pakistan International Airlines (Dubai, Islamabad, Karachi, Lahore). The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models, an up-to-date ground layout, custom dynamic lighting, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.08, requiring at least 119.62 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fratrai</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Launches Mega Airport Frankfurt Trailer for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fratrai"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d66345018e269f48d96e9b_trailer3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft, in collaboration with AviationLads, has recently launched the official trailer for their upcoming Frankfurt Airport (EDDF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which will be released on Thursday (05/09). Developed by Jo Erlend Sund and his team, Mega Airport Frankfurt promises a highly accurate rendition of Germany’s busiest airport. It features custom ground textures, custom jetways,  custom ground service equipment, terminal interiors, custom terraforming, and much more. The final minute of the trailer also provides details on the launch party, which is set to start at 1800Z on the 5th of September, with the presence of Jo Erlend and Lukas Vezyroglou (the lead developers), LondonController (a Twitch Streamer), and Calum (FSElite). IVAO and VATSIM will be fully staffed for the night, warranting a busy release night. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wfssha</id>
    <title>WF Scenery Studio Releases Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wfssha"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d79c55b11a90ad9c3a4fce_shanghai1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WF Scenery Studio recently released their rendition of Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport (ZSSS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Shanghai, the largest city in China, with a yearly average of 33.2 million passengers. Construction started more than a century ago, in 1921, and opened for mixed civilian use in 1923.  It was occupied by the Japanese during the Second Sino-Japanese War and used as an air force base. Even after being handed over to the Chinese government, it remained used for military purposes, only being fully converted into a civilian airport between 1963 and 1964. Two major expansions followed in 1984 and 1988, significantly increasing the airport’s passenger handling capabilities. Since the early 2000s, the airport has mainly operated domestic routes, with most international routes being transferred to Shanghai Pudong. The only exceptions to this rule are a couple of international flights to Taipei, Seoul, Hong Kong, and Tokyo.  It was expanded in 2010 for the Shanghai Expo, which included a new runway and a new terminal capable of handling up to 40 million passengers a year. It’s four times the size of Terminal 1, inaugurated in 1964. It houses 80% of the domestic airlines at the airport. Terminal 1 underwent a major renovation at the end of 2014, bringing it up to modern standards. The renovation was done in two phases, with the final phase reaching completion in 2018. It’s a hub for China Eastern Airlines, Juneyao Air, and Shanghai Airlines. Air China, Air Macau, All Nippon Airways, Asiana Airlines, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Southern Airlines, China United Airlines, EVA Air, Hainan Airlines, Hebei Airlines, Hong Kong Airlines, Japan Airlines, Korean Air, Lucky Air, OTT Airlines, Shandong Airlines, Shenzhen Airlines, Spring Airlines, Tianjin Airlines, Tibet Airlines, and XiamenAir also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, realistic ground markings, a detailed terminal interior, custom jetways, animated vehicles, and more. It’s available in the MSFS Marketplace for $23.99. Shout out to aca343 for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsnij</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Nijima Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsnij"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d8e264d33de41cc6819dc4_niji1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Nijima Airport (RJAN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Nijima Village in Japan and has a yearly average of 32,170 passengers. It was opened in 1970 by the local government, and regularly scheduled flights were only to start nearly a decade later, in 1979, flying passengers to Chofu, in western Tokyo.  With the success of their early scheduled operations, the airport was granted a construction permit in 1984 to undergo upgrades to a national-standard tertiary airport. The work finished in 1987. New Central Airservice serves it with flights to Chofu. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, AI traffic compatibility, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $5.52, requiring at least 7.26 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sibubu</id>
    <title>The Secret Studio Releases Sibu Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sibubu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d8ec11743e29d1332e6d19_sibu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Secret Studio has recently released their new rendition of Sibu Airport (WBGS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator (not to be confused with the one released in late 2022). It serves Bintangor, Sarikei, Kapit, and Sibu in East Malaysia, with a yearly average of 569,000 passengers, making it the 11th busiest airport in the country. It opened in 1994, replacing Sibu’s former airport, which was demolished to make way for the Laila Taib College (its runway can still be seen, albeit partially).  In 2010, the airport underwent a massive expansion project, upgrading the terminal building and car park. With the upgrade, the airport could handle 1.8 million passengers per year. AirAsia, Batik Air Malaysia, Malaysia Airlines, and MASwings serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, PBR texturing, custom ILS, highly detailed passenger terminal, custom aerial imagery, custom jetways, AI traffic compatibility, and custom ground textures. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.24, requiring at least 1.14 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/denup</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Updates Denver for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/denup"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d9c562ce78f52521803bec_C%20Regional.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. X-Codr’s rendition of Denver Airport has received an update to Version 1.1. The update brings many improvements to the terminals and beyond. Some main features include Increased terminal detail (with signs and boarding area enhancements) and higher-quality apron models and textures. The complete changelog follows below: The airport plays a key gateway into the Colorado, with a vast route network across North America and beyond. The airport is also an important hub for United Airlines and the main operating base for both Frontier Airlines and Southwest Airlines.  The updated X-Codr Denver can be purchased from Orbx for US$26.88 and will soon be available on the MSFS Marketplace. In the meantime, make sure to stay tuned to Threshold and join our discord server. </summary>
    <published>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/frafur</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/frafur"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66d9ca4fc7854f2e42602171_frankfurt1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently released their rendition of Frankfurt Airport (EDDF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It is Germany’s busiest airport, with a yearly average of 59 million passengers. Inaugurated in mid-1936, Frankfurt quickly became a central distribution point for airmail transport to North America, and its passenger figures were not too shabby: It carried over 58,000 people during its first year of operation!  It was transferred to the Luftwaffe during World War 2, which led to the dismantling of the famous airships and their hangars. Then, the runway was fully converted into a military airfield. Four years later, Allied bombings destroyed it. Shortly after the war, the US Army took over the airport and built a new main runway and a base (Rhein-Main base).  In the early 1950s, civil air traffic slowly returned to normal: over 400,000 passengers passed through the airport in 1951. It wasn’t until 1958 that Frankfurt would emerge as an international airline hub with the opening of East Terminal. Within four years, it was already too small for the figures at hand, with Frankfurt being the second busiest airport in Europe after Heathrow. In 1965, a new terminal was built to handle 30 million passengers per year, followed by a runway extension to accommodate larger aircraft. A new main terminal, known as the “Central Terminal,” was built in 1972. It is divided into three concourses with 56 gates. At the time, it was assumed that the capacity would be sufficient for the next 30 years! Work on Terminal 2 started sooner than expected (in the early 1990s) because it turned out their Central Terminal was insufficient for the next thirty years. It opened in 1994, bringing the passenger handling capacity to 54 million passengers annually. Developed by Jo Erlend Sund, Lukas Vezyroglou, and their team, Mega Airport Frankfurt promises a highly accurate rendition of Germany’s busiest airport. It features custom ground textures, custom jetways,  custom ground service equipment, terminal interiors, custom terraforming, and much more. It’s available on the Aerosoft Shop for roughly $22.17 (excluding VAT) and requires at least 4.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/virpil</id>
    <title>VIRPIL Shares More Yoke Previews</title>
    <updated>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/virpil"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66da17c920ad1df1cecbfffd_GWtl72oXAAATpr-.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. VIRPIL, a hardware manufacturer well-known in the military flight sim community, has recently shared previews of their upcoming products. Until now, they have been mostly military-oriented, offering joystick bases and military plane grips, collective sticks, rudders, and control panels. Posted on their social media accounts, they showed a piece of hardware resembling a yoke, although a piece of cloth covered it. The following post presented more pieces of hardware that looked like they were connected to the yoke base, on the right side, one could see a knob with a switch that reminded of the Boeing-styled engine start panel.  The next post brought even more details, and caused more speculation. Again, a similar panel to the engine starter was present, except this time, the panel had light controls. The interesting part is that right next to the panel, a landing gear lever on an unscrewed panel. Not much information has been provided by VIRPIL, but one of the theories was that the panels are customisable and that one could set them up to their liking. The latest and the most exciting post, however, was released today. It featured two yokes, the left one shared a striking resemblance to the B737 and B747 yokes, although slightly modified, as the right side had hat switches which are most likely for view controls. The right yoke was a big surprise though, as it looked very similar to the good old bicycle yoke, commonly used on Embraer aircraft. Alongside the image of two yokes, VIRPIL posted a caption saying “Prepare for flight briefing - 06.09.2024!” Keep an eye out, as Threshold will keep you updated on the progress of VIRPIL yokes and any other big news about them. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fask21</id>
    <title>f7 Simulations Releases ASK 21 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fask21"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66db12266c078041daacb892_Microsoft_Flight_Simulator_Screenshot_2024.08.01_-_04.24.20.80_4472x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. f7 Simulations has recently released their rendition of Schleicher ASK21 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  Designed as a replacement for the ageing ASK 13, ASK 21 became one of the most popular two-seat trainers, with over 1,000 of them being built by May 2024. Four versions of this glider were made: ASK 21, ASK 21 Mi (self-launching, equipped with a retractable rotary engine), Vanguard TX.1 (RAF training version), ASK 21B (improved version of ASK 21). This rendition of ASK 21 will feature three different panel layouts, custom sounds, a custom variometer, a realistic flight model, an aerobatic variant, a detailed manual, wingtip smoke, a fully clickable cockpit and a paint kit. It is available for purchase on the iniBuilds store for roughly 18.40 $ and takes up 2.37GB of disk space when installed.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vcayfp</id>
    <title>VIRPIL Announces Advanced Flight Yoke Project</title>
    <updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vcayfp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66db1c388399e65924d7d94a_YokeReveal1.png.76195da414f9cd21a4ba5348ba7218f1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. After a couple of days of teasing, VIRPIL has finally revealed their newest project. The ‘VIRPIL Controls Advanced Flight Yoke Project’ is their first project in the general aviation segment, with the goal of creating the best yoke on the market for an attainable price.  The project revealed two yokes, one of which looked like a Boeing-style yoke, while the second one looked very similar to the Embraer Phenom yoke. The VIRPIL Controls will feature metal construction, a wide range of adjustments, high-precision digital sensors, and swappable yoke handles. Alongside the yokes, VIRPIL confirmed that they will be working on a throttle unit and a lineup of panels.  The ‘Advanced Flight Yoke Project’ will be launched as a project on Kickstarter, starting October 1st 2024. The targeted Recommended Retail Price will be around €500. The Kickstart supporters will also receive early-bird pricing and have exclusive access to discussions about the VIRPIL future lineups.  As always, Threshold will keep you updated on the progress and news about the VIRPIL Flight Yoke Project! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/imadfw</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Previews Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/imadfw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66dc6fab0b1eb45b14733768_Banner_Image-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Imaginesim has offered a sneak peek into its upcoming scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring the Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW). As the third busiest airport in the world, serving nearly 82 million passengers annually, this massive hub presents an exciting challenge for Imaginesim to replicate. Imaginesim has confirmed that most of the terminal buildings with complex geometry have been completed, and they are now moving on to work on the inter-terminal, support structures, towers, airside service buildings, Skylink structure, and all the jetways. Although no release date or price has been announced yet, we will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/warsaw</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Warsaw Chopin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/warsaw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66dca889811ee11ede54fadd_waw1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Warsaw Chopin Airport (EPWA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Warsaw Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 18.5 million passengers, roughly 40% of the country’s total air passenger traffic. Urban development in the mid-1920s led to air traffic complications around Warsaw’s former aerodrome, leading to the need to build a new airport elsewhere. A decade later, a new airport was finally ready to roll, built near the village of Okecie. It featured a ticket office, customs post, police station, newspaper kiosk, restaurant, and viewing terrace—state-of-the-art infrastructure for early 1930 standards.  After the civilian infrastructure was considered ready, they began developing its military potential by constructing a Polish Air Force base, an Institute of Aviation building, an aircraft-building plant, and other military-related structures. In the late 1930s, the airport was equipped with radio navigation equipment to aid pilots during low-visibility conditions.  World War 2 wholly destroyed the airport, which happened to be a battleground between the Germans and the Polish Resistance. It was a bombing target from day one and was occupied by the Luftwaffe as soon as Germany took the country over.  The Germans built their first concrete runways and taxiways, which remained undamaged until the final days of the war when they were deliberately destroyed to prevent the enemies from using them. After the war, LOT Polish Airlines resumed operations at what used to be the airport, kicking off the reconstruction efforts. In two years, they have built a new terminal, a new control tower, and many aircraft parking stands, making it ready to serve people again. The airport’s terminal was reconstructed between 1964 and 1969 after LOT transferred its maintenance rights to state administration. By 1970, it already hit the one millionth passenger mark. It made them realize that their new terminal was already too small, leading to the construction of a temporary arrival hall, and a pre-war structure was used for domestic operations. While passenger numbers slightly declined in the early 1980s, the mid-80s and beyond were the opposite, with the administration urging further expansion of the airport. The expansion plans from the late 1980s only started after the fall of communism in the early 1990s. The new terminal was finally brought to life at the cost of 300 million German marks, using 164 subcontractors and 24 months of work. With a maximum capacity of 3.5 million passengers, it could handle 3.5 more people than the previous terminal, which was more than enough at the time. A new terminal (North Hall) was built in 2008, featuring a considerably larger footprint. It now handles arrivals for Star Alliance and Oneworld Airlines. It’s a hub for LOT Polish Airlines and a focus city for Enter Air, Smartwings Poland, SprintAir, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Air China, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, Ethiopian Airlines, Finnair, flydubai, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Qatar Airways, TAP Air Portugal, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features custom ground textures, PBR materials, performance-friendly optimization, custom jetways, custom ground service equipment, custom landside buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket or OrbxDirect for roughly $24.98/$24.00, requiring at least 1.91 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
