<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-09-20T18:29:03.436579+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vcayfp</id>
    <title>VIRPIL Announces Advanced Flight Yoke Project</title>
    <updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vcayfp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66db1c388399e65924d7d94a_YokeReveal1.png.76195da414f9cd21a4ba5348ba7218f1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. After a couple of days of teasers, VIRPIL has finally revealed their newest project. The 'VIRPIL Controls Advanced Flight Yoke Project’ is their first project in the general aviation segment, with their stated goal of creating the "best yoke controller available to virtual pilots, at an attainable price." The project revealed two yokes, one of which looked like a Boeing-style yoke, while the second one looked very similar to the Embraer Phenom yoke. The VIRPIL Controls will feature metal construction, a wide range of adjustments, high-precision digital sensors, and swappable yoke handles. Alongside the yokes, VIRPIL confirmed that they will be working on a throttle unit and a lineup of panels.  The ‘Advanced Flight Yoke Project’ will be launched as a project on Kickstarter, starting October 1st 2024. According to VIRPIL, the target retail price will be around €500 ($552USD). Kickstarter supporters will also receive early-bird pricing and have exclusive access to discussions about VIRPIL's future lineups.  As always, Threshold will keep you updated on the progress and news about the VIRPIL Flight Yoke Project! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/imadfw</id>
    <title>Imaginesim Previews Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/imadfw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66dc6fab0b1eb45b14733768_Banner_Image-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Imaginesim has offered a sneak peek into its upcoming scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, featuring the Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW). As the third busiest airport in the world, serving nearly 82 million passengers annually, this massive hub presents an exciting challenge for Imaginesim to replicate. Imaginesim has confirmed that most of the terminal buildings with complex geometry have been completed, and they are now moving on to work on the inter-terminal, support structures, towers, airside service buildings, Skylink structure, and all the jetways. Although no release date or price has been announced yet, we will keep you updated. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/warsaw</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Warsaw Chopin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/warsaw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66dca889811ee11ede54fadd_waw1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Drzewiecki Design has recently released their rendition of Warsaw Chopin Airport (EPWA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Warsaw Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 18.5 million passengers, roughly 40% of the country’s total air passenger traffic. Urban development in the mid-1920s led to air traffic complications around Warsaw’s former aerodrome, leading to the need to build a new airport elsewhere. A decade later, a new airport was finally ready to roll, built near the village of Okecie. It featured a ticket office, customs post, police station, newspaper kiosk, restaurant, and viewing terrace—state-of-the-art infrastructure for early 1930 standards.  After the civilian infrastructure was considered ready, they began developing its military potential by constructing a Polish Air Force base, an Institute of Aviation building, an aircraft-building plant, and other military-related structures. In the late 1930s, the airport was equipped with radio navigation equipment to aid pilots during low-visibility conditions.  World War 2 wholly destroyed the airport, which happened to be a battleground between the Germans and the Polish Resistance. It was a bombing target from day one and was occupied by the Luftwaffe as soon as Germany took the country over.  The Germans built their first concrete runways and taxiways, which remained undamaged until the final days of the war when they were deliberately destroyed to prevent the enemies from using them. After the war, LOT Polish Airlines resumed operations at what used to be the airport, kicking off the reconstruction efforts. In two years, they have built a new terminal, a new control tower, and many aircraft parking stands, making it ready to serve people again. The airport’s terminal was reconstructed between 1964 and 1969 after LOT transferred its maintenance rights to state administration. By 1970, it already hit the one millionth passenger mark. It made them realize that their new terminal was already too small, leading to the construction of a temporary arrival hall, and a pre-war structure was used for domestic operations. While passenger numbers slightly declined in the early 1980s, the mid-80s and beyond were the opposite, with the administration urging further expansion of the airport. The expansion plans from the late 1980s only started after the fall of communism in the early 1990s. The new terminal was finally brought to life at the cost of 300 million German marks, using 164 subcontractors and 24 months of work. With a maximum capacity of 3.5 million passengers, it could handle 3.5 more people than the previous terminal, which was more than enough at the time. A new terminal (North Hall) was built in 2008, featuring a considerably larger footprint. It now handles arrivals for Star Alliance and Oneworld Airlines. It’s a hub for LOT Polish Airlines and a focus city for Enter Air, Smartwings Poland, SprintAir, and Wizz Air. Aegean Airlines, Air China, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Emirates, Ethiopian Airlines, Finnair, flydubai, KLM, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Qatar Airways, TAP Air Portugal, and Turkish Airlines also serve it. The scenery features custom ground textures, PBR materials, performance-friendly optimization, custom jetways, custom ground service equipment, custom landside buildings, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket or OrbxDirect for roughly $24.98/$24.00, requiring at least 1.91 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/x12nue</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases Nuremberg Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/x12nue"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e21471721051ac024049c6_nue1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aerosoft has recently updated their Nuremberg Airport (EDDN) rendition for X-Plane 12, bringing revised lighting, revised orthophoto, reworked vegetation, custom weather effects, and more. It’s the 9th busiest airport in Germany, with a yearly average of 4.5 million passengers. As an operating base for Ryanair and Corendon Europe, it connects the city to most of Europe, north and south. The updated rendition brings a standalone, fully customized XP12 version with revised lighting, revised orthoimagery, reworked vegetation, custom PBR textures, weather effects, full support for native XP12 seasons, reworked autogen, and revised static aircraft. It’s available on the Aerosoft Store for roughly $23.10, requiring at least 6.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brasil</id>
    <title>Brazil Land Games Releases Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brasil"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e2179d721051ac0244294f_bruhsilia1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Brazil Land Games recently released their rendition of Brasilia—President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. SBBR is the third busiest airport in Brazil, with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. The airport was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more. It was divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, custom terminal interiors, custom landside representation, accurate runway profile, and more. It’s available in their store for roughly $10. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddulli</id>
    <title>Digital Design Releases St. Petersburg Pulkovo Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddulli"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e33e5a880cf62aee2030c2_347024__07-06-2024_154752.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Digital Design has recently released their rendition of Saint Petersburg Pulkovo Airport (ULLI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the city of Saint Petersburg and Leningrad Oblast, it had more than 18,000,000 passenger operations and more than 144,000 aircraft movements, making it the 4th busiest airport in Russia.  After a year and 6 months of construction, the Shosseynaya Airport (named after a nearby railway station) was opened on 6th June 1932. The first flights to this airport carried passengers and mail from Moscow. Soon after, the airport had scheduled flights to four other regional airports. During WWII, the Shosseynaya Airport was at the front line during the Siege of Leningrad. It took more than 3 years after the war for the airport to be fully repaired, and the scheduled passenger service between Moscow and Leningrad was resumed.  In the mid-1950s, a new extended runway was built and the airport could handle larger aircraft such as Ilyushin Il-18 and Tupolev Tu-104. The early 1960s brought AN-24 and Yak-40 to the airport, and flights to Vladivostok also started to emerge. By the late 1960s, more than 60 airlines offered flights to and from Leningrad Airport. In 1973, the airport was renamed Pulkovo Airport, and the new passenger terminals were opened. In 1990, Pulkovo reached the passenger traffic rate of over 10,000,000 passengers. Unfortunately, after the dissolution of the Soviet Union, the number of passengers rapidly declined.  In 2007, new terminal expansion projects began, and since then, the Pulkovo Airport has seen a constant rise in passenger operations (with an exception in 2020 due to COVID).  The Pulkovo Airport is the hub for Rossiya Airlines, Nordwind, Pobeda, Smartavia, and Ural Airlines, and a destination for over 50 airlines flying to 168 destinations across Europe, Africa and Asia.  Digital Design’s rendition of Pulkovo airport features highly detailed airport objects including interior terminals, custom animated GSE, custom GSX profile, customised jetways, accurate terrain and runway profiles, custom areal imagery, realistic dynamic lighting, St. Petersburg major landmarks, custom helipad at Gazprom Arena, custom animated yachts and boats near the coastline and compatibility with free St. Petersburg landmarks by SkySorceress. This scenery is available for purchase on SimMarket for roughly 21.50 $ and requires at least 4.10GB of free disk space.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cfcygk</id>
    <title>Canadian Flight Sim Studios Releases Kingston Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cfcygk"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e3470a92a6a5432634fdae_5718e7_2a32b0433f1545d893286a364d93b6f9~mv2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Canadian Flight Sim Studios has released their rendition of Kingston Norman Rogers Airport (CYGK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving Kingston (not to be confused with the Jamaican capital!) and the metropolitan area of Ontario. Located 5 miles west of downtown Ontario, it is the largest airport in the area and had 70,000 passenger operations in 2019.  During the WWII, an airfield near Kingston was built for training purposes. In 1942, it began serving as a training station for T-6 Texan and Fairey Battle. In 1953, a Naval Air Squadron was formed, using C-45D Expeditor (military version of Beechcraft Model 18) and T-6 Texans, operating from Kingston Airport until 1959 when the unit was disbanded.  In 1972, the city took control of the airport and extended two runways, while the third runway (12/30) was decommissioned and turned into a taxiway. Runway 01/19 also saw further expansion as it was extended to 6,000ft, while the terminal was expanded in order to accommodate Q-400 and B737.  Today, Kingston Airport is served by Air Canada, FlyGTA and Pascan Aviation, while SkyLink Express offers cargo flights between Kingston and Hamilton. Canadian Flight Sim Studios rendition of Kingston Norman Rogers Airport features custom animated objects, accurate airport layout, accurate ground texture and weather effects, enhanced night environment, dynamic lighting and weather effects and optimised performance.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and high-quality reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oxymml</id>
    <title>Orbx Previews Melbourne Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oxymml"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e34f7fdd32f078a7c07559_Screenshot%202024-09-12%20223025.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently published previews of their upcoming rendition of Melbourne Airport for X-Plane 12. Serving the city of Melbourne, it had more than 30,500,000 passenger operations in 2023 and more than 215,000 aircraft movements, making it the second busiest airport in Australia. In May 1957, plans for making a new airport near Melbourne were announced. Thirteen years later, the Melbourne International Airport was opened, ending Melbourne Essendon’s 20 years of being an international airport for Melbourne. During the first year of operation, Melbourne Airport handled 155,275 passengers and six international airlines. During the late 1980s, the Australian Government formed the Federal Airport Commission and placed Melbourne Intl’ Airport under their control along with 21 other airports. The first major updates were carried out at the domestic terminals, while the other upgrade included a new three-story concourse equipped with 10 jet bridges.  However, in 1994, all FAC-operated airports would be privatised in several phases. This included Melbourne International Airport as well and since then, it has been under the control of Australia Pacific Airports Corporation. Since the privatisation, further improvements to the infrastructure were completed, such as expansions to the runways, terminals, and car parks. In 2005, the airport underwent construction to prepare for the arrival of the Airbus A380. This included widening the main runway by nearly 50ft, construction of dual jetbridges, as well as extension of the terminal building.  Today, more than 40 airlines offer passenger flights to Melbourne to over 120 destinations on four continents. Melbourne also receives a significant amount of cargo flights, as 8 cargo airlines serve Melbourne with regular scheduled cargo flights to 21 destinations.  Orbx’s rendition of Melbourne International Airport will feature high-resolution imagery, updated airport layout, SAM and OpenSAM custom animated jetways, dynamic lighting, animated 3D vegetation, detailed terminal interiors and control tower interiors, and custom ground polygons with detailed markings. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/volv19</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta v1.10</title>
    <updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/volv19"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e355eb170e0b9545039a7b_intelligent-tracking.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated their flight tracking platform to version 1.10, adding a lot of highly-requested features.  The new update has brought profile and aircraft screenshot galleries, where users can check out the gallery with all of the screenshots that they posted, as well as all the screenshots that were posted while flying a certain airframe. Other additions related to screenshots are that users can now add descriptions and tags to screenshots, and while looking at screenshots in galleries, a line containing various information about the flight during which the picture was taken will be displayed. Another highly awaited and requested feature is the user’s average landing rate. You will also be able to filter the flights based on landing rates. If someone isn’t quite satisfied with the landing rate they had on a certain flight, hiding it is also another new feature! Clicking on the landing icon gives you an option to hide the landing.  Other new features include a new section in the ‘Statistics’ section of a flight showing which sim was used, the ability to filter the flight map based on the sim flown in, as well as setting a custom SimBrief airframe to a certain aircraft in your fleet.  The full changelog from Orbx is as follows: ‍Volanta is a free flight tracker that can be used with all popular flight simulators (MSFS, XP11/12, P3D, FSX, FlightGear, DCS, and Aerofly). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eyevea</id>
    <title>EYEVIONICS Launches Early Access For Electronic Flight Information App</title>
    <updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eyevea"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e404705ecefba33f476f1d_EYEVIONICS-Early-Access-2048x95.jpeg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Announcing development last November, EYEVIONICS have been hard at work to create an Electronic Flight Information App. The tablet-based app will allow users to control critical systems in the aircraft without facing the cost of external simulator hardware. The integration into iOS and Android tablets allows users and cockpit builders to pull the virtual screen out of the sim into their hands. Key Features of EYEVIONICS EFIS: The app is available for free on both the iOS and Android store. Once installed, a licence can be purchased from their website for a one-off price of €19.99. This is just for MSFS integration and allows basic features. A more advanced version, what EYEVIONICS calls the "AVIATOR" package will be available at a later date. This includes 3D terrain, terrain alerts as well as a premium support system. Pricing for this package has not been confirmed by EYEVIONICS at the time of writing. ‍ Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold and join our Discord server. </summary>
    <published>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxymmlxp12</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Melbourne International for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxymmlxp12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e54bb831ba03c6717cb561_66e0e6d91890e.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has released their latest scenery for X-Plane 12. The capital of Victoria, Melbourne, is home to many airlines offering flights around the country and beyond. Melbourne features a custom-detailed terminal interior as well as a control tower. It also utilises SAM and OpenSAM to incorporate jetway and VDGS into the scenery. A full feature list can be seen below: Melbourne International acts as a key gateway into the Victoria Capital. Serving as a base for Qantas and Virgin Australia, the routes from this scenery are broad. Suiting all flights from long hauls to other continents or domestic hops. Melbourne International can be purchased from OrbxDirect for $22.95AUD and will require 3.28GB worth of space.  Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold and join our discord server.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jslsgg</id>
    <title>Jetstream Designs Further Previews Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jslsgg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e73b60048e0618298b44db_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Jetstream Designs has recently shared additional previews of its highly anticipated Geneva Airport (LSGG) project for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The team has stated that this scenery is their most detailed and realistic creation to date, adding to the anticipation surrounding its release. The various screenshots offer a detailed glimpse of the airport's features. Although the pricing and release date of the scenery have not been announced yet, the team tells us to stay tuned for an official release date as it is coming very soon. We'll keep you updated with more information as it becomes available. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/feupaf</id>
    <title>Fenix Updates Airbus Family for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/feupaf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66e899efb536751c4841a97b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix has recently released a new update for its Airbus Family for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The A319, A320, and A321 have received a variety of fixes. The team has also added an extra rear window configuration for the A319. The latest version, Fenix A32X 2.2.0.351, includes a number of fixes. The update has mainly addressed the issue of engines spontaneously combusting by fixing and preventing this from happening. Additionally, various other fixes have been implemented. The team has also added a new feature, which is an extra rear window configuration for the A319 variant. The new version Fenix A32X 2.2.0.351 has an extensive changelog, which can be found below: ‍ Fenix A32X 2.2.0.351 changelog:  Known Issues Avionics and Systems Art and Sound EFB Flight and Engine Models The newly updated Airbus Family is available for download through the Fenix Installer. The entire family is available and on sale for £79.99 at Fenix Sim.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/waw111</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Updates Warsaw Chopin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/waw111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66eb8b46f1c4f6889f72fd6e_warsaw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Drzewiecki Design has recently issued an update to their recently released rendition of Warsaw Chopin Airport (EPWA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding an option to remove static aircraft, minor fixes, and more. The changelog follows below: The scenery is available on Contrail and OrbxDirect for roughly $25, requiring at least 5.66 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs24tr</id>
    <title>Everything New About FS24: The Threshold Rundown</title>
    <updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs24tr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ec7fff22729782e85cd48b_ezgif-2-c4a4590944.avif"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft and Asobo have recently announced a plethora of new details about the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, including opening pre-orders for the new sim. They are very confident about the new game, calling FS24 “The Most Ambitious Flight Sim Ever”. ‍One of the flagship features coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is the new career system. Microsoft says that their system “[...] mimics the experience of how real-world pilots start their aviation careers”. In the new simulator, users will be able to pick an airport to start their training journey at, and meet a mentor. The training will start out with the basics of flight in a smaller aircraft, and then users will be able to go through a certification tree for different aircraft plus specialties for things like airliner flying, firefighting, search and rescue, and more.  Performance on those missions will give the user experience and credits, which can be saved to eventually buy aircraft and manage a fleet, which will be affected by how aircraft are flown. According to Microsoft, “[...] every landing, every bump on the runway, is going to impact the warranty of your planes, affecting the cost to keep them maintained”.  ‍The full list of aircraft that will be included at release has also been revealed. Some notable additions include the Boeing 737 MAX8, Northrup Grumman A-10C II, Airbus A321LR, and the Airship Industries A600. Included in the Standard Edition are many of the default aircraft from MSFS 2020 upgraded for FS24, as well as 30 new aircraft, bringing the total to 70 aircraft. The Deluxe Edition adds another 10 aircraft, with 5 more new with FS24. Premium Deluxe gives users 15 more aircraft on top of the standard and deluxe versions bringing the total to 95, with 10 new with FS24, including aircraft such as the Boeing Dreamlifter, Saab 340, and Boeing C17 Globemaster III. (For a more in-depth breakdown on the categories that you can buy, check the “Pre-Orders” section below.) Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is slated to include many new technological improvements. First and foremost, they are introducing a cloud-focused “thin client”. Much more data will be streamed over the internet including all Marketplace content, reducing overall installation size, which was a very common complaint about MSFS 2020. Microsoft claims that the base installation size will be around 30 gigabytes, which makes for more than a tenfold decrease from the previous simulator. Asobo Co-Founder and CEO Sebastian Wloch explains further that they have “[...] integrated everything into the cloud, and it is all streamed and kept into a rolling cache on the hardware. You don’t have to install any new World Updates; they’re just streamed seamlessly.”  Another major addition is the Electronic Flight Bag built by the team at Working Title. It will be accessible from the aircraft as well as the main menu, giving users a more powerful tool for flight planning, integrated charts, and weight and balance management. Some other features include a revamped UI, first person mode, overhauled weather and seasons, “soft body” physics simulation, simulation of every glider port and all maritime traffic, new AI traffic, new photogrammetry, wake turbulence, and much more.  The Marketplace is also going to receive many significant changes in the new sim. One of the most requested features was to overhaul the rating system. The new system will include different ratings for different aspects of a product, such as visual fidelity, system depth, and more. All of those ratings are combined to an overall rating, but users are able to see both the aggregate score as well as the individual categories. Microsoft will also be introducing a rental period for products on the Marketplace. Users will be able to rent some products for a certain period of time for a fee, the price of which depends on how long the rental period is. If the user decides to purchase the product some time after purchasing the rental, the user will only have to pay the difference between the full product price and the rental fee. At the time of writing, Microsoft has not specified how long that period will be. This rental practice will be implemented into all Microsoft products on the Marketplace, but third-party developers will have to opt in to make this available for their products.  If a user owns any Marketplace content from MSFS 2020, it will be brought to FS24, with limited exceptions for addons that may not be compatible with FS24.  FS24 will also include gifting products and virtual currency to friends, provided that users know the recipient’s Xbox Gamertag.  Microsoft has opened up pre-orders for the new simulator today, with 4 editions being available for purchase. Like MSFS 2020 before it, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will have the Standard, Deluxe, and Premium Deluxe editions, but Microsoft is introducing a new tier with FS24, the “Aviator Edition”. The Aviator Edition will come with everything included in the Premium Deluxe Edition, as well as all 30 of the Microsoft-published Marketplace aircraft released from 2021 to 2024. There is also a new limited physical “Collector’s Edition” for sale at the Aerosoft Store priced at $259.99 before tax and shipping, which will come with the Aviator Edition of FS24 plus other physical goodies exclusive to the Collector’s Edition, which we’ve listed in full below. Here’s a detailed breakdown on what each edition will include (all prices in USD):  At the time of writing, Microsoft has not specified what the list of handcrafted airports included in FS24 will be. You can pre-order FS24 at the Microsoft Store. All pre-orders will come with the De Havilland Canada CL-415 firefighting aircraft to fly in MSFS 2020. Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will have major impacts for the hobby, the extent of which is still yet to be seen. As new information comes out about the new entrant in the Microsoft Flight Simulator franchise, Threshold will keep you updated, so stay tuned for that and for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jdgare</id>
    <title>Jetstream Designs Releases Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jdgare"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ed70857ba525ecf74fba1b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Jetstream Designs has just released its highly anticipated version of Geneva Airport (LSGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Swiss city of Geneva and is the second busiest in Switzerland, after Zurich Airport. Annually, the airport welcomes around 16.5 million passengers. The airport opened in 1919 as a small airfield in the area of Cointrin, just outside of Geneva. It wasn't until 1937 that the airport got its first concrete runway. Throughout the Second World War, the airport received various expansions. The first terminal was ready for use in 1946. On multiple occasions, the runway has been further expanded. Today, the airport has two passenger terminals and one Business Aviation Terminal. It serves as a hub for Swiss International Air Lines and is an operating base for easyJet Switzerland. The airport also serves a variety of other airlines from all over the world, offering destinations such as New York, Beijing, Dubai, Oslo, Barcelona, and Palma de Mallorca. With around 173.000 aircraft movements yearly, the airport was able to cater to around 16.5 million passengers last year. The recently launched version of Geneva Airport is filled with features, including a highly detailed and accurate representation of the airport, fully functional VDGS, modeled interiors of all terminal buildings, dynamic airside traffic, custom GSX profile, stunning night lighting, and much more. The add-on requires 2.42 GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for approximately $21.23. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
