<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-09-13T18:31:55.019598+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhsbd2</id>
    <title>LHSimulations Releases Budapest Airport v2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhsbd2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/630b0d2fbe6387116cb4b82b_31.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3392837"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer LHSimulations released Budapest International Airport v2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport, equipped with everything from detailed ortho to high quality PBR textures, will provide sim-pilots with a gateway into the historical city and the country of Hungary itself. According to the developers, Budapest v2 will feature the latest layout of the airport, including a brand new cargo area furnished with aprons and hangers. In addition, the airport will also house functional jetways and “high resolution photobackground” for maximum immersion.  Finally, LHSimulations has promised to bring an array of improvements through future updates from performance patches to custom air traffic. For a full list of features, check out LHSimulations webstore.  Currently, Budapest International Airport can be purchased in the Microsoft Flight Simulator ingame Marketplace, though it is unclear if owners of the original version will receive v2 for free or with a discount. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inijen</id>
    <title>ini Builds Announce The Curtiss JN-4 Jenny and The Grumman G-21A </title>
    <updated>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inijen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/630b3bd342457517411b5b2f_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1468068"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. After having developed the A310 for MSFS, iniBuilds announces the continuation of its partnership with MSFS with two new aircraft under development: The Curtiss JN-4 Jenny and the Grumman G-21A Goose. Both aircraft will be 100% free and developed exclusively for MSFS. In a forum post, the CEO of iniBuilds is pleased to announce the continuation of their partnership with MSFS with these two historic aircraft under development. The Curtiss JN-4 Jenny, was a military training aircraft with production starting in 1915. After the end of the First World War, there was a surplus of aircraft that became civilian aircraft in 1918. From then on, the JN-4 became a very popular trainer for solo training flights, for the civilian market. It is therefore a historic aircraft full of adventure and history that iniBuilds is developing for a modern simulator, more than 100 years after the real-life Curtiss JN-4 Jenny was released. The second aircraft under development, the Grumman G-21A Goose, has a different story. Originally, it was a group of Long Islanders who wanted a business aircraft to fly to and from New York. So they approached Grumman. Following discussions, Grumman converted the Grumman Goose and that's how the G-21A was born, in around 1936. The G-21A was later upgraded to carry 8 passengers and fly military missions all over the world. iniBuilds has endeavoured to reproduce this atmosphere in the aircraft cabin with a bar, champagne bucket and restroom facilities to remain true to the model.  The first pictures of the cockpit show the progress the developers have made on this aircraft, which already makes us want to fly it!</summary>
    <published>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12pr</id>
    <title>X-plane 12 On The Horizon </title>
    <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12pr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/630e5546d03ed8751f504f18_FbbRDtFXoAMOkdh.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="381275"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-plane 12 is well and truly just around the corner! Over recent weeks Laminar Research have released more and more teaser footage of X-plane 12 to the public.  Perhaps the most significant update so far, alongside the release of the X-plane mobile version 12 update, has been published just moments ago via the official X-plane twitter in which Laminar disclose a new build, which is a strong candidate for public early access and is currently being wrapped up and prepared for testing by the team. Testing is likely to begin tomorrow according to Laminar. Once this testing begins we should have a much better idea of timeline for release!  Exciting times for X-plane fans, for quick and correct information keep your eyes on www.thresholdx.net For now, we will leave you with some stunning photos released by the X-plane team in preparation for release.  ‍ Thanks to community member Serzh for highlighting this news! </summary>
    <published>2022-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inihop</id>
    <title>iniScene Release Hooper Heliport </title>
    <updated>2022-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inihop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631398e491ee611357bc243a_4.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1503369"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniScene has released their all-new X-plane 11 Hooper Heliport scenery. This is a new milestone for iniScene being their first-ever entry into the helicopter market. the iconic Hooper Heliport (58CA) is located in thriving downtown Los Angeles, California. Owned by the City of Los Angeles, the heliport is used exclusively by the LAPD's 16 helicopters. Key features of this scenery include;  ‍ iniScene has released a trailer for their all-new scenery which can be seen; ‍ Hooper Heliport is available now from the ini-Store for just £4.99 GBP ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rjp146</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes Blog on Differences Between RJ Professional and 146 Professional</title>
    <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rjp146" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63153e5ea1b32d75101a875b_RJ_9.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="275969"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, developer Just Flight published a short blog on the key differences between its upcoming RJ Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator and the 146 Professional for MSFS that was released almost a year ago. Through the post, Just Flight briefly introduced the most noticeable, as well as the more hidden, differences in exterior modeling and cockpit layout of the two products. Starting with the exterior, the developer pointed out that RJ Professional will feature different probe configuration, more powerful engine options, and as many as 29 new liveraries. Moving on to the cockpit, the most significant upgrades to the aircrafts can be seen. Most of the analog instruments from the HDI to the engine indicators are placed with a new suite of electronic flight instrumentation systems. The new system will also include a brand new primary flight instrument system, and navigational display. Furthermore, the cockpit will feature a digital metric altimeter, full authority digital engine control system, and a “more capable digital flight guidance system (FGS) is controlled by the mode control panel (MCP)” Finally, the RJ Professional will be equipped with two custom-coded GNLU-910 FMSs and a new automatic pressurization system in the overhead panel. In addition to the upgrades described above, a series of more subtle changes from a reworked radio panel and yoke checklists are also added to the aircraft. A full list of changes can be checked out on Just Flight’s website. Currently, Just Flight is yet to announce a release date and pricing for the RJ Professional for MSFS. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12fl</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 Release On Very Short Final! </title>
    <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12fl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63162b3f35ac39c183d12bb6_Fb5zPBUWIAsOIEo.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="857267"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research, Developers of X-Plane have announced that their all-new and game-changing Flight sim is on short final and expected for release within 24 hours!  In an official X-Plane Twitter announcement, the developers revealed;  ‍ Update:  As of two minutes ago, the X-plane website has gone down for maintenance which X-plane has confirmed on Twitter, “down for obvious reasons…. It's happening” Release is expected very shortly.  Keep your eyes peeled for more articles as the next 24 hours unfold. We will be discussing statements from developers on their products for X-Plane 12. We endeavour to bring you all the latest news surrounding this exciting new release!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerfal</id>
    <title>Aerobask Provide Update On Falcon 8X</title>
    <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerfal" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63162b3b5ff28b1db212e3cd_312719733_Slection_1125.jpg.3a54ceeb64fd577b86706c42da0ace99.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="137511"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane 12 is just around the corner, and with NDAs lifted as of the 5th of September, many developers have been providing updates on their new and converted products for X-Plane 12. One of the most eagerly anticipated products is the all-new Aerobask Dassault Falcon 8X.  Updates on Falcon 8X development have been few and far between as of late due to Non-disclosure agreements between developers of aircraft and Laminar Research, developers of X-Plane 12. Now that such agreements have been lifted, Aerobask has provided some stunning new images through a forum post of the Falcon 8x in the X-Plane 12 world.  Its worth mentioning that each screenshot has been taking in stock X-Plane 12, we can see just how stunning the new sim is!  Although not much information surrounding progress or a timeline has been released, we have been provided with a closer look at the aircraft than ever before!  We will keep you updated on this as it progresses but for now, enjoy these beautiful screenshots ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12re</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 Released</title>
    <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12re" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63162c1e2485a0822bcf4b73_Fb5r2HLXgAUS8Mf.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="76582"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The moment has arrived, and a new generation of flight simulator is upon us. Taking to Twitter just moments ago X-Plane announced that X-Plane 12 is now available. X-Plane 12 can be purchased from X-Plane.com for $59.99  Laminar Research has provided the following information;  New features:  This Early Access digital edition is ideal for people who: X-Plane 12 Early Access includes: Continue to keep your eyes on Threshold over the coming weeks for the latest updates and news surrounding aircraft, scenery and much more for this all-new simulator. ‍ ‍   ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pcmsfs</id>
    <title>Project Coastline For MSFS Released</title>
    <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pcmsfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6318c38cffe8d6748154f34b_279722058_397582412376955_6692229729613934459_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="813814"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Project Coastline Italy and Malta have been released for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This version may be a work in progress but it is still a jaw-dropping scenery package and is now available for purchase. Containing 400km of the Italian coastline this VFR scenery is a pilot's dream. ‍ “Rocks, cliffs, boats, yachts, docks, harbours, marinas, palms, working lighthouses, moving harbour crane lifts, parasols, night lights, animals, and more have been added to improve the overall quality of the coast, which by default is flat and dull. Landmarks have been added to the world map so you can easily plan your trip.”   According to the developers the addon currently includes;  - The whole Tuscany region improved with rocks, marinas, harbors, boats etc. - The commercial harbours of Genova, La Spezia, Savona-Vado  (Liguria). - The commercial harbours of Cagliari, Olbia, Porto Torres (Sardegna) - The commercial harbours of Gioia Tauro, Reggio Calabria (Calabria) - The commercial harbour of Catania, faraglioni di Aci Trezza, - Palermo, Messina, Gela (Sicily) - The commercial harbour of Civitavecchia, Fiumicino, Olbia (Lazio) - The commercial harbour of Trieste (Friuli-Venezia-Giulia) Venezia (Veneto) - The commercial harbour of Bari, Taranto and Brindisi (Puglia) - The commercial harbour of Ravenna (Emilia-Romagna) - The commercial harbour of Naples and Salerno(Campania) - The commercial harbor of Ancona and Pescara (Marche) - Malta - Astronomical Observatories - Boats have been added to the whole Italian coast and lakes. - An optional freeware version of the Grosseto Military Airport LIRS (USAF planes are present just for eye candy). - All the rivers bridges and underwater objects of the 9 photogrammetric Italian cities have been cleaned up. Now all the bridges are visible and not covered in water. The cities are Milan, Verona, Venice, Bologna, Florence, Rome, Naples, Catania, Palermo, and Bari.   This is well and truly a must-have for VFR pilots who enjoy flying in the region and is available from both Flighsim.to and Simmarket for approximately €25.00  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aero12</id>
    <title>Aerobask Announces Upcoming Release of ViperJet</title>
    <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aero12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631914afdfb6c651033ab6bf_1677803628_viperjet-2022-08-2409_51_00.jpg.8e2f5543f43b4ad8bb55c49cbd2f1f61.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="157684"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. This week, Aerobask announced information regarding the ViperJet for the newly released X-Plane 12 Public Beta. Originally released in 2015 for XP10, the ViperJet has been updated to keep up with the improving progress of Laminar’s X-Plane Flight Simulator. New improvements for XP12 include updated avionics, a flight model tailored for XP12, along with all the expected visuals such as 3D model textures. Aerobask rebuilt the entire aircraft to take advantage of the latest features the new sim has to offer. Detailed in this forum post are XP12 images of this sleek home-built jet showcasing the new XP12 effects added to the new model. We will keep you updated with more Aerobask news here on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilax</id>
    <title>iniScene Announces LAX For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilax" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631a70eb202ef72b5c1cc906_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2117777"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The iniBuilds team have announced the release of their upcoming scenery, Los Angeles' LAX Airport. Over 170 different airlines serve the Los Angeles International Airport, being one of the busiest airports in the world making it a must-have in your flight sim. It is well known that iniBuilds pay close attention to detail when it comes to making scenery, making this upcoming release is no exception! This version of LAX is based in early to mid-2022, easily familiar if you've flown into LAX recently. iniScene detailed a slew of features in the official forum post here. Features include handmade ground textures and dynamic airport lighting. You'll find familiar logos, decals, and ground vehicles on the ramps creating the busy congested feel of LAX. iniBulids have also modeled terminal concourses by hand, giving you more things to check out and explore between flights. Of course, the iconic LAX entryway sign is modeled with dynamic lighting!  Currently, KLAX is in beta testing so expect a release in the near future. iniScene has released a promo trailer detailing more features and details not listed in the announcement post. Check it out below It's worth a watch! Expect more information regarding the release here at THRESHOLD.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xpil12</id>
    <title>xPilot release XP12 Compatibility Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xpil12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/5f3b23368a65f3d9a7c9a339_MainWindow.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="31476"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular plugin xPilot has been updated to beta version .35 which adds support for X-Plane 12 among some other changes. xPilot is a cross-platform pilot client for X-Plane 11 originally, and now X-Plane 12 that allows you to connect to the VATSIM Network so you can fly amongst aircraft and receive virtual air traffic control services in real-time. For a full changelog and the free download link, you can click here ‍ Threshold, bringing you the latest in flight sim news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xenv17</id>
    <title>xEnviro Release Progress Update On Version 1.17 and Beyond </title>
    <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xenv17" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631cf39ddb8f385a8463607d_scale_2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="78835"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The team behind the popular X-Plane addon xEnviro have released an update on what's in store regarding the project's future development.  ‍In a forum post this evening, head of development Magnus has outlined future plans for the project along with reasons behind the perhaps seemingly slow development of version 1.17 ‍ It has been revealed that xEnviro will not be released during the Beta phase of X-Plane 12. Magnus provides us with the reasoning behind this;  “xEnviro will not be released in this Beta run. Laminar Research has closed off all access to the platform by not giving access to the 3D draw callback, depth buffer and so on. X-Plane 11 was already limiting us and thus demanded a lot on performance to work. Especially when Vulkan was released, and our dynamic seasons got abruptly cut off. “  Magnus goes on to further state; “However. We are in a dialogue with Austin on the matter, and I am optimistic that we will find a solution to our limited access so that we can release 1.18 in XP12. Regardless of when this access is given, we must finish 1.17 in XP11.” New features expected in version 1.17 of xEnviro include;  Magnus has disclosed that they are currently rebuilding the beta testing team and while he is not in a position to provide a time frame he provides us with in update in stating “We’re at the final stretch before the chicanes that lead to the finish line” We will keep you update on the development of xEnviro V1.17 as it progresses.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xworld</id>
    <title>X-WORLD Europe Released For X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xworld" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631e5ade0228d10a8e8f8a95_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="481665"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Highly popular scenery package X-World developed by SimHeaven has released its European scenery package for X-Plane 12! In a post on their website, SimHeaven have announced the free scenery package which is now available.  The post on their website states;  "X-World continues for X-Plane 12 the successful and high quality sceneries for X-Plane 11 like X-Europe, X-America and so on. Objects are not set by an autogen rule, they are set  following OSM data in addition with Microsoft building footprints, which leads to a more realistic look and feel." SimHeaven go on to further explain;  "X-WORLD is a series of scenery packages covering the whole world, each continental package is separate available: X-World_Africa, X-World_America, X-World_Antarctica, X-World_Asia, X-World_Australia-Oceania, X-World_Europe" The download for X-Europe can be found here. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fisf6f</id>
    <title>Flyingiron Simulation Releases its F6F Hellcat</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fisf6f" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631f1fa7aad167d92aefa828_f6f-32_900x.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="93348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flyingron Simulations released its long-anticipated F6F Hellcat, adding to its ever-growing war-bird hangar. In WWII, the Grumman Hellcat served primarily as a NAVY bird on aircraft carriers. It replaced the F4F Wildcat to take on the A6M Zero. The Hellcat later became one of the top performing combat aircraft of the war gaining over 5,000 kills by the end of World War II. Flyingiron has brought the Hellcats legacy to Microsoft Flight Simulator with meticulous attention to detail. Flyingiron has also gained recognition for its Spitfire and P-58 models developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The F6F-5 HELLCAT is for sale for the reasonable price of $45 AUD.  ‍ The model is well detailed and handcrafted, taking over six months to complete. A few notable features include attention to aircraft systems and thermodynamics, factors to be considered in terms of wear and tear, and power plant management. Expect a learning curve when flying the Hellcat, which will challenge your manual flying skills. The F6F will be an exciting aircraft to switch to if you are used to flying today's modern birds. Usability features include a virtual tablet with customization options, maintenance, live aircraft monitoring, and more.  For a complete list of features including the product manual, check out the Hellcat product page here on the Flyingiron Simulations site. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcdesh</id>
    <title>DC Designs Announce Harrier Update and Surprise Fighter Project</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcdesh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631fbedc50514036f29d3eea_305975846_507159501412807_4030653392269115163_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="488607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DC Designs have posted a news update to their Facebook page detailing requested features from several customers. One such request from customers is if the Harrier could bow as it does in real-life air displays, as seen in this video. Here is the response. ‍  “I had not had the chance to test this until recently, and yesterday was able to give it a go. The answer was: yes you can! However, to balance the Harrier while performing the bow and not climb, drift, or descend is really difficult even in light winds. The aircraft’s engine thrust responds to N2, which means there is a lag between adding or removing power, and the thrust altering to climb or descend in the hover, which complicates things even further.” Check out more test footage of the Harrier here. The developer also dropped hints of a "Secret project” within the post. Just today the project was announced via Facebook as a partnership with a new developer “CJ Simulations". The pair are working together in bringing the Eurofighter Typhoon to FS2020.  This will be a well detailed model with a fully operational cockpit. The Typhoon will have a custom flight model simulating its unique delta canard system. You can expect many liveries and visual aerodynamic effects to be featured with this fighter as well. DC Designs also released a video displaying the Typhoon's maneuverability, aerodynamic effects, and modeling details! The Eurofighter is slated to be released in October for PC and XBox. We’re looking forward to these releases. DC Designs is known for their awesome fighter aircraft for FS2020, especially the F-14 Tomcat. We’ll keep you updated with more information here at Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
