<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-10-20T18:47:33.818159+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/osalhx</id>
    <title>Origami Studios Announces London Heathrow for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/osalhx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634a0f48a4b16a5c57451dd6_lhr1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1596674"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Origami Studios has recently announced their rendition of London Heathrow (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, the home of British Airways and Virgin Atlantic. It is the 7th busiest airport in the world, averaging 80 million passengers yearly, and has a route network that covers the whole globe. According to their product page, the scenery will feature an accurate rendition with custom buildings, a modeled Terminal 5 interior, moving jetways, landmarks, and points of interest, and modern X-Plane 12 features such as snow and rain effects, reflections and 3D forests. It is said to be coming soon to the iniBuilds store. There is no information regarding the release date or pricing yet, but we’ll keep you updated.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/usrsam</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Spaceport America for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/usrsam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634a3b20f3dfcb35d624a342_space1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2206963"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Spaceport America (9NM9) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an FAA-licensed spaceport in New Mexico (United States) for vertical and horizontal launch space vehicles, launched in 2011 and deemed ready for operations in 2019.  Owned and operated by the State of New Mexico, it is the first purpose-built commercial spaceport, focusing solely on commercial operations. It’s home to companies such as HAPSMobile and SpinLaunch, and a hub for Virgin Galactic, Up Aerospace, and Exos Aerospace.  Its concept was first introduced in 1990 by Dr. Burton Lee, a Stanford University engineering lecturer. Responsible for writing the initial business and strategy plans, he secured 1.4 million dollars in seed funding, aided by Senator Pete Domenici. In 1992, they formed the Southwest Space Task Force, focusing on advancing New Mexico’s space industry  infrastructure and activity-wise. After lots of research, they chose a 70 square kilometer plot of state-owned land, near Las Cruces, to build the spaceport. In 2003, the Economic Development Cabinet Secretary Rick Homans presented the idea to Governor Bill Richardson, which then reached an agreement with Sir Richard Branson from Virgin to make New Mexico the headquarters for Virgin Galactic and consequently facilitate it for the state laws to be enacted and authorize the construction of the airport.  The scenery was built with PBR textures, accurately replicating the real-life counterpart as it looks in 2022. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ It’s available for purchase on FlightSim.to for $7.49 or on UK2000’s website for £7.49, requiring at least 77 MB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffa320u</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases New Update for A320</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffa320u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634a5fd29bff5644bb3c7f2a_Screenshot%202022-10-15%20at%202.22.54%20AM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3340893"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Aircraft developer FlightFactor has recently released a new update to its popular A320 aircraft for X-Plane. This update brings various bug fixes and quality of life improvements to the plane, as well as an array of other misc. features. The A320 made by FlightFactor was first released for X-Plane 10 in February 2018. It was further updated to be made compatible with X-Plane 11 a short time later. The team at FlightFactor has been making constant progress at  fixing any issues and adding new systems to the aircraft. However, there was a long period of no development to the A320 for X-Plane 11 and some users were experiencing performance issues. FlightFactor had reacted to this by releasing a major new update towards the end of 2021 which had fixed many issues users were experiencing. When X-Plane 12 was released, FlightFactor had worked hard on the constant updates with this aircraft and are still continuing to make the small little changes to enhance the users experience within the sim. The new version marks another solid step in the development of the Airbus A320, which is currently an open BETA phase for X-Plane 12. The update provides overall improvements to the flight deck such as font stylings and colors and other quality of life updates to the aircraft systems. Below, You will find the changelog for newly updated A320 v1.5.2 BETA. ‍ Improvements: Fixes: ‍ The update is free and now available to download for all current owners of the A320. You can do this by updating it through the X-Updater or heading over to the X-Plane.org Store. If you want to become an owner of this aircraft then you can purchase it on the X-Plane.org Store. In addition to the A320 beta, the team at Flight Factor has also been hard at work developing their upcoming 777 Professional v2. They have recently released a small development update in regards to the emergency batteries panel. Currently, no further updates have been provided in regards to the 787. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfrjpr</id>
    <title>JustFlight Release Update on RJ Professional Development</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfrjpr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634abbb3a52156542b692494_4_RJ100_BA_Colum_e7EKPrRyT.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="93190"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight have released a new development update on their upcoming RJ Professional series. Announced officially on the 15th of August 2022, the RJ professional line is set to be a more modern and streamlined version of their previous “146 Professional” addon. Differences include slightly larger and more powerful engines, but the most significant difference comes in the flight deck! The RJ professional line will boast an all-new EFIS system replacing the traditional analogue ADI, HSI and engine instruments.  In providing an update on the development process, JustFlight has said: “The interior and cockpit modelling and texturing has been undergoing extensive testing in recent weeks, with every rivet, screw and label being compared to its real-life counterpart, to ensure 100% accuracy. After spending many months developing the 146, it’s been interesting to see just how much was improved and upgraded in the later RJ, and how all come together to reduce pilot workload without losing the appeal of the aircraft.” JustFlight has informed us that throughout the cockpit the majority of instruments are now “alive” and being fine-tuned. The other significant bit of work to take place has been the development of over 30 different true-to-life liveries which will be released with the aircraft!  To read more from JustFlight's latest RJ development update click here! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwoneo</id>
    <title>X-Works Release A330-900NEO Mod for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwoneo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634ae17aa8b1bb7dfa7b4eb8_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="454110"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Works have released their A330-900neo mod for the Laminar Research A330-300 in X-Plane 12. They have worked hard as a team to bring this modification together for users to enjoy the newest variant of the A330. During the time this aircraft modification has been in development , the development team has given sneak peaks and modeling updates to show the progress of the A330-900neo. X-Works have also stated, “If you are on windows: DO NOT update to beta 7! Laminar broke the A330-300 and thus our mod too.” If you want to use this modification you will have to avoid the latest X-Plane 12 BETA update until a fix has been brought out to the Laminar Research. ‍ Features of the X-Works A330-900neo: ‍ To obtain this modification, you can head over to X-Plane.to to download it for Free. To install, you simply duplicate the default Laminar Research A330 folder and drag the new files in, overwrite when prompted to. ‍ If you would like to download liveries for this aircraft, then you can head over to their discord server where they have a selection of liveries. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/versir</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Release KSYR Syracuse for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/versir" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634c0db8014580b7685b6640_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="445532"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Syracuse Hancock International Airport (KSYR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a joint civil-military airport located in central New York that first opened in September 1949. ‍ The real airport is operated by the Syracuse Regional Airport Authority (SRAA) and encompasses approximately 2,000 acres of land in Onondaga County, about 6 miles northeast of the city of Syracuse. ‍ The airport serves as a major transportation centre in central New York, providing direct connections to 29 destinations which are served by a multitude of aircraft from General Aviation, cargo, scheduled commercial flying as well as military aircraft. The airport has a challenging cross-runway configuration as well as a beautiful approach overflying the Oneida and Onondaga Lakes. The original airfield was opened in 1927 as a node for handling airmail for Syracuse and the surrounding towns, the airport expanded into a training centre for the Army Air Forces 14 years later. A short while later in 1949, the airport was replaced with a new airfield that we know today as the original complex could not accommodate the rapidly increasing traffic and demand. Since then, the airport has received numerous enhancements and upgrades, the most recent being a $62 million renovation of the main terminal.  ‍ For Verticalsim’s rendition, the scenery comes with a standard set of features that we can expect from most airport sceneries on Microsoft Flight Simulator, built with high-definition PBR textures and models that accurately represent the airport in its current form. Verticalsim announced that the airport is the team’s most detailed airport to date. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ Verticalsims rendition of KSYR Syracuse airport for MSFS is available for purchase on Verticalsim's website for $17.99, requiring over 4 GB of free disk space to install. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbd757</id>
    <title>Blue Bird Simulations Releases New Previews for 757 in MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbd757" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634c0e74e521b66e3410709c_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="382977"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Blue Bird Simulations has recently released new previews of their upcoming Boeing 757 project for MSFS. The update, which was made on the Blue Bird Simulations Facebook page, provided new images of the nose gear area of the aircraft including textures imported into the sim for the first time. The release, which is planned for late summer/fall 2023 is set to include passenger versions of both the 200 and 300 variants of the Boeing 757. Each variant will include the Pratt &amp; Whitney as well as the Rolls Royce engine options along with winglet and non-winglet types. ‍ Launched back in February this year, the project has seen rapid a development pace, with multiple update drops: one in April and more recently a few months back in July.  The Boeing 757’s stunning performance makes it one of the most popular Boeing aircraft ever built. Its adaptable seating configurations, spacious cabin, and suitability for short, medium and long-range operations offer its users flexibility and its passengers the ultimate in comfort. The first prototype completed its maiden flight on February 19, 1982, and it was FAA certified on December 21st. Blue Bird have said that their rendition of the 757 will be a mid-level complexity aircraft which will be several layers more complex than the default airliners.  The team have a dedicated airline pilot who is putting in a lot of time and effort to make sure the flight model is as realistic as possible using real-world data. The product is a combined effort from developers with decades of experience in flight simulation development.  The Blue Bird Simulations Boeing 757 is set to release in mid to late 2023 and is likely to be available from the Just Flight store, till then, stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsqkia</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases King Air Analogue Gauge Overhaul</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsqkia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634c2bb945464d5e2a272ea5_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="433191"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently released their steam gauge overhaul for the Asobo King Air 350i, the second add-on in Black Square’s overhaul series for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  The new study-level remake of the Beechcraft King Air 350i, which is provided as default with the simulator, provides a completely redesigned interior and panel for the mid-range turboprop aircraft. The overhaul features a fully custom and remodelled electrical system, full 3D cockpit lighting for each gauge and panel, improved flight and turbine dynamics, panel state-saving options, crew oxygen system, checklists, flight manuals and custom failures. Users will find an increased level of detail on the various instrument panels compared to the default level which is also replicated in the cabin.  The Beechcraft King Air 350i is one of the world's most popular business turboprop aircraft due to its versatility. The aircraft is an updated version of Beechcraft’s very sucessful and popular B300 series and features improvements in the cabin, better performance as well as a lower operating cost compared to other models. The aircraft's Pratt &amp; Witney PT6 turboprop engines produce over 1000 horsepower each allowing the aircraft to maintain a speed of 290 knots cruising at 35,000 feet.  Various radio navigation systems are available from several eras of the King Air’s history, so users can pick and choose how they would like to outfit their aircraft’s avionics suite. The Black Square 350i is equipable with a Bendix KNS-80 RNAV system or they can fly with the convenience of a fully digital Garmin GTN 750, giving the user true customisation over their aircraft. The complete feature list follows down below: ‍ Model Cockpit Systems Flight Dynamics  The Black Square King Air 350i steam gauge overhaul for MSFS is available on the JustFlight store for £27.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrgaa</id>
    <title>ST Simulations Releases Gazipasa-Alanya Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrgaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634ccba44c7d629ec1eb6754_gazi1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1900712"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ST Simulations recently released their rendition of Gazipasa-Alanya Airport (LTFG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the city of Gazipaşa (Turkey) and its surroundings, it averages 500.000 passengers every year (pre-pandemic), visited by airlines such as AnadoluJet, Finnair, Scandinavian and Turkish.  The construction finished in 1999, but it only opened in 2010, after TAV Airport (Tepe Akfen Ventures) won the bid to operate the airport for 25 years. It’s famous for being the only airport in Turkey with a highway passing right under it. With a terminal area of 6700 square meters, it has an annual capacity of 1,500,000 passengers.  The scenery features advanced terraforming to replicate the highway tunnel, an accurate terminal replica and taxiway layout, custom models, PBR textures, and many airport buildings. It’s available on FlightSim.to for $12.50 and requires at least 323 MB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpgrhu</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Releases New H145 Update</title>
    <updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpgrhu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634d6ebc5a810ad33e334ce9_hype2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2221281"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Not long after releasing their Hot Air Balloon, Hype Performance Group has updated their Airbus H145 to version 1.0, adding brand new features to both the Base Pack and the Action Pack expansion. “After over 18 months of development, we are very pleased with the breadth of the product and overall fidelity, as well as the built-in activities and functions”, said the Lead Developer in the official update announcement on their Discord. The update adds two new variants to the Action Pack (Offshore and Cargo), four new liveries, additional missions, and variant-related features such as a functional cargo hook. The base package gets several bug fixes and the Hype Radio. The complete feature list follows down below: The base pack and expansion are available on Hype Performance Group’s website (on sale) for $42.99 and $35.00, respectively. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/akdg50</id>
    <title>AKD Studio G550 Release Date Announced</title>
    <updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/akdg50" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634db8b5eb47a77682e256ef_GLF550_AKD_-_2022-10-14_11.43.23.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1941442"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The much anticipated AKD G550 for X-plane 11 and 12 release date has finally been announced! Rarely do jets of this type get attention in simulators, so it will come as a joy to many to find that they can soon fly their favourite business jet in XP11 and XP12.  We recently caught up with the developer of the upcoming G550, Antek. He provided us with details of the aircraft's release date, price and different versions which will be available.  ‍ ‍ The G550 will retail for $31.95, this price remains the same regardless of whether you purchase the XP12 or XP11 model. The good news is: For those who purchase the XP11 model, you will also receive the XP12 model! The G550 will go on sale this October 28th, 2022!  ‍ Threshold will be sure to keep you up to date on the latest developments with this project!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12ac</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12's New ATC Features</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12ac" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634fd2a67c9233813e19c0cc_Screen-Shot-2022-10-17-at-3.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="1155566"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. With X-Plane 12, there have come many improvements from the previous versions of X-Plane. Notably in Xplane 11, the built-in ATC function was somewhat lacking depth, this has been addressed and overhauled with an all-new system for XP12!  In a post on the X-plane website, Laminar Research discusses about the various ATC system improvements in their most recent version of the X-Plane series.   New features include:  Perhaps the most significant improvement to the ATC system however is the addition of global regions, X-Plane will now follow procedures and use voices that are suitable for different regions of the world. This is a huge improvement on the previous system which in essence treated the entire world as if it followed FAA procedures.  Another big improvement to the built-in ATC system is the quality of VHF communications, this will now change, taking into account your distance from the controller, relative altitude, the type of controller, and any blocking terrain that may be around you.  The ATC dialogue menu has also received an overhaul making it more intuitive.  This is a big step in the right direction to improving the overall experience with Xplane, although many agree from participating in the latest public beta, it still has a long way to go.  ‍ Threshold will keep you up to date with all the latest news! </summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aucnfx</id>
    <title>AirfoilLabs Updates C172 NG for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aucnfx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634fd91e612ec12cd4a2b699_afl34.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="955218"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. AirfoilLabs has recently updated their C172NG for X-Plane 12, ensuring it benefits from the new additions to the platform, such as the rain effects. Featuring an accurate flight model, built with real-life flight data and recordings in mind, meaning the aircraft accurately represents effects such as crosswind, air pressures and stalls, along with  a complete rebuild of the 3D model. The Cessna 172 is one of the most iconic aircraft in all of aviation, being one of the first airplanes many pilots will fly. It has developed a strong pedigree through the years, adopting various routes of upgradeability and future-proofing. The aircraft has several use cases, with training being one of its most important roles. The 172's 2400rpm, 175hp piston engine allows the aircraft to maintain a speed of 125 knots and a maximum altitude of 13,000 feet.  The AFL Cessna 172NG is equipped with Garmin G1000 Avionics, advanced maintenance and failures system and even the ability to encounter a birdstrike. The feature list follows down below: ‍ New X-Plane 12 Features  ‍ 3D Model ‍ FMOD Sound ‍ Flight Model ‍ Aircraft Systems  ‍ Electrical System ‍ Engine Logic ‍ Failure Management System and Scenarios Saving  The AirfoilLabs Cessna 172 NG is available on the X-Plane Store for £49.95.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/osrlhx</id>
    <title>Origami Studios Releases London Heathrow for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/osrlhx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634fff2d77435c1046dfffd5_london1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1456939"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Origami Studios has worked hard to get this project released in the last two days after announcing its development for X-Plane 12. London Heathrow (EGLL) is the busiest airport in the United Kingdom and within the top 10 in the world! Founded in 1946 and originally known as London Airport, it was renamed London Heathrow in 1966. It used to have six runways, placed in a Star-Of-David pattern. As Heathrow became bigger and bigger over the years, it was decided there was no longer a need for the 3 of Heathrow’s four diagonal runways, culminating on their closure by the 1970’s, leaving one runway intact (05/23), eventually decommissioned in 2003 for an extension of an existing terminal. It’s the hub for British Airways and Virgin Atlantic, and they cater for many other airlines that fly in and out daily from different countries. It has four passenger terminals which can see over 78 million passengers a year, according to data shown in 2017, heading to and from 185 countries around the world. Fun fact, did you know that aircraft had to be moved from the Terminal 4 remote stands when runway 23 was in use? Origami Studios have brought out a massive asset to X-Plane 12. Including custom buildings, a highly detailed rendition of Terminal 5, landmarks and moving jetways. ‍ Key Features: Want to fly to the busiest UK airport in X-Plane 12? Head over to the iniBuilds Store to purchase Origami’s London Heathrow Airport for £21.99 GBP. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hrdf</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Destin-Fort Walton Beach Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hrdf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/635001f6ac01b2f46c087c67_fwb1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1062607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Destin-Fort Walton Beach Airport (KVPS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an airport within Eglin Air Force Base and serving the cities of Destin and Fort Walton Beach in Florida. It’s exclusively commercial, known for being a focus city to Allegiant Air, and often visited by American, Delta, and Southwest, with Sun Country to begin seasonal operations to Minneapolis/St. Paul in April 2023. With nearly 2 million passengers between 2021-2022, it’s among the busiest airports in the state.  Formerly known as Okaloosa Regional Airport, it was renamed Northwest Florida Regional Airport in September 2008 and then given its current name in February 2015.  ‍ The scenery features a fully modeled terminal exterior, PBR materials on buildings and ground, apron clutter, and animated humans.  ‍ It’s available on FlightSim.to for $8.99 and requires at least 2.4 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gaftam</id>
    <title>Gaffer Simulations Releases FAOR O.R. Tambo International For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gaftam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63508df31d6a19bf2b6b5c39_305916_74_MSFS.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1687964"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Gaffer Simulations has released their highly anticipated O.R. Tambo International scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, South Africa’s biggest international airport located in Johannesburg that first opened in 1952. The airport, serves as the primary international gateway for South Africa and is home to several notable African carriers including Airlink, CemAir, FlySafair, LIFT Airline &amp; South African Airways. The airport encompasses around 4000 acres of land in Kempton Park, Gauteng, situated about 12 miles from the city of Johannesburg. The airport has two runways parallel to each other adjacent to the airport’s terminal buildings, and provides direct connections to over 75 destinations which are served by a multitude of aircraft from general aviation, cargo and commercial aircraft. originally served under the name Jan Smuts International Airport, it was renamed in 2005 after former African National Congress member Oliver Reginald Tambo. The airport has received  numerous upgrades and expansion projects, the most notable being the major developments which took place in preparation for the 2010 FIFA World Cup. For Gaffer Simulations rendition of O.R Tambo International, the scenery comes with a standard set of features that we can expect from most airport sceneries on Microsoft Flight Simulator, in which the recreation is built with high-definition PBR textures and models that accurately represent the airport in its current form. The complete feature list follows down below: Gaffer Simulations’ O.R. Tambo International airport for MSFS is available for purchase on the SimMarket store for €21.60, requiring over 6 GB of free disk space to install.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
