<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-10-31T18:22:15.373429+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pdch7p</id>
    <title>PILOT'S GesmbH announces the upcoming release of the Dash 7</title>
    <updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pdch7p" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6537def75eaeb757d29960be_NNOSE.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="374149"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Today PILOT'S GesmbH announced the imminent release of their long-awaited Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Known for their scenery and utility addons for FSX and P3D, they'll add the Dash 7 to their lineup soon. The Dash 7 is a rugged four-engine turboprop developed and manufactured by de Havilland Canada. It is known for its STOL performance, which gives it more destination options in rugged terrain and unpaved landing surfaces. Making its first flight in March of 1975, approximately 113 were built. The DHC-7 is powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney PT6A-50 engines producing around 1,100 shaft horsepower, allowing it to cruise upward to 230 knots. Its STOL capabilities allow it to operate out of runways as little as 2,000 feet long. This capacity makes it useful for passenger service and cargo. ‍ ‍ According to a recent Facebook post by PILOT'S GesmbH, you will soon be able to experience the STOL performance of the DHC-7 this weekend. The addon will include real-world liveries and equipment, such as the Working Title GNS 530 and a specific model supporting the GTNXi. Additionally, custom sounds are engineered for the Dash 7 with assistance and input from Air Tindi. There are many operational quirks modeled after the real Dash 7"One such unique feature is the nose wheel gear doors slowly opening after engines shut down with the subsequent hydraulic pressure drop". ‍ The Dash 7 will be available on their web store at www.pilots.shop this weekend. Make sure to create an account for purchase.   As always stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/8ak5es</id>
    <title>Emerald Scenery Design Releases, Fort Crosby </title>
    <updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/8ak5es" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6538103279bc2a87edba98db_9c38e6a5848b098fa0b42db4c410f85385de8fb1.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="178450"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Emerald Scenery Design, a developer creating sceneries for Prepar3D and Microsoft Flight Simulator, has recently released its newest addition - 8AK5 Fort Crosby. This latest release fits in well with their backcountry and tropical air strip themes. Located near Talkeetna, Alaska, this privately owned airstrip features a 1,500-foot gravel strip that turns into a dirt strip during summer; wintertime has snow berm build up alongside it. The development team has done an excellent job capturing the snow build-up, as shown in the screenshot below.  ‍ ‍ The scenery encompasses an area of 2.5 NM²/4.7 KM² and includes numerous hand-built home cabins and other lively objects that bring the scenery to life. The textures are high quality, featuring PBR and 4K resolution textures. Terraforming, dirt textures, ground coverage, and shrubbery are custom-made, and the 3D trees make the environment feel more vibrant. The development team paid close attention to environmental details to create an immersive Alaskan experience. ‍ ‍ The scenery has been improved with new features such as dynamic objects. These objects include automatic hangar doors, fauna, growing vegetation, and seasonal mushrooms. Butterflies can also be seen in the spring. Furthermore, there are weather effects such as rain puddles, roof snow, and icicles that appear at certain temperatures. With such a vast coverage area, you are bound to discover something new during each flight. ‍ ‍ ‍ Listed below is the full feature list from Emerald Scenery Design Features ‍ Dynamic Features ‍ ‍ Emerald Scenery Design’s Fort Crosby v1 can be purchased on their website and the (Marketplace coming soon) for only $9.99USD. File sizes are about 1.04GB unzipped on your machine. The release will also be available for Xbox users! Check out their official release trailer below! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more exciting releases and flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orvo17</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta 1.7</title>
    <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orvo17" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653987eaa6d74bf4afcc7e80_vol.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2107444"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated their flight tracking platform to version 1.7, adding a new user interface and many new features. Volanta’s new update brings  a new and improved navigation bar, a replay on altitude chart, new aircraft icons, flight and aircraft filtering, a dynamic airport display that will show airports based on their activity, an “Events” page with Volanta’s official events, and much more.  ‍  Many issues from the previous version were also addressed:  ‍  Volanta is available for free on their website.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pksgra</id>
    <title>PKSIM Releases Granada Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pksgra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6539a0ef89f80acd3bf67d6c_gra1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1685360"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PKSIM has recently released their rendition of Federico García Lorca Granada Airport (LEGR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Granada in Spain with a yearly average of 1.1 million passengers. ‍ Construction work started in 1970, and the airport opened two years later as Aeropuerto de Granada. It replaced Armilla Airfield, which was Grenada's first airport.  ‍ The airport underwent multiple improvements in the 90s for the 1995 World Alpine Ski Championships, with an expansion of the apron, runway extension, and many improvements to the main terminal.  ‍ International service started in 2000, with a flight to Marrakech. Beforehand, the airport used to average 500,000 passengers a year, and with the advent of international operations, that rate was doubled within five years.  ‍  The promising growth was rapidly halted after the 2008 crisis, leading to a massive drop in passenger count and with the departure of Ryanair, one of their biggest carriers.  ‍  Numbers only were to recover in 2014, when British Airways embraced Granada on a seasonal basis, helping Granada to reach their highest average since 2008. Numbers kept steadily growing in the following years, despite nowhere close to the 2006 figures.  ‍ Things changed substantially with the arrival of Vueling in 2017, helping the airport return to its 1 million mark.  ‍ Air Europe, Binter Canarias, Iberia, Volotea, and Vueling currently serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, a new terminal interior, a GSX profile with walk-in gates, and landside buildings.  ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $19.67, requiring at least 218.19 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boudev</id>
    <title>Boundless Publishes Development Update </title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boudev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653a15204dab3b655828e252_vatry.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1091843"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently published a new development report on their progress on Paris Vatry and Inverness for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12. ‍ They begin with information on Paris Vatry (LFOK), which is claimed to be 95% finished, only depending on fixing a couple of issues that arose before release. While a time frame was not provided, it’s said that everything is in place to get them moving pretty quickly once the problem is solved.   ‍ New Inverness (EGPE) previews were also shown. It was announced recently, promising improved terminal textures, improved night lighting, new ground textures, improved FPS, new lorry and vehicle models, animated ground traffic, and optional static aircraft. ‍  They conclude by letting everyone know that their website has recently been updated with a new design (focusing on usability), and they have been working in the background on five unannounced projects, which should be revealed soon. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbpng</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbpng" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653a19978d68e76ff3fe4350_bush1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="553155"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released the PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a package with three challenging airstrips in Papua New Guinea, the toughest country in the world to be a bush pilot.  Bush airstrips in Papua New Guinea are generally the only gateway to certain remote villages, meaning it’s vital to their existence and the only way to bring supplies in. The weather is often harsh, the runways are often short and hand-carved, and the challenge is unparalleled.  Developed by Ken Hall, an independent developer, the scenery package brings three airstrips (AYYE, AYYW, and AYDN), featuring PBR texturing,  custom 3D vegetation (with modeled bananas), 100 custom-built and hand-placed models, handcrafted mesh for each airstrip, and custom hand-placed objects and people.     It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $11.94, requiring at least 2.40 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2gpk</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases Glasgow Prestwick Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2gpk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653a1d651a1a861855e274fc_glashow.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1050676"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of Glasgow Prestwick Airport (EGPK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in Glasgow (Scotland) with a yearly average of 445,211 passengers.  It was officially opened in 1935, despite operating as an airfield for longer (since the early 1910s). Passenger facilities were added in 1938 and remained untouched until the government made them compatible with jet aircraft. ‍ The RAF used Prestwick to control trans-Atlantic flights during World War 2 as a gateway for US Army personnel and a training base for RAF pilots. ‍ Its commercial duties started right after the war, with a transatlantic flight between Prestwick and New York. ‍ The main runway was expanded in 1960 from the original 2,100 meters to 3,000 meters, which is still its current length.  ‍ During the early 1990s, Prestwick was in shambles, desperately needing “rescue,” which came in the form of a takeover from a Canadian entrepreneur (Matthew Hudson), who constructed a railway station beside it, making it the first Scottish airport with its own railway station. To this day, Matthew’s rescue effort is unanimously recognized as heroic. ‍ Ryanair embraced Prestwick in 1994, with a route from Dublin and a second route a year later to London Stansted. A third one followed suit in 1998, taking passengers to Paris-Beauvais. ‍ 1998 also marks the ownership transfer from Matthew Hudson to the Stagecoach Group, a transport group based in Perth, primarily focused on buses, trams, and train services. They sold it three years later for 33 million pounds. ‍ Infratil, a Kiwi company, was the new owner from 2001 onwards, responsible for revamping the main terminal in 2005 and redecorating most of it with very controversial touches. ‍ After over a decade of ownership, Infratil called it a day and passed it on to a new owner, which was no less than the Scottish government. They paid an incredible sum of 1 pound for it. ‍ It’s currently served by Ryanair, with flights to Alicante, Faro, Lanzarote, Málaga, and Tenerife-South. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, PBR materials, optional static aircraft, and more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.85, requiring at least 60.82 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fbmmsp</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Releases Minneapolis-Saint Paul International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fbmmsp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653aeb5a0623f1f8447b61e5_msp.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="212362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam has recently released their rendition of Minneapolis-Saint Paul International Airport (KMSP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the metropolitan area of Minneapolis and Saint Paul with a yearly average of 31 million passengers.  It was built in 1919 on top of a former racetrack (Twin City Speedway), which also explains its first name: Speedway Field. It got its first hangar a year later, constructed for airmail services.  ‍ Terminal 1 was built in the late 50s, costing the administration around 8.5 million Dollars, with 56,000 square meters of total area, 24 gates, and two concourses designed by Lyle George Landstrom. It was concluded in 1962 and inaugurated a few days later. Further expansion happened a decade later with the construction of Pier D (now Concourse G). Existing concourses were rebuilt into bi-level structures with holding rooms and jet bridges. That same concourse was later improved in 1986. ‍ Terminal 2 was built in 1986 and rebuilt in 2001. It currently features 14 gates and serves Sun Country, Southwest, Condor, Icelandair, and JetBlue. ‍  It’s a hub for Delta Air Lines, Sun Country Airlines, and Bemidji Airlines. Aer Lingus, Air Canada Express, Air France, Alaska Air, Allegiant Air, American Airlines, American Eagle, Condor, Denver Air Connection, Frontier Airlines, Icelandair, JetBlue, KLM, Lufthansa (mid-2024), Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, United Airlines, United Express, and WestJet also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-resolution textures, dynamic jetways with custom signage, custom ground textures, new flightbeam sound effects, key interior areas modeled in the terminal, dense amount of custom tarmac objects, and performance-friendly optimization. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $20, requiring at least 407.1 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpg160</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Releases H160 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpg160" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653af541b8d120f680d27217_hyp.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="112782"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has recently released their rendition of the Airbus H160 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a medium utility helicopter formally launched in 2015 and introduced in 2021.  First revealed in 2011, the H160 was declared a “game changer” with advanced fly-by-wire controls, advanced pilot edge functionality, reduced vibration, Blue Edge active tracking rotor blades, and a “radically different cockpit.” With the development costs rapidly racking up, some of the promised features were either toned down or eliminated when the helicopter was formally introduced in 2015. The H160 features a light and efficient design, eliminating conventional hydraulic parts like the landing gear and brakes for electrical counterparts. It is one tonne lighter than its rival, burns less fuel, and is cheaper to operate in the long run.  It’s powered by two Safran Arrano 1A turboshaft engines, producing 1280 hp each, with a total range of 880 km, at 255 km/h, with a service ceiling of 20,000ft. HPG’s rendition features a high-detail 3D model, two variants (Civilian and Luxury), six liveries for each variant, PBR texturing, VR support, working doors, animated windshield wipers, animated flight controls, functional emergency floats, advanced avionics and systems, compatibility with either the PMS or the TDS Garmin GTN device, a functional weather radar, and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍ Highly Detailed 3D Model, Textures and Animations Advanced Avionics &amp; Detailed Systems ‍ Powerful 4-axis Autopilot ‍ Helicopter Flight Model ‍ Immersive Sounds It’s available for $49.99 on HPG’s website.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsswin</id>
    <title>FSimStudios Releases Winnipeg International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsswin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653c03082703ca4659ceeaae_win1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="228278"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSimStudios has just released their rendition of Winnipeg International Airport (CYWG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 7th busiest airport in Canada with a yearly average of 3 million passengers. ‍ It opened in 1928 as Stevenson Aerodrome, over a local aviator. It was Canada’s first international airport, with Northwest Airways’ passenger and air mail service to Pembina, North Dakota, in 1931. Five years later, the City of Winnipeg and the Rural Municipality of Saint James agreed on developing the airfield as a modern municipal airport. ‍ The original main terminal was built in 1964 and expanded and renovated 20 years later by IKOY. It was closed in 2011 and demolished. A modern project from Cesar Pelli/Stantec replaced it, started in 2007 and finished in 2011. ‍ It’s a hub for Calm Air, Cargojet, Perimeter Aviation, and Bearskin Airlines. Air Canada, Air Canada Express, Delta Air Lines, Flair Airlines, Lynx Air, Porter Airlines, Sunwing Airlines, WestJet, and WestJet Encore also serve it. ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-quality texturing, high-detail models, custom ground textures, a fully modeled terminal interior, custom jetways, and more. ‍ It’s available on their store for $18.99, requiring at least 2.93 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pildah</id>
    <title>PILOT’S Releases Dash 7 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pildah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653c0a80649d2fb01311f6fa_das1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2339944"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PILOT'S has recently released their rendition of the de Havilland Canada Dash 7 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a turboprop-powered regional airliner with STOL Capabilities introduced in 1978.  ‍ First flown in 1975, the Dash 7 is a "Twin Otter but larger and with four engines," with oversized fan blades that would rotate at a slower speed to emit as little noise as possible, complying with the noise restrictions that were starting to creep in. It could carry up to 50 passengers, with a service ceiling of 21,000 feet and 690 nautical miles of range, all powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A-50 turboprop engines, with 1,120 hp each.  ‍ As of July 2018, 17 Dash 7s were still flying worldwide with six different operators. However, the list of former operators is substantial: sixty civilian and three military operators. ‍ The add-on features 4K textures, authentic and realistic gauges, full TDS GTN750xi support (and default GNS 530), nine liveries, authentic color matching, and more. ‍ It's available on their website for roughly $21.13. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmduft</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Universal Flight Tablet for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmduft" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/653f0a89100a96d2d8973bb5_1250410_20231029210734_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1332295"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently released the long-awaited Universal Flight Tablet update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing an advanced Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) to the 737 Lineup with SimBrief integration, performance calculation, and more. ‍  Update 3.0.80 brings the first public version of the Universal Flight Tablet with a feature set that includes SimBrief integration, charting (for Navigraph Ultimate subscribers), and performance computation. The complete feature list follows below:  Flight Plans/SimBrief Integration - Importing flight plans from SimBrief. - Download weather for the flight plan route. - Flight plan/weather sharing between tablet/aircraft. - Display of Operational Flight Plan. - Display of real time METAR information (native or simplified format)  Charting: - Navigraph Charts (Requires Navigraph Subscription) - Georeferenced aircraft on displayed charts where appropriate. - Flight centric chart selection/pinning of desired charts.  Performance Computation: - T/O, Diversion, Landing computations. - Data Import from flight plans or from the aircraft itself. - Reduced runway length computations. - Graphic display of displaced threshold data.  ‍  New features will be added in future updates, such as the ability to manage all of the PMDG options, functions, and failures from the tablet (and they will also remain controllable via FMC).   They will also offer the possibility of integration with third-party applications, all from within the tablet. PMDG will provide further information on that in the future.  The update is now available for PMDG.com customers, and the marketplace release will depend on Microsoft’s internal intake process. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a320fx</id>
    <title>Fenix Block Two Delayed</title>
    <updated>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a320fx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654105395b41de7fb127a008_windows_sunset_edit.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1554799"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍Fenix Simulations announced the news of the much-anticipated Block Two update of their A320 aircraft via Discord. Fenix's Project manager, Aamir, provided details and progress of the remodeling and improvement of the external model. The team has been working hard to get the update out as soon and smoothly as possible.  Aamir further enlightens us on the changes to the artwork side of the project. They are still working on moving textures and remaining decals to their new workflow. The team shared images of the recent model highlighting improvements in texturing window modeling and other noticeable details. According to the Discord post, the windows now match more accurately to the interiors, giving a greater sense of depth. The team also worked heavily on improving access panels, doors, and latches, with 3D modeling of their physical shapes. These details are further completed with textures highlighting the dirt and grime that build up over time. The landing gear is another critical rebuild mentioned, taking four months to complete. The improvement over V1's landing gear is night and day. New attention to details like hydraulic lines, tensioning springs, actuators, and fasteners are major improvement areas.  The team highlighted many further details by modeling every panel and seam throughout the bird. The overall shape is noted as an improvement, showing a three-quarters overhead shot. This shot shows off the improved modeling and accuracy matching closer to the real-world counterpart. According to Aamir, V2 will consume much less VRAM, even with enhanced modeling and details. V2 will run much better than V1 now, stating, "It feels like voodoo.". The delay was unexpected, but the Fenix's continues to work on making this version a completely new experience. Aamir thanks the community for "for sticking with us through the bumps in the roads." To read more on the subject check out the link to the Discord announcement here  ‍ Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/brcbia</id>
    <title>Bruno Reichert Releases Brasília International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/brcbia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/654124e0ccfdaa735563411d_sbbr.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="605490"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Bruno Reichert has recently released their rendition of Brasilia - President Juscelino Kubitschek International Airport (SBBR), the third busiest airport in Brazil with a yearly average of 13.5 million passengers. ‍ It was built in 1956, four years before the city it serves, which was still under construction. With a small wooden terminal and a 324-meter-long runway, it received its first flight and inauguration in 1957. The runway was later extended to its current length of 3,300 meters, which had been part of the original plan all along, but for whatever reason, they made it 90% shorter at first. ‍ A proper terminal building was inaugurated in 1971, designed by Tércio Fontana Pacheco, a Brazilian Air Force architect. ‍ The first major renovation happened in 1990, with terminal expansions, the first circular satellite, and more, divided into a two-phase project that reached total completion in 2004, followed by the construction of the second runway in 2005. ‍ New expansion work was announced in 2009 to prepare the airport for the 2014 World Cup. It consisted of an enlargement of the apron and taxiways, a passenger terminal renovation (and enlargement), and extra parking lots, mitigating an issue with the airport operating at capacity (85%) for many years. ‍ It’s served by Aerolíneas Argentinas, Azul Brazilian Airlines, Copa Airlines, Gol Transportes Aéreos, LATAM Brasil, LATAM Perú, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed custom terminals and hangars, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, PBR texturing, correct runway slope, custom terraforming, and more. Future update plans include an FPS-friendly terminal interior, custom jetways, and more details.  ‍ It’s free on flightsim.to, requiring at least 1.48 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/2mhvyf</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases the Mitsubishi MU2</title>
    <updated>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/2mhvyf" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65412a47a2661c6b82dfb2d7_MSFS_MU2_06-1-scaled.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="193393"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator releases the Mitsubishi MU2 as its Famous Flyer 7! The MU2 is now available for FS2020. Mitsubishi Heavy Industries built the MU2, a high-performing turboprop that is primarily used in general aviation and some military operations. It first took flight on September 14th, 1963, and over 700 have been built so far! The MU2 filled the gap in the corporate aviation market for an economical, fast turboprop with state-of-the-art engines.  Powered by TPE331-6251 Engines, the MU2 typically cruises at FL250 and reaches around 260 knots with a range of 1,450 miles. This version of the MU2 has a seating capacity of four in the rear and has a fully pressurized cabin. It has a service ceiling of 29,590 feet, allowing you to fly above most weather conditions. MU2 also has de-icing equipment and ice detections for flight into known icing conditions. Although equipped with such equipment, the MU2 has a unique ice build-up pattern to keep in mind. Mitsubishi unconventionally designed the MU2's wing with double-slotted Fowler flaps running the length of the entire wingspan for STOL performance. That design choice canceled out room for conventional ailerons; instead, Mitsubishi went with roll spoilers for roll control. Roll spoilers retain positive control during slow flight without being subjected to aileron snap, delivering smoother operation during rollouts and turbulence. The decision for roll spoilers gives the Mu2 its infamous flight characteristics.  The MU2 aircraft was built with sturdy and durable landing gear, making it capable of short, non-paved airstrips ops. The Mu2 gets you above the weather and at high speeds. With its STOL abilities, you can choose from a wide variety of landing options. You can now purchase it for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 at a price of $14.99 from the Marketplace.  ‍ As always make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simudi</id>
    <title>SIMMAN Releases Udon Thani International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simudi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65412d46ef062ed38086847a_udi.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1781874"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SIMMAN has recently released their rendition of Udon Thani International Airport (VTUD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Udon Thani, Nong Khai, and Nong Bua Lamphu in Thailand with a yearly average of 2 million passengers. ‍ It was built in 1932 in the Nong Kohn Kwang subdistrict, sporting a 500-meter-long gravel runway. A concrete runway was constructed 25 years later, with 3048 meters of extension. It was built with help from the United States. ‍ In the early 2000s, the runway’s width was changed from 38 meters wide to 45, followed by an entirely new terminal building in 2003. The original terminal was renovated in 2015 to conform to international standards. ‍ ‍ Nok Air, Thai AirAsia, Thai Airways International, Thai Lion Air, Thai Smile, and Thai VietJet Air serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom-made terminal and its interior, custom ground textures, realistic ground markings, custom jetways, and more. ‍  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.43, requiring at least 600.73 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
