<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-08-14T18:38:14.101109+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilc1</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilc1"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6892896b9862bc4b3681943e_FlightSimulator2024_YDm5vAPbHV_4472x.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following its initial announcement in July, iniBuilds has now released Larnaca International Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The scenery provides a detailed and performance-optimised representation of Cyprus’s busiest airport, based on the current real-world layout as of 2025. Larnaca Airport is located on the southern coast of Cyprus and serves as a hub for both regional and international flights. The scenery includes hand-crafted ground textures, HD jetways, and a fully modelled terminal building, with interior detailing. More than 180 custom models and structures are included across the airside and landside areas, complete with accurate signposts, vegetation, and dynamic lighting. The product features high-resolution PBR textures and comes with its own GSX profile. LOD’s are applied across all assets to ensure optimised performance on a wide range of systems. Built using the latest Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 software development kit, this scenery is now only available for the newer simulator. Larnaca International Airport for MSFS 2024 is available now through the iniBuilds store for £9.99, excluding taxes. For all the latest news and updates in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cfsydt</id>
    <title>Canadian Flight Sim Studios Releases Boundary Bay Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cfsydt"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68928eef34e4b6bb8b7c32bb_688a25ae1fd88.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Canadian Flight Sim Studios has released its rendition of Boundary Bay Airport for X-Plane 12. The scenery aims to provide a realistic and detailed general aviation environment at one of Canada’s busiest airports. Located in British Columbia, Boundary Bay Airport is a leading centre for flight training and private aviation in the Vancouver area. The scenery features accurately modelled terminals in high detail, hangars, and fixed-base operators, with designs tailored for business jet and light aircraft operations. Animated hangar doors have also been included at key general aviation facilities. Taxiway and apron layouts are built to match current charts, with custom markings and lighting throughout. The environment has extensive detail across all airport structures to mirror the real-world location closely.  Boundary Bay Airport is available now through the Orbx Store for $12.29, excluding sales tax. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerostar098</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Updates Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerostar098"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/685de0d3a636c169f3aba0c4_aerostarpog.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. A2A Simulations recently issued a new patch for their newly released Accu-Sim Aerostar 600 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, which brings many improvements and tweaks. Update v0.9.8, also known as “Scott’s list update” brings a significant amount of changes to the product, including new beacon lights, tinted glass, windshield texture improvements, the addition of the Davtron 307FCI cabin temperature indicator, a working cabin temperature gauge, the landing gear’s got extra weathering, new sounds were added, and more. The changelog follows below: v0.9.8 Changelog Highlights: - New Beacon Lights - Added fan sound files - Added jacks - Added pitot tube cover - Air vents sound reduced - Ammeter no longer shows battery charging amps - Autopilot: Alt hold more resilient to sim stutter - Autopilot: Tweaked interaction between pitch and trim servo - Bug in aux hydraulic pump sound where it would keep playing fixed - Cabin fan hi/low sounds added - Cabin heat now draws slight electricity but requires the cabin fan to be on - Compass correction card. - Defroster blower sounds added - Flap and gear sound physics rumble tuned - Flaps pressure damage physics tuned - Fuel booster pump sounds reduced - Fuel selector servo sounds play properly with electricity on or off - Fuel will now drain out of the fuselage tank when fuel selectors are off - Individual cabin lights now draw current - Nose steering moves to center a bit faster - Nosewheel steering dash switch sounds - Opening door creates stronger air flow exchange - Prop feathering issues fixed, including an issue feathering the right engine - Right engine not feathering bug fixed - Slightly faster starter cranking speed, starter cranking physics sent into the airframe - Throttle, mixture and prop end sounds - Tinted glass - Windshield texture details - Yoke anim range fixed - Yoke trim knob sounds - [Tablet] Disabling / enabling jacks, heaters and pitot cover controls - Improved Active Pause &amp; Photo Mode handling - Fixed Landing Lights check in walkaround + using new .fx not the defaults - Added Davtron 307FCI cabin temp indicator - Fixed high speed buffet from magnetic compass - Working cabin temperature gauge - Improved handling of mixture events which may help FSUIPC users - Tablet moved to not cover ASI as much - Fixed tablet colliding with right sun visor - Updated baggage door textures - Fixed reg numbers clipping - Increased tail area reg number - Added some extra weathering to landing gear The add-on is available on their website for $49.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/20su26</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases Sim Update 16 for MSFS 2020</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/20su26"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68936c78301a9fdd93dac9fd_MFS-40th_Evergreen_KeyArt_Horizontal_9600x5400_RGB%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Microsoft has released Sim Update 16 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. The update, version 1.39.9.0, introduces a broad range of improvements across avionics, aircraft, navigation, scenery, and system stability. Among the most notable updates are stability fixes targeting specific crash conditions, such as the Pecs TV Tower in Hungary, and improved memory management on Xbox Series S and Xbox Series X. The update also includes refinements to timezone accuracy and improved coastline and border data within the world environment. Other enhancements include updated Bing Maps data, to the 2024 standard, improved terraforming, and water body rendering. In terms of aircraft, the Boeing 787-10 Dreamliner, Cessna Citation Longitude, and Daher TBM 930 each received targeted fixes and feature improvements. These have been updated with changes to spoiler behaviour, thrust reverser behaviour, updated cockpit annunciators and autopilot logic. Updates to the Cessna Citation Longitude include new flight director modes, FMS initialisation, and pressurisation controls. Avionics platforms, including the G1000 NXi, G3000, G3X Touch, Primus Epic 2.0, and UNS-1Ew, have also been improved, addressing both performance and functionality. Navigation logic has been improved, especially in cases involving runways not present in the base simulator.  Peripheral support now includes the Honeycomb Aeronautical Alpha Lite, and Sim Update 16 also addresses infinite loading issues in specific activity scenarios. Developers also gain new tools, with 3ds Max 2024 support added to the simulator’s SDK exporter. You can view the full changelog below: The update is available for download now, on all compatible platforms. For all the latest in flight simulation, be sure to stay updated on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsg8r</id>
    <title>SimWorks Studios Announces August Release Date for GA-8 Airvan </title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsg8r"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6893a9586961dfde00f2191c_526999050_1303830975077913_7290887599307644825_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. SimWorks Studios has recently confirmed that its upcoming GA-8 Airvan will be released on the MSFS Marketplace on Aug. 21st, initially for MSFS 2020. A version tailored for MSFS 2024 will follow shortly after, and be made available at no extra cost to existing owners. The aircraft will launch in two editions. The base GA-8 Airvan will include both cargo and passenger configurations, authentic sound design, and fully modelled systems. An optional "SystemsPulse" expansion pack deepens the simulation further, adding features such as failures and persistent wear. The SystemsPulse expansion pack will require the base aircraft to function. While the base version is compatible with MSFS 2024, the SystemsPulse expansion is not, due to file system restrictions in the new simulator. A compatible version is already in development and will be released as a free update once complete. The aircraft package is prepared for upload, with review copies being distributed to streamers and media partners ahead of launch. SimWorks Studios has also confirmed that a storefront release of the Airvan will follow at a later date, once internal testing of a new installer is complete. The base GA-8 Airvan will retail for $29.99, with the SystemsPulse expansion pack being priced at $17.49. For all the latest flight simulation news, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/css-updates-737-classic-family-adds-msfs-2024-support</id>
    <title>CSS Updates 737 Classic, Adds Experimental MSFS 2024 Support</title>
    <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/css-updates-737-classic-family-adds-msfs-2024-support"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6893ddf5a3e6a8c458980e37_0cbl50DohCfmz51wVvLCcCHv0el5w14EFJJfCpG1sE.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Commercial Simulation Systems has released version 1.4.6 of its 737‑500 Classic for MSFS 2020 and 2024, introducing new features, system fixes, and an experimental 2024-compatible build. The update delivers a wide array of improvements, including optional eyebrow windows, cosmetic winglets, refined flight model behaviour, updated lighting logic, and various fixes to avionics and electrical systems. The changelog also notes enhanced performance tuning and stability corrections. Included in this release is an experimental build for MSFS 2024, made available at no additional cost to current MSFS 2020 customers. While functionally identical to its predecessor, the MSFS 2024 version additionally benefits from the simulator’s multithreading upgrades, although known issues, such as quiet audio and Walkaround Mode conflicts, remain. The update also marks the debut of the 737‑500 on simMarket, where it is now available in three licence tiers. Each purchase comes with a key for activation in the CSS Launcher, providing parity with purchases from the developer’s storefront. While the team advises those seeking a stable experience to continue using the MSFS 2020 build, ongoing development is underway to polish the 2024 release and expand system support. Work is also progressing on sound improvements with help from a professional sound designer, as well as additional 737 variants. The full changelog follows below: 1.4.6 Changelog‍‍ Added - Optional eyebrow windows - Optional winglets - Optional fluorescent main panel lights - Missing light emissions in virtual cockpit - Livery-specific aircraft configuration options in aircraft.cfg - Landing lights now light up gradually Changed - Fuselage texture mapping due to eyebrows - Rewritten exterior lighting from scratch - Improved stall behaviour at low speeds - Adjusted red and yellow speeds - Adjusted engine spool factors - Adjusted engine degradation factors - General engine performance improvements - Fixed GND PWR AVAIL remains lit and GND PWR remains available even if GPU is disconnected - Fixed minor winglet texture issue - Landing light halo size scaled down - Fixed default tug attaching to center of aircraft - Fixed backlighting on pedestal light knobs - Improved FMC path calculations - Fixed CDU scratchpad failure when entering GW on PERF APP page - Improved Korry textures - AFDS flood light now has four lamps - Fixed windshield rain effect direction - Fixed MAP light knob animation - Improved wing leading edge shape near wingtip - Fixed some electrical systems being connected to incorrect busses - Fixed GROUND POWER AVAILABLE light not illuminating without electrical power - Fixed glareshield FIRE WARNING not illuminating during FIRE TEST - Fixed Green Banana - Fixed BAT Voltmeter not working without electrical power - Fixed Auto Speedbrake only deploying middle spoiler section - Top of Descent is no longer shown if no Arrival is entered - Fixed yellow speed slowly moving up after entering initial GW - Fixed lower collision light flash and spill not in sync - [2024] Fixed jumping gauge needles - [2024] Fixed lights disappearing when changing views - Various FMC fixes and improvements - Various small fixes - Various small Navdata fixes You can purchase the CSS 737 Classic via subscription for $5 per month or $50 per year, or as a one-time purchase for $120 through the CSS website, or via simMarket, for a slightly higher rate. For all the latest in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdg28</id>
    <title>PMDG Marks 28 Years with Aircraft Updates</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdg28"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6894affe9762d591641095f5_pmdg_ng38_hero1__97709.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. PMDG is celebrating its 28th anniversary this week, giving a suite of updates across its line of products. In a post on the PMDG forums, CEO Robert Randazzo confirmed that owners of the 737NG series for MSFS 2020 must now migrate to Operations Center 3 (OC3), retiring the legacy InstallShield and OC2 system. The process involves uninstalling existing aircraft and liveries, reinstalling them via OC3, and then restoring liveries. The update preserves the current version, 3.0.112.  The 777 series has recently received an update, build 121, with additional fixes expected next week. The 777-200LR is scheduled for Marketplace release for both MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024 within 7–10 days. Randazzo also briefly addressed the 777X, noting that “positive discussions” about access are underway. For MSFS 2024, work is underway on the 737NG line, with beta testing expected to commence soon, alongside preview imagery. Meanwhile, the DC‑6 is currently awaiting improvements to MSFS 2024’s LOD system to resolve visual issues before release. Development on the 737 MAX and the 747-100 and 400 is ongoing, though no release timeline has been specified.  In honour of its anniversary, PMDG is offering 28% off all products on PMDG.com, starting 0000 UTC on Aug. 7 through 2359 UTC on Aug. 10.  A YouTube version of Randazzo’s announcement is also available to watch here. For all the latest flight simulation news, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbjrw</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Jurassic World: Archipelago for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbjrw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6894c71dc37a442a5f8aa269_Orbx-JW-Archipelago-submission-20250704__12.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has announced Jurassic World: Archipelago, a new, officially licensed flight simulation experience for MSFS 2024, developed in collaboration with Universal Products and Experiences. Recreating the fictional Muertes Archipelago off the coast of Costa Rica, the package features a detailed rendition of the Jurassic World islands, just before the events of the 2015 film. Isla Nublar is presented in its prime, with the active monorail system, the Innovation Centre, and the island open for business. Isla Sorna and other locations meanwhile remain remote and overgrown. In a post on the Orbx website, the developer confirmed the add-on includes eight destinations: the fictional Isla Nublar, Isla Sorna, Isla Matanceros, Isla Muerta, Isla Peña and Isla Tacaño, as well as the real-life Herradura Bay Marina and Juan Santamaría International Airport. Custom airstrips, helipads, animated dinosaurs, and unique aviation-themed challenges, such as VIP transport and guided tours, will be integrated into the experience. You will encounter various prehistoric creatures, both airborne and land-based, such as the Tyrannosaurus rex, Velociraptor, Apatosaurus, Brachiosaurus, Mosasaurus, Pteranodon, and more. The release will also feature unique aircraft liveries, themed infrastructure, and the ruins of the original Site B facilities on Isla Sorna. Jurassic World: Archipelago will launch for PC and Xbox via the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace. A release date and pricing have yet to be announced. A teaser previewing the product is available to watch on Orbx’s official YouTube channel. Visit the product page on Orbx’s website for more information. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/madtash</id>
    <title>Middle Asia Developers Releases Tashkent International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/madtash"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6896b4ff6ac47aa8744b5bf0_tashkent1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Middle Asia Developers has recently released their rendition of Tashkent International Airport (UTTT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Tashkent, in Uzbekistan, with a yearly average of 8.7 million passengers, making it the 8th busiest in the Post-Soviet states. The airport’s first records date back to 1924, when the first passenger flight was completed on a Junkers R-13, flying the Tashkent-Pishpek-Almaty route.  It eventually evolved into a transportation hub during the Soviet era, embracing the jet age as soon as 1957 with the Tu-104. By 1967, Tashkent had routes to Leningrad (Saint Petersburg), Novosibirsk, Sverdlovsk, Chelyabinsk, Simferopol, certain cities in the Baltic states, the Caucasus, and some in the Far East. ‍ The airport underwent many changes during the post-Soviet era, struggling to cope with the passenger volume. Western construction companies helped out quite significantly during the mid-1990s. Terminal 2 was rebuilt in 2001 to serve over 2 million passengers a year. It has modern waiting lounges, VIP halls, restaurants, bars, duty-free shops, and even a pharmacy. ‍ Terminal 3 was launched a decade after Terminal 2, and it could handle 400 passengers per hour (half the capacity of Terminal 2). ‍ The airport has been expanded in recent years, going from 45,000 square meters to 65,000 square meters of terminal area, allowing it to handle even more passengers per hour. ‍ In August 2024, they finished another expansion project, renovating the airport’s facade while at it. Later that same year, they started expanding the arrivals hall by 2,500 square meters.  There are plans to merge the arrival and departure terminals by 2026. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom jetways, a basic interior, and much more. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.64, requiring at least 984.50 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/implinc</id>
    <title>Impulse Simulations Releases Port Lincoln Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/implinc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6896bda9f875f3b9cd19917c_linc1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Impulse Simulations has recently released their rendition of Port Lincoln Airport (YPLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Port Lincoln, South Australia, with a yearly average of 199,546 passengers. The airport’s history dates back to World War 2, when it was established as a Royal Australian Air Force training facility for bomber crews. This laid the groundwork for the infrastructure that would eventually become a civil airport in the not-so-distant future. For nine years after the war, the airport remained closed, only reopening as a civilian airport in 1954. It then had a short grass runway and rudimentary passenger infrastructure. During that time period, Adelaide was the only scheduled destination. Eleven years later, the infrastructure saw major improvements with the sealing of the runway and the construction of a new terminal building, attracting airlines such as ASA (Airlines of South Australia) with their Fokker 27s.  The start of the 21st century led to many changes and improvements as the region saw its demand increase with its growth as a tourist destination. A new terminal was inaugurated in 2013, significantly increasing its passenger handling capabilities and bringing modern amenities. QantasLink and Rex Regional Express are the only airlines currently serving Port Lincoln. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an accurate terminal model and its respective interior, custom ground textures, custom terrain and vegetation, high-quality PBR texturing, realistic night lighting, custom orthoimagery, performance-friendly optimization, a custom GSX profile, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.91, requiring at least 996.74 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iamd8x</id>
    <title>Immersive Audio Releases Fly The MaddogX Soundpack for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iamd8x"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6897a7c92ca37a0cc80079d8_6896ea4e62e78.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Immersive Audio has released its MaddogX Sound Immersion NG, a sound pack designed for the Leonardo Fly The MaddogX, for MSFS 2020 and 2024. Featuring more than 235 authentic sounds captured exclusively from the MD-80 series, Immersive Audio aims to deliver one of the most detailed and accurate audio experiences available for the type. Developed over eight months, the pack uses 48kHz field recordings to replicate the MD-80’s cockpit atmosphere and mechanical nuances. This includes the distinctive sound of the JT8D engines, switch clacks, air conditioning pack howls, rack fan hum, and subtle rattles and squeaks unique to the aircraft. The pack also features dynamic taxi and landing roll effects, authentic gear operation noises, and smaller quirks, such as FO window wind leak whistling sounds on climbout. Many of these features can be toggled on and off manually from the MD-80’s overhead audio control panel. The full feature list follows below: You can watch a preview video showcasing the sound pack here. Immersive Audio’s MaddogX Sound Immersion NG is compatible with the Leonardo MD-82, as well as the MD-83 and MD-88 expansions. It is available now via the Orbx store, for US$16.17, excluding sales tax. For all the latest news in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carb55</id>
    <title>Carenado Announces Beechcraft Baron B55 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carb55"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6898cbab679d4cb403ab59b0_527516492_1171259145041887_2804892709349720491_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following its first teaser in a Facebook post earlier this month, Carenado has announced that the Beechcraft Baron B55 will be coming to MSFS 2024. The B55 is known for its stable handling, solid performance, and flexibility for both private and business flying.  Further updates have since been shared, including a closer look at the cockpit, featuring an Aspen Avionics EFD1000 unit. The product is also set to feature Carenado’s new "RealXperience” concept, which aims to add extra depth to the flying experience by utilising some of the newer MSFS 2024 features, such as various wear and tear effects, dirt, vibrations, mud buildup, and bug splatters. The Beechcraft Baron family, including the short-body Baron 55, Baron 56, and long-body Baron 58, is a series of piston aircraft evolved from the Beechcraft Travel Air,  itself a twin-engined development of the Beechcraft Bonanza. Model 55 Barons were produced until the early 80s, with a total of 3,651 units manufactured between 1961 and 1983.  While Carenado has not confirmed a release date, more details, including avionics options and other features, are likely to be announced as the project nears completion. For all the latest news in flight simulation, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/crzcsj</id>
    <title>CRZ Studio Releases The Aeroplane Manufactory Chinook SJ</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/crzcsj"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6898f50ed43f53e9af652922_Skjermbilde%202025-08-10%20213710.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Newcomers, CRZ Studio has recently released its first aircraft, the Chinook SJ from the Aeroplane Manufactory. CRZ Studio were founded in 2023 by two brothers, aiming to “bring highly authentic, handcrafted aircraft to the flight sim world”.  The Chinook SJ is an ultralight homebuilt kit aircraft available in two versions: one designed for the 4-stroke Rotax 912UL engine and the other for the 2-stroke Rotax 582UL engine. The 2-stroke version has now been recreated by CRZ Studio in Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with the 4-stroke version coming at a later date. According to CRZ Studio, the Chinook SJ was developed using actual aircraft assembly manuals, ensuring unmatched accuracy and realism. The developers also claim that the Chinook SJ is the ideal aircraft for exploring remote islands, mountain valleys, and other inaccessible areas, thanks to its exceptional Short Takeoff and Landing (STOL) performance. CRZ Studio has announced a variety of upcoming updates for the Chinook SJ. The future releases will, according to the developer, include a custom sound set for the Rotax 582 and 912 engines, a new sport light DR2 variant, an optional Rotax 912 engine, a floats configuration, optional GPS units, and dynamic effects for dirt, mud, dust, and grime, among other features. A DLC expansion celebrating the record-breaking competition-ready Chinook variant, titled "Dan Reynolds Valdez Special," is also in development. ‍ The Chinook SJ Aeroplane by CRZ Studio is now available for $26.83 on CRZ Studio's website, exclusively for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csdttf</id>
    <title>CAT3DUAL Studios Releases Gafsa - Ksar International Airport for MSFS 20/24</title>
    <updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csdttf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6898fb0037a5644593a3eefb_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. CAT3DUAL Studios has recently released its latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, Gafsa - Ksar International Airport (DTTF). Situated near the cities of Gafsa and Ksar in Tunisia, the airport currently has no scheduled passenger flights. The airport features a 9,514-foot-long runway, three helipads, and two parking stands for aircraft. While there are no regular commercial flights, the Tunisian Air Force operates from the airport, primarily using helicopters. The newly released scenery is packed with features including a handcrafted passenger terminal, a handcrafted air traffic control tower, an accurate airfield wayfinder, custom apron flood lights, a custom windsock, and much more. The 2024 version of the scenery is available on SimMarket for approximately $9.31, with the 2020 version also offered on SimMarket at the same price. If you purchase the 2020 version, you can receive the 2024 version as a free upgrade. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/350133</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/350133"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689b8c8ac64be90cff774481_HVNa359.png.3357d569aa794db40a666ac1d4e25350.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has released version 1.1.3 of its Airbus A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020 and 2024, delivering a range of fixes and improvements, across systems, visuals, and sounds. Key changes in v1.1.3 include refinements to the Flight Management System, fixing SEC/F-PLN display issues, VNAV constraint handling, and LNAV sequencing after go-arounds. HUD performance has been improved, with more accurate acceleration cues, proper minimum height indications, and better in-sim alignment. Brake to Vacate logic now responds correctly to runway exit changes, and brake thermodynamics have been adjusted, for slower, more realistic cooling rates.  System updates cover electrical, hydraulic, and pressurisation behaviour, including more accurate vent system effects, consistent GPU availability on spawn, and correct yellow electric pump ECAM alerts, on cargo door opening. Stability fixes address WASM-related crashes, tied to custom waypoints and certain procedures, while art updates have resolved cockpit LOD flicker, as well as various floating livery decals. The visibility of exterior lights in the wingtip assemblies has also been improved.  Furthermore, OIS enroute maps and Navigraph authentication should now be more reliable, and flap deployment sounds are now more audible across all configurations. In a significant announcement, iniBuilds also confirmed a partnership with Echo 19 Audio Productions, to deliver a complete sound overhaul for the A350. This update will bring richer and more detailed cockpit, engine, and environmental audio, aiming to provide a more immersive soundscape in future releases. You can view the full feature list for the update below: v1.1.3SystemsFIXED: Various EFIS and MFD related WASM crashesFIXED: WASM crash after inserting custom waypoint into next waypointFIXED: Overweight landing: brake temps already decreasing during landing roll, brakes cooling down too fastFIXED: Discon, incorrect track maintainedFIXED: PFD altitude vertical profile refinementFIXED: SEC/F-PLN edits and display issuesFIXED: SEC flight plan modification now displays holds on NDFIXED: SEC index button now returns to original page if pressed twiceFIXED: VD reaction in PLAN modeFIXED: Manual aircraft time entry now acceptedFIXED: Yellow electric pump ECAM missing when cargo doors openedFIXED: Pressing return on FMS performs correct action on FMS1FIXED: Brake cooling rate reducedFIXED: Notify max uplink delay message displayed correctlyFIXED: D-ATIS header and message handlingFIXED: Position time marker and data display when IRS is not alignedFIXED: Tropopause value rounding improvedFIXED: ATC COM connect armed color displayed correctlyFIXED: VHHH Kai Tak - runway length validation improvedFIXED: BTV does not disengage properly on go aroundFIXED: BTV does not disengage when ground spoilers disarmFIXED: BTV display remains at 10kts even when braking has stoppedFIXED: Changing RWY exits does not affect ROT or Turnaround time displayed on NDFIXED: Crossing Managed SPD LIMIT Pseudo-Waypoint behavior in Selected SPDFIXED: FMS 2 submenu navigation restoredFIXED: Grid heading logic correctedFIXED: LNAV sequencing after go-around path captureFIXED: Direct-To behaviour on SIDFIXED: HUD shows "No MINIMUM" indication below minimumADDED: Backing up a non-precision approach using an ILSADDED: D-ATIS previous message behaviorFIXED: Fix info on abeam pointsFIXED: Fix info not updating EFB/OISFIXED: OIS Enroute map functionality restoredFIXED: EFB lbs readout now truncates decimal placesFIXED: GSX boarding/deboarding stutters resolvedFIXED: Navigraph token resets after 6–8 hours ARTFIXED: Odd shadows toward the front of the fuselageFIXED: Nose cone mesh precision improvedFIXED: PAX signs no longer illuminateFIXED: GPU sometimes missing on spawnFIXED: "Landing" pilot camera view better aligns with HUD viewADDED: Windshield ITO effect (indium tin oxide) - Please note: Windshield ITO effect requires "windshield effects" setting on 'High' to render. SOUNDSFIXED: Flap sounds missing or inaudibleFIXED: Gear lowering sound played even if gear not lowered ‍ If you want to read the full update post, you can do so on the iniBuilds forums. The A350 Airliner is available for purchase at the iniBuilds Store for approximately $76.16 and requires at least 10.63 gigabytes of free storage to install. The v1.1.3 update is available now, and can be downloaded through the iniManager. ‍ For all the latest news in flight simulation, be sure to stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdrkevv</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Library and KEVV Scenery Receive Free Updates</title>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdrkevv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/689bc19c6316e0b87879192f_11897a_d1ace438d0804814bd0cbb79e6491ee9~mv2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr Designs has recently announced extensive updates for both their Scenery Library and Evansville Regional Airport (KEVV) scenery. ‍ Evansville Regional Airport (KEVV) Owners of X-Codr Designs’ Evansville Regional Airport can now upgrade to the new V2 version at no cost. According to the developer, the scenery has undergone extensive work aimed at enhancing both usability and visuals. These updates feature a complete rework of the ground textures, a nearly fully remodelled and retextured terminal with a custom interior, and new custom jetways that utilise X-Plane’s built-in jetway animation system. ‍ Living Scenery Technology Updates The key improvements to KEVV include significant updates to the "Living Scenery Technology." The updates now enable the scenery to interact better with moving objects. For example, according to the developers, doors will automatically open and close as people enter the terminal, and cars will stop to avoid colliding with pedestrians.  ‍ X-Codr Designs Library V2.0 The X-Codr Designs Library offers a unified collection of assets used across various sceneries. Therefore, any updates made to the design library will also affect other airports. For instance, new 3D people have been introduced with enhanced animations. ‍ A full changelog can be found below: Evansville Regional Airport V2 is available for new users now for $21.95 on the x-plane.org store, existing owners may download the update free of charge. ‍ For more details on updates made to Evansville Regional Airport, Living Scenery Technology and the X-Codr Designs Library, visit the X-Codr Website ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon. ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
