<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-07-17T18:24:59.826249+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shasah</id>
    <title>Shadescene Releases Sultan Abdul Halim Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shasah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ab99225dd5c7048687677d_sul1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1124070"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Shadescene has recently released their rendition of Sultan Abdul Halim Airport (WMKA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Alor Setar in Malaysia with a yearly average of 817,253 passengers.  It was established as an airfield in the early 1930s known as Lapangan Terbang Kepala Batas, becoming a military airbase soon after WW2 for the Japanese during their occupation of Malaysia.   The post-war period saw the ownership change to the Royal Air Force, which controlled the airfield until Malaysia gained independence in 1957.  Two years later, the airport was heavily upgraded to accommodate commercial operations, being re-inaugurated in 1965 as Alor Setar Airport. It was a domestic airport with flights to Kuala Lumpur and other major cities.  The current name was given during its redevelopment project in 2006, featuring a much larger passenger capacity, modern amenities, and more.  It’s served by AirAsia, Batik Air Malaysia, Firefly, and Malaysia Airlines, with flights to Kuala Lumpur and Johor Bahru (AirAsia only).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, a terminal interior, hand-placed taxiways, full day and night cycle, hand-crafted ground markings and textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.79, requiring at least 180.42 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxikuk</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Kukës International Airport Zayed for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxikuk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ab9e6fdaaa7dd819558b00_kuk1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3023955"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has recently released their rendition of Kukës International Airport Zayed (LAKU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Kukës in Albania with a yearly average of 40,000 passengers.  The airport was built in 1929 as a domestic airfield offering an air connection to Tirana, which operated for 15 years until it was turned into a military airport.   Civil service was only reactivated in the late 90s, during the Kosovo War, when the United Arab Emirates organized a refugee camp in Kukës, which also required an airfield for supplies. It didn’t take long until they had the idea to develop a civil airport instead as a gift to the population. Two years later, an understanding was reached, and the construction work got the green light.  Construction started in 2003, reaching completion in 2005, generating more than 200 jobs, and opening more tourist opportunities for the region. On the other hand, the opening only happened very recently, in 2021, when the first-ever commercial flight took place.  The airport is served on a seasonal basis by Air Albania and Wizz Air, with five destinations in total.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-detailed ground textures, PBR materials, a terminal interior, 3D passengers, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.88, requiring at least 449.77 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/swsp12</id>
    <title>SimWorks Shares Exclusive Previews of Upcoming PC-12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/swsp12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64acf60bf7040bec03cf4cc7_Microsoft_Flight_Simulator_Screenshot_2023.07.08_-_16.01.15.18.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3710215"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, SimWorks shared a few exclusive previews of their upcoming PC-12 aircraft for Microsoft Flight Simulator, showcasing the plane’s detailed exterior modeling and texturing in various liveries and weather conditions. From the pictures provided by SimWorks, we can see that the PC-12’s exterior has been meticulously recreated. Everything from the propellers (4 blades and 5 blades options are available) to the landing gear and cabin door have been modeled and textured in great detail. As for the interior of the aircraft, the developer claimed that it is almost complete with the team putting on the final touches in the cockpit. In addition to the new images of the plane, the developers also shared a roadmap for the PC-12. The roadmap provides an overview of the various systems that are currently being worked on for the aircraft. We can see that SimWorks has already completed the engine stimulation and is around 50% done with the avionics system. Currently, SimWorks has not revealed the release date and pricing of the much anticipated PC-12. Threshold will keep you updated on this front. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ttrnnw</id>
    <title>Double T Releases Newport News/Williamsburg International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ttrnnw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ad1fea778ac791a55baf44_phf1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1147023"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Double T has recently released their rendition of Newport News/Williamsburg International Airport (KPHF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Virginia Peninsula in the United States with a yearly average of 430,000 passengers.  The airport was built on a patch of land that belonged to Camp Patrick Henry, with commercial service starting in 1949 with Piedmont and Capital Airlines.  In 1951, a fire caused significant damage to the passenger terminal, leading to a complete rebuilding that was finished in 1955. It also included upgrading the traffic control tower and a runway extension.  In 1975, the airport was granted international status, back when it was still called Patrick Henry Airport (after the aforementioned military camp). It was served by four airlines: Allegheny, National, Piedmont, and United.  The airline deregulation of 1978 led to a massive drop in passenger numbers and airline service, with four major operators abandoning the airport one after the other.  A few years later, in 1984, they hired a new executive director to try and fix the unimpressive traffic figures. He planned to construct a business park within the airport to attract air carriers.   The plan was a huge success, with Newport becoming America’s fastest-growing airport two years in a row.  In the early 2000s, the airport was expanded to meet the demand, with new parking lots, a new passenger concourse, and, consequently, more airlines embraced Newport.  The last decade was rough with PHF, with AirTran stopping its operations after the Southwest merger and Delta suspending their service to Atlanta in 2020. Avelo brought hope in 2022, but the operations were suspended within months.  The airport is currently served by American Eagle (Charlotte) and Netjets (Birmingham, Columbus, Knoxville, Minneapolis, Raleigh-Durham, and Teterboro).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made PBR ground textures, hand-made terminals, cargo buildings, custom night lighting, sloped runways, custom jetways, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.97, requiring at least 660.03 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barssk</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Sir Seretse Khama International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barssk" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ad2a697200fb9b5f6a5d6b_gaborone.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="599838"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS.  Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Sir Seretse Khama International Airport (FBSK) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Gaborone in Botswana with a yearly average of 1.5 million passengers.  It was established in the 1950s as a small airstrip, serving as a military airfield for the British colonial administration until its independence in the mid-60s.  With the long-sought-after independence came the need for an international airport to serve the capital city. The construction started in 1980, reaching its completion and inauguration in 1984.  It’s served by Air Botswana (Cape Town, Francistown, Harare, Johannesburg–O. R. Tambo, Kasane, Lusaka, Maun) - the local carrier -, Airlink (Johannesburg), and Ethiopian Airlines (Addis Ababa).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, landside buildings, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.37, requiring at least 56.07 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpf28</id>
    <title>Just Flight Publishes F28 Professional’s Product Overview and Tutorials</title>
    <updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpf28" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ae74356b5fa40322ba6763_fokker1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="726648"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently uploaded a series of videos to their YouTube channel, further showcasing the upcoming F28 Professional, starting with a product overview video and four tutorials ranging from startup to landing. The Fokker F28 is a twin-engined regional jet developed in the late 1960s, first flown in 1967, and introduced two years later. Multiple variants were built, ranging from 70 seats to 89 seats in various fuselage lengths.  As of 2019, there are no current operators of the F28 around, with Fly-SAX being the last to operate it commercially. Garuda Indonesia was the largest former operator, with 62 of them. Other Major operators include the Ansett Group (13), AirQuarius Aviation (4), and Biman Bangladesh Airlines (4). The Ansett Group was also responsible for the longest nonstop F28 route in the world, between Perth and Kununurra, roughly 2300 km apart.  The first video goes through some of the main features and functionalities, variants, and their respective livery list. The subsequent videos are tutorials on operating the aircraft from cold and dark to landing. ‍ The aircraft is set to release later today for roughly $69.99. ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baremg</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Málaga Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baremg" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64ae79b0345edd638b583993_lemg1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="258384"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Málaga Airport (LEMG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Spain after Madrid, Barcelona, and Palma de Mallorca, averaging 18.4 million passengers per year.  It’s one of the oldest Spanish airports, opened in 1919, with scheduled air service starting that same year with Didier Daurat flying passengers to Barcelona, Toulouse, Alicante, Tangier, and Casablanca.  The runway had its first extension work in 1960, followed by the construction of a new passenger terminal at the very center of the site.  In 1991, a new passenger terminal (now Terminal 2) was opened, designed by Ricardo Boffil. The old terminal was transformed into a general aviation terminal four years later.  Terminal 3 was opened by King Juan Carlos in March 2010, starting operations the day after.  Only two of the three terminals are currently operating (Terminals 2 and 3). Terminal 2 is low-cost oriented, and hosts EasyJet, EasyJet Switzerland, and Ryanair, and Terminal 3 is used by the other airlines.  Being one of the busiest airports in Spain, the list of operators is substantial: it’s a focus city for EasyJet, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, and Vueling, and most European carriers regularly visit it. London Gatwick is the busiest destination, with an average of 885,608 passengers, and Barcelona is a close second with 778,527.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, landside buildings, custom ground clutter, custom night lighting, and an up-to-date ground layout.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.23, requiring at least 261.01 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf28r</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases the Fokker F28 Professional for MSFS‍</title>
    <updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf28r" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64af022dd1db9c4f5979e124_f28-professional_5_ss_l_230703100258.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="808925"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Following the release of the highly popular BAE 146 Professional, Just Flight have released the next aircraft in their Professional Series of aircraft. The Fokker F28 is a 1960s-designed short-range airliner popular with European carriers of the time.  The Fokker F28 flew in 1967 and entered into service in 1969 with Braathens SAFE of Norway. The type was produced until 1987 among several models before being phased out in favor of the newer Fokker F70/F100 series. The 65 to 85-seat jet remained in service worldwide until as recently as 2019. The type also entered into military service with a handful of jets remaining in military service.  The Just Flight rendition of this aircraft covers several variants of the aircraft with the Mk. 1000 Mk. 2000, Mk. 3000, and Mk. 4000 all being covered. Just Flight used real plans from the aircraft and extensive study of a museum aircraft to ensure model accuracy. Just Flight has also utilized many newer features in MSFS to create an accurate addon.  Features of this new airplane include:  And many more.  To purchase a copy of this aircraft please visit the Just Flight Store. Stay tuned to Threshold to stay up to date on all flight sim news.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eaa2023</id>
    <title>SimVenture 2023, fly EAA AirVenture Oshkosh from your home flight simulator! </title>
    <updated>2023-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eaa2023" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b07099f6e7f65a27eec659_simventure-2023-oshkosh.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="85272"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Last year was a record-setting year with approximately 650,000 attendees, seven percent more than 2021’s attendance. With less than 10 days remaining, the show will be filled with exciting exhibits and events! Pilot Edge is hosting Sim Venture 2023, providing you the opportunity to utilize your preferred flight sim to experience the exhilaration of flying into EAA! Pilot Edge's Sim Venture will simulate flight procedures with virtual airspace controlled by Oshkosh experienced controllers immersing you in the hustle and bustle of the world's busiest airspace during the remaining seven days of July! This time of year, Wittman Regional Airport aka Oshkosh will be filled with tens of thousands of aircraft during the fly-in! EAA Air Venture hosts exhibits of a wide range of aircraft, from iconic WW2 warplanes to unique experimental ultralights, rotorcraft fighters, and commercial airliners. From air shows to flight experiences and learning events! If you're a vintage aviation enthusiast or a modern aviation lover, EAA AirVenture Oshkosh offers something for all aviation enthusiasts at this mega fly-in. Flying into the event is tricky; managing the influx of air traffic requires impeccable coordination and robust logistical support. Such procedures are crucial to ensuring smooth operations, akin to a finely tuned machine. These procedures are published for those wishing to fly into EAA. The flight into Oshkosh requires special nonstandard maneuvers and approaches to make specific landing zones aka spots. Your timing, precision, and coordination with the traffic flow are a must for a safe landing. Pilots must monitor ATC frequencies due to the high rate of instructions given to individual aircraft, requiring pilots to listen for their call signs and instructions, which is the utmost challenge. It takes incredible planning, patience, and airmanship to pull it off, and it is well worth it when mastered.  The EAA is also providing a $10 discount of the latest version of Microsoft Flights Simulator EAA members here! More info from the EAA Sim Venture subpage Useful links to get you started flying!  PilotEdge’s SimVenture event Join Pilot Edge here  Pilotedge’s Discord  Prizes! https://www.pilotedge.net/pages/simventure2023-prizes ‍ And finally a great pilot Briefing video posted by The Flight Simulation Association!</summary>
    <published>2023-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsfpen</id>
    <title>FS Formosa Releases Penghu Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsfpen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b1a2b35bf98c52628b39d7_penghu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="467067"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FS Formosa Project has recently released their rendition of Penghu Airport (RCQC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in Taiwan with a yearly average of 2.3 million passengers.  Built in 1957 as a military airport, Penghu got a proper passenger terminal only nine years later, mainly serving as an alternate airport to Kaohsiung Airport.   The airport was last upgraded in 2004, with a new - and larger - terminal building to deal with the increased demand for air travel in the region.   The authorities have been considering a new expansion project in the future, making the terminal larger and extending the runway to accommodate larger aircraft.  It's served by Daily Air, Mandarin Airlines, and Uni Air.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR texture mapping, custom ground service equipment, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and custom landmarks in the city, including the Mudouyu Lighthouse, the Penghu Great Bridge, the Tongpanyu Geopark, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.02, requiring at least 1.01 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vpdyam</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases Yampa Valley Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vpdyam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b1a91ee818e2f26371929d_yampa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="775999"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. V Pilot Designs has recently released their rendition of Yampa Valley Airport (KHDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Steamboat Springs, Hayden, and Craig, with a yearly average of 160,000 passengers. The airport was built on a 435-acre parcel of land in Hayden, Colorado, acquired by the Rott County Board of Commissioners in 1946. It opened to the public in 1950, with a single grass runway and basic facilities. It was then called Rott County Airport. The runway was paved 14 years later, in 1964, allowing more aircraft to fly into the airport. Then, in 1996, the airport underwent a major transformation by constructing a new, state-of-the-art terminal that made Yampa Valley more efficient and passenger-friendly. It’s currently a gateway to the Yampa Valley Region and its world-renowned ski resorts, natural beauty, and parks. It recently underwent a two-stage expansion project, with an apron expansion adding a new parking position in 2018 and a terminal expansion in 2020 with a seventh gate to match the seven parking positions.  As a curiosity, the airport has no control tower, and pilots must coordinate their actions via CTAF or UNICOM. It’s served on a seasonal basis by Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, custom textures, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for $14.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aermjs</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes Statement on A330 Project’s Future</title>
    <updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aermjs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b1b094f0a862ac3cc37043_a330-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1880414"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mathijs Kok’s surprise resignation earlier this month after 20 years of Aerosoft raised many questions regarding the future of the A330 Project, formerly managed by him. Yesterday, Aerosoft made a public statement on their forum with answers.  They claim to have seamlessly staffed the project with a new head and complimentary team members (Mathijs wasn’t the only one who left), and they announced a new landing page for the project, releasing next Friday and featuring information, media, and development updates.   There’s still no information regarding a potential release date or pricing, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tidcsn</id>
    <title>Threshold Introduces DCS News Coverage</title>
    <updated>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tidcsn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b326ad1bbfe06abceac86f_DCS.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="128760"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Hello everyone, In the many years we've shared this journey, you've known us at Threshold for our passion for flight simulation, our commitment to insightful reporting, and the joy we derive from staying on the cutting edge of simulation news. Our community has grown around the love for Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS) and X-Plane, and we are so grateful for your continued support and engagement. ‍ Today, we are thrilled to announce that we're opening a new chapter in our Threshold story. It's time to widen our horizons and delve into the dynamic world of the Digital Combat Simulator (DCS) World! ‍ We've heard from many of you about your interest in DCS World, a free-to-play digital battlefield game renowned for its authentic and intricate simulation of military aircraft, ground vehicles, and even geographical landscapes. You've shared your experiences, your insights, and your enthusiasm for this unique simulation platform. Now, we're excited to include this amazing world in our daily news coverage. ‍ It's important to note that our move into DCS World News doesn't mean we're leaving our roots behind. We will continue our in-depth coverage of MSFS and X-Plane while bringing the same fervour and attention to detail to the DCS World. ‍ Our journey into the world of DCS will bring us closer to virtual pilots from all areas of flight simulation. We are ready to embrace this challenge and provide you with the latest, most comprehensive, and engaging news about DCS World. We can't wait to explore this new arena, and we're excited to bring you along on this adventure. ‍ Thank you for being part of our community, for sharing in our love for flight simulation, and for joining us on this exciting new journey into DCS World. Let's soar to new heights together! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/abltdw</id>
    <title>AviaStorm: Breathing Life into the Tornado in DCS World</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/abltdw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b3fb5ff1342e5b1458d2cc_Kopie_von_Tornado_model_reveal01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2488835"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. The team at AviaStorm has chosen to simulate the IDS (Interdiction/Strike) version of the Tornado as seen in service with the German Air Force (GAF). This variant was in service up until the early 2000s and comes armed with a substantial range of unguided weapons including the MK-80 series and European weapons such as the Matra 250ED. In addition, AviaStorm is also introducing several new weapons to DCS, including the Komoran anti-ship missile and MW1 cluster munition dispenser. In a nod to the varied roles the Tornado played in real-life, the team is incorporating a reconnaissance pod into the model. This inclusion promises to add another layer to DCS mission planning, especially for virtual squadrons. Despite their focus on the IDS variant, AviaStorm is also committed to including liveries of every user nation at the module's initial release, namely GAF, RAF, IAF, and RSAF. However, they've hinted that RAF exclusive weapons are not planned for the initial release. As for future versions of the Tornado, AviaStorm has kept plans close to their chest, only hinting that anything is possible. One thing is certain: an AI backseater akin to Jester is in the pipeline. As the role of the backseater is more challenging than that of the pilot, the team is deliberating the most efficient way to implement this feature. On the topic of radar technology, AviaStorm is also exploring available options. They will either adopt suitable existing technologies or, if necessary, build a new radar system from scratch. In their pursuit of accuracy, AviaStorm is using multiple reference aircraft for their simulation. The primary aircraft being scanned is the 44+56 Tornado, now adorned in a commemorative scheme "Bunte Kuh" (Colorful Cow) to honor the Tornado's service with JaboG-34. This plane is currently on display at the Traditionsgemeinschaft JaboG 34 Allgäu. In addition, the team is also using the IDS/RECCE Tornado 44+97, which is on display at the Flugwerft Schleißheim near Munich, Germany. This aircraft went into service in 1985 and retired after reaching the 4000 flight hour limit in 2008, with its last two years spent as part of the ISAF troops supporting operations in Afghanistan. The Following chart displays the weapon chart which depicts what AviaStorm are planning to bring to this magnificent jet. This is all subject to change however this is already an extensive list and is sure to keep users satisfied with plenty of options. AviaStorm refrains from setting a specific timeline for the release of the Tornado IDS. Their commitment is to quality over speed, striving to create the highest level of Tornado simulation possible. While this approach may mean a longer wait for fans, the team is confident that the eventual release will provide an unmatched virtual flight experience, worth every second of the wait. ‍ Threshold now covers all DCS World related news. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sqanad</id>
    <title>Squawk Ident Releases Hang Nadim International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sqanad" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b401c43cc89d698b9fa60a_nadim1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1410690"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Squawk Ident has recently released their rendition of Hang Nadim International Airport (WIDD), serving the city of Batam, Indonesia, with a yearly average of 6.5 million passengers.  Officially opened in 1965 as Batam Island International Airport, it was later renamed Hang Nadim International Airport after Laksamana Hang Nadim Pahlawan Kechik, a legendary warrior from the Batam region.   The airport was very important to the industrial growth of Batam, which was designated as a free trade zone in 1971. Its proximity to Singapore made it a gateway for foreign investments and trading.  A new passenger terminal was built in 2002, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and focusing heavily on attracting more international flights and promoting regional tourism.  Five years later, the airport underwent a major upgrade program, with the construction of a new runway, taxiways, aprons, and the extension of the passenger terminal. The new infrastructure attracted airlines from various countries, becoming a low-cost alternative to Singapore Changi.  It has the longest runway in Indonesia at 4,028 meters, making it the perfect diversion airport for Singapore Changi, easily accommodating Boeing 777s, 747s, Airbus A380s, etc.  Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Citilink, Garuda Indonesia, Jeju Air, Lion Air, Nam Air, Saudia, Super Air Jet, Susi Air, and Wings Air serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, cargo hangars, a basic terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.21, requiring at least 165.27 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/peddev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes MSFS Development Update </title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/peddev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b4279b4c1fbeea9727d61b_pmdg1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1880921"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published the second development update of this month, with information on future 737 updates, console liveries, new marketplace arrivals, UFT, 777, and more.  Randazzo begins with information on the 737 Lineup updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which have been sent to the beta team, including changes to prepare the aircraft for the Universal Flight Tablet.   The Xbox liveries for the 737 are going through marketplace intake and should be made available soon. They are still exploring manners to minimize user costs for liveries.  They have also begun pushing the 737-600 and 737-900 to the Marketplace along with their liveries, with their prediction pointing to an end of July release.  The Universal Flight Tablet is being moved into its final leg of testing. It has been tested on a single airframe so far (the 737-700) to minimize developmental hassles. No previews are available yet.  The 777 has progressed significantly since FSExpo, with PMDG looking into previewing it soon.   They finish with a quick note on the DC-6, which should be getting an update in August.  Their product lineup for MSFS is available on their website and in the Marketplace, although only partially. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
