<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-06-20T18:26:21.551703+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lhrzdp</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Updates London Heathrow Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lhrzdp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666b7d9752124d1e83c7c236_zd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently updated their freeware and open-source rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, adding a custom model for Terminal 5B and fixing issues with lights and pre-existing models. London Heathrow is the eighth-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprising international travel and the remaining 6% strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it.  Update 0.4.0, the first since its public open beta release brings a custom model for Terminal 5B, T5C improvements, lighting updates, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ It’s available for free on the Threshold Forum. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mseddf</id>
    <title>Aviotek Simulation Software Releases Freeware Frankfurt Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mseddf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666c511c8b470c555156b1f4_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Simulation Software has recently released its first airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new version of Frankfurt Airport (EDDF) is now available for free, following its previous release for X-Plane. Frankfurt Airport is the busiest airport in Germany, servicing numerous regional and international destinations. The newly released Frankfurt Airport features handcrafted airport buildings, custom ground support equipment (GSE), custom animated jetways, a custom GSX profile, realistic ground textures and layout, custom terminal interiors, points of interest (POIs), and more. The scenery can now be downloaded for free from Orbx.  For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/taff62</id>
    <title>TAF Studio Previews Hayfork Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/taff62"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666cb618a2958c860bd16999_6632f0c686be6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. TAF Studio has teased their newest scenery for MSFS - Hayfork Airport (F62). Located in a mountain valley in Northern California, Hayfork Airport is a small airfield with a long runway (4100 ft) for its size. This scenery will feature some interesting additions, such as a modelled race track made for offroad vehicles and roads with signs leading up to Hayfork’s Bally lookout!  Aside from the automotive part of the scenery, two bush spots with three runways are also featured in Hayfork scenery. With an elevation of 6250ft and a length of only 295ft, serious STOL skills are required to land successfully. Another bush spot, located a couple of miles to the east of Hayfork’s Bally, has an even more challenging runway! Only 250ft of the runway on an uphill cliff, without an option for a go-around. Key features of Hayfork California are F62 Hayfork Airport, 2 bush spots with 3 runways, functional hangar doors at Hayfork Airport, custom charts for Hayfork Airport and Hayfork Bally Bushstrip, tiedown points at Hayfork Airport, Mountain Valley Raceway, Custom 3D buildings, and custom trees and vegetation. ‍ The release date and price of this scenery haven’t been announced as of the time of writing, however, as always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdlsgg</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdlsgg"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666cc1cfa73b93c4b2454e8e_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently released its version of Geneva Airport (LSGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Swiss city of Geneva and is located approximately 2.5 miles from the city centre. As the second biggest and busiest airport in Switzerland, it welcomes around 16.5 million passengers annually. Geneva Airport opened in 1919 as a simple airfield. The first concrete runway was constructed in 1937 to accommodate the increasing number of planes flying to Geneva. During World War II, all flights from Switzerland were prohibited, but after the war, passenger traffic at the airport steadily increased. Subsequently, more airlines began operating at the airport, leading to numerous developments and upgrades over the years. Today, airlines such as easyJet and Swiss International Air Lines ensure that the airport connects to a wide variety of destinations worldwide, resulting in approximately 165,000 aircraft movements annually. The newly released Geneva Airport from RDPresets comes with a variety of features, including completely custom modeling and texturing with PBR textures, 3D interior, custom ground textures, accurate night lighting, and much more. The add-on requires 3.13 GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for approximately $19.15. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2aa60</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Announces Aerostar 600 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2aa60"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666df4c4c46e8cd22c52d76e_aerostar.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently announced the development of a new Accu-Sim airplane for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the Piper Aerostar 600, a twin-engined propeller aircraft designed and built by Ted Smith Aircraft Company in the late 1960s.  Ted Smith, then an already experienced aircraft designer, envisioned a fast twin-engined airplane with no compromises, sleek lines, powerful engines, and speed as the main priority. By the late 1960s, the first prototype was already breaking records, making it the fastest twin-piston general aviation aircraft at the time, thanks to its light construction, low drag, and sheer power.  ‍ The Aerostar 600 had two Lycoming IO-540-K engines, producing 290 horsepower each. These allowed it to cruise at 408 km/h, with a service ceiling of 25,000ft and 1,500 miles of total range on a single tank of fuel.  ‍ Like their Comanche 250 (released mid-2023), the upcoming airplane will be built on Accu-Sim 2.0 technology. This technology features an advanced aerodynamics system that tries to accurately represent how an aircraft flies through the air, realistic wear and tear on the airframe and engine, in-depth electrical simulation, and much more.  ‍ They have owned and operated a real Aerostar 600 for several years, and it was assumed for the longest time that it would be their first product for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  Not much has been revealed yet, but they mention it’s an entirely different experience from flying the Comanche, with their Accu-Sim 2.0 technology accurately recreating the feel of flying a piston twin. It’s expected to be released “later in 2024.” ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxdc</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Detroit City for XP12 and MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxdc"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666df7f3fd5f4e53f95ddf19_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has released another addition to their “Landmarks” product series, this time being a rendition of Detroit City for both X-Plane 12 and MSFS.  Being the biggest city on the USA-Canada border, as well as the most populous city in the state of Michigan, it is known for its contributions to art, music architecture, and its great automotive history. Orbx’s Detroit City scenery features over 52 custom-made buildings (the Renaissance Center, the Spirit of Detroit Sculpture, Comerica Park, the Guardian Building, Michigan Central Station, Ford Field, Little Caesars Arena, and the Aretha Franklin Amphitheatre), and a detailed representation of the waterfront and industrial areas along the Detroit River. Also included is a large amount of highly detailed models replacing the city’s photogrammetry data, including models for cranes, chimneys, vehicles, structures, animated Detroit People Mover on the raised tracks through the city’s downtown, and emissive textures on all buildings for nighttime flying across the city. The product can be bought on OrbxDirect for $9.88 for the MSFS version, while the X-Plane version costs $13.20. The XP version will require at least 1.92GB of free disk space, whereas the MSFS version requires 1.02 GB. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tcj525</id>
    <title>TorqueSim CitationJet 525 Enters Beta Testing</title>
    <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tcj525"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666ea7ec53965f75781f7919_CJ-2024-06-12-0023-825x510.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The Cessna CitationJet is a series of light business jets, and are a part of the Citation family. Launched in 1989, the CJ 525 had its first flight in October 1991. Using the Citation II’s fuselage, the CJ 525 has a different wing box and T-tail design. After the original CJ proved to be a success, the 525 received an upgrade in avionics and engines and was marketed as CJ1, CJ1+, and M2, depending on the equipment the aircraft had.  Aside from the original 525 model, Cessna also produced prolonged versions: 525A, 525B and 525C. All of these versions later received avionics and engine upgrades and were marketed as CJ2, CJ3 and CJ4, respectively. During the testing phase, various aspects of TorqueSim’s CJ525 will be tested and examined, such as flight dynamics, systems accuracy, visual fidelity, and performance testing.  As of the publishing of this article, no information about the release date or pricing of this addon has been released, however, make sure to keep an eye out as Threshold will keep you updated with the progress of TorqueSim’s CitationJet 525! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777rdr</id>
    <title>PMDG 777-300ER’s Possible Release Date Revealed</title>
    <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777rdr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/666f692fe859b81b3df12044_randango1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published a new thread on their forum with a possible release date for their long-awaited Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator: June 25th, with five extra backup days just in case something goes wrong. They also confirm it's the first of many 777 variants to be released for the platform, with the 777F, 777-200ER, and 777-200LR to follow. Each will be a unique product, so users can only purchase what they want.  The product incorporated feedback from their previous releases (DC-6 and 737), intending to bring a fully detailed LiDAR-scanned cockpit, ensuring accurate proportions and looks. The aircraft systems are promised to be second to none, with all major and minor systems simulated to a degree where they allegedly pass the scrutiny of experienced pilots, engineers, and maintainers.  Their Universal Flight Tablet will bring many new features specifically for the 777, including full SimBrief compatibility and Hoppie datalink. Furthermore, the navdata will be SQL-based, providing richer information to make advanced lateral pathing possible.  It will also include the Boeing Electronic Checklist and all the certified normal and abnormal procedures for the airplane, aiding the user with troubleshooting if required. The engine model will feature fuel burn figures within 0.3% of real-world figures, accurately reflecting the airplane's performance and range. In unusual fashion for PMDG, they have included a high-detail passenger cabin with four distinct seating zones, seat-back displays, integrated cabin lighting that follows day and night changes, and more. ‍ They will highlight some features of their upcoming product in the following week, and streamers will soon be able to stream it online. Regarding availability, it will be available on PMDG.com from day one, and the marketplace release might take a few weeks.  They are not sure yet about compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, but if what Microsoft said about seamless compatibility is true, it will probably work just fine.‍ Threshold will keep you updated with further information when available. ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42tab</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases Taboo Performance Tool for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42tab"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6670a7fecfc9a4710f944398_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 has recently launched its newest add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The new tool called Taboo is a performance utility designed for Xbox, but it's also beneficial for other platforms. Taboo allows users to reduce stuttering and enhance FPS by disabling and unloading avionics to decrease memory usage. Taboo offers various features, including Non-Destructive Mod (which means it does not permanently alter an aircraft), Reduce Avionic Blackouts (ABO), Memory Optimization, and Enhanced Performance. The add-on is now available at the Parallel 42 Store for $7.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sfo619</id>
    <title>Flightbeam Studios Releases San Francisco International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sfo619"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66724f4a068d6af6f95c5975_captain1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Flightbeam Studios has recently released their rendition of San Francisco International Airport (KSFO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the San Francisco Bay Area with a yearly average of 50.1 million passengers. Initially meant to be a temporary and experimental airport project when the city of San Francisco leased 61 hectares of land in 1927 from the Mills Estate (owned by Ogden L. Mills), it quickly became a permanent commitment with the purchase of the land and its surroundings, totaling up to 450 hectares of area.  It was briefly used as a Coast Guard base and an Army Air Corps training and staging base during World War 2. Following the war, international air travel boomed, prompting the airport's final name change to San Francisco International Airport in 1945. The jet age ushered in a new chapter for SFO. In the 1950s, longer runways were constructed to accommodate larger jetliners, and new terminals were built to handle the increased passenger volume and the demands of international travel. SFO's commitment to innovation continued throughout the latter half of the 20th century. The airport embraced new technologies, such as jet bridges and baggage carousel systems, to improve passenger experience. In 1971, SFO became the first airport in the United States to have an automated people mover system, the AirTrain. It's a hub for United Airlines (44% of the market share) and Alaska Airlines (10.66% of the market share) and is visited by multiple international carriers such as Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, Air New Zealand, American Airlines, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, KLM, Lufthansa, Qatar Airways, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, and WestJet. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-detail 4K textures, custom jetways, detailed interior modeling, custom ground clutter, performance-friendly optimization, and much more. It's available on their shop for $19.99, requiring at least 2.54 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbf62</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Hayfork Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbf62"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6672719b4da42a3ebc53d882_hayfork1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx recently released their rendition of Hayfork Airport (F62) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This public general aviation airport serves Trinity County, California, and has a yearly average of 12,500 operations.  Opened sometime before the FAA was created (pre-1958), the airport was built to facilitate personnel transport to and from the city, whose economy was mainly based on resource extraction (logging and mining).  Its 1,254-meter-long runway at 714 ft elevation can comfortably accommodate a wide variety of general aviation aircraft, large or small. Although there's no scheduled commercial aviation per se, on-demand charters are available (Surf Air). Hayfork Airport's significance lies in its role as a lifeline for the Hayfork community. It facilitates travel for residents, medical personnel, and businesspeople. Additionally, its existence allows for scenic flights, bringing tourism dollars to the area. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with fully custom 3D buildings, custom trees and vegetation, animated objects, 3D tiedown points, two bush spots with three short landing strips, custom airport charts for the airport and one of the strips, and more. It's available on OrbxDirect for roughly $10.65, requiring at least 732.27 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/casj3c</id>
    <title>Classic Aircraft Simulations Releases Piper J-3 Cub for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/casj3c"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/667276ca8cc8fdcd74fee341_cub1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Classic Aircraft Simulations has recently released its rendition of the Piper J-3 Cub for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This popular high-wing monoplane, built by Piper Aircraft between 1938 and 1947, had nearly 20,000 manufactured units. The Cub's story begins in the late 1920s with C.G. Taylor, an aeronautical engineer with a vision for a simple, affordable airplane. His initial design, the Taylor Cub, laid the groundwork for the J-3. In 1937, the Piper Aircraft Company acquired the rights to the Taylor Cub and introduced the J-3, boasting a more powerful engine and several improvements. The J-3's key strength was its simplicity: its lightweight fabric-and-steel construction, paired with a low-horsepower engine, made it easy to fly and maintain. Its ease of use and affordable price tag opened the skies to a new generation of pilots. The J-3's impact indeed soared during World War II. The U.S. Civilian Pilot Training Program (CPTP) adopted the J-3 as its primary trainer, churning out thousands of qualified pilots for the war effort. Nicknamed the "Grasshopper" for its ability to take off and land in short fields, the J-3 played a crucial role in training pilots for combat aircraft. Even after the war, surplus J-3s flooded the civilian market, further democratizing aviation and fueling a surge in recreational flying. Thanks to its ability to land in remote locations, J-3's influence extends far beyond pilot training. It is invaluable for tasks like crop dusting, aerial photography, and banner towing. It even played a part in search-and-rescue missions and disaster relief efforts. J-3's versatility and reliability cemented its reputation as a workhorse of the skies. While production of the J-3 ended in 1947, its legacy lives on. Over 20,000 J-3s were built, making it the most-produced airplane in Piper's history. Many remain operational today, cherished by private owners and flown in airshows and recreational outings. Several companies continue producing certified replicas, ensuring the J-3's design inspires new aviators. The add-on features an accurate rendition of the aircraft, with a computational fluid dynamics flight model, hand-prop start procedure simulation, physics-based animations, aircraft state and condition persistence, landing gear failure simulation, interactive refueling, custom visual effects, compact and hideable custom avionics, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: It's available on Contrail for roughly $16.11, requiring at least 2.1 GB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to DragonRuins for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsstar</id>
    <title>Black Square Previews Beechcraft Starship for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsstar"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6672a6708727c06797f5804f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has recently released a development update where they previewed their newest project for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the Beechcraft Starship. This futuristic-looking aircraft was one of the most technologically advanced aircraft in the 80s and was designed by Burt Rutan Scaled Composites, a well-known aircraft designer. The Starship was also the first all-composite business aircraft with a pressurized cabin.  Unfortunately, despite its design, the Beechcraft Starship was a commercial failure, as during 7 years of production, only 53 were made. Many of the aircraft never found a buyer and were later leased to Raytheon. Today, only 5 Starships are airworthy. The Beechcraft Starship was also the first certified aircraft with a canard wing, the first business aircraft with an all-composite structure, the first certified twin-pusher turboprop, the first general aviation aircraft with a glass cockpit, and one of three civilian turboprops that are certified with a service ceiling up to 41.000 feet.  According to the last development update, the cabin is finished, and the developers are focusing on the Starship’s unique systems and avionic suites such as the AMS-850. The AMS-850 is an avionic suite that was used only in the Starship. It was one of the most advanced avionic suites in the 80s, and many of the feature used in today’s suites were pioneered by the AMS-850. As GPS wasn’t publicly available when the prototype made its first flight, the avionics would automatically tune to the nearest navigational aid and would generate an estimate of the current position. The positional estimation could be enhanced by manual pilot input. Along with other navigational receivers, the Beechcraft Starship had receivers for VLF (Very Low Frequency) radio stations, such as Omega. Omega consisted of 9 transmitters located in various locations around the globe.  Black Square’s rendition of the Starship will feature all technology developed for Dukes, which will also be added to the TBM850 in a free update this summer. This update will include a tablet with options to manage payload, control failures, change options, monitor engines, as well as a live schematic of the electrical and environmental control system. The Starship will feature CRT displays that take time to warm up, and navigational databases that can be updated with floppy disks. Over 230 failures and 172 circuit breakers will be present. The Black Square developer will be attending the FSExpo 2024, where you will be able to learn more about this amazing aircraft and its progress. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftkric</id>
    <title>FeelThere Releases Richmond International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftkric"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6672af70aae102505ed0d456_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FeelThere recently released its rendition of Richmond International Airport (KRIC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving the Greater Richmond Region, it is situated approximately 7 miles from downtown Richmond and accommodates over 4.75 million passengers annually. The airport underwent several name changes before becoming Richmond International Airport. In 1927, it was dedicated as Richard Evelyn Byrd Flying Field and then renamed Richard E. Byrd Airport in 1950. It wasn't until 1984 that it became known as Richmond International Airport. Over the years, the airport has undergone various upgrades and expansions and has seen an increase in passenger traffic and aircraft movements. Today, airlines such as Breeze Airways, Southwest Airlines, and Spirit Airlines offer flights to destinations all over the United States. The newly released Richmond International Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator comes with numerous features, including highly detailed buildings, PBR texturing, a partially modeled internal terminal, custom animated jetways, improved lighting, and more. The add-on requires 693.80 MB of storage space and is available on SimMarket for approximately $16.09. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tf24we</id>
    <title>Threshold at FSExpo 2024: What to Expect</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tf24we"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66742d6a006bf686a9ebd7c1_threshold_at_FSExpoV2.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Time has just flown away, and FlightSimExpo 2024 starts tomorrow! North America’s largest flight simulation event drew over 3,000 attendees last year, and is expected to draw even more at this year’s event in Las Vegas! With such a large concentration of flight simulation enthusiasts and developers in one place, there are bound to be many exciting announcements and updates during the event, and the Threshold team will keep you up to date with coverage from around the event, live from Las Vegas!  The freshest news will be on our social media pages, and we’ll be posting live updates there from the #FSExpoFriday announcements, as well as a live stream on our YouTube channel. We’re also interviewing some pretty big names at the event, so keep an eye out for those! Don’t want to miss out on the news but can’t watch it live? Don’t worry, because at the end of each day we will have roundup articles putting all the day’s news in one place! If you’re attending the event in person, come stop by the Media Partner Lounge and say hi! We hope you’re as excited for the event as we are to cover it, so stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news, reviews, and more!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hcrepa</id>
    <title>Honeycomb Charlie Rudder Pedals Enter Production, Ship In August</title>
    <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hcrepa"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66744690048554085c9e1285_HC_Pedals_02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. After many months of uncertainty, and with questions still swirling about the status of the company as a whole, Honeycomb Aeronautical’s highly anticipated Charlie Rudder Pedals have gone into production today and will finally ship to customers starting in August, according to a statement from Aerosoft. Early this year, Honeycomb fell into hot water as many months of radio silence led to a statement by the company’s CEO, Nicki Repenning, admitting that they were struggling financially, and that his former business partner and CEO of Snakebyte-group, Mike Steup, hid this information from him and stole pre-order money set aside for the Charlie Rudder Pedal production had “gone elsewhere.” Snakebyte and Mr. Steup denies these allegations. Threshold interviewed Mr. Repenning as a culmination of a weeks-long initial investigation, which you can read here.  According to Aerosoft, production of the pedals has started today and they have been able to “test the pre-production models extensively,” and they are “impressed by the quality of the materials and the realistic feel of the pedals.” Aerosoft plans to start deliveries on August 29th. As a compensation for the long waiting time, all customers who have pre-ordered the Charlie Pedals via the Aerosoft Shop or have already pre-ordered them will receive an Aerosoft Shop voucher worth 30€ ($32.17USD). Aerosoft also says that those who are attending this weekend’s FlightSimExpo in Las Vegas can try out the Charlie Pedals at their booth. As a special promotion for the UEFA European Championship, New customers can get a Honeycomb Alpha Yoke at a discounted price of 199.99€ ($214.43USD), for as long as the German national team is in the tournament. The Charlie Pedals can now be pre-ordered on the Aerosoft Shop for 369.99€ ($396.70USD).  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more high-quality flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
