<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-03-29T18:21:11.062809+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ctlapa</id>
    <title>VATSIM Confirms The Airports for Cross the Land: Asia Pacific</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ctlapa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009a41e36708a2da90408f_APAC.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. VATSIM just announced airports for Cross The Land: Asia Pacific Westbound edition in April on their Twitter account. This event involves the Australian and South Eastern Asian airports. ‍ Cross The Land is one of the biggest events on VATSIM, and just recently it got an expansion. Along with the Europe-MEA edition, CTL now has the Americas edition, where pilots fly from Northern American airports to South America, and the Asia Pacific edition, which brings the Australia-SE Asia connection.  ‍ The airport list for this year’s CTL: Asia Pacific is smaller than expected, only 6 airports were chosen, three in Australia and three in Asia: ‍ As of the posting of this article, no information about slot booking has been disclosed. Any new information will be posted on the Cross the Land Discord server and Twitter, as well as on Threshold! If you are interested in learning more about VATSIM, you can visit their website here. ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdplhr</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases London Heathrow Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdplhr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66009dfee9eefa0b6ca2a6dd_deathrow1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently released their freeware and open-source rendition of London Heathrow Airport (EGLL) for X-Plane 12, serving Greater London with a yearly average of 80 million passengers. London Heathrow is the eight-busiest airport in Europe by total passenger traffic, flying to over 184 destinations in 84 countries. It’s the main gateway to England, with 94% of the traffic comprehending international travel, and the remaining 6% is strictly domestic.  It’s the Main hub for British Airways, the biggest carrier in the United Kingdom, offering a wide range of destinations from within and worldwide. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, All Nippon Airways, Austrian Airlines, Brussels Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Emirates, Eurowings, Japan Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Oman Air, Saudia, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP, Tunisair, and many others also serve it. The scenery features custom orthoimagery, custom ground textures, 3D grass, SAM jetways, VDGS, custom buildings, realistic dirt and grunge, and more. Its open-source nature warrants constant improvement, and ZDP has already shared a list of future futures, including more custom buildings, a Concorde static model, improved clutter, improved ground markings, improved vegetation, and more. ‍ It’s available for free on the Threshold Forum. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsapar</id>
    <title>FSA Announces 60+ Confirmed Partners for June’s FlightSimExpo</title>
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsapar"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6601c95965684f346ca40009_fse1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. In a livestream, Flight Sim Association confirmed more than 60 hardware, software, training, and community organizations are participating in FlightSimExpo 2024, which is set to take off in June.  Phil Coyle, FSA's co-founder, says it's just the beginning, as there's still three months to go and plenty of time left for more partners to get involved. Perspective exhibitors can learn more at FSExpo's website; the deadline is May 31st. Attendees are encouraged to register before April 1st to get the year's best prices. The event registration includes in-person and online seminars, a free drink and appetizers at Friday's Attendee Welcome Reception, exhibit hall access on Saturday and Sunday, and more. FSA members are eligible for special pricing conditions. The partner list includes Navigraph, Orbx, Got Friends, Blackbird Simulations, Aerosoft Flight, Lockheed Martin Prepar3d, X-Plane (Laminar Research), SimFab, WinWing, SKALARKI, and Virpil Controls. The complete list is available on their website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bouukh</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases UK Helipads Pack 2 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bouukh"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6601ce44ddba9dec7064e36f_ukh1.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has recently released their second package of UK Helipads for X-Plane 11 and 12, including five helipads spread across the United Kingdom, created in exceptional detail and featuring full XP12 compatibility.  The package features the helipads of Almondsbury (an NPAS and Air Ambulance base near Bristol), Brook Farm (a maintenance-centered helipad near Milton Keynes), Castle Air Liskeard (Run by Castle Air, a luxury helicopter fleet operator), Penzance Heliport (a newly opened and bustling site in Penzance), and Tresco Heliport (located near Penzance, on the island of Tresco. It’s highly scenic and very close to the Abbey gardens). ‍ The package features a high-detailed rendition of each helipad, with full XP12 optimization, dynamic weather effects (XP12 only), PBR textures, 3D vegetation, dynamic lighting, accurate custom static clutter, custom static vehicles, up-to-date layouts and locations, and a performance-friendly optimization. It’s available on the Boundless Store for roughly $13.89, requiring at least 1.9 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vsmmyr</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Releases Myrtle Beach International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vsmmyr"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6601d313baf70c24890cd71f_myr4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Verticalsim has recently released their rendition of Myrtle Beach International Airport (KMYR) for X-Plane 12, serving Myrtle Beach, South Carolina, with a yearly average of 3.3 million passengers. It was built on property from a former air base, transferred by the government through the Surplus Property Act. Initially, the city of Myrtle Beach did not want to use the property for an airport, but the funds had to be used for an airport, which meant they funded Horry County Airport instead for 18 years. It wasn’t until 1977 that the city annexed the area of Myrtle Beach Airport, with the airport and the Air Force Base sharing the same runway until 1993 when the AFB closed, and the portions of the former military flight line were turned over to the County. Myrtle Beach became an international airport in 1996 and got a brand new passenger terminal for that exact purpose. Twelve years later, it underwent two major renovation projects to modernize the infrastructure. It’s currently undergoing expansion work, with six new gates being added to Terminal A, bringing the total number of gates to 18 and significantly increasing the traffic handling capabilities. Allegiant Air, American Airlines, Avelo Airlines, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Frontier Airlines, Southwest Airlines, Spirit Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Airlines currently serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date layout, custom autogen, high-resolution PBR ground textures, animated car traffic, 4K textures, 3D grass, color-graded satellite imagery, HDR night lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on the Verticalsim Shop for roughly $14.99, and X-Plane 11 users are eligible for a $9.99 upgrade fee.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/boureu</id>
    <title>Boundless Releases Reus Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/boureu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6602d1cb436d0b2858ef8e9f_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Boundless has just released their rendition of Reus Airport for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. The Spanish airport serves the city of Reus and has a yearly average of just over 1 million passengers. Located about 88 kilometers southwest of Barcelona, Reus Airport opened all the way back in 1935. The airport was used as a Republican base during the Spanish Civil War. After the war, the airport became a Spanish Air Force base. In the late 1990s, the airport became fully civilian, and has since been the destination for those who seek the sun. The airport has and is being served by airlines like Ryanair, TUI, and Jet2. The last few years, the yearly amount of passengers has seen a big rise, and the airport is becoming an increasingly more popular holiday destination for those wanting to visit the Spanish coast. The scenery has lots of features with the most noticeable of them being up to date Ortho imagery, 4K PBR Terminal &amp; Airport buildings, 3D vegetation, HD custom clutter objects, Animated airport ground traffic, 4K custom ground textures and fully accurate ground markings. According to Boundless, the airport has thousands of accurately placed objects and textures. Reus Airport is now available on the Boundless Store for £15.99GBP, or roughly $20.25USD and takes up around 970 MB of space on disk. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hrsu</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Yeosu Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hrsu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6602d64ad944e801f0324953_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has just released their rendition of Yeosu Airport (RKJY) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The South Korean airport serves the city of Yeosu and has a yearly average of just under 650,000 passengers. Located in Yeosu, South Korea, Yeosu Airport opened on 23 May 1972. The airport is served by airlines like Asiana Airlines, Jin Air and Korean Air. These three airlines give the airport a total of two destinations, Jeju and Seoul-Gimpo. The scenery has lots of features with some of them being sloped runway, accurate simulation of Yeosu Airport, hand-made ground textures, dynamic airport lighting and highly detailed models of all airport buildings, objects and surroundings. Yeosu airport is now available on Orbx for $18.85AUD and takes up around 3.37 GB of space on disk. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssgaa</id>
    <title>FlightSim Studio Previews Ganderkesee Atlas Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssgaa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66043e5c377167e7c314f777_gander1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlightSim Studio AG has recently previewed their upcoming rendition of Ganderkesee Atlas Airfield (EDWQ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a commercial airfield in Ganderkesee, near Bremen. It was constructed by Mr. Helmut Weyhausen and Mr. Jochen Weyhausen-Sauer in March 1970, along with Atlas Air Service AG, a maintenance and aircraft charterer/retailer company specializing in Embraer aircraft, but also a Cessna, Beechcraft, and Hawker service center (it started as a Cessna retailer in the past). They also handle the sales of aircraft on behalf of their customers. It is one of the most popular airfields in Lower Saxony, used for business flights, air sports, and flight training, and often used by celebrities who live in Bremen. Its 836x22 meter runway makes it strictly a small aircraft airport, limited to a take-off weight of 5.7 tonnes.  FSS’s rendition will feature an up-to-date layout, custom ground textures, interiors, and more. There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wince</id>
    <title>WinWing launches A320 FCU</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wince"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/660444cba604c5350ce70b1d_GJpFlLxbUAATX65.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. WinWing has just announced that their newest product from the Airbus lineup is available for pre-ordering.  On their social media, along with information about the pre-order and official price, WinWing also compared their FCU and a real Airbus FCU. The FCU features an accurate knob look and function, a push-pull mechanism, and adjustable backlighting that is auto-synced with Aircraft in the simulator. The only exception is the EXPED button, which is still functional, but unmarked, as users can change its function in the SIMAPP application. The WinWing A320 FCU is plug-and-play with SIMAPP, and no additional setup is required. Prices are as follows: Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/minick</id>
    <title>miniCockpit Releases 2024/2025 Roadmap</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/minick"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6604473b86ad320b2c2d7843_433500828_355017780872574_1264756462961031050_n.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. miniCockpit - best known for miniFCU, announced on their social media their 2024/2025 roadmap, and four new products as follow-up of the mini lineup: miniOVHD, miniRMP, miniECAM, and miniEFIS. miniEFIS - EFIS panel with a small addition - Chrono button. The miniEFIS panel has knobs for range selector on ND, the knob for switching between NAV modes on ND, ADF-VOR select switches, Barometer Selector knob, and display, as well as FD and LS push-buttons. miniOVHD represents a compact version of the Airbus overhead panel. According to miniCockpit, the controls were carefully chosen according to the Airbus SOP. The panel has an APU master switch, start and bleed buttons, seat belt sign, EXT PWR button, wiper knob, and light switches. miniRMP is a unified communications and navigation panel, where you can control the comm frequencies, squawk code, and nav frequencies. It also features a switch where the user can change between COM1 and COM2, as well as VOR1 and VOR2. Last but not least, miniECAM - an extended version of the ECAM Control Panel, with Master Warning and Master Caution buttons. It contains all the System Page buttons that control the Lower ECAM, along with CLR, RCL, EMER CANC, and TO CONFIG buttons. The price and release date of new miniCockpit products isn’t known yet, but stay tuned, as Threshold will keep you updated!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flykef</id>
    <title>Fly X Simulations Releases Kefalonia International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flykef"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66047c96e309f3894a04e153_kefa1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly X Simulations has recently released their rendition of Kefalonia International Airport (LGKF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Kefalonia, Greece, with a yearly average of 817,216 passengers. It was opened in 1971 to serve the municipality of Leivatho, which no longer exists. A decade later, a new runway and the former main passenger terminal were built. The airport was privatized in December 2015 as part of a government plan to privatize some of their airports, in a batch with 13 other regional airports. A joint venture between Fraport AG/ Copelouzos Group won the concession to operate the entire batch for 40 years as of April 2017. The new operators heavily upgraded the airport, constructing a new passenger terminal building and modernizing the infrastructure with new check-in desks, security lanes, and a larger airside space with more shops. Aegean Airlines (year-long), Air Serbia, Animawings, Austrian Airlines, Avanti Air, British Airways, Condor, Discover Airlines, easyJet, ITA Airways, Jet2.com, Marathon Airlines, Norwegian Air Shuttle, People’s, Ryanair, Sky Express, Smartwings, Transavia, TUI Airways, TUI fly Netherlands, Tus Airways, Volotea, and Wizz Air serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom airport buildings, custom ground textures, high-resolution PBR textures, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $12.79, requiring at least 852 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilut</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases Upcoming London Luton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilut"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66048a447bad63a31734918e_luton2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently teased the development progress on their rendition of London Luton Airport (EGGW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Greater London, Bedfordshire, Buckinghamshire, Northamptonshire, Hertfordshire, and Cambridgeshire with a yearly average of 13.3 million passengers, making it the fifth busiest airport in the United Kingdom. Opened in 1938, Luton was of great importance to the Royal Air Force during World War 2, with commercial activities only resuming seven years after the conflict.  Luton was pivotal to developing the package holiday business in the UK, amounting to a fifth of all holiday flights in the United Kingdom by 1969, leading to a major expansion plan in the subsequent decade to accommodate the ever-increasing traffic figures.  Fate might have been a bit cruel to Luton, as the figures dipped massively in the 1980s, leading to the addition of “London” to its name to emphasize its proximity to the capital. ‍ While the extra traffic did, in fact, come during the 1990s, it was in no way due to the renaming strategy, but by embracing charter operators and low-cost carriers such as Debonair and easyJet, which transformed it into the fastest growing major airport in the country.  ‍ The rapid growth was rewarded with an 80 million pound investment program, which improved its infrastructure and facilities. It was followed by the construction of a 40 million pound terminal in 1999, opened by Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Phillip, housing 60 check-in desks and a range of commercial outlets. Six years later, the departure and arrival lounges were redeveloped at the cost of 38 million pounds. ‍ Further development was conducted in 2018 at the cost of 160 million pounds, including new shops, a new boarding pier, and more boarding gates, increasing the passenger handling capabilities to 18 million a year.  ‍ It’s an operating base for easyJet, Ryanair, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air UK, which, aside from Dan Air, El Al, FlyOne, and SunExpress, are the only ones that serve the airport, making it a full LCC-centric hub.  ‍ There’s no information on the release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2abz</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Aberdeen Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2abz"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6604c1c80b999da8e2b1bede_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has just released its latest product for MSFS. This time it’s Aberdeen Airport (EGPD). With a yearly average of just over 1.9 million passengers, the Scottish airport serves the city of Aberdeen. Located in the Dyce suburb of Aberdeen, Scotland, the international airport opened back in 1934. The airport started as Dyce Aerodrome, before becoming a Royal Air Force station during the Second World War. After the war, the airport slowly became the international airport it is today. Located around 9.3 km (roughly 5.8 mi) from the city center, the airport is a focus city for airlines like Eastern Airways, Loganair, and TUI Airways. Although the airport was ranked worst in Scotland in 2019, it made a comeback in 2022, being named Scottish Airport of the Year. The airport has a multitude of destinations, ranging from chilly Norway to sunny Spain. The scenery has a variety of features included, some of them being Full Detail Buildings, Realistic Ground Markings, Hi Res Ground Images, Stunning Night Effects, High Detail Airport Vehicles, Fencing, vegetation and PBR Materials. The scenery package also includes an optional feature of Static Aircraft. Aberdeen Airport is now available on SimMarket for $17.30USD. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfbae2</id>
    <title>JustFlight Announces BAe 146 V2 Update</title>
    <updated>2024-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfbae2"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66056d4e069cd4c2780e8f0c_Screenshot%202024-03-28%20083822.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. JustFlight has announced a new update for BAe 146 Professional for MSFS on social media. This update will be free of charge for all customers on both PC and Xbox. The update will be available on the 1st of April. This update will bring users the highly-requested UNS-1. The FMS will feature a unique interface of the real unit along with the holding pattern, direct to, and command heading functions, TOD calculations based on target VS, navigation monitoring, real-time performance information, support for SID and STAR, as well as the ability to import and export flight plans.  An in-depth manual for UNS-1 that contains all its features will be provided with the update.  The WT ProLine 21 that was included in v1 will still be available in the new update, and the two types of the FMS can be changed in the EFB. A brand new, high-detailed passenger cabin will also be present in v2. Each version of BAe146 will receive a new cabin design, followed by fully interactive FWD and AFT galleys (yes, the coffee maker is functional!), cabin lighting controls, cabin calls, and ground service electrical supplier simulation. Another interesting feature is a music player - it comes with 7 music tracks that can be controlled by the user. Players will be able to import their custom music through the cabin speakers. A new boarding simulation will be added in the update. The EFB will now feature several different boarding/deboarding speeds, ranging from instant to realistic. For instance, boarding a fully loaded BAe 146-300 could take up to 20 minutes! During boarding, you can hear new passenger boarding sounds. GSX profiles for each variant will be included. Another highly-requested feature is a paper clipboard instead of the modern EFB. Unfortunately, it will take some time to convert all the functions of EFB to the clipboard, but JF has announced that they have started working on that. This update will feature something rustic though, as pilots will be able to use a paper checklist on the yoke, which can have up to 15 pages, and the paper charts that are stored in the charts holder will hover over the top pedestal after being clicked on. Up to 20 charts can be stored, and custom checklists and charts can be imported by placing PNG images in the necessary folder. The new update will also feature three new default liveries for the -200 and -300 variants. The -200 variant will receive a Discovery Air livery (US Honolulu-based airline), while the -300 will receive United Express Battleship Gray and buzz liveries (not to be confused with Buzz - Ryanair subsidiary) A plethora of new features are in the v2 update, some of them being: an updated flight model for better ground handling, improved AP altitude capture, improved cabin door and airstair animation, as well as new wiper animations. The full changelog can be found here. Updated BAe 146 Operation Manual, EFB manual, and UNS-1 manual are provided with the newest update. How do you like the newest update? Is there anything new you would like to see in the future on BAe 146 Professional? Let us know in the comments! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inipwu</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Teases A300-600R’s Pratt &amp; Whitney Update for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inipwu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6606cac867720fcf289e3cb1_pw6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently uploaded a video teasing their upcoming Pratt &amp; Whitney engine option update to their Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing it up to pair engine option-wise with their X-Plane version. Set to release over the Easter weekend, the new update will also bring the modern radio unit with CPDLC and overall improvements (which were not mentioned).  The add-on features a realistic rendition of the classic airliner, with a detailed custom - and independently operated - FMS, custom systems, realistic RNAV, an extensively tuned flight model, custom maintenance functions, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $44.79, requiring at least 6.05 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniggw</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases London Luton Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniggw"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6606f1e13e5286d1e071ebf1_luton1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of London Luton Airport (EGGW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Greater London, Bedfordshire, Buckinghamshire, Northamptonshire, Hertfordshire, and Cambridgeshire with a yearly average of 13.3 million passengers, making it the fifth busiest airport in the United Kingdom. Opened in 1938, Luton was of great importance to the Royal Air Force during World War 2, with commercial activities only resuming seven years after the conflict. Luton was pivotal to developing the package holiday business in the UK, amounting to a fifth of all holiday flights in the United Kingdom by 1969, leading to a major expansion plan in the subsequent decade to accommodate the ever-increasing traffic figures. Fate might have been a bit cruel to Luton, as the figures dipped massively in the 1980s, leading to the addition of “London” to its name to emphasize its proximity to the capital. While the extra traffic did, in fact, come during the 1990s, it was in no way due to the renaming strategy, but by embracing charter operators and low-cost carriers such as Debonair and easyJet, which transformed it into the fastest growing major airport in the country. The rapid growth was rewarded with an 80 million pound investment program, which improved its infrastructure and facilities. It was followed by the construction of a 40 million pound terminal in 1999, opened by Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Phillip, housing 60 check-in desks and a range of commercial outlets. Six years later, the departure and arrival lounges were redeveloped at the cost of 38 million pounds. ‍ Further development was conducted in 2018 at the cost of 160 million pounds, including new shops, a new boarding pier, and more boarding gates, increasing the passenger handling capabilities to 18 million a year. It’s an operating base for easyJet, Ryanair, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air UK, which, aside from Dan Air, El Al, FlyOne, and SunExpress, are the only ones that serve the airport, making it a full LCC-centric hub. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, high-detail models of all airport buildings and objects, an up-to-date layout, an official GSX profile, LOD optimization, custom static aircraft, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $17.91, requiring at least 5.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
