<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-17T18:24:59.958336+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdter</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Teruel Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdter"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663c57c28af77f5ee750fcc9_teruel2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDG has recently released their rendition of Teruel Airport (LETL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a maintenance and storage airport in Teruel, Spain, inaugurated 11 years ago. Originally a military airbase, the airport was repurposed into a maintenance/storage facility due to its dry climate, which is highly suitable for long-term aircraft storage. It played a considerable role during the pandemic, storing over 100 airplanes from multiple carriers. Given the lack of passenger traffic, the airport features only a basic terminal and has no infrastructure for passenger handling. It also houses the PLD Space Propulsion test facility, where they conduct rocket engine tests. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, dozens of parked aircraft, performance-friendly optimization, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.54, requiring at least 775.67 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ptdbbs</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases The Dukes Bundle</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ptdbbs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663d72e7d7cfb5042bb636d5_black-square-piston-turbine-duke-bundle_37_ss_m_240313162327.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Up-and-coming development team Black Square have released their second stand-alone aircraft add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the highly anticipated Piston and Turbine Duke bundle. Known for their Steam Gauge Overhaul packs for existing aircraft, the Duke Bundle is Black Square’s first attempt at a stand-alone aircraft.  The Beechcraft 60 Duke, which first flew in December of 1966, was originally outfitted with two Lycoming TIO-541 turbocharged six-cylinder engines, each outputting 380 horsepower. With its pressurised six-seat cabin the Duke was originally designed to fill the gap in the market between the Beechcraft Baron and Queen Air. The Black Square Dukes Package features multiple GPS and Radio options, 130 possible failures, and a multifunction tablet, the developer also claims it features “the most advanced pressurisation and cabin temperature simulations in MSFS.” The Dukes also feature a custom sound set created by Boris Audio Works. You can find the Black Square Piston and Turbine Dukes bundle here for $69.99. Be sure to keep your eye on Threshold to stay up to date on everything flight simulation! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sda50u</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Releases DA-50RG Update</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sda50u"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663e7c4f711d871e6c35467a_DA50-5.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Coming just a few days after its initial release, developer Skyward Simulations has published the first update for their new Diamond DA-50RG that was released for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The updates bring changes to both the Flight model and textures of the aircraft addressing both functional and visual bugs.  Flight model change log Flight Model &amp; Systems Improved flight model. Improved startup Improved engine cooling  on the ground at idle Faster warm-up Improved ground idle and flight idle logic Added Xfer pump auto shutoff Added Fuel slosh bug fixes.  3D and Texture change log Fixed low-res/wavy default liveries Dynamic registration added  Fixed emissive textures on the right G1000 Fixed sun-visor reflectiveness Fixed gear decals Various other texture improvements Users of the DA-50RG can install the update from the Contrail app. Be sure to keep an eye on Threshold for the latest in flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/nncnfs</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates Navigraph Charts with New Features</title>
    <updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/nncnfs"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f51c907e7d16c1f089136_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph has recently released an updated version of its popular Navigraph Charts, which includes a new feature to enhance navigation assistance. Thanks to data from Microsoft, Impact Observatory, and Esri, users can now display land cover details such as forests and glaciers on the map. In addition, the new update includes a terminator layer that shows day and nighttime on the Naivgraph globe view and Mercator map. These new features are available to users with the Unlimited Subscription plan, which provides access to Navigraph Charts. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mssu15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Posts Development Update about Further Delay to Sim Update 15</title>
    <updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mssu15"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f5c512009038b7a042874_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has provided an update on the status of Sim Update 15 on their forum. The team has decided to postpone Sim Update 15 further due to some new issues. The release date of 7th May had to be delayed due to some issues with WASM. Unfortunately, the team has not yet shared a new release date for Sim Update 15. On a positive note, a new beta build, version 1.37.17.0, has been released for those enrolled in the beta program. This update includes several bug fixes for the beta program. We will keep you informed as soon as the team provides more information on Sim Update 15. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lva340</id>
    <title>LatinVFR Releases Airbus A340-300 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lva340"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f5dffe863734a7d952c13_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. LatinVFR recently released its version of the Airbus A340-300 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This four-engine airliner had its maiden flight in 1991 and has been used by many airlines since then. The aircraft has an impressive length of 208 ft 11 in (63 m). The A340-300 was introduced as the first of four variants of the A340 model. Along with the -300 variant, Airbus also developed the -200, -500, and -600 variants. With a total of four engines, the A340-300 has a range of 7.300 nautical miles (13.500 km). The -300 variant turned out to be one of the more popular variants, being used by many airlines such as Lufthansa, Emirates, and SAS. The new add-on offers a range of features, including a highly detailed external and interior model, a realistic cockpit, an EFB, VNAV implementation, realistic sounds, a variety of liveries, and much more. The add-on requires 11.17GB of storage space and is available on the in-sim Marketplace for approximately $29.49. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pesbod</id>
    <title>Pilot Experience Sim Releases Bordeaux-Mérignac Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pesbod"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66407a23a9e61deacd2d9eb1_bordeaux1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pilot Experience Sim has recently released the second version of their Bordeaux-Mérignac Airport (LFBD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the commune of Mérignac with a yearly average of 7.7 million passengers. It was built in 1910 to host a major Aviation Week event, making it one of the oldest French airports.  In the early 1930s, the French Air Force heavily upgraded the airport by constructing many new hangars, surface improvements, and more. A passenger terminal was built in 1935, officially going from an air station to an airport.  With World War 2 looming, the government invested more money in transforming Bordeaux into a proper military base, adding two runways, which were completed in 1939 and 1940, respectively. Mérignac’s brand-new runways were quite attractive to the Germans during their invasion of France. The structure was mostly new, and the runways were long and hard, ideal for their operations. They rushed to complete the work on runway two, and soon enough, it became one of their air bases. It was heavily bombed in 1944, and the German soldiers blew up the last remaining buildings before leaving the area.  Repairing was carried out right after the war, between 1945 and 1947. Prisoners of war built a terminal, a restaurant, offices, and a control tower. They were meant to be temporary and made of wood, but an actual replacement only happened twelve years later. In 1959, a new terminal was inaugurated, designed by Raymond Mothe. It was expanded several times, and its capacity maxed out at 2 million passengers annually. Further expansion occurred in the early 2000s, bringing its passenger handling capabilities to over 6 million a year. It’s a focus city for easyJet, Ryanair, and Volotea. Aer Lingus, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Turkish Airlines, and Vueling also serve it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimization, 3D people, custom aerial imagery, PBR texturing, custom static aircraft, and more. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.40, requiring at least 4.58 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2wpb</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases North Palm Beach Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2wpb"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66407f115972d4e91e7d4a11_beach1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of North Palm Beach County General Airport (F45) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving West Palm Beach, in Florida, with a yearly average of 100,000 aircraft operations. Opened in 1994, it’s the county’s newest airport. It sits right next to the town of Apix, a former rocket testing facility created as part of Project Suntan during the Space Race. Covering an area of 741 hectares, with a huge part of it dedicated to environmental preserves, it has two asphalt runways and a single turf runway. Both asphalt runways are the exact same length (1,311 meters) but have different widths (30 and 23 meters, respectively). The turf one is slightly shorter, at 1,121 meters. The traffic consists mainly of general aviation activities (93%), with the remaining 7% corresponding to air taxi operations. There are 264 aircraft based at the airport in total. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, PBR materials, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.77, requiring at least 22.22 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/axybcg</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Gold Coast Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/axybcg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6640963972d7a8203075fdc3_663bec1616443.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos have released their rendition of Gold Coast Airport (YBCG) for X-Plane 12, serving Gold Coast and Queensland, with a yearly average of 5,7 million passengers. ‍ Created in 1936, it was originally named Coolangatta (Aboriginal word for "Place of Good View"), consisted of three grass runways and served as an emergency airport for airmail aircraft flying between Brisbane and Sydney. With the first regular passenger service starting after WWII, it received service from Ansett Australia, Trans Australian Airlines and Butler Air Transport with DC-3s and DC-4s. In 1958, runways and taxiways got paved, allowing the usage of jet planes such as DC-9, and some bigger prop planes like L-188 Electra. Despite the name change in 1989, Gold Coast Airport still retains its original ICAO and IATA codes: YBCG/OOL.  The latest terminal expansion was completed in 2022 and includes more than 19 new parking stands, out of which 4 are equipped with jetbridges. Today, Gold Coast Airport serves 10 airlines flying to 26 different destinations in 3 countries, as well as two more seasonal destinations.  The Axonos YBCG features a highly accurate representation of YBCG with a new apron and taxiway, 3D grass, custom HDR night lighting, PBR and HD textures, color-corrected orthophotos and animated marshalls. ‍ This scenery is available for purchase at the OrbxDirect for roughly $19.89 and requires at least 2.32GB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsyam</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Yamagata Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsyam"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66409d15f59e34317076fd59_yama1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Yamagata Airport (RJSC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Yamagata in Japan and has a yearly average of 223,000 passengers. ‍ It was opened by the Imperial Japanese Navy in World War 2 and briefly used by the United States military after the war. Later, it was utilized by the Japanese Self-Defense Force as a training facility.  It was turned to civilian control in mid-1964 as a third-class regional airport. Eight years later, the runway was extended to 1,500 meters, leading to a reclassification to Class II in 1979. A new - and final - extension happened in 1981, followed by the construction of a new terminal building in 1984. International charter services started in 1981, taking full advantage of the newly expanded runway. Destinations included Finland, Hungary, New Zealand, and even Mexico. The airport's traffic peak was in 1991, followed by a rapid decline in 1992 due to the inauguration of the Yamagata Shinkansen. While the airport saw almost 500,000 passengers in 1991, the figures were down to 50,000 in 2002.  Fuji Dream Airlines (Nagoya, Sapporo), J-Air (Osaka), and Japan Airlines (Tokyo) currently serve it.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom ground-poly, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.86, requiring at least 29.20 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xtragu</id>
    <title>X-Trident Releases AW-109 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xtragu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6642fa918a03b5c1706d472d_agusta1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Trident recently released its rendition of the AgustaWestland AW109 for X-Plane 11 and 12. This multi-purpose helicopter is used in a variety of roles, both military and civil. Its development began in the late 1960s, with the first prototype making its maiden flight in 1971. The official FAA certification in 1975 followed, and it was officially introduced in 1976.  Originally designed and manufactured by Agusta as A109, it was the first all-Italian helicopter to be mass-produced. An eventual merger of Agusta and Westland Helicopters from Britain led to a rebranding as AW109. Powered by two Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PW206C engines, the AW109 can cruise at 285 km/h and has a maximum range of 932 km.  The add-on features an accurate rendition of the popular helicopter, with a high-quality 3D model, fully animated cockpit elements, a fully digital instrument panel, a functional circuit breaker panel, a custom FADEC with fully automated engine start sequence, realistic performance across all envelopes (tested by real-life pilots), and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍3D Model Instruments and controls Autopilot Flight model Liveries Documents Support for both XP12 and XP11 ‍ The AW109 is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $45.00, requiring at least 593 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwikri</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Kristiansund Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwikri"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6643bc3d01bd7a8f67a8b6a0_kri1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios recently released their rendition of Kristiansund Airport (ENKB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Kristiansund in Norway and has a yearly average of 314,000 passengers. The airport was inaugurated in mid-1970 after almost two years of construction, costing the government 31 million NOK. There was a competition to serve the new airport from the start: Both Braathens SAFE and Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) wanted the lucrative route to Oslo Airport, Fornebu. Both were granted the route on a temporary basis.  The construction and eventual inauguration of Molde airport in 1972—which kicked in right after Kristiansund Kvernberget's inauguration—led to a massive drop in traffic figures, given that it single-handedly cut half the region's catchment area. For comparison, Kristiansund averaged 88,246 passengers a year during its second year of operation, and it took another fourteen years to match that figure again after Molde Airport's inauguration. It underwent a massive overhaul in 2010, funded by Avinor, including a runway expansion, a larger car parking lot, and the construction of a larger terminal.  It's currently served by Braathens Regional Airlines, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, detailed landside recreation, custom elevation for the entire island, custom night lighting, an up-to-date airport layout, a custom GSX profile, and more. ‍ It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $13.74, requiring at least 1.90 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrx121</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.1.0’s First Public Beta </title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrx121"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6643d498922cd349104b90c0_xpl1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research recently released the first public beta of X-Plane 12's long-awaited 12.1.0 update. This update introduces improved anti-aliasing, new particle effects, lighting improvements, and more. With a strong focus on visual quality improvements, X-Plane 12.1.0's first public beta brings a glimpse into the heavy strides made into improving the anti-aliasing system, depth of field, shadows, lighting, particle effects, water, and autogen. Below is a list of the key takeaways from the visual improvements at hand:  Anti-aliasing (AA): Improved quality with better scene handling and coverage for alpha-tested surfaces (those with transparency). Depth of Field: More control with a setting for Real Camera Shake (RCAS) and a notification when textures are reduced due to memory limitations. Shadows: Smoother shadows overall, cloud shadows on water, and faster rendering times. Lightning: This version features more realistic visuals with subtle color adjustments, distance variations, and bolt thickness changes. Sound effects have also been improved for a more immersive experience. Particle Effects: The new system allows for particles on ground contact, easier editing with copy/paste, and datarefs for better control. Pre-built effects include jet engine afterburners (JATO), water bombing, ground scrapes, and rotor wash from helicopters. Aircraft configuration files (ACFs) let you disable these effects if desired. Water: Fixed water clarity issues, with color and transparency depending on location. Cloud shadows are now visible on water surfaces. Compatibility note: existing X-Plane 11 water scenery packs may not work perfectly due to differences in water rendering and might require updates from the creators. Autogen: Enhanced visuals for high-rise buildings in European cities and improved parking aircraft placement at airports, prioritizing larger planes for bigger spots. The update also enhances the G1000 navigation system, including an accurate startup splash screen, a NAV page, a stormscope, datalink weather support, Terrain, a WPT page, an AUX page, and new datarefs.  It also includes two additions to the supported flap systems, allowing the accurate simulation of manual flap controls such as the one in the Piper PA-28, with precise and gradual adjustments, and the dial-a-flap system, which is present in some McDonnell-Douglas aircraft. The complete feature list and changelog can be found here, along with further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/davdub</id>
    <title>Davor Puljevic Releases Dubrovnik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/davdub"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664655f565e14e530705cb9e_davor1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Davor Puljevic recently released their rendition of Dubrovnik Airport (LDDU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Dubrovnik-Neretva County and has a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers. The airport opened in 1962 and quickly became Yugoslavia’s busiest. By 1987, it had already served nearly a million passengers.  In the 2000s, a new passenger terminal was built to replace the original from 1962, costing the administration 70 million euros. It’s the most modern terminal in the country so far.  It’s a hub for Croatia Airlines and many other European carriers, including Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Volotea, Vueling, and Wizz Air, serve it on a seasonal basis. ‍‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom photo imagery, custom jetways, custom ground service equipment, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.65, requiring at least 443.95 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rot109</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-11 v1.09 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rot109"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66465ae49662f5f3767b306c_rotateupdate.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate has recently issued a new update to their MD-11 for X-Plane 12, adding Apple Silicon architecture support, pop-up displays, FMS improvements, and more. For pilots of all experience levels, the update offers improved functionalities, including pop-up windows for easier screen display management and additional options on the STAR page and FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator) for more precise flight planning and monitoring. The update also addresses a variety of user-reported issues. Improved VOR interception accuracy and tuned landing roll brakes ensure a more realistic and controlled flying experience. The update tackles numerous bugs related to flight controls, displays, navigation systems, and aircraft behavior. For virtual pilots seeking a more immersive experience, the update boasts improvements to LCDs' LED lighting and a reduction in dirt texture on the windshield, providing a clearer view of the virtual skies. ‍ The developers have also addressed compatibility issues with popular add-ons like A Pilot's Life, ensuring a smoother experience for users who have customized their flight simulator environment. ‍ The complete changelog with all the changes follows below: ‍ Please refer to their website for further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfs15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Posts Development Update with New Sim Update 15 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfs15"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f5c512009038b7a042874_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently shared a new development update including an updated development roadmap and further information about the latest news from the team. The updated roadmap has provided a new scheduled release date for the delayed Sim Update 15. The new release date is now set for May 23rd. Additionally, the Microsoft team has released a small update for all simmers, which includes updated navdata, AIRAC cycle 2405. This provides simmers with newer and more up-to-date navdata. We'll keep you informed as soon as Sim Update 15 is released or if we have any more news about it. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
