<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-10-22T18:37:24.297224+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a340101</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a340101"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f21a7d81b3fb734a9fc5cd_forty.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to the A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, bringing a vast list of fixes across systems, EFB, art, and sounds.  Update v1.0.1 is the first update so far since the aircraft’s release, and the main highlights are the fixes to VNAV wind logic, flight display alignment, and multiple FMS and ATC messaging improvements. Furthermore, display issues were resolved, details were refined on the externals, the cockpit now features dome lighting, the sound set was improved, and more. The complete changelog follows below: V1.0.1SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED Tailwind and Headwind components possibly being inverted in VNAV calculationsFIXED Crossfeed diagram incorrect displayFIXED EIS2 LS course in PFD separationFIXED EIS1 and EIS2: PFD ALT target incorrect position, too far rightFIXED EIS2 WXR modes in ND should be blue not greenFIXED Rudder trim indication is too dim vs xpndr/RMPFIXED EIS2: ELEC DC SD page BAT arrowsFIXED Missing FINAL APPR disengagement logic &lt;MDAFIXED IGS13 course auto-tuning as 136 and not 088FIXED DDRMI should only show decimals below 20nmFIXED All PRIMs and SECs OFF lead to uncontrollable out of trim flightFIXED AP off from FCU (or AP fail due other failure) CRC cant be cancelledFIXED Incorrect inop systems in STS on groundFIXED SEC F-PLN cannot insert OVFYFIXED DCDU send button should be on rightFIXED DCDU missing recall functionalityFIXED Incorrect MORA calculationsFIXED CPDLC message advisory notification revisedFIXED ATC MSG logic refinedFIXED XPNDR Mode "auto" coded for simconnect usageFIXED Pressing PRINT on the DCDU does not print any messagesFIXED Step alt vert ref addedFIXED Turnaround Logic revised for F-PlansFIXED Closest Airport page does not show airports beyond a set distanceFIXED STEP DELETED message logic revisedFIXED ATIS request logic revisedFIXED Lat rev page request revisionsFIXED ATC COMM request logic revisedFIXED ATSU request logic revisedFIXED SEC PLAN SID page missing "insert" promptFIXED No GPS PRIMARY message on NDFIXED NAV ACCUR DOWNGRAD message on MCDUFIXED NAV ACCUR UPGRAD Typo on NDFIXED EMER GEN at over 300% when GEN 1 2 3 4 are selected offFIXED SEC failures still not working as expected during ENG SHUTDOWN sequenceFIXED Over speed ECAMs all working with no ADRsFIXED Clipping of UPPER Display unitFIXED VOR range display on ND revisedFIXED DIR TO ABEAM function revisedFIXED Time marker insertion generates a PD pointFIXED OP DES level-off symbol prediction inaccurateFIXED RTE Reserve should become 0 when inflightFIXED Stuck in pauseFIXED WASM crash when inputting hold into SEC PLANADDED ETP ART 🎨FIXED SAS livery cargo door decal left behindFIXED Iberia livery crown not attached to rudderFIXED Iberia livery issues with decals near horizontal stabilizerFIXED Jettison VFX missingFIXED Pack outlet doors should swing outFIXED C&amp;D oxy maskFIXED Chocks sunk below groundADDED Simulated secondary DOME LIGHT switch on aft cockpit wall EFB💻FIXED Reconfigure GSX to prioritise L2FIXED EFB close all doors inc. refuel doorFIXED In-sim EFB checklists revisedFIXED boarding door priorityFIXED Time compression changed to buttonsFIXED Throttle calibration reverse on axis issueADDED No landing performance calculator SOUNDS🔊FIXED Missing APU pb ON&gt;OFF soundFIXED The Sunshades make no sound when movedFIXED Add speedbrake vibration/sound when using itFIXED Cruise wind sound level fixesFIXED 340 RA callout samples changedFIXED Cabin electrical hum mixing improvedFIXED Spoiler drag sounds/rattling improvedFIXED Toilet sounds in aft cabin fixFIXED BAT horn directionality fixFIXED APU push button no soundFIXED Touchdown sound intensity bumpedFIXED Sunshades volume adjusted in flightADDED Turbulence/banking sounds addedADDED Toilet flushing soundsADDED Event condition for GPS jam soundADDED Solution for system sounds disappearing on nodesADDED More cargo sounds The add-on is available exclusively in the MSFS Marketplace for $59.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mmshahn</id>
    <title>MM Simulations Releases Frankfurt-Hahn Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mmshahn"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f21d1492c693bb78593322_hahn1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MM Simulations has recently released their rendition of Frankfurt-Hahn Airport (EDFH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, the low-cost oriented gateway to the Rhineland. Hahn dates back to the early 1950s when it was founded by occupying French forces and taken over by the USAF a year later, where it initially hosted the 7356th Air Base Group, responsible for improving the facilities and getting it into an operational state. The USAF used the Hahn Air Base until the early 1990s, when it was handed over to Germany. The German government decided to transform the Air Base into a civil airport to alleviate the traffic at Frankfurt International Airport. Nowadays, the airport averages around 1.3 million passengers yearly, served by Ryanair or WizzAir, the two low-cost giants operating in Hahn. The Irish carrier offers seventeen fixed destinations (and fifteen seasonals), and the Hungarian sports eight destinations. As a curiosity, Frankfurt-Hahn recently filed for bankruptcy and was sold to a new investor in mid-2022, which ended up not transferring the funds. Now they have signed two preliminary contracts with two new potential buyers, one of them being no more, no less than the owner of the Nürburgring. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with handcrafted terrain elevation, updated satellite imagery, a detailed 3D terminal, an accurate ground layout, custom ground textures, and more. ‍ It’s available on Contrail for roughly $19.87, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/naveurts</id>
    <title>Navigraph Brings Real-World European Routes to SimBrief</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/naveurts"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f220de92c693bb785a8ec6_nav1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Navigraph’s SimBrief now features real-world European routes, which were hard to obtain in the past due to certain restrictions, which is why only North America used to feature real-world routes.  ‍ Navigraph has finally managed to get their hands on that data, though, so SimBrief now features high-quality routes straight into the planner, with the same level of accuracy as their NA data set. ‍ They demonstrated the new system by flying from Stansted, London, to Skiathos (Greece) on a Jet2 737-800. The image below shows that the route planner now displays a green label marked as “real world” next to the route string.  To ensure the routing is real, they ran it through Eurocontrol for validation, throwing no errors. The new data set is available to every SimBrief user, but non-Navigraph subscribers may encounter errors or discrepancies due to their out-of-date cycle. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsc25a</id>
    <title>FS Conference 2025 Date Confirmed</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsc25a"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f2613b2665f72ad6cf89a6_FS-Conference-02.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Aerosoft has confirmed the 20th FS Conference for Nov. 15  2025, at Paderborn–Lippstadt Airport, Germany. Expect a full day of talks, live demos, and community meet-ups, all with free admission! Developers, hardware makers, and online networks are set to attend, including Aerosoft, Honeycomb Aeronautical, IVAO, SayIntentions.AI, PILOT’S, and MobiFlight. Guided airport tours will run from the terminal to the apron, offering a behind-the-scenes look at ground ops and movements up close. These tours can be booked through this link. A paid MobiFlight workshop lets you build a take-home, multi-function device in 75–90 minutes. It starts at 1500 local (1400Z) and covers components, configuration, and MSFS assignments. You can fetch tickets here. The day wraps with the traditional Captain’s Dinner at the Airport-Forum from 1800 local (1700Z).  Threshold will also be in attendance, and we'll cover all the latest from the event. Stay tuned! For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/at346p</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Further Preview A340-600 Pro for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/at346p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f268109616642482fbc026_A340-600_13.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has shared a batch of A340 previews on their Discord, complete with a development brief from community manager Raphael.  Furthermore, the long-haul aircraft is now set to release ahead of Aerosoft’s A330 NEO, which was previously said to release in the Fall of 2025. The previews shared focus on cockpit and cabin progress, with Aerosoft stressing that these are still in an unfinished state, shared for transparency’s sake. Among the highlights is the team’s so-called “sleeping sidestick”, hopefully a bug to be fixed. Colours, wear, and detailing are still being tuned, but the core systems shown are functioning, according to Rafi. Expect more angles in upcoming Friday updates, including exterior modelling. A full showcase is expected closer to launch. For the full update, visit Aerosoft's Discord server. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/idfteft</id>
    <title>IndiaFoxtEcho Details Release of Eurofighter Typhoon for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/idfteft"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f279d78d5d3e162d75db10_560558151_1383010860495397_8443586208946758006_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. IndiaFoxtEcho has finally resurfaced with new details on its long-awaited Eurofighter Typhoon for Microsoft Flight Simulator, and this time, there’s a potential release window. In a new post, celebrating the studio’s 10th anniversary, the team confirmed they are now deep into debugging the Typhoon, and “hopefully” preparing it for release in November. The update comes after several months of radio silence, which the team addressed directly, apologising for the lack of news, while reassuring fans that progress has not stalled. According to IndiaFoxtEcho, the Eurofighter is currently being tested by a mix of internal staff and real-world Typhoon pilots. Alongside the Typhoon, IndiaFoxtEcho shared news on a few other projects. Their F-16A, developed in collaboration with Heatblur Simulations, is progressing steadily on the art side and is now targeted for a Q1 2026 release.  The TA-4J remains on hold until the Typhoon is wrapped, while DCS fans can look forward to ongoing work on the G.91 and a maintenance realignment for the MB.339. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/irsa24</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Svalbard Longyear Airport for MSFS24</title>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/irsa24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f2a81db94686308ced53b0_FlightSimulator2024_qrclJTs70K.png.76d989c52904082979ec1f0bc339d20e.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently released their newest scenery creation for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, this time heading to the arctic airport of Svalbard Longyearbyen (ENSB). Located at 78 degrees north of the equator, the airport is the northernmost with scheduled passenger service. The first airport on Svalbard was constructed during World War II by the Luftwaffe. After the war, it was taken over by the Norwegian Air Force, who started occasional postal flights. However, operations were tricky due to harsh conditions, and could only operate a few months out of the year. In the 1970s, it was decided that a new airport was needed, so a site was selected near Hotellneset, and construction began in 1973. Svalbard Airport was officially opened on September 2, 1975 with its first flight being operated by SAS. Over the years, the airport has undergone various renovations, with the most recent being an upgrade to the passenger terminal in 2007. Today, the airport serves as a vital link to mainland Norway, with flights to Oslo and Tromso being operated by both SAS and Norwegian. Additionally, there are charter flights to Moscow and Murmansk operated by Arktikugol, a Russian mining company, to serve the mining town of Barentsburg, which has a population primarily consisting of Russian nationals. iniBuilds’ rendition features high-quality textures, detailed building interiors and parallax, recreation of landside areas including the Svalbard Global Seed Vault, custom night lighting, custom static aircraft, and more. Svalbard Airport is available for purchase on the iniBuilds Store for approximately $13.35, requiring at least 2.29GB of disk space. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/spehse</id>
    <title>SimPixel Releases Breda International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/spehse"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f370f78ef000260bed60bc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. SimPixel has recently launched its version of Breda International Airport (EHSE) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. This general aviation aerodrome is located in North Brabant, Netherlands, and features a runway that is 2,723 feet long. Opened in 1949 as a glider field, the airfield was originally named Seppe Airfield. Powered aircraft began flying at the airport in 1969. In 2002, the original grass runway was replaced with an asphalt runway. The airfield does not accommodate aircraft with jet engines. In 2015, the airfield was rebranded from Seppe Airfield to Breda International Airport, following an announcement made in 2014. The ICAO code EHSE remained unchanged. In addition to general aviation traffic, the airfield is home to the Vliegend Museum Seppe, which showcases various aircraft on display. The aviation training company Aviation Performance Solutions is also located at the airfield. The scenery is rich with features like high-resolution textures, custom 3D models, dynamic lighting, detailed interiors, static aircraft, ground vehicles, and much more. The newly released Breda International Airport by SimPixel is now available from iniBuilds for approximately $9.39. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skar24</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases El Edén International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skar24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f3b5179c6322fd2a935041_01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. V Pilot Designs has recently released a rendition of El Edén International Airport (SKAR) for MSFS 2024, building on the new sim’s new lighting, materials, and terrain tech.  Set in Colombia’s coffee region near Armenia, Quindío, the package delivers a custom terminal and tower, accurate runway and taxiway layout, full PBR textures, realistic night lighting, and optimised models with LODs, for smooth performance. The MSFS 2024 edition is a free upgrade for existing MSFS 2020 owners, and it is available now on the in-sim Marketplace. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw771</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Updates PMDG 777 Sound Set for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw771"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f4fc54484fa9e7b6d14ec7_maxresdefault%20(3).jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Boris Audio Works has recently pushed V1.1.0 of his PMDG 777 Sound Set for MSFS 2020 and 2024.  Included is a complete rework of the GE90-94B buzz on the 777-200ER, improved PW4000 drop-spool behaviour, a fix for missing Rolls-Royce Trent engine idle, refined hydraulic and fan attenuation, a louder APU on the exterior, and added flap, slat, and slat-turbulence effects.  A PDF manual is now also included on the Orbx product page. Here’s the full changelog: ‍ Changelog:  ‍Added a PDF Manual - Refer to manual on product page via ORBX Direct or Central - PLEASE take a look at the recommended settings, try it with those, and adjust to your liking. There are quite a few settings that can totally wreck the sounds ‍ Boris' 777 Sound Set is available via Orbx Direct, retailing for $18.54. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vrspcl</id>
    <title>VeroRoutes Releases Pilot-Controlled Lighting for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vrspcl"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f506c41df07feba3065fac_c18f78213210f22cd7973d3b5c92c9d3c4cdba91.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. VeroRoutes has released their Pilot-Controlled Lighting addon for MSFS 2024, a first for the sim, letting you key the mic to control the runway lights.  You do this by tuning the published PCL frequency, clicking your push-to-talk three, five, or seven times within five seconds, and the lights will then spring on for 15 minutes, with low, medium, or high intensity. Coverage is broad, too. The add-on simulates pilot-activated lighting at roughly 4,500 airfields and heliports worldwide, with runway edge, centreline, threshold, and approach systems all modelled.  By default, the field stays dark, and the package can even be driven remotely via SimConnect. You can try it with a free trial, then pick it up from the VeroRoutes website for $23.20, as well as simMarket. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oby1tf</id>
    <title>OBY1 Releases EuroFly Twinfox for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oby1tf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f5129d02f41e1a95877ded_1146d4313cccea75d92c47d9359fb68e71832f3c.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. OBY1 has recently released the EuroFly Twinfox for MSFS 2020 and 2024, bringing one of Italy’s most distinctive ultralights into the simulator. Developed in close cooperation with Eurofly, and tested by real-world pilots, the Twinfox delivers an authentic, short-field flying experience. The cockpit environment has been carefully modelled, and it also includes authentic checklists. You can swap between a glass cockpit and steam gauges on the fly, and the aeroplane also supports VR out of the box.  Bundled with the release is a companion activity pack, too, giving plenty of things to do with the new plane. As always, here is a key feature list: ‍ Aircraft key features: You can get it on the MSFS Marketplace for both MSFS 2020 and 2024. For a handbook and more information on the aircraft, visit the official download page, on OBY1's website. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ldeyvi</id>
    <title>Lisium Design Releases Vilnius International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ldeyvi"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f682dcb49b25b0048ed07b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Lisium Design has launched its latest scenery package for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, featuring Vilnius International Airport, which serves the capital of Lithuania. The airport is located just under four miles from the city center and connects Vilnius to numerous destinations across Europe. Opened in 1932, the airport initially operated only a few commercial flights to various cities. This continued until the outbreak of the Second World War when the airport served as a military airfield until 1944. After the war, a new terminal was constructed, which was completed in 1954. To accommodate an increase in air traffic, a new departure terminal was built in 1993. Another terminal followed in 2007, and yet another was completed this year. Today, the airport is a hub for airBaltic and serves as a focus city for GetJet Airlines, Ryanair, and Wizzair, among others. The airport handles nearly 5 million passengers annually, connecting them to destinations all over Europe. The scenery comes packed with features such as a true-to-life terminal, true-to-life apron layout, detailed custom ground textures, custom lighting, and more. The newly released Vilnius International Airport by Lisium Design is now available on Contrail for $20.19. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/confa50</id>
    <title>Contrail Publishes FA50 Development Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/confa50"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f8b7c1b62b3ca0205fcf2f_fa50-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Contrail has recently shared the development progress on their upcoming FA50 for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showcasing their ongoing work on the cabin door, new flight deck textures, and much more. The cabin door is now fully complete, with authentic animations and interior detailing. Furthermore, Contrail has also completed the cockpit texture overhaul. It now features the rather distinctive rough-painted metal finish found in many real FA50s, significantly reducing glare and bringing it one notch closer to reality. Their work in the systems department is going well, thanks to feedback provided by real pilots and mechanics, who helped them capture the aircraft’s true essence, quirks and all. They have also provided a first look at the hydraulics system, demonstrating how the elevator drops to a full nose-down position when hydraulic pressure is lost, making the yoke move fully forward. In contrast, the ailerons only sag ever so slightly and remain that way even when pressure is wholly restored. Once the plane is airborne, of course, the airflow over the wings brings them to a neutral position—or slightly above center—as per real-life behavior. ‍ Contrail says, “more updates are on the way” as their product continues to take shape for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f282310</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s Fokker F28 Professional V2.2 Launches Tomorrow</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f282310"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/67d324a8883ddb907aea4d80_fuk3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight’s long-awaited full revamp and port to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 of their Fokker F28 is set to land soon—tomorrow—entirely free of charge for V1 owners and with a 20% discount for new buyers. While they prioritized making it Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 native—allowing it to launch on the Marketplace for the first time—they also took the opportunity to improve the 2020 version, adding unique cabin branding for all the included liveries, with period-authentic touches, featuring some of the “bold” design touches from the 1970s and 1980s. ‍ They will also include MSFS 2024’s pre-flight walkaround mode and a new EFB tablet model with a window-mount option. The complete 2.2 changelog will be made available at release time tomorrow. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfpa28x12</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases Piper PA-28-181 Archer III for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfpa28x12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68f8be44d4d77c506d11a7d8_archer31.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Just Flight and Thranda Design have recently released their rendition of the Piper PA-28-181 Archer III for X-Plane 12, following on from their Warrior II as part of their new general aviation aircraft lineup for Laminar Research’s latest simulator. The add-on features a highly accurate rendition of the Piper PA-28-181 Archer III, following comprehensive hands-on research on a real unit - G-CIFY - based at Turweston Airfield in the United Kingdom. It’s a four-seater piston-engine airplane with a four-cylinder 180-horsepower plant, a fixed tricycle landing gear, and a fixed-pitch propeller. It’s one of the most recent PA28 variants to be built, easily seen through its relatively modern and streamlined flight deck design, especially on the overhead. It cruises at 118 knots with a range of nearly 500 miles, making it perfect for touring and flight training. Furthermore, the cockpit features a rich avionics suite with a Garmin GNS 530 GPS unit, a GNC 255 radio, a S-TEC autopilot, HSI, and ADF instruments.  The add-on accompanies six liveries from the USA, Australia, Switzerland, Spain, Germany, and the United Kingdom. Thanks to the dynamic livery EFB app, a near-infinite variety of paint schemes can be created within the simulator. The aircraft sports full PBR texturing in 8K with real-time environment reflections. Additionally, there’s an Electronic Flight Bag tablet with many settings such as aircraft configuration options, panel states, interactive checklists, and more. It’s available on the Just Flight website for $42.99, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
