<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-07-22T18:20:21.368852+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsfpen</id>
    <title>FS Formosa Releases Penghu Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsfpen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b1a2b35bf98c52628b39d7_penghu1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="467067"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FS Formosa Project has recently released their rendition of Penghu Airport (RCQC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in Taiwan with a yearly average of 2.3 million passengers.  Built in 1957 as a military airport, Penghu got a proper passenger terminal only nine years later, mainly serving as an alternate airport to Kaohsiung Airport.   The airport was last upgraded in 2004, with a new - and larger - terminal building to deal with the increased demand for air travel in the region.   The authorities have been considering a new expansion project in the future, making the terminal larger and extending the runway to accommodate larger aircraft.  It's served by Daily Air, Mandarin Airlines, and Uni Air.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, PBR texture mapping, custom ground service equipment, custom night lighting, performance-friendly optimization, and custom landmarks in the city, including the Mudouyu Lighthouse, the Penghu Great Bridge, the Tongpanyu Geopark, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $20.02, requiring at least 1.01 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vpdyam</id>
    <title>V Pilot Designs Releases Yampa Valley Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vpdyam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b1a91ee818e2f26371929d_yampa1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="775999"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. V Pilot Designs has recently released their rendition of Yampa Valley Airport (KHDN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Steamboat Springs, Hayden, and Craig, with a yearly average of 160,000 passengers. The airport was built on a 435-acre parcel of land in Hayden, Colorado, acquired by the Rott County Board of Commissioners in 1946. It opened to the public in 1950, with a single grass runway and basic facilities. It was then called Rott County Airport. The runway was paved 14 years later, in 1964, allowing more aircraft to fly into the airport. Then, in 1996, the airport underwent a major transformation by constructing a new, state-of-the-art terminal that made Yampa Valley more efficient and passenger-friendly. It’s currently a gateway to the Yampa Valley Region and its world-renowned ski resorts, natural beauty, and parks. It recently underwent a two-stage expansion project, with an apron expansion adding a new parking position in 2018 and a terminal expansion in 2020 with a seventh gate to match the seven parking positions.  As a curiosity, the airport has no control tower, and pilots must coordinate their actions via CTAF or UNICOM. It’s served on a seasonal basis by Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, Delta Air Lines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, custom textures, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on the MSFS Marketplace for $14.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aermjs</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Publishes Statement on A330 Project’s Future</title>
    <updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aermjs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b1b094f0a862ac3cc37043_a330-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1880414"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Mathijs Kok’s surprise resignation earlier this month after 20 years of Aerosoft raised many questions regarding the future of the A330 Project, formerly managed by him. Yesterday, Aerosoft made a public statement on their forum with answers.  They claim to have seamlessly staffed the project with a new head and complimentary team members (Mathijs wasn’t the only one who left), and they announced a new landing page for the project, releasing next Friday and featuring information, media, and development updates.   There’s still no information regarding a potential release date or pricing, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tidcsn</id>
    <title>Threshold Introduces DCS News Coverage</title>
    <updated>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tidcsn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b326ad1bbfe06abceac86f_DCS.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="128760"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Hello everyone, In the many years we've shared this journey, you've known us at Threshold for our passion for flight simulation, our commitment to insightful reporting, and the joy we derive from staying on the cutting edge of simulation news. Our community has grown around the love for Microsoft Flight Simulator (MSFS) and X-Plane, and we are so grateful for your continued support and engagement. ‍ Today, we are thrilled to announce that we're opening a new chapter in our Threshold story. It's time to widen our horizons and delve into the dynamic world of the Digital Combat Simulator (DCS) World! ‍ We've heard from many of you about your interest in DCS World, a free-to-play digital battlefield game renowned for its authentic and intricate simulation of military aircraft, ground vehicles, and even geographical landscapes. You've shared your experiences, your insights, and your enthusiasm for this unique simulation platform. Now, we're excited to include this amazing world in our daily news coverage. ‍ It's important to note that our move into DCS World News doesn't mean we're leaving our roots behind. We will continue our in-depth coverage of MSFS and X-Plane while bringing the same fervour and attention to detail to the DCS World. ‍ Our journey into the world of DCS will bring us closer to virtual pilots from all areas of flight simulation. We are ready to embrace this challenge and provide you with the latest, most comprehensive, and engaging news about DCS World. We can't wait to explore this new arena, and we're excited to bring you along on this adventure. ‍ Thank you for being part of our community, for sharing in our love for flight simulation, and for joining us on this exciting new journey into DCS World. Let's soar to new heights together! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/abltdw</id>
    <title>AviaStorm: Breathing Life into the Tornado in DCS World</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/abltdw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b3fb5ff1342e5b1458d2cc_Kopie_von_Tornado_model_reveal01.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2488835"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. The team at AviaStorm has chosen to simulate the IDS (Interdiction/Strike) version of the Tornado as seen in service with the German Air Force (GAF). This variant was in service up until the early 2000s and comes armed with a substantial range of unguided weapons including the MK-80 series and European weapons such as the Matra 250ED. In addition, AviaStorm is also introducing several new weapons to DCS, including the Komoran anti-ship missile and MW1 cluster munition dispenser. In a nod to the varied roles the Tornado played in real-life, the team is incorporating a reconnaissance pod into the model. This inclusion promises to add another layer to DCS mission planning, especially for virtual squadrons. Despite their focus on the IDS variant, AviaStorm is also committed to including liveries of every user nation at the module's initial release, namely GAF, RAF, IAF, and RSAF. However, they've hinted that RAF exclusive weapons are not planned for the initial release. As for future versions of the Tornado, AviaStorm has kept plans close to their chest, only hinting that anything is possible. One thing is certain: an AI backseater akin to Jester is in the pipeline. As the role of the backseater is more challenging than that of the pilot, the team is deliberating the most efficient way to implement this feature. On the topic of radar technology, AviaStorm is also exploring available options. They will either adopt suitable existing technologies or, if necessary, build a new radar system from scratch. In their pursuit of accuracy, AviaStorm is using multiple reference aircraft for their simulation. The primary aircraft being scanned is the 44+56 Tornado, now adorned in a commemorative scheme "Bunte Kuh" (Colorful Cow) to honor the Tornado's service with JaboG-34. This plane is currently on display at the Traditionsgemeinschaft JaboG 34 Allgäu. In addition, the team is also using the IDS/RECCE Tornado 44+97, which is on display at the Flugwerft Schleißheim near Munich, Germany. This aircraft went into service in 1985 and retired after reaching the 4000 flight hour limit in 2008, with its last two years spent as part of the ISAF troops supporting operations in Afghanistan. The Following chart displays the weapon chart which depicts what AviaStorm are planning to bring to this magnificent jet. This is all subject to change however this is already an extensive list and is sure to keep users satisfied with plenty of options. AviaStorm refrains from setting a specific timeline for the release of the Tornado IDS. Their commitment is to quality over speed, striving to create the highest level of Tornado simulation possible. While this approach may mean a longer wait for fans, the team is confident that the eventual release will provide an unmatched virtual flight experience, worth every second of the wait. ‍ Threshold now covers all DCS World related news. ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sqanad</id>
    <title>Squawk Ident Releases Hang Nadim International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sqanad" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b401c43cc89d698b9fa60a_nadim1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1410690"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Squawk Ident has recently released their rendition of Hang Nadim International Airport (WIDD), serving the city of Batam, Indonesia, with a yearly average of 6.5 million passengers.  Officially opened in 1965 as Batam Island International Airport, it was later renamed Hang Nadim International Airport after Laksamana Hang Nadim Pahlawan Kechik, a legendary warrior from the Batam region.   The airport was very important to the industrial growth of Batam, which was designated as a free trade zone in 1971. Its proximity to Singapore made it a gateway for foreign investments and trading.  A new passenger terminal was built in 2002, increasing its passenger handling capabilities and focusing heavily on attracting more international flights and promoting regional tourism.  Five years later, the airport underwent a major upgrade program, with the construction of a new runway, taxiways, aprons, and the extension of the passenger terminal. The new infrastructure attracted airlines from various countries, becoming a low-cost alternative to Singapore Changi.  It has the longest runway in Indonesia at 4,028 meters, making it the perfect diversion airport for Singapore Changi, easily accommodating Boeing 777s, 747s, Airbus A380s, etc.  Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Citilink, Garuda Indonesia, Jeju Air, Lion Air, Nam Air, Saudia, Super Air Jet, Susi Air, and Wings Air serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, cargo hangars, a basic terminal interior, an up-to-date ground layout, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.21, requiring at least 165.27 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/peddev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes MSFS Development Update </title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/peddev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b4279b4c1fbeea9727d61b_pmdg1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1880921"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published the second development update of this month, with information on future 737 updates, console liveries, new marketplace arrivals, UFT, 777, and more.  Randazzo begins with information on the 737 Lineup updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which have been sent to the beta team, including changes to prepare the aircraft for the Universal Flight Tablet.   The Xbox liveries for the 737 are going through marketplace intake and should be made available soon. They are still exploring manners to minimize user costs for liveries.  They have also begun pushing the 737-600 and 737-900 to the Marketplace along with their liveries, with their prediction pointing to an end of July release.  The Universal Flight Tablet is being moved into its final leg of testing. It has been tested on a single airframe so far (the 737-700) to minimize developmental hassles. No previews are available yet.  The 777 has progressed significantly since FSExpo, with PMDG looking into previewing it soon.   They finish with a quick note on the DC-6, which should be getting an update in August.  Their product lineup for MSFS is available on their website and in the Marketplace, although only partially. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2acom</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Releases Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2acom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b6746774c1b65fbb19f3d3_comanche1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="240459"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently released their first airplane for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the Accu-Sim Comanche, based on a real Piper Comanche 250 they have owned and operated for a decade. The first of the Comanches, the PA-24, had its prototype built in 1956, sporting a semi-monocoque construction with retractable landing gear and powered by a 180 hp Lycoming engine. Production started a year later and continued until 1972, ended by a flood that compromised the entire production line beyond recovery. The Comanche 250, the one A2A simulates, came two years after the 180hp variant, with a 250 hp engine (hence the 250). Early models had manually operated flaps and up to 230L of fuel. At the same time, future units (post-1961) could carry up to 340L total on auxiliary tanks, and electrically actuated flaps were made standard in 1962.  A2A’s rendition is their first AccuSim 2.0 product, which is a culmination of years of experience with aircraft simulation, featuring a brand new aerodynamics system that accurately models how an airplane flies through the air. The aircraft features the aforementioned aerodynamics system, accurate engine performance based on their own Comanche 250, realistic handling characteristics and trim behavior, a physics-based per-cylinder simulation of the engine, dynamic ground physics, an advanced turbulence system, airframe vibration physics, authentic fuel simulation, a custom oil system with dynamic viscosity, advanced engine starter simulation, a physics-driven sound environment, a detailed JPI EDM 830 engine monitor, custom-coded Narco avionics, further integration options for third-party GPSs, and much more. The complete feature list follows down below: It’s available at the A2A Simulations Store for $49.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfspes</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Abruzzo Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfspes" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b69deadd74108f59130ab7_pesc1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3164741"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Abruzzo Airport (LIBP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Pescara, Italy, with a yearly average of 700,000 passengers.  It was built in 1917 by the Regio Esercito (Royal Italian Army), initially with their fleet of two Farman 14s. A year later, it hosted the 302° Squadron and their Ansaldo SVA Biplanes, among the best fighter bombers of the time.  After World War I, it was renamed Pasquale Liberi after a local aviator. Then, in 1927 it was expanded to 50 hectares and modernized.  With the advent of commercial aviation in the 1930s, Abruzzo was served by Società Area Mediterranea (SAM) with a tri-weekly service from Pescara to Rome Urbe Airport with a single stop.  World War 2 stopped commercial aviation in Pescara, which only resumed two years after the war with Transadriatica and their Douglas DC-3s. Avio Linee Italiane soon joined with a route between Milan to Brindisi, with stops in Pescara, Foggia, and Bari. ‍ Most commercial operations were suspended in 1979 after a revision of the minimum landing requirements by the ANPAC, a national association of civil aviation pilots. Pescara did not have the required ILS instruments, which made airlines like Itavia shy away from operating at the airport.   Things only improved in the early 1980s, after the arrival of Aermediterranea, a little airline controlled by Alitalia, and eventually Aero Transporti Italiani in 1984, also controlled by Alitalia.   The current terminal was opened in 1996, and the old building was reutilized for logistical and technical support. That terminal underwent multiple improvements between 2008 and 2018, including its expansion, modernization, and renovation, costing 33 million euros.  It’s currently served by ITA Airways (Milano Linate), Luxair (Luxembourg), Ryanair (Bergamo, Bucharest–Otopeni, Catania, Charleroi, London–Stansted, Turin), and Wizz Air (Tirana).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom ground service equipment, custom night lighting, realistic windows, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.28, requiring at least 72.82 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simper</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Presidente Perón International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simper" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b6d9658d7f99ba614b6264_peron1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2261705"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Presidente Perón International Airport (SAZN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Neuquén, Cipolletti, Plottier, Centenario, and General Roca, in Argentina, with a yearly average of 800,000 passengers.  The airport was built in 1936 as Aero Club Neuquén, with a single gravel runway. Its paving and modernization only happened in 1951, when Argentina planned to pioneer air transport in Latin America.   Eight years later, the surrounding terrain was expropriated so they could build an International Airport with a longer runway, a proper passenger terminal, and proper general infrastructure.  The airport was renovated in 2013 and expanded in 2019, with the construction of a domestic and international pre-boarding area, with 1500 square meters for the first one and 630 for the latter. They have also built a new security area, two commercial lots with 80 square meters each, bathrooms totaling up to 140 square meters, and 18 check-in gates.  Aerolíneas Argentinas, Flybondi, JetSmart Argentina, American Jet, LADE, and Latam Argentina currently serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom jetways, custom ground textures, 4K PBR textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.60, requiring at least 957.13 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gds14b</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Announces 14-bis for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gds14b" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b83fb291aa874b929a8135_14bis2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="171603"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations, in partnership with RPSimulations and a popular aviation channel from Brazil (Aviões &amp; Músicas), has recently announced the development of a 14-bis for Microsoft Flight Simulator, first flown in 1906 and known (although not worldwide) as the world’s first airplane.  Inspired by Gabriel Voisin’s glider, Santos Dumont’s 14-bis was made of a Hargrave-cell and powered by a 50 horsepower fuel-injected V8 engine, making it able to fly for a few hundred meters at a time at an impressive (by the early 1900s standards) 40 km/h. It won the second prize in November 1096 at the Chateau de Bagatelle after flying for 220 meters, earning Santos Dumont a monument at the place, which is still up to this day. There’s no information about features, pricing, or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shapen</id>
    <title>SHADESCENE Releases Penang International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shapen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b84b81f8dd6ff40ba6521f_pen1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1145312"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SHADESCENE has recently released their rendition of Penang International Airport (WMKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 7.23 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1935 as Bayan Lepas International Airport when Penang was still a British colony.  It was heavily expanded in the 1970s, with a new terminal and a longer runway to accommodate the Boeing 747.   The administration has recently announced a 4-phase expansion plan, which started in 2020 and should reach completion by 2024, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It’s currently served by AirAsia, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Citilink, Firefly, Firefly, Indonesia AirAsia, Jetstar Asia, Lion Air, Malaysia Airlines, MYAirline, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, Starlux Airlines, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Smile.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom-modeled terminal, custom terraforming, custom jetways, high-resolution textures, custom objects, a terminal interior, custom night lighting, custom ground markings, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.49, requiring at least 370.23 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfspen</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Penang International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfspen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b84d8eb22bd91c913d0f6e_penang1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="704153"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Penang International Airport (WMKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 7.23 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1935 as Bayan Lepas International Airport when Penang was still a British colony.  It was heavily expanded in the 1970s, with a new terminal and a longer runway to accommodate the Boeing 747.   The administration has recently announced a 4-phase expansion plan, which started in 2020 and should reach completion by 2024, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It’s currently served by AirAsia, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Citilink, Firefly, Firefly, Indonesia AirAsia, Jetstar Asia, Lion Air, Malaysia Airlines, MYAirline, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, Starlux Airlines, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Smile.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an updated ground layout (2023), custom ground textures, custom jetways, and AI traffic compatibility.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.19, requiring at least 38.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Owners of the FS2004/FSX/P3D version get the scenery free of charge. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sxaarr</id>
    <title>SXAirportDesign Releases Antonio Rivera Rodríguez Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sxaarr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b85a367e7bab97314d77b0_rivera1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3248140"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SXAirportDesign has recently released their rendition of Antonio Rivera Rodríguez Airport (TJVQ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Vieques in Puerto Rico with a yearly average of 100,000 passengers.  It was built by the United States Navy in the mid-20th century as a small airstrip to support their military operations, only becoming a proper passenger airport after the army ceased training operations on the island in 2001.   It was renamed Antonio Rivera Rodriguez Airport in 2004 after a prominent Puerto Rican politician and former Mayor of Vieques.   There were plans to extend the runway in 2005 so smaller jets could fly into the airport, but it didn’t work out. The current length (1,311 meters) only comports small regional aircraft.  Air Sunshine, Cape Air, M&amp;N Aviation, Silver Airways, and Vieques Air Link serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-resolution aerial imagery, custom PBR ground polygons, custom night lighting, and custom 3D vegetation.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.25, requiring at least 257.67 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdssdm</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Releases 14-bis for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdssdm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b9aee76558999ded1a81ab_14bis.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="30986"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations, in partnership with RPSimulations and a popular aviation channel from Brazil (Aviões &amp; Músicas), has recently released a 14-bis for Microsoft Flight Simulator, first flown in 1906 and known (although not worldwide) as the world’s first airplane.  Inspired by Gabriel Voisin’s glider, Santos Dumont’s 14-bis was made of a Hargrave-cell and powered by a 50 horsepower fuel-injected V8 engine, making it able to fly for a few hundred meters at a time at an impressive (by the early 1900s standards) 40 km/h.  It won the second prize in November 1906 at the Chateau de Bagatelle after flying for 220 meters, earning Santos Dumont a monument at the place, which is still up to this day.  The add-on accurately simulates the aircraft’s performance and flight dynamics based on its original documents.   It’s available on the GearDown Simulations Store for roughly $2.51 (limited-time offer). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asf330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases A330 Project's Website</title>
    <updated>2023-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asf330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bab87e06f5355d8ded615d_as1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="903327"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft released the A330 Project's website following their statement post Mathijs Kok's resignation a week ago. The new portal will update customers on the development progress, screenshots, upcoming features, and frequently asked questions.  Along with the brand new website, they have also published an update on the project's current status, covering their extensive effort in rebuilding the 3D model for Microsoft Flight Simulator and rewriting some of the systems.  Furthermore, they have mentioned it can now fly from A to B safely, with most systems working decently but with odd behavior still happening during testing because the flight management system and the autopilot were coded from scratch. Aerosoft has made a list with a few examples:   They are currently working on the soundscape, cockpit usability, and documentation.  There's yet to be any information on the release date or pricing, but Threshold will keep you informed!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
