<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-03-20T18:21:26.072435+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inu211</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A300-600 and BelugaST for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inu211"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65eb8deb5a3e794e89ad96d6_beluga1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. iniBuilds has recently updated their X-Plane 12 fleet (Airbus A300-600R and BelugaST) with a comprehensive list of fixes, improvements, and flight model tweaks. The updates (v2.1.1 on the A300 and v1.1.4 on the BelugaST) address the nose landing gear light not working, flight model improvements, engine fixes, system freeze mitigations, and more. Both changelogs follow below: ‍  The A300 and the BelugaST are available on the iniBuilds Store for $67.49 and $43.38 (on sale), respectively. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdbem</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Previews Bembridge Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdbem"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ee3dbd7cba641bd527d014_bem1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Burning Blue Design has recently previewed their work on Bembridge Airport (EGHJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, an unlicensed aerodrome in Bembridge, Isle of Wight, England.  It opened in 1920 on land owned by Bembridge Farm, becoming a licensed aerodrome one year later.  Airline services started in 1934 with Spartan Airlines, and other airlines followed suit, such as Portsmouth Southsea, Isle of Wight Aviation, and Channel Air Ferries). It ended abruptly shortly after the start of World War 2, as the airport was closed and ditches obstructed the runway to make it unusable. It reopened as soon as the war ended, but airline services never resumed. It continued as a general aviation airfield and eventually became a manufacturing ground for Britten Norman in the 60s, where they built many Islanders and Trislanders. They are still in production today, with over 1200 produced so far. ‍ One of Britten Norman's subsidiaries, Aero Composites Ltd, began assembling Cirrus aircraft (SR20 and SR22s) in 2005. ‍ There’s no information on pricing or a release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx392</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates Fenix A320 V2B2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx392"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ef3af763ddd86bf65881ee_1250410_20240307064307_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently issued a new update to their Airbus A320 V2 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing adjustments and fixing issues found by the community during the week and a half it’s been out.  ‍ Update V2.0.0.392 is the first update since the release of Block 2 V2 in late February, and it addresses issues with high CPU usage, autopilot engagement, performance in exterior view, the RETARD callout bug, and more. The complete changelog follows below: ‍ The update is available to all customers on the Fenix Dashboard.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmxhsi</id>
    <title>Project MAX Releases Husein Sastranegara International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmxhsi"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65ef477cb350984538ed9c6f_husen1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Project MAX has recently released their rendition of Husein Sastranegara International Airport (WICC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Bandung in Indonesia, with a yearly average of 4.3 million passengers. It was built during the Dutch colonial period and was a low-traffic airport for many decades, with less than 30 flights a day. The situation changed in the 2010s, leading to a surge that its infrastructure was not quite ready for, as the old terminal could only handle up to 750,000 passengers yearly. It eventually led to the construction of a new terminal. ‍ It’s being gradually replaced by Kertajati International Airport, the second largest airport by area in the country, inaugurated in 2018. It has been getting most of the domestic traffic that once landed in Sastranegara. The airport has already been partially retired as of late 2023, with turboprop flights from Susi Air being the sole exception.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, PBR textures, a 3D detailed full interior, custom ground poly, detailed landside, and more. ‍ It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $9.63, requiring at least 3.38 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/siahat</id>
    <title>SiamFlight Releases Hat Yai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/siahat"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f272f73cbb5a6a8d5bc49d_hat1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SiamFlight has recently released their rendition of Hat Yai International Airport (VTSS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It serves Hat Yai in Thailand, with a yearly average of 3.1 million passengers, making it the 5th busiest airport in the country. It has a single terminal building that handles both domestic and international flights. It is well-equipped with facilities and services for travelers, including restaurants, shops, currency exchange counters, and car rental services. For Thai Muslims, it’s the gateway to Mecca, Saudi Arabia, and is responsible for a significant portion of its traffic figures. It’s an operation base for Thai AirAsia and is served by Bangkok Airways, flyadeal, Nok Air, Scoot, Thai Airways International, Thai Lion Air, and Thai VietJet Air. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal (with its respective interior), landside buildings, custom animated jetways, custom ground textures, hand-placed signage, custom night lighting, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.12, requiring at least 90.57 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mks110</id>
    <title>MK Studios Updates Barcelona Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mks110"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65e3a79e20bf83fad30d0730_bcn7.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has issued another update to their rendition of Josep Tarradellas Barcelona - El Prat Airport (LEBL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, fixing the terminal model, parking positions, airline codes on AFCAD, and more. ‍ Update 1.1.0, the third since its release in early March, brings more changes based on user feedback, with fixes ranging from the terminal to the photogrammetry. The complete changelog follows below: MK’s Barcelona can be yours for roughly $14.55 (on sale) on OrbxDirect, requiring at least 2.37 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dd1dca</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Releases Washington Airport and City for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dd1dca"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f4cc4e5f7f023ceeb5a9f0_dca1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Drzewiecki Design has recently released an updated version of Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport (KDCA) and the city with its landmarks for X-Plane 12. It’s the busiest airport in the region, with a yearly average of 25 million passengers and 310,000 aircraft operations. It opened in 1941 as Washington National Airport, replacing Washington-Hoover Airport as Washington’s main airport.  The original terminal was expanded in 1950, and a new terminal was built in 1958 to supplement the first. Both were connected in 1961. The terminals were majorly expanded in 1997, with the construction of terminals B and C and a new control tower. The layout has been the same since. It’s a hub for American Airlines. Air Canada Express, Alaska Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express also serve it. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport and its surroundings, with custom ground textures, PBR, custom night lighting, animated jetways, VDGS, a thousand landmark buildings surrounding the airport, and orthophoto coverage. It is optimized for performance. It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for roughly $25.00 (on sale), requiring at least 1.5 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777315</id>
    <title>Flight Factor Teases Boeing 777 V2 </title>
    <updated>2024-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777315"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f4d5875d0491e2030f90cb_t71.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Factor has recently shared new screenshots of their upcoming Boeing 777 V2 while also stating that they have already addressed the aircraft’s nose, but the images are from an older version. The 777 V2 will bring an entirely rebuilt rendition of their popular add-on, with an improved 3D model, textures, flight model, systems, sounds, and more. It was first introduced in the mid-90s with United Airlines. It was designed to bridge the gap between the 767 and the 747 and offer a viable replacement to trijets, which were starting to become a problem to many airlines due to their high fuel burn and ever-increasing fuel costs. It’s known for its reliability, efficiency, comfort, and technology, with a full fly-by-wire system. There’s no information on the release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fw24d1</id>
    <title>FSWeekend 2024 Day 1 Roundup</title>
    <updated>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fw24d1"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f64ff63e40df7c5a86fb64_IMG20240315142351.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Today has been an exciting day in the world of flight simulation! We’re one day into the amazing event that is FSWeekend in Lelystad, The Netherlands, and we’ve prepared a roundup of all the day’s news if you didn’t catch it yesterday.  ‍ Today’s event was kicked off by Magnus Axholt, CEO of Navigraph, and his announcements on some new features coming to their Charts software, chiefly among them being able to now annotate charts, as well as Operational Flight Plans from SimBrief. Along with being able to highlight taxi routes, users are also able to create boxes around important items such as minimum speed restrictions. Along with changes to Navigraph Charts, Axholt mentioned a new project dubbed “Navigraph Academy” set to debut this fall. According to him, the project “basically stems from the fact that you guys have been missing an instruction manual."  Moving on to the next announcements, which came from Thompson on the X-Plane team, discussing all that is to come with the upcoming X-Plane 12.1.0. First, he went over how graphics will be improved in the update, with fixes to CPU performance, clouds, and highly requested fixes for the Multi-Sample Anti-Aliasing (MSAA) in the sim. Along with those, there are new particle effects, improving immersion in-sim. Thompson went on to describe improvements for the weather system, including a brand new real weather server, as well as improvements to METAR parsing, and fixes for odd weather data. Phillip from the team discussed improvements to avionics, including the G1000, STEC S-360 Autopilot, and new ice/de-ice visual effects. Also discussed during the presentation was additions for Pro users of X-Plane.  After X-Plane came a video showcase from the team at FlyByWire, which featured their highly anticipated A380X, and showed progress on visuals, systems, sounds, and even a fully modeled cabin. You can watch the showcase video on YouTube here and see the amazing work they’ve done! Next up was Mobiflight, hosted by creator Sebastian (who I had the pleasure meeting at FSExpo ‘23). The main emphasis during their presentation was the power that the flight simulation community has, and how amazing it can be through the power of open source software. Mobiflight also announced that they are getting a new UI and frontend framework, which will include lots of design improvements as well as a dark mode. Last, but certainly not least was a lesser known company amongst the mainstream flight sim community, ProSim. ProSim is mainly known for their aircraft software that can be used to integrate into home built full flight simulators, and is very popular in that market, but has recently gained traction due to the fact that the Fenix A320 was based off of ProSim’s A320. They are also known for their commercial solutions through their fixed base trainers. In their presentation, ProSim renewed their focus on home cockpit building, by launching a new brand, called HomeSim. They have split their consumer business and commercial business, where the consumer side is now HomeSim, and the commercial side is still ProSim. They have a substantial development roadmap for home users, and have rededicated themselves to home simulation. And with that closes a very packed day at Europe’s largest flight simulation convention! But, there’s still another day, so stay tuned to Threshold for the roundup for Day 2, and a sneak peak behind the scenes on what goes on at FSWeekend!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fb380x</id>
    <title>FlyByWire Publishes A380X Sneak Peek </title>
    <updated>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fb380x"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f6bbf5c0ee6cc1b14a2d6c_9.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyByWire has recently shared a video of their upcoming Airbus A380 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, demonstrating a full flight - albeit with cuts and acceleration - from Toulouse to Munich. ‍ The 10-minute video is their most revealing A380 footage yet, and it shows a bit of the cockpit modeling, aircraft system power-up from cold and dark, engine startup, take-off sounds, and more: ‍ The developers emphasize it's still in development, and the video does not represent the final stage of the product. Designed to challenge Boeing's monopoly in the large aircraft market, the A380 is a double-deck, wide-body, four-engine jet airliner manufactured by Airbus. It is the world's largest passenger airliner, seating up to 853 passengers in a single-class configuration or 525 passengers in a typical three-class configuration. There's no information on the release date yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmd773</id>
    <title>PMDG Teases Upcoming Boeing 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmd773"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f6debf45a267f4b4325a97_6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently broken the silence about which variant is releasing first, along with a full-blown 45-minute live stream answering many questions regarding upcoming features, potential limitations, and more. ‍ There was a lot of mystery surrounding the first 777 variant to release, with a considerable part of the community supposing it would be the 777-200ER for the longest time. It had not been revealed when PMDG shared the first images a few months ago, but Robert Randazzo finally broke the silence during the live stream, revealing it would be the 777-300ER to release first. With the variant out of the way, many people also wanted to know about the presence of RF legs and CPDLC, to which Randazzo responded with a “maybe” for the former, and the latter will initially see a basic implementation with Hoppie, which will then get updated in the future with an in-house solution, as Hoppie is said to “not be a realistic representation of how it works in real life,” according to Robert.  While they still don’t have an exact date for the release, Robert expects it to come out within two months if things go according to plan, and it just might have a basic weather radar - albeit sim limited - included, unlike their 737 Lineup.  PMDG has also uploaded a 2-minute showcase video of the upcoming product, with shots of the interior, exterior, and passenger cabin, emphasizing their modern modeling techniques.  There’s no release date or pricing yet, but Threshold will keep you informed on the matter! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fw242r</id>
    <title>FSWeekend 2024 Day 2 Roundup</title>
    <updated>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fw242r"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f763c683db81aefe3e38ca_DSC00657.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. It was another exciting day packed with amazing things at FSWeekend in Lelystad, Netherlands! Today’s presentations were announcements, panels, and we’ve prepared a roundup of all the news on the final day of FSWeekend 2024.The first presentation was from Papa Hotel, who showcased his rendition of Lelystad Airport, which is the location of FSWeekend, in Microsoft Flight Simulator! In the presentation, he confirmed features such as custom 3D objects, custom orthophotos, interior modeling for the terminal, and more! He also said that he is committed to upgrading the airport with new features in the future. After the panel by FSElite, which included names such as Andreas from cruiselevel.de, Jamie, more commonly known as LondonController, Jordan from FSElite, and Threshold’s own Magnus Lorvik, there was a presentation by Mike from FlightSimCoach. Mike discussed aspects of FlightSimCoach, which is a service that helps flight simmers get a more in-depth introduction into flight simming, as well as offers one-on-one instruction with an instructor that can help with anything and is bespoke to a simmer’s needs. Keeping on ahead there was a presentation by ToLiss, being a retrospective on the past decade of ToLiss products. He went into more depth on the ToLiss history, and highlights of the products they’ve released. Also in their presentation was a hint at what aircraft they were working on next, but unfortunately, the only thing that was mentioned was that it was going to be another Airbus aircraft. And with that concludes FSWeekend 2024, and all the exciting announcements and showcases that happened today! Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold, because we have some exciting behind-the-scenes content at FSWeekend we’re excited to share, and we’re so excited on what amazing things will happen at next year’s FSWeekend!</summary>
    <published>2024-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/skyda5</id>
    <title>Skyward Simulations Announces DA-50RG for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/skyda5"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f8b4a45f891004adaaa17d_da501.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Skyward Simulations has recently announced the development and imminent release of their first add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the DA-50RG, a five-seat, single-engine airplane. Designed and built by Diamond Aircraft Industries, it was first shown in 2006, albeit unofficially, and test flown for the first time a year later in Austria, followed by its first public appearance in Germany during the AERO Friedrichshafen show. The crisis of 2008 led to the project being put on hold for many years, which explains why it was only certified recently. Powered by a Continental CD-300 Turbocharged engine producing 300 horsepower, the DA-50 RG has a range of 1,389km, with a cruise speed of 319 km/h, and a service ceiling of 20,000ft. The upcoming add-on will feature an accurate 3D model, true-to-life high-definition textures, custom-coded systems, an accurate flight model, Working Title G1000 NXi integration, custom liveries, and sounds by Boris Audio Works. There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! The developers welcome everyone to join their Discord for further info.</summary>
    <published>2024-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdsbcg</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Releases Campo Grande International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdsbcg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f9202abdac1d7ab43f00fa_cgr1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently released their rendition of Campo Grande International Airport (SBCG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Campo Grande, Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil, with a yearly average of 1.5 million passengers. The airport started as a single concrete runway in 1953, and the passenger terminal was built a decade later, which counts as its official inauguration. Three years later, in 1967, an apron (military and civilian) was built. Twelve years after its inauguration, the apron had to be expanded to keep up with the traffic boom of the 1970s. That is also when INFRAERO first took charge of the airport, investing heavily in expansion work and overall infrastructure improvements.  In the 1980s, the terminal was first expanded from 1,500 square meters to 5,000.  In 1998, the passenger terminal got its first international section, increasing its area from 5,000 square meters to 6,082.  It was expanded again very recently, with 7,215 square meters, a new external look, and under a new concession: AENA won the rights to manage the airport for the next 30 years in 2022. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, landside buildings, PBR textures, custom night lighting, and more. ‍ It’s available on the GearDown Store for roughly $10. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwirfd</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Chicago Rockford International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwirfd"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f92b2ee48cc229e4406e51_rfd1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios has recently released their rendition of Chicago Rockford International Airport (KRFD) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Rockford and the Chicago metropolitan area with a yearly average of 102,000 passengers. The airport was originally part of a US Army facility called Camp Grant. It was established in 1917 and functioned until 1946, when it was transferred to the Greater Rockford Airport Authority, marking its official inauguration as a civilian airport. Terminal construction work started eight years after the transfer, in 1954. The current passenger terminal was built in 1987, and its two first cargo facilities were constructed in the mid-90s by the United Postal Service. While the cargo operations were thriving, scheduled passenger services were never its forte, ceasing in 2001. It’s a UPS hub, handling over 3 billion pounds of cargo annually, making it the 14th busiest cargo airport in the country. Allegiant is the only passenger airline currently serving it. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom imagery, custom ground polygon, an up-to-date ground layout, PBR models, 4K textures, accurate dynamic lighting, and LOD optimization. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.54, requiring at least 2.54 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcr112</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Publishes Development Update for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12 </title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcr112"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65f963cdc0f20bee12132ce8_X-CRAFTS-E-JETS-FAMILY-MARCH-LINEAGE-1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts has recently published a development update covering what they have been working on recently, which includes a brand-new aircraft, an upcoming e-Jets update, and a surprise project. ‍ The Lineage 1000, the highlight of the dev update, has gotten new WIP previews, showcasing the work on the cabin, which has now reached “1.0”, meaning they have finished creating and UV mapping all the parts, with texturing work being the next step ahead. The E-Jets Update 1.1.0 will bring many new features, including FMS Speed, meaning the speeds will change automatically based on the phase of the flight without any user input. It will also include the steep approach system for the E170 and E190, allowing simmers to fly into airports such as London City accurately.  It also brings new pop-up screens for the PFD, MFD, and EICAS, working like the FMS and EFB, with the possibility to lock, unlock, resize, and interact by scrolling over the numbers on the screen. X-Plane 12 E-Jet pilots will also get a flight model update, which aims to bring the performance figures closer to real life, along with autopilot and autothrottle adjustments. They have also mentioned a free surprise project, which is yet to be announced (within weeks). The E-Jets are available on their website for $74.95/$134.95 (single variant and complete package, respectively). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
