<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-07-24T18:28:07.642897+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxiorb</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Örebro Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxiorb"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/668f0ab78a9fb8a2eca3e18d_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. MXI Design recently released its version of Örebro Airport (ESOE) for X-Plane 12. Located just over 6 miles from the city of Örebro, the airport is the 23rd largest airport in Sweden in terms of passengers. It serves around 80,000 passengers yearly and is also involved in various cargo operations. Örebro Airport opened in 1978 after discussions about a new airport in the region were ongoing in the early 50s and 60s. The airport initially had a 1,300-meter-long runway, which has now been extended to 3,300 meters. In the 1990s, the airport started to focus on cargo operations in addition to passenger transport. In terms of regional freight, Örebro Airport is the largest in all of Sweden. The airport is currently used by several airlines, including Ryanair, Sunclass Airlines, and ASL Airlines France, for both passenger and cargo operations. The scenery package includes an accurate and highly detailed rendition of the airport, an up-to-date ground layout, basic interior, PBR implementation, animated flags, 3D passengers, custom aerial imagery, and more. The newly released Örebro Airport requires 2.14 GB of storage space, and it is available on both SimMarket and Orbx for approximately $13.10. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777037</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 777-300ER for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777037"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66904e3dbe652ec8847e6d37_ana1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued a new update to their newly released Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing a few more fixes to the WASM issues, sound tweaks, and news on future updates for the DC-6 and 737s.  In an unusual fashion, the forum post begins with a paragraph on a future DC-6 update, which will improve texture clarity on gauges and dials and many of the placards and indicators throughout the flight deck. The update stems from what they have learned with the 737 and 777, which were initially applied on an experimental basis but were deemed too good to be kept private. The following bit details an SU15-induced issue that led to the aircraft freezing entirely, although the simulator would keep running. They claim it has to do with changes in how the platform handles C++ code issues that otherwise wouldn’t cause crashes. PMDG has been working hard to find and mitigate the triggers to provide maximum stability.  Said fixes are being rolled out gradually on the 777 and will also be rolled out to the 737 in due time. A beta version has been pushed out to their testers so they can ensure it’s working fine before a full rollout. PMDG is confident that update 2.00.0037 will give the 777 stability and protection against the SU15 issues that were unmasked with the help of their testers and customers. They have found most of the root causes and dealt with them accordingly.  With that being said, their “guard is still up,” and bug reports are still being constantly evaluated, with more fixes on the way.  The next update is already being worked on, and it’s anticipated to include a fix for the long filenames problem and a potential new feature: Navigraph data might be updated through the Ultimate Flight Tablet. Other fixes are also pending. The changelog for today’s update follows below: ‍ The 777-300ER is available on PMDG.com for $77.73. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kolanf</id>
    <title>Orbx Updates DCS Kola Map with New Features</title>
    <updated>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kolanf"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66910148f92d9469c9e0c35b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. Orbx has released a new update for its Kola map for DCS. The update includes new features and improvements. The main feature of the update is a set of winter textures, allowing users to explore the harsh and cold climate of the North. Further improvements to the map have been made based on community feedback. The update includes new winter textures that accurately represent cold climates. These textures will be adjusted based on the date of the mission. Additionally, the update features the Port of Kirkenes and includes enhancements within the Russian/Finnish border. Based on community feedback, the new update includes several improvements. These include performance optimizations, corrected placement of wind turbines, removal of orange trees from fields, and increased depth of the Polyarny harbor. All these improvements have been made to ensure that the map is as accurate as possible. The updated add-on is currently available on Orbx for $57.66 during early access and will increase to $69.99 upon full release. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777ime</id>
    <title>Parallel 42 Releases 777 Immersion Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777ime"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66916d0b19060b9b782afb42_par1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Parallel 42 recently released their 777 Immersion package for Microsoft Flight Simulator—part of their SimFX add-on—aiming to improve the overall realism of the effects for the PMDG 777 (and CaptainSim, eventually) with condensation, realistic chemtrails, brake smoke, and more. Available as a single package for all major renditions of the triple seven airframe regardless of the livery used, bringing immersive effects for the PMDG and CaptainSim (at a later date) and customized for each with performance as their top priority.  Built on the SimFx framework, it offers the best combination of effects and customizability via the SimFx interface. For the unaware, Parallel 42’s SimFX is a visual effects utility covering a range of immersive scenarios. Environmental variables and formulas authentically govern every particle on the screen, and dynamic effects appear under the right conditions, creating unique moments in the virtual skies. The effects include contrails, heat blurs, wing wash, rotor wash, and more. Their immersion package for the 777 builds on top of what SimFx already offers, bringing nineteen custom effects for the mighty triple seven, including swirling contrails, condensation effects, waste water drain every hour, engine cold start effects, fuel jettison, cloud illumination, hot brakes smoke, carbon brake dust, and water droplets. The APU heat blur and the St. Elmo’s fire are not supported because of a development choice by PMDG, using a deprecated technique preventing SimFX or 777 Immersion from injecting their version of those effects. The package is available on Contrail for roughly $15.00, requiring at least 2 MB of free hard disk space to install. Bear in mind that the 777 Package requires SimFX to work. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdmoor</id>
    <title>Cli4D Designs Releases Moorea, French Polynesia for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdmoor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6692fcd7f7417e921894b5dc_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cli4D Designs has recently released its latest add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator, focusing on the island of Moorea. Situated in French Polynesia, Moorea is surrounded by the Pacific Ocean. This add-on enhances the area originally created by Asobo and Microsoft, aiming to capture the island's breathtaking beauty. Moorea is a volcanic island with about 18.000 residents, located roughly 11 miles northwest of Tahiti. Although it covers only 52 square miles, the island boasts stunning visuals, including the coastal area and the extinct volcano Mount Tohivea, providing users with plenty to explore. The newly released add-on is loaded with features, offering an enhanced coastal area with tropical vegetation, human models, custom buildings with PBR textures, stationary and moving boats, improved ground textures, as well as enhancements on the hills and mountains, numerous points of interest, and more. The Moorea add-on from Cli4D Designs requires 3.68 GB of storage space and is available on Orbx, SimMarket, and Contrail for around $13.00. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/egphii</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co’s Edinburgh Airport II Gets Release Window</title>
    <updated>2024-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/egphii"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6694022df71e3916b6a85678_edinbruh1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue has recently teased their rendition of Edinburgh Airport V2 (EGPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with a release window: “Prepare for take-off. Next week”. It is the busiest airport in Scotland, with a yearly average of 14.7 million passengers. Over 200 scheduled flights connect Edinburgh to the world every day.  Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada (seasonally), Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, easyJet, Edelweiss Air, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, Jet2.com, JetBlue, KLM, Loganair, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and Vueling serve it. Edinburgh 2 fully rebuilds the first version with improved models and texturing, an up-to-date layout, improved custom jetways, a custom GSX profile, and much more. The pricing has yet to be revealed, but his last releases were around the $21 ballpark (roughly).Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/omgthd</id>
    <title>Orbx Previews Upcoming MSFS Global Trees HD</title>
    <updated>2024-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/omgthd"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6696cb7a24581f1c5b72e369_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently added a new product named MSFS Global Trees HD to their "Upcoming Products" section on their website. The product page for this upcoming add-on is now available. This new add-on will replace all standard vegetation with high-quality specimens, enhancing the overall appearance of the flora in Microsoft Flight Simulator. The product page provides a lot of information about the add-on and includes numerous screenshots. Some key features to expect are high-quality replacement vegetation for the default, the option to change vegetation seasons, six new types of grass to replace the default grass, a tool to change vegetation seasons and grass type, and more. Although Orbx has not yet announced a release date or pricing, the comprehensive product page may indicate that a release is not too far away. We will keep you informed once more information about the add-on is announced. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thirdwind-simulations-announce-feiseler-storch</id>
    <title>ThirdWind Simulations Announce Feiseler Storch</title>
    <updated>2024-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thirdwind-simulations-announce-feiseler-storch"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6696fe201feb3d9f115fe56b_image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Thirdwind Simulations, a new collaborative venture between veteran developer Nervegas and flight sim content creator BurstixTV, has announced its first project: the Fieseler Fi 156 Storch. The announcement was made on the MSFS forums and featured a preview of the current 3d model being shown in Blender. The Storch was a liaison aircraft developed for the German Ministry of Aviation in the 1930s. The original aircraft was powered by an Argus V8 engine and had a range of 210nm at a cruise speed of 81 knots. The Storch was retired by the German military but went on to serve with French forces until the 70s. For more information on the Storch project by Thirdwind Simulations, you can check out their discord here.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for the latest in flight simulation! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdghh</id>
    <title>FSDG Releases Hurghada International Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdghh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66982f6a315f9ccbe4defeb3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FSDG has recently released its latest scenery for X-Plane 12, Hurghada International Airport (HEGN). Located in and serving the city of Hurghada, Egypt, the airport is one of the busiest in the Middle East. The airport serves as an important hub for a variety of leisure flights coming from Europe. Hurghada International Airport began operating in 1977. Over the years, it has expanded and is now the second busiest airport in Egypt, after Cairo International Airport. The airport consists of two terminals: Terminal 1 and Terminal 2. It is situated just 3.1 miles southwest of Hurghada's city center. Air Cairo considers the airport a focus city, and it serves many other airlines year-round as well as seasonally, including Corendon Airlines, easyJet, TUI Airways, and Wizz Air. The airport's diverse airline operations contribute to a significant influx of visitors from across Europe to the city of Hurghada. The new scenery for X-Plane 12 includes a fully accurate rendition of Hurghada International Airport and its surroundings, an updated airport layout, several hotels, resorts, and landmarks, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, and more. The newly released Hurghada International Airport scenery is now available on FSDG for around $21.87. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vstboh</id>
    <title>Velocity SkyTech Releases Bournemouth Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vstboh"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66997e90f6ea520bbabe692b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Velocity SkyTech has recently released its rendition of Bournemouth Airport (EGHH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport is located just 4 miles away from Bournemouth, England, and is an international airport that serves a variety of destinations, particularly warm and summer destinations. The airport first opened as a Royal Air Force station, called RAF Hurn, in 1941. In 1944, it was transferred to civil control and even served as London's international airport before the opening of Heathrow in 1946. Over the years, the airport has served a variety of airlines and destinations, growing to its current state. Last year, the airport served just over 950.000 passengers and had over 5000 aircraft movements. It is the focus city for Jet2.com, Ryanair, and TUI Airways, and also serves airlines like easyJet, offering flights to destinations including France, Greece, and Spain. The newly released Bournemouth Airport add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator comes with several features, such as exterior and interior 3D modeling of the terminal buildings, PBR textures, performance optimization, and more. The add-on requires 375.07 MB of storage space and is currently on sale on SimMarket for approximately $13.02. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/777038</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates Entire MSFS Product Lineup</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/777038"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66999818f0169fc6be3b28f7_anz1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued significant updates to all of their products for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing stability improvements, bug fixes, new textures (DC-6), and more. ‍ The newly released 777-300ER has been updated to 2.00.0039, focused once again on stability and performance improvements, mitigating new issues reported by the customers, with more to come in the near future as they are not convinced about finding all of them.  ‍ The new update also brings the possibility of updating the Navigraph navdata via the Ultimate Flight Tablet, ultimately allowing seamless data updates straight from the flight deck on both PC and Xbox (when available). A QR code within the UFT also links people to the 777 online manual. ‍ The complete changelog for 0039 follows below: Regarding the 777’s appearance on the Marketplace and Xbox, it’s set for a dual release and expected to happen within two to four weeks. The upcoming 77F is their current development focus and is nearing its beta testing stage. PMDG anticipates it to be a rather quick process, and they are already evaluating the next variant after that. A major update has also been pushed to the 737 lineup, bringing the stability and performance fixes they used on the 777. It has also been pushed to the marketplace and might take around two weeks to show up. ‍ More 737 updates are expected as they continue squashing the issues with the 777, and some of the structural changes from the Triple Seven will be back-ported, including the new navdata format, updated lateral path solving, updated autopilot roll modes, updated EFB, and more. ‍ Last but not least, the DC-6 has been updated with the new cockpit textures. It has also been rolled out to the marketplace and might take around two weeks to become available. ‍ PMDG concluded the weekly update thread with a brief note on the 747’s progress. It has been in development since January and is progressing nicely, with “unexpected and very exciting things planned for this product line.”  ‍ PMDG’s product line is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $77.73.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!   ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bai103</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Dubai International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bai103"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66999b04d8d3c84361a86bb5_dubai4.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently updated - again - their rendition of Dubai International Airport (OMDB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressing the ILS/PAPI mismatch in previous versions and more. Update v1.0.3 brings a complete repositioning of the ILS beacons and PAPIs using GE coordinates to match real life, adjusted autogen building heights, and minor ground service equipment tweaks. The airport is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $18.11 (on sale), requiring at least 4.4 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dtw105</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Detroit Metropolitan Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dtw105"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66999f47a97a2a5f8a2322a9_dtw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their rendition of Detroit Metropolitan Airport (KDTW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing new ground service equipment, new car models, reworked building LODs, and more. Update v1.0.5 brings newer variants of people, cars, vegetation, and ground service equipment, new building LODs for improved performance, an overall reduction in clutter, and other minor bug fixes. The changelog follows below: v1.0.5 - Rework of building LODs - Removed SD/HD option - Replaced all GSE with new versions - Replaced vegetation models - Replaced people models - Replaced car models - Updated terrain sculpting method - North terminal LOD radius issue fixed - Added A65 parking - Significant reduction in the number of parking and hash markings (replaced with more efficient decals) - no visual change. - Overall reduction in the number of people, cars, GSE etc. - Corrected missing ILS from VFR map. - Closed fence gap The scenery is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $16.30 (on sale), requiring at least 4.73 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/egphv2</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases Edinburgh Airport II for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/egphv2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/669a826c5a9f7b377c663753_egph1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ Pyreegue Dev Co. recently released their new rendition of Edinburgh Airport (EGPH) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This is a major upgrade to the original release from 2021, entirely rebuilt from the ground up. It is the busiest airport in Scotland, with a yearly average of 14.7 million passengers. Over 200 scheduled flights connect Edinburgh to the world every day.  Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada (seasonally), Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, easyJet, Edelweiss Air, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, Jet2.com, JetBlue, KLM, Loganair, Lufthansa, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Pegasus Airlines, Qatar Airways, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, Virgin Atlantic, and Vueling serve it. Rebuilt from the ground up to meet the ever-growing industry standard, Pyreegue’s Edinburgh II features an accurate rendition of the airport, with true-to-life terrain elevation profile, a 3D model of their drainage system, LiDAR scanned interiors and buildings, latest satellite imagery data, an up-to-date ground layout, custom night lighting, dynamic ATC tower lights, many landside buildings, custom static GSE vehicles, dynamic gate doors and VDGS (requires GSX), and a custom-made GSX profile. It’s available on Contrail for $14.15 (Temporary launch price; regular price will be $28.22). To install it, you need at least 3.4 GB of free hard disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ia3112</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates Airbus A300-600R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ia3112"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/669ac52fd397ac66977bf7ac_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released an update for their Airbus A300-600R add-on for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The aircraft has been updated to version 1.1.2 and includes various fixes to systems, art, sound, and more. The new update has been in the works for the past 10 weeks. It has been designed to provide the aircraft with more immersion and authenticity. Some of the notable changes include performance improvements, an overhaul of lateral and vertical navigation, and the ability to have a custom EFB background. The new version features a significant changelog, which is listed below: ‍ v1.1.2 ‍ LNAV  Major overall system rewrite to better handle turns into initial fix and SID/STARS and holds. ‍ Systems New improvements: 1 - bleed PSI should be +/- 30psi during start 2 - LO OIL PRESS should be on at fuel lever on and ECAM oil pressure should be red, until 70PSI (goes out and goes green at 72PSI) 3 - engine generators should come online at 52% N2, not 49% 4 - Overhauled PW start sequence following feedback from real A300 pilot 5 – Optimisations to increase performance 6 - ENG FADEC CHANNEL 1+2  FAULT – ECAM logic [Feedback from real A300 pilot] 7 - Significant improvements to stability with WASM crashes and CTD Fixes: Fixed - WASM Crash on SEC-FPLN Deletion/Activation  Fixed - WASM crash doing right turns Fixed - WASM Crash on exiting Hold - EGSS ILS04 at ABBOT  Fixed – WASM crash related to terrain radar  Fixed - WASM crash when entering ZFW Fixed - SD Wheel Page - Green/Orange overtemp Arc showing around wrong wheel Fixed - Engine/APU Fire test logic corrected to match RW flow  Fixed - N1 Command/TLA Position Needle in wrong position during REV THRUST Fixed - When on glide aircraft can't be controlled Fixed - IRS mode and source selectors missing interaction Fixed - EFB remains off until Ext Power connected Fixed - If ISOL valves off fuel line is drawn between ctr and outer tanks Fixed - Showcase camera views Fixed - Quick views R and L view corrected to 90* Fixed - 3 max waypoints loading on AIRWAYS Fixed - ECAM FUEL Page - Right Inner fuel feed line not drawn  Fixed - Throttle Calibration not working (Throttle input not detected)  Fixed - TCAS traffic INOP Fixed - FCU Speed reverts to IAS when cruising in MACH mode once TOC is reached Fixed - Flight perf feedback – refined overall flight performance Fixed - Trim wheel missing integral lighting Fixed - Shutdown Checklist Fixed - FO Alt gauge OFF flag black pixels Fixed - FUEL SD page and left ECAM MEMO page updating at different rates Fixed - Fuel Pred - Pressing Fuel button in flight erases values Fixed - IRS Alignment logic  Fixed - Direct to logic – Now allows for direct entry change Fixed - VNAV Climb logic  Fixed - FMA/FMGS Logic  Fixed - MDCU Perf page logic Fixed - MCDU F-PLN page - END OF F-PLN stuck on L2 Fixed - Trim wheel set to 1.0NU, but when adjusting with key controls it snaps to 0NU Fixed - Speed targets in FMS don't match what PROF commands Fixed - TACT Mode logic Fixed - PROG - FUEL PRED PAGE - Altn airport EFOB showing as "-N&lt;-N" Fixed – Holds adjusted to follow magnetic course Fixed - ECAM - TO Mode Fixed - STBY Horizon lost alignment after landing when the APU on Fixed - Changing descent winds forecast does not affect T/D prediction | BTG Fixed - Engine Start Sequence logic Fixed - ND Config logic Fixed - ND Display logic Fixed - MDCU perf page logic Fixed - FD1 annunciation disappears from PFD Fixed - FMA modes logic corrected Fixed - BRK TEMP HIGH ECAM message not clearing when Brake Fan selected Fixed - MCDU flight plan display Fixed - Assigning a button to control brakes causes conflicting command Fixed - Secondary flight plan on the ND should be blue Fixed - "500" Callout on Takeoff in pax variant Fixed - Oil temp not rising fast enough Fixed - FLT CTL page missing title Fixed - FPLN Page - unable to input Lat/Lon as a fix Fixed - Erroneous T/D Fixed - Scrolling through F-Plan should be one wp per arrow press Fixed - CTD When loading into plane (FLY NOW button) Fixed - Rudder should still turn nosewheel by 6° Fixed - MCDU F-PLN page additions and corrections Fixed - ND Runway length filter for fields under 5000' length (may sometimes return smaller fields based on sim logic) Fixed - Plane stalls in VS mode when trying to hold a pitch below stall speed. Aircraft will now pitch down Fixed - Airway L620 not returning fixes on FLT plan page Fixed -  T/O Perf calc page hPa/inHg tied to WEIGHT UNITS option in settings Fixed - Weight &amp; Fuel changing mid-flight, then FU bugged and SBY Horizon bugged Fixed -  Loss of systems after returning from pause Fixed  -Systems and display freezing - LSGG-LFSB with the LUMEL 8K arrival, ILS Z 15 approach. Fixed -  CTD - KLAX star ANJLL4 via DNERO transition, ILS 25L via CRCUS Fixed  -Speedbrakes show as deployed on ECAM on spawn in Fixed - No Flex temp on TO calcs with PW Fixed - BUS 1 should be connected to ESS BUS, GEN OVRD should have an arrow [Feedback from real A300 pilot] Fixed -  Landing distance calculator bug fixed  Fixed - Elapsed Timer does not show "1" in 10h02m ET Fixed - Fix landing distance calculator (in current state, the METAR data does not sync) Fixed - T/o Perf calculator does not mirror altimeter units from settings Fixed - Eng Fire squib test still shows in Amber Fixed - [EFB] MTOW discrepancy on TakeOff Perf Calculator Added – You can now have a custom background on your EFB Fixed - FMS: Distance to T/D should report actual distance and not distance between last w/p and T/D (distance between last and to should be actual distance, not segment distance between waypoints. [Feedback from real A300 pilot] Improvement – Overhauled Packs off operations following feedback from real A300 pilot Fixed  - ILS freq selection: Only ILS freqs should be avail – uneven after “.” E.g.10/15/30/35…) .20/40/60 are not valid ILS freqs [Feedback from real A300 pilot]  Fixed - ECAM logic on start [Feedback from real A300 pilot] Fixed -  ECAM Brightness panel labels disappear when IDC Radios selected from EFB Fixed  - MODE CHG stuck on ND Fixed  - RMI Gauge VOR bearing/declination issue Fixed - Eng N1 should show until +/- 1% on shutdown Fixed - IMM EXIT prompt bug  Fixed - MCDU: PROG page - cannot return out of ENG OUT mode Fixed - FCU lights disappearing in flight (daytime) Fixed - Simbrief weights bugs Fixed – TOD ETA incorrect  Fixed - Winds have no effect on INIT B or FUEL PRED page Fixed - TRIP TIME and fuel burn predictions exaggerated Fixed  - FACT RWY19 TETAN 1A SID Fixed - FMS: OPT and MAX FL’s are in steps of FL005 [Feedback from real A300 pilot] ‍ Art Fixed - All outside animations and cockpit yoke tiller animations running at 5/10 fps Fixed - Stairs don't spawn on freighter Fixed - Backpanel  APU EGT, N1 and OIL gauge needles not lit at night Fixed - EGT warning light on GE engine config lighting up at PW limits Fixed - Oil QTY bugs animation no longer as smooth as before Fixed - Hole in rear of GE model (Checked all liveries) Fixed - FO TERR MODE GPWS decals missing Fixed - Floating fan blade numbers PW DHL (D-AEAF) Fixed - D-AEAF red texture line floating when bulk door opened Fixed - Reversed text on tyres when worn Fixed - Fuel Pressure Indicator Window missing on liveries Fixed - [XBOX][ART] Double edge around windows (and no textures) Fixed - L/R Stairs not showing when selected from EFB ‍ Sounds Fixed - External airport ambience sound adjustment Fixed – Various overhauls and minor tweaks  Fixed - Allow warnings/callouts/alerts volume to be controlled separately Fixed - Trim “Whooler” sound missing Fixed - APU external sounds  ‍ EFB Added can now create a custom background. The updated Airbus A300-600R is now available for download on the iniManager. At the time of writing, the aircraft is on sale and can be purchased from the iniBuilds Store for approximately $26.01. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniddu</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Dubrovnik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniddu"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66a010f4e94078d32d9948e9_dub1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Dubrovnik Ruđer Bošković Airport (LDDU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Dubrovnik-Neretva County with a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers. The airport opened in 1962 and quickly became Yugoslavia’s busiest. By 1987, it had already served nearly a million passengers.  In the 2000s, a new passenger terminal was built to replace the original from 1962, costing the administration 70 million euros. It’s the most modern terminal in the country so far.  It’s a hub for Croatia Airlines and many other European carriers, including Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Volotea, Vueling, and Wizz Air, serve it on a seasonal basis. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, custom night lighting, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, an up-to-date layout, and a custom GSX profile.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.36, requiring at least 3.94 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
