<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2025-11-22T18:33:52.681468+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/n707nv</id>
    <title>Nimbus Shares New Preview of Boeing 707 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/n707nv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69179dd49e6d293daa358bd7_707-2024-08-2313_43_51%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Nimbus Simulation Studios has released a new work-in-progress video, showcasing its upcoming Boeing 707 for X-Plane 12, with a focus on the JT3D powerplants. The footage highlights the characteristic fan roar and exhaust scream that defined early jet travel, giving a first taste of the audio experience the team is aiming for. According to Nimbus, the 707 is being built as a high-fidelity recreation of the classic three-crew jet. The aircraft features carefully modelled and textured visuals, with wing and engine vibrations, rattles and shakes, driven by physical forces, to provide visual cues about what is happening outside the cockpit.  Additional animations will depict the movement and complexity of mechanisms in the wings, tail, and landing gear. On the systems side, Nimbus plans to simulate all major systems, based on original manuals and available references. Meanwhile, the flight model is being tuned using performance charts and pilot testimonies to capture the hands-on feel of the era.  A virtual crew is also planned to assist with flow and system management, helping to reduce the workload for one simmer operating the aircraft alone. Nimbus has not yet announced a release date for the Boeing 707, but development updates will continue to be shared via its forum and Discord. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dffwindsor</id>
    <title>Dfflyer Releases Windsor International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dffwindsor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6917ad305ddc49e2ef2abbdb_windsor1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Dfflyer - a new scenery developer in the scene - has just released their first scenery: a rendition of Windsor International Airport (CYQG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving the Detroit-Windsor region with a yearly average of 330,000 passengers. It opened in 1928 as Walker Airport, after Hiram Walker, a Canadian whiskey distiller and distributor. It joined Canada’s national portfolio of airports in 1967, when it was recognized for its regional importance as a hub for Southwestern Ontario.  Since early 2007, the airport has been managed by an ad hoc group on behalf of the City of Windsor. This arrangement followed the request by the last operator, Serco Services Inc., for early termination of their airport management contract in 2006, as the airport was losing 40k USD monthly. The new administration had a better fate, managing to post a small profit instead, and has since been granted an indefinite contract. It’s served by Air Canada Express, Air Transat (to start in late 2025), Cameron Air Service, Porter Airlines, and WestJet. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom taxiway and runway lights, custom ground service equipment, custom cars, a high-quality rendition of the main terminal and all hangars, and more. It’s available in their store for roughly $12.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcsbal</id>
    <title>OnReTech Announces DCS: Balkans Map for 2026</title>
    <updated>2025-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcsbal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691a5dc6fd17d3b64286d8cc_In_Dev_07.11.2025.6.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: DCS. OnReTech, the team behind DCS: Sinai, has announced its next terrain for DCS World, DCS: Balkans, developed in partnership with Eagle Dynamics,  and currently planned for a 2026 release. The map is designed to recreate NATO air operations over the former Yugoslavia between 1991 and 2001, with players able to fly as either NATO or Serbian forces.  It will cover large parts of the Balkans, the Adriatic Sea, and sections of Italy, combining varied coastlines, numerous islands, and several major mountain ranges, including the Dinaric Alps, Apennines, and Dolomites. OnReTech plans to include a broad mix of urban centres such as Venice, Dubrovnik, Belgrade, Zagreb, Trieste, Bari, and Rijeka, connected by highways and rail networks.  Alongside this, a range of military airbases and civilian airports will be located across Italy, Serbia, Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Kosovo.  The newsletter specifically highlights Aviano Air Base, home to the United States Air Force 31st Fighter Wing, and Venice Marco Polo Airport. The map is designed as a suitable theatre for aircraft such as the F-16C and MiG-29A, and will be accompanied by further additions to the popular Currenthill asset pack, including a Grisha-class corvette for coastal and anti-submarine operations, and an AI-only EC-665 Tiger UHT attack helicopter. You can check out the full newsletter here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff777fnw</id>
    <title>Flight Factor’s 777 Freighter Expansion to Launch This Week</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff777fnw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691b4f0bc917354639e486ce_freight1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flight Factor has recently teased their upcoming 777 Freighter Expansion for X-Plane 11 and 12, scheduled to launch this week. The long-awaited freighter expansion for Flight Factor’s 777-200ER V2 Ultimate is a week away from the virtual shelves, and selected streamers have already received preview keys from Flight Factor to showcase the product.  In similar fashion as of the 772, Flight Factor’s 777F will feature a deep systems simulation, a proprietary flight model within 2-5% of standard certification tests, true-to-life dimensions, authentic systems, a new weather radar, a custom sound system with 3D stereo engine sounds, a failure and maintenance system with over 1,000 simulated failures, an advanced EFB with SimBrief integration, and much more. ​ There’s no pricing information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf146v242024</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s 146 Professional v2.4 Releasing by the End of the Month</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf146v242024"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691b50f142dd4063fed49569_bingo1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently provided a brief development update on their 146 Professional v2.4 update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing full compatibility with the latter and introducing brand-new features yet to be revealed. The development process is nearing completion, and the team aims to release it by the end of the month for both platforms. As usual for Just Flight, this will be a free update for existing owners, and new buyers will benefit from a temporary discount upon launch. ​ They claim it’s the most substantial upgrade yet to the 146, bringing it up to pair with the RJ Professional in terms of features and realism. They will soon be sharing more photos, videos, and the “massive” changelog. ​ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fssoct</id>
    <title>Flight Sim Studios Shares E-Jets Progress for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fssoct"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691b9a91a7bb9844e03f0331_Another-ejets-header.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Flight Sim Studios (FSS) has released a development update on its awaited E-Jets overhaul for MSFS 2020 and MSFS 2024, highlighting progress on the custom FMS, improved navigation behaviour, and the final pieces still in the works. The new version has been in testing for several months, and according to FSS, with over 88 testers, logging more than 2,000 recorded sessions, identifying 64 issues, and prompting over 350 code changes. The aircraft, the studio says, is now fully flyable in normal operation. Major FMS pages are implemented, LNAV tracks reliably, and VNAV is already functional. Integrating Navigraph navdata proved to be one of the biggest hurdles, forcing a rebuild of the entire ILS system, but the team reports that it is now “rock solid”. Significant fixes have also been made to SIDs, STARs, and unusual procedure types, along with a much-improved Direct-To function. Before the wider community can try it, the remaining blocker is the suite of vertical autopilot modes, which are still being refined to ensure stable behaviour. With LNAV now fully rebuilt for the new CFMS, the vertical logic is the last major component that can still misbehave, particularly during RNAV approaches. Sound logic and the EFB’s performance calculator also remain unfinished, as both require systems to be migrated from older frameworks. FSS plans to invite another 100 testers shortly. If progress on the autopilot continues at its current pace, the team aims to release an experimental, public build in December. This version will ship with a few known gaps, including missing sounds, such as the TO CONFIG check, and the temporary removal of the performance calculator. However, it is already described as being far more enjoyable to fly than the existing E-Jets release. Regarding a full v1.0, the developer is not yet ready to set a release date. Instead, they emphasise delivering the significantly improved version as soon as possible, regardless of what the eventual update is called. Read the full update here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mplbud</id>
    <title>MicroProse Updates B-17G Flying Fortress to v0.9.2 for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mplbud"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691ba7a575592fdcf3ae01bc_579314912_1273604118139836_1757491807982642047_n.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. MicroProse and Just Flight have released the second Early Access update for the B-17G Flying Fortress in MSFS 2024, titled the “Long Beach” update (v0.9.2). The new build continues to refine the heavy bomber, focusing on cockpit detail, performance, and a few long-requested quality-of-life tweaks.  On the visual side, the developers have overhauled internal texture ambient occlusion baking, refined the internal 3D mesh, and resolved several internal LOD issues. Externally, various texture fixes and updates have been applied, and a new empty bare-metal livery has been added. Under the skin, the update adjusts the centre of gravity, applies further flight model and aerodynamic improvements, and corrects both the manifold pressure and vertical speed gauges, so that they now use the proper units. Spawning on the runway now loads the aircraft with all four boost pumps enabled by default, which should make quick-start operations in MSFS 2024 a little smoother.  The “Long Beach” patch follows October’s “Seattle” update, which addressed LODs, mesh, and texture issues, as well as aircraft weights and dimensions. It also significantly reworked the fuel, engine, and system setup, laying much of the groundwork for the current round of refinements.  Existing owners of the Early Access B-17G Flying Fortress can download version 0.9.2 from the “Your Orders” section of their Just Flight account; new buyers will receive the latest version by default. You can get it here. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atanov</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Publish Third A340-600 Update for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atanov"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691c75750c7856e803322d60_videoframe_8778%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft and ToLiss have recently released the third development update for their Airbus A340-600 Pro series in Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update continues the deep dive into aircraft systems, with ToLiss head Torsten explaining the intricacies behind hydraulics, air, and avionics, hosted by Aerosoft's Rafi. Indeed, the Hydraulic systems were a key focus, with Torsten detailing how the four engines feed into three hydraulic circuits, including redundancy measures and the limited capacity of the ram air turbine. He noted that the user would see slower flap movement or gear extension under low-pressure scenarios, reflecting real-world limitations. The air and bleed systems were also discussed, illustrating how four engines distribute air into two systems, which in turn impacts fuel flow and engine behaviour. Each engine is simulated with unique tolerances, meaning oil pressure, temperature, and acceleration rates vary. Attention then shifted to avionics, including the three MCDUs, which mirror the real aircraft’s functionality. Only two can connect to the flight management system at a time, while the third, situated further back on the console, supports ATSU functions and acts as a backup. Display reconfigurations and redundancy were also covered, ensuring failures behave as they would in reality. The electronic flight bag (EFB) was also discussed, which appears to integrate the same principles as ToLiss’s previous EFB system for X-Plane. Here, you can control loading, ground services, performance calculations, Navigraph charts, and SimBrief connectivity. Situation and auto-saving are also included in the EFB. Finally, the team showcased their implementation of a taxi camera. While limited by MSFS technology, Aerosoft and ToLiss have adapted satellite imagery overlays to provide taxi guidance, calibrated to the aircraft’s position.  This marks the conclusion of the current interview series, with Aerosoft confirming future showcases, including a livestream featuring a real A340-600 pilot.  The product was also showcased over the weekend, at Aerosoft’s FS conference in Paderborn. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fel742f</id>
    <title>Felis Releases Boeing 747-200F for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fel742f"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691cca02c9fde2f6172b8175_369346_X-Plane_58fBpGHBM2_1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Felis has just released the highly anticipated Boeing 747-200F for X-Plane 12 The Boeing 747 needs no introduction. It is one of the most iconic aircraft ever built, and the -200 variant is the second most sold variant, following the -400. The Boeing 747-200F is the freighter version of the -200. Most of the remaining Boeing 747-200s are freighters, with the exceptions being two Iranian aircraft - one for the air force - and six that operate for the U.S. Air Force, two of which serve as Air Force One. The Felis Boeing 747-200 has been one of the most popular high-quality aircraft add-ons for X-Plane for years. The new freighter variant includes a fully modelled main cargo deck, side cargo doors, and the iconic nose cargo door. Additionally, the cockpit has been updated for freighter operations.  Felis states that the freighter variant is constructed with the same level of detail as the passenger variant, featuring a few new system variants, including the optional tape-style instruments. The Felis 747-200F is available now on the x-plane.org store for $70. Owners of the passenger variants are eligible for a $30 upgrade price. ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/blsend</id>
    <title>Boundless Simulations Officially Shut Down</title>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/blsend"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691cf7b7de61e51621520b29_image%20(1).webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Boundless Simulations has now closed its online store, bringing an end to the studio’s five-year run as one of X-Plane’s most prolific scenery developers.  The shutdown follows a July message from founder Lew, who explained that real life had taken over, and that the studio would shut its doors, with the store staying open until November. That deadline has now passed, and the storefront has quietly disappeared, leaving only the Discord server, which remains open for now. Boundless began in 2020 as a bedroom project, and went on to produce an enormous catalogue for X-Plane, covering everything from tiny Irish helipads to major airports, including Dublin, Stansted, Inverness, Faro, and Bournemouth.  Along the way, Lew used the income to fund his flight training, eventually securing a place on the A320 flight deck, something he openly credits to the community that supported the studio. A handful of Boundless products seemingly remain available through the iniBuilds store, though only select titles, and not always in their latest versions.  With the storefront now gone, we see quite an influential developer finally leave the scene. With a remarkable number of airfields built over the years, the legacy of Boundless will certainly be remembered for a long time. For all the latest news and updates, stay tuned on Threshold! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bbdwol</id>
    <title>Burning Blue Design Releases Wolverhampton Halfpenny Green Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bbdwol"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691f73b89ea6c607047027b4_wolf1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Burning Blue Design has recently released their rendition of Wolverhampton Halfpenny Green Airport (EGBO) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Wolverhampton in the United Kingdom. It was constructed in the 1940s for World War II, then named RAF Bobbington, and later renamed RAF Halfpenny Green due to its similarity with RAF Bovingdon.  It didn’t see much activity after the war, with flights only returning in 1952 with the No. 2 Air Signallers School, which disbanded a year later. Then, a ground-based equipment sub-unit occupied the airfield until 1956, after which the airport fell into disuse until it was revived as a civil airport in 1961. In the early 2000s, the airport’s previous owner - CityHopper Ltd. - had ambitious plans for Wolverhampton Airport, including a substantial expansion, a longer runway, and open-air facilities for Boeing 737 engine testing, but none of that came to fruition, as it was sold to a new owner (MAR Properties Ltd.) and they had no intent on doing any of that.  It’s currently a popular airport for general aviation, especially among flex-wing and three-axis microlight pilots, and there’s even a microlight flight school on-site.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, over 200 custom 3D objects, a detailed control room and hangar interiors, full dynamic weather compatibility, animated spectators, and high-resolution colour-corrected ground textures. It’s available in their store for $19.56. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff77fxp12rel</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Releases 777 Freighter Upgrade for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2025-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff77fxp12rel"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/691f76bd375f23bcec9a5bc6_freighter1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has recently released their long-awaited 777 Freighter upgrade for X-Plane 12, expanding on their 777-200ER released earlier this year. In similar fashion as of the 772, Flight Factor’s 777F features a deep systems simulation, a proprietary flight model within 2-5% of standard certification tests, true-to-life dimensions, authentic systems, a new weather radar, a custom sound system with 3D stereo engine sounds, a failure and maintenance system with over 1,000 simulated failures, an advanced EFB with SimBrief integration, and much more. The complete feature list follows below: 777 Freighter version  It’s available in the X-Plane.Org Store for $30.00. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jf124upnw</id>
    <title>Just Flight’s 146 Professional v2.4 Upgrade to Release Next Week</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jf124upnw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6920d612184c76d69878868f_bah1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Just Flight has recently shared the substantial changelog for their upcoming 146 Professional v2.4 upgrade for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, introducing numerous improvements and full compatibility with MSFS 2024. Currently discounted by 30% due to a Black Friday sale, the 146 Professional will receive a massive update next week - free of charge for previous owners -bringing feature parity with their RJ, native compatibility with Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, and much more. The complete changelog follows below: If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/iniman24new</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares New Manchester Airport Previews for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/iniman24new"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6920d8014883e30c3d0812c9_manny1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently shared new screenshots of their upcoming Manchester Airport (EGCC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, with “more to come soon”.  Their next addition to the British lineup is nearing completion, built with extreme attention to detail using thousands of reference photos and textures. They also gained insight into their daily operations, future expansion plans, and design updates, which helped them further increase overall accuracy. Furthermore, they have also gained access to Terminal 2, which is still under construction, photographing every detail to ensure the scenery is as accurate as possible. The scenery will feature hand-made ground textures, a true-to-life landside recreation, dynamic airport lighting, custom jetways, over 180 hand-crafted models, a full HD ground poly, an up-to-date ground layout, performance-friendly optimisation, and much more. ​ There’s no release date or pricing yet, but iniBuilds says it’s “coming soon” and streamers will be getting their hands on it shortly. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia350117</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia350117"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68bb62be9b12a08a648472f2_FlightSimulator2024_cpVHkz3KzX_4472x.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued a new update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, bringing extensive bug fixes, performance improvements, and a refined audio experience. Update v1.1.7 has a strong focus on performance improvements, and they are pleased to report significant gains across the board. Their team has worked very hard to optimize every area of the airplane, which will hugely benefit those on weaker hardware. Based on customer feedback, they have developed a new performance-friendly cabin as the default, eliminating the need to disable the cabin entirely for performance. However, the option to turn the cabin off will remain available for those who wish to do so. ​ They have also decided to sunset the cabin packs from 1.1.7 onward, focusing their efforts on further optimizing the core product experience. iniBuilds also clarifies that custom cabin livery textures are still fully supported across all cabin variants. ​ Furthermore, they have reduced the quality of some textures on the A350 while ensuring they do not impact the visual fidelity in any way. ​ Their 3D model also underwent a slight optimization process, significantly reducing the node count by several thousand, resulting in a positive improvement to main thread performance. The wingflex system was also changed to a more optimized method, reducing the number of “bones” by 50%. ​ The optimization work also extended to the LODs, which, although not heavily contributing to performance gains, helped somewhat, making the transitions smoother.  ​ The average framerate has improved by 19.6% on their test system, and the 1% lows went up by 58%.  ​ The sound department has also seen improvements, as seen below: The complete changelog follows below: ​V1.1.7SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED FLS clearance logic after NEW DEST insertion.FIXED VNAV wind component direction/sign conventions and path geometry.FIXED VNAV path agreement with VSD (constraint interpolation &amp; smoothing).FIXED PERF DES speed schedule and VDEV stability.FIXED Vertical Display showing ETP/time markers.FIXED DIR TO logic, temporary flight plan creation, and waypoint ordering.FIXED Wind page ordering (highest FL to lowest).FIXED Manual leg sequencing, waypoint deletion behaviour, and scratchpad validation.FIXED Custom waypoint handling (PBD / LAT-LON / 3–4 letter stored waypoints).FIXED Incorrect destination field elevation and altitude reference usage.FIXED Departure SID parsing and selection reliability.FIXED Arrival/Approach selection and correct propagation to SEC F-PLN.FIXED RNP AR guidance stability, VDEV behaviour, and RF-leg tracking.FIXED LS and FLS course sourcing for PFD annunciation.FIXED Constraint displays relative to TL/TA logic.FIXED Step climb ETA and calculation logic when offsets or conditional waypoints are present.FIXED Oceanic Clearance entry workflow and CPDLC handling logic.FIXED Offset waypoint creation (-XX nm) and abeam logic.FIXED ACTIVE/SEC common-leg behaviour.FIXED Cruise MACH, REC MAX, and ISA deviation integration.FIXED Step climb trigger logic and TO waypoint formatting.FIXED High-elevation airport logic for TO/DES predictions.FIXED GS mini computation using correct wind component.FIXED APP DES behaviour and pitch/thrust blending.FIXED AP V/S mode pitch-command smoothing.FIXED Pitch trim initialisation for airborne starts.FIXED V/S display behaviour during preflight.FIXED EO acceleration altitude logic.FIXED VAPP/VLS consistency and wind additives.FIXED VFE and VMAX CONF1 accuracy.FIXED Aileron neutral feedback indication.FIXED FLS/LOC/VOR approach symbology across PFD/ND.FIXED BLEED 1+2, PACK 1+2, and X-BLEED ECAM logic.FIXED WING ANTI-ICE ECAM behaviour.FIXED TR1/2/EMER voltage modelling.FIXED HYD and F/CTL SD page alignment and indication precision.FIXED Fuel quantity resolution (10kg).FIXED IR/ADR switching behaviour and OFF annunciation.FIXED ADIRS pushbutton logic.FIXED Cargo temperature regulation indication.FIXED Brake temperature arc placement.FIXED Beacon/chocks logic for ground ops.FIXED Door/cabin readiness indications.FIXED Engine/pitot cover detection logic.FIXED Loadsheet formatting and message record handling.FIXED Turnaround/MCDU reset behaviour.FIXED BTV stop margin entry behaviour.FIXED LDG MEMO timing alignment.ADDED Local terrain database download capability.ADDED RMP frequency uplink via ACARS.ADDED ACARS timeout logic.FIXED RAD NAV auto-cleaning and frequency handling.FIXED HUD symbology stability (FPV, track bug, LS scale).FIXED PFD track/altitude indications around 360° transitions.FIXED ISIS text and menu alignment.FIXED ND symbology for terrain, RF legs, and approach overlays.FIXED FO-side ND airport data call.FIXED SEC PLAN ND rendering.FIXED OIS layout and format improvements.FIXED L/G Gravity Ext erroneous message ART 🎨FIXED AP disconnect and priority pushbutton animations.FIXED Reverser lever animations and detent accuracy.FIXED Vertical tail aerodynamic behaviour with no hydraulics.FIXED Spoiler droop representation on SD and external model.FIXED Wing/lighting interaction (flash issue).FIXED Jetway 2L behaviour (A340 parity).ADDED Full cabin light-off option on FA Panel.FIXED Setting "Night Mode" on FA Panel correctly dims lightscape OIS💻FIXED Door control logic from EFB ground menu.FIXED Enroute map rendering, refresh logic, and layer stability.FIXED Multi-page SID/STAR/APP chart rendering.FIXED Takeoff config workflow when cabin not ready.FIXED Terrain download status reporting.FIXED ZFW entry and performance workflow in OIS.FIXED Landing performance FT/M conversion.FIXED EFB map refresh &amp; state management.ADDED “Reset to Recommended Levels” for volume settings.ADDED Permanent HUD cover toggle in equipment page.ADDED Chart viewer UI improvements (text scaling, accessibility). SOUND 🔊ADDED Sound OverhaulFIXED Electrical power-up transitions and sequence timing.FIXED Callout timing including altitude, configuration, and GPWS events.FIXED RAT deployment audio.FIXED Internal engine volume scaling across all phases.ADDED full overhaul of engine and ambient soundscape (interior + exterior).ADDED Improved buzzsaw, spool, and airflow effects.ADDED Avionics bay ambience with no power.ADDED Cockpit-door attenuation for cabin announcements.ADDED New layered cockpit and cabin ambience for more spatial depth.  Please see below a known issues list that will be fixed in next week hotfix: 1.1.7 RC1 Known Issues- FS24: Wipers animation  Inop- FS24: 900/ULR - Rear cargo door model mesh causing all liveries with intersecting colorways to render white square- FS24: Cabin IFE tied to Cabin Lighting power instead of individual power state ‍ The add-on is available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $51 (30% discount). If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/atfsws</id>
    <title>Aerosoft and ToLiss Showcase Flying the A340-600 Pro </title>
    <updated>2025-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/atfsws"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6921a5774976dcbd6fcb7071_-RgS560d3fA-HD.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has released a brand-new preview of its upcoming Airbus A340-600 Pro for MSFS 2024, offering a full-length walkthrough of four scenarios that were first shown publicly at last week’s FS Conference. It gives the clearest look yet at the aircraft’s systems, failure logic, and in-flight behaviour. In the new video, Aerosoft community manager Rafi and ToLiss developer Torsten guide viewers through each scenario, crafted specifically to highlight various system features, rather than simply A to B (which we will see more of later!). You can watch the full scenario showcase here.  The first scenario is a “straightforward” landing into Quito, as straightforward as landings into Quito can be.  Throughout the video, Torsten offers commentary on how each system reacts, why specific procedures exist, and what real-world Airbus pilots would experience in each situation. The aircraft is set up for an RNP final at around 9,000 ft, using the built-in autosave/load system. Here, there are no failures at the show, though the thin air and higher ground speed at Quito still make for a challenge.  The second run repeats the approach, but sabotages the air data system midway, leaving the aircraft in alternate law, and forcing you to fly pitch and power using the backup speed tape. From there, the demo moves to Frankfurt for a dual hydraulic failure, with both green and blue systems out, autopilot gone, and even the slats freeze after the second hydraulic loss. We also get to see the gravity-drop landing gear extension. The final scenario recreates a V1 engine failure in Frankfurt, with knock-on failures such as a green-system leak, slat asymmetry, an abnormal bleed configuration, and an eroded braking option. While Aerosoft emphasises that the aircraft is still in development, this video marks the first time the public has seen the A340-600 Pro in action. The team avoids showing the external model for now; however, external previews are “not far away”. There will also be a full-flight livestream featuring real A340 pilots down the line. They also previously stated the A340-600 Pro is still on track for release before Christmas, though a short slip into January remains possible if a late blocker appears.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2025-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
