<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-03-24T18:23:18.634620+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/adipwm</id>
    <title>AeroDesigns Releases Portland International Jetport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/adipwm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64162f77353639cc044e95cf_jet1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="152312"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AeroDesigns has recently released their rendition of Portland International Jetport (KPWM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Portland in Maine with a yearly average of 2 million passengers.  The airport was conceived in the late 1920s as a landing strip for Dr. Clifford Strange. It saw commercial action for the first time in 1931, with a Boston-Maine Airways flight from Portland to Boston. The city of Portland eventually purchased the airport and renamed it to Portland-Westbrook Municipal Airport, which explains its origin code (PWM).  Portland Jetport is served by eleven domestic airlines: American Airlines, American Eagle, Breeze Airways, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Frontier Airlines, JetBlue, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. Cheapflights consider it the third most affordable airport in New England.  Originally intended to be just a port of their KPWM for X-Plane 11, the scenery’s assets were entirely reworked, including ground textures, ground markings, taxi layout, a complete retexturing of the terminal building (externally and internally) with extra clutter to provide even better immersion. It also includes extra work on details such as dirt, extra ground service equipment, etc.   It features highly accurate and detailed 3D models of the terminal (internally and externally), detailed landside buildings, custom-modeled jetways, HDR, accurate night lighting, high-resolution ground textures and markings, custom PBR for all textures, accurately placed ground clutter, fully customized runway and taxiway lighting, and a custom GSX profile, packaged into the scenery folder.  It’s available on the Contrail Store for roughly $18.26 (excluding VAT), requiring at least 1.23 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dbsbei</id>
    <title>DarkBlueScenery Releases Beijing Capital International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dbsbei" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6416390f3ea2020411c1000b_pek1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2453585"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane.  DarkBlueScenery has recently released their rendition of Beijing Capital International Airport (ZBAA) for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12, one of the two international airports serving the Metropolitan Area of Beijing, in China. Pre-pandemic, the passenger figures sat at a whopping 100 million passengers annually (2018), placing it among the busiest in Asia.   Opened in March 1958, the airport initially had a single terminal building and a 2,500-meter runway. It was extended to 3,200 meters in 1966 and 3,800 meters in 1982. The second runway was built in 1978, 3,200 meters long. Around that same period came the new Terminal 1, large enough for 12 aircraft but soon proven inadequate given the traffic boom in the 1990s, justifying further expansion that came to fruition in 1999, with the opening of Terminal 2 and a total renovation of Terminal 1.   The Beijing Olympics called for further expansion work to handle all the extra work, bringing a new runway and a new terminal (T3), which was the largest man-made structure in the World in terms of area coverage. After hosting the Olympics, it quickly rose to the top among the busiest airports in Asia, surpassing Tokyo Haneda.  It’s a hub for Air China and Hainan Airlines, offering a broad domestic and international route network. It’s visited by many airlines from all over the World, including Air France, Cathay Pacific, Egyptair, Emirates, Etihad Airways, Japan Airlines, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Singapore Airlines, Thai Airways, and Turkish Airlines. Cargo-wise, it houses Air China Cargo and China Postal Airlines and gets visited by many cargo carriers from all over, including Cargolux, FedEx, Lufthansa Cargo, and Singapore Airlines Cargo.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground markings, high-detail 3D model of the terminal, cargo buildings, custom night lighting, updated ground layout, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.99, requiring at least 1.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/barcia</id>
    <title>Barelli MSFS Addon Releases Rome-Ciampino International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/barcia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64163f5a3b87d45f63ea3a16_cia1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="414356"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Barelli MSFS Addon has recently released their rendition of Rome-Ciampino International Airport (LIRA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the secondary international airport of Rome, averaging 5 million passengers per year.  Ciampino is one of the oldest airports in operation, dating back to 1916. It was the airport of choice for Umberto Nobile on his expedition to the North Pole ten years after the airport’s opening with the airship Norge. It was the first aircraft to reach the north pole and fly across the polar ice cap from Europe to North America. Four years later, Ciampino was the testing ground for the first helicopter prototype, designed by Corradino D’Ascanio.   Captured by the USAF during late World War 2, it became a USAF military airfield, used as a transport air base by C-47 Skytrains, and temporarily flying A-36 Apaches right after its capture from the German forces. ‍ Before the opening of Fiumicino, Ciampino was Rome’s main airport, with an average of 2 million passengers a year. It saw its darkest age during the next couple of decades after Fiumicino’s opening, handling only charter and executive traffic until low-cost carriers embraced it in the early 2000s. It went from stagnation to one of the fastest-growing airports in Italy, with a whopping 16.75% increase from 2005 to 2006 and 9% from 2006 to 2007, sitting at that 5 million ballpark up until recently (with an apparent drop during the pandemic).  It’s a hub for the low-cost giant Ryanair, with thirty-two European destinations. WizzAir is also a frequent visitor, with six destinations.   The scenery features a high-detail terminal with custom ground markings, custom ground clutter, a detailed parking lot, landside buildings, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $18.27, requiring at least 1.2 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/alklar</id>
    <title>Alkee Creations Releases Larestan International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/alklar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6416439fb87dcfda2a43c9e9_lar1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2183638"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Alkee Creations has recently released their rendition of Larestan International Airport (OISL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Lar, in Iran.   With its initial operations dating back to 1983, it was an exclusively domestic airport until the end of the Persian Gulf War, when it got its first international route to Dubai.   The airport is owned by the Government of Iran and operated by Iran Airports Company, featuring a single terminal that can handle up to 250,000 passengers a year.   The annual figures sit at 161,000 passengers annually (as of 2017). It’s served by five airlines, including flydubai (Dubai), Iran Air (Doha, Dubai, Kuwait City, and Tehran-Mehrabad), Kish Air (Najaf, Tehran-Mehrabad), Pars Air (Tehran-Mehrabad), and Qeshm Air (Dubai, and Tehran-Mehrabad).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the passenger terminal with its interior, PBR texturing on most models, accurate ground layout, taxi signs and taxiways according to real-world charts, accurate windsock positioning, and FPS-friendly optimization.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.44, requiring at least 297.47 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tsskuc</id>
    <title>The Secret Studio Releases Kuching International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tsskuc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64179473b915f1077ed78f4f_kuc1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="803491"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Secret Studio has recently released their rendition of Kuching International Airport (WBGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 6 million passengers.  Kuching Intl serves the southwestern region of Sarawak, in Malaysia, sitting just 11 kilometers south of Kuching. The structure is partially shared with RMAF Kuching, which houses the 7th squadron of the Royal Malaysian Air Force.   The airport started as an airstrip in 1938, with 640 meters of total length. The first terminal building came nearly 12 years later, relatively small, “L” shaped, and single-story. The runway then was just 1,372 meters long. With the rapid growth in the 50s, the early 1960s saw further expansion work, with a new runway lengthening and a terminal enlargement.   The 1970s started with plans to transform Kuching into an international airport, which demanded further runway length and terminal size expansions. It all came to fruition within that decade, with the runway reaching 2,454 meters in length, and the new terminal opened in 1983, replacing the old one with a three-story, 13,000 square meters passenger terminal.  The early 2000s brought a massive increase in traffic figures, making the now-old terminal feel cramped. They have decided to build a new terminal from the inside out and progressively replace the old bits. It was inaugurated in January 2006, with full completion in April of that same year. It increased the terminal size from 13,000 to 46,000 square meters, along with a runway extension from the former 2,454 meters to 3,780 meters.   KIA is served by nine airlines (AirAsia, AirAsia X, Batik Air Malaysia, Firefly, Malaysia Airlines, MASwings, MYAirline, Royal Brunei Airlines, and Scoot), sporting a significant domestic network and a couple of international destinations.   The scenery features custom-made buildings that match as closely as possible with reference data, a custom CAT I ILS for runway 07, a detailed rendition of the main passenger terminal with its interior, retail booths, and stores, and a custom-made VDGS system.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $19.11, requiring at least 467.30 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/caprin</id>
    <title>CanadianFlightSimStudios Releases Prince Rupert Airport for MSFS and XP</title>
    <updated>2023-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/caprin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6417b6e698a66b751ca2d5f9_5718e7_513edd9c965f4c13949932f0b7e6c1da_mv2.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="526478"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Canada4XPlane, who rebranded to CanadianFlightSimStudios to better represent their product line, has released Prince Rupert Airport (CYPR) for both Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12. Prince Rupert Airport, located in the Pacific Northwest in the province of British Columbia, is an island airport that sees a plethora of general aviation traffic while also servicing various commercial airlines, such as Air Canada Express and Northern Thunderbird Air. The field contains a single runway at a length of 6000 feet, allowing for various aircraft types. The scenery contains various similar features available in both the MSFS and XP12 versions, including custom vegetation models, nearby landmarks, HDR lighting, and even a custom mesh to bring the airport surroundings to life. The MSFS and XP12 feature lists can be seen below. Microsoft Flight Simulator Feature List: X-Plane 12 Feature List: ‍ CanadianFlightSimStudio’s rendition of Prince Rupert Airport is available for both Microsoft Flight Simulator and X-Plane 12 for CAD $13.00 via the developer’s store, or via Orbx for AUD $13.00. The stores are linked below. CanadianFlightSimStudio’s Store: X-Plane 12 Version Microsoft Flight Simulator Version Orbx Store: X-Plane 12 Version Microsoft Flight Simulator Version ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/320neo</id>
    <title>Toliss Release A320 NEO For X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/320neo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6419fb20501b9dfbeffb3d18_315337_ToLiss_A320_NEO_store_images_-_Picture25.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3030524"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Plane aircraft developers Toliss have released their all-new A320 Neo for XP11 and XP12. The aircraft comes as the latest edition to their fleet of Airbus products, which includes the A319, A321 and A340. This latest release aims to simulate the NEO version of the A320 to the highest level possible with many new and improved features not seen before on Toliss aircraft.  Some of the featured highlights of this new aircraft include:  This latest edition to the Toliss fleet can be picked up from the Xplane.org store for $89.99 </summary>
    <published>2023-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmds12</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS SU12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmds12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641b72c5f77af91b0b0a0e18_pin1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2801136"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently issued a new update to their 737 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding SU12 compatibility, bug fixes,  navdata format changes, and structural work to support the upcoming Universal Flight Tablet better.  Among the bug fixes, it’s important to mention that PMDG has addressed the parking brake bug introduced with SU12 Beta. It’s a temporary fix that will give mostly regular operation but with some oddities if the user has high-end pedals, as the parking brake could be set or released without entirely depressing both pedals. They mention it will be reverted to the usual logic once Asobo fixes the problem.  In the announcement post, PMDG briefly mentioned the status of the remainder of the 737 lineup in regards to their Marketplace availability, saying it’s still being prepared and the release date will vary according to Microsoft’s approval process, which has been sped up recently but they hesitate on setting a specific timeline. The same applies to the upcoming Xbox compatibility, with no timeframe but work being done in the meantime.   The Universal Flight Tablet is progressing nicely, with a functioning Operational Performance Tool and charts. Both features are soon to hit testing for validation. They also mention further work on improving the UI/UX before the testing begins, which is why they haven’t shown any screenshots yet.  They finish with the NAVDATA progress, which is still underway and soon to hit testing, allowing for advanced FMS lateral path management capabilities once it’s done.  The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600), $49.99 (737-900), and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Pictures are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lshmd8</id>
    <title>Leonardo Software House Updates MD-82 and Releases MD-83 &amp; MD-88 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lshmd8" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641c248fe177817d2f170b29_le1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="997779"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Stefano from Leonardo Software House has announced in their forum an upcoming update to the MD-82 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, along with the release of two expansions, the MD-83 and the MD-88, free for previous owners (of the P3D version).  The new update brings quality-of-life enhancements while keeping your previous settings and airframes. The fixes include MDClient CTD mitigations, SimBrief import unit mismatch (pax weight approximations), improved visual effects for engine smoke and engine fire, compatibility improvements with default jetways, and documentation changes. The full changelog follows down below:  FIXED - fixed issue when changing APPROACH while already navigating the STAR; - fixed issue in W&amp;B efb app resetting changes when reopening app (if SimBrief/PFPX option not set); - fixed issue in MDClient crashing to desktop when printing subsequent ACARS messages; - fixed approximations issues for pax weight when importing from SimBrief using lbs units; EFFECTS - improved engine smoke effect; - improved engire fire effect; MODEL - fixed wrong uv mapping of lower aft antenna; OTHER - added option to force 'norm to' in efb perf app (so it shows the same values as the speed card); - changed jetwey setup to have it properly set on defualt scenery. Many add-on scenery do not comply with ASOBO req, and the result is poor there; - elevator will always be displaced when resting or taxing very slow on a windy day, even after end of first flight; - added compatibility for MD-83/-88 extension pack; - added volume settings for BG music in Load Manager; - when realistic mode is enabled, ACARS LOAD SHEET can have small random varation with respect to OFP; DOCUMENTATION - updated Fly the Maddog X Quick Guide MSFS 2020; - updated Fly the Maddog X User Manual MSFS 2020.  The MD-83 &amp; MD-88 expansion is free for previous owners (Prepar3d version). It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $26.96, requiring at least 212.95 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cdrgot</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Releases Göteborg Landvetter Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cdrgot" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641cb4889b9d510039d9c3c6_esgg1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3357863"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Chudoba Design has recently released their rendition of Göteborg Landvetter Airport (ESGG) for X-Plane 11 and 12, serving the city of Gothenburg in Sweden. It’s the second largest airport in the country after Stockholm-Arlanda, averaging nearly 7 million passengers yearly.  The airport, built to replace the Torslanda Airport, was inaugurated in October 1977 by King Carl XVI Gustaf after five years of construction work. It’s located in Härryda, a municipality near Gothenburg, yet named after the neighboring administrative district (Landvetter) because it was easier to pronounce. Air traffic was launched three days later, with a SAS DC-9 being the first airplane to land on the runway. The first day of operations saw around 60 movements in total.   Landvetter originally had two terminals, built to handle up to 3,500,000 passengers yearly. Eventually, they merged into a single terminal with eleven air bridges and many remote stands.   It’s a focus city for Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, Scandinavian Airlines, SunClass Airlines, and TUI fly Nordic, sporting a considerable inter-European route network. The visitors’ list includes major European carriers, like Air France, Austrian Airlines, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Finnair, KLM, Lufthansa, and Swiss.   The scenery features PBR textures, SAM integration, performance-oriented optimization, custom buildings and objects, custom jetways, accurate night lighting, and compatibility with X-Plane 11 and 12.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $17.25, requiring at least 1.8 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dwcrjr</id>
    <title>DeltaWing Simulations Releases CRJ-1000 for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dwcrjr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641cb781677b132bdff8ca71_DWSim-CRJ1000-001-1024x609.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="105681"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. DeltaWing Simulations, the developers of the CRJ 700/900 for X-Plane, have released the next model of the CRJ family. The CRJ-1000 is the largest member of the Canadair Regional Jet Family and the final model produced.  The Mitsubishi CRJ-1000 was originally designed and built by Bombardier Aerospace of Canada. The CRJ-1000 was the final model of the CRJ family. The -1000 was an extension of the earlier models and featured more powerful General Electric engines. This aircraft has a seating capacity for 107 passengers in a single-class layout, which proved to make the aircraft extremely unpopular in the North American regional market. The CRJ-700 was the overwhelmingly more successful model of the family. This was due to the United States Regional Carriers being limited by scope clauses set by the larger mainline aircraft. The CRJ-1000 ended production in 2018 having only produced 63 units.  The DeltaWing CRJ-1000 has many features users of their CRJ 700/900 products will already be familiar with, a brief feature list is as follows: ‍ To find the complete feature list, or to purchase the aircraft, please visit the X-Plane.org Store. This aircraft will cost $49.95 USD and is X-Plane 12 compatible only. Existing owners of the CRJ-700 or -900 can find a coupon for 30% off with the invoice for your original purchase.</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a1rdw1</id>
    <title>A1R Design Bureau Releases Chilton DW-1A for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a1rdw1" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641cbd50dd19958e4fd2347e_a1r-chilton-dw-1a_1_ss_m_230307122802.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="25550"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Long-term aircraft developer A1R Design Bureau, known for creating vintage aircraft for MSFS and other simulators; such as the Ryan ST-A Special, has released its next project. The DW-1A is a Light Sport Aircraft designed in Britain in the late 1930s. It featured a 32-Hp automobile engine that had been modified for aviation use. Only 4 examples were officially built, with another 3 being built for amateur use. The DW-1A featured an all-wood construction with fabric control surfaces. This aircraft represents the pre-war recreational aircraft that vintage aircraft lovers can bring to their MSFS hangar. The A1R DW-1A can be purchased at the Just Flight Store for $21.49 USD and will require 1.42 GB of storage to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more aircraft releases.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsbonz</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Bonanza Steam Gauge Overhaul</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsbonz" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641cbf997f77eaac7893fe45_steam-gauge-overhaul-analog-bonanza_1_ss_l_230215160444.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="502647"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has released the following product in its line of aircraft overhauls. Similar to their King Air release, Black Square has created a study-level remake of the Beechcraft Bonanza, an aircraft that is provided with the simulator. As with the previous release, this aircraft includes a completely reimagined interior and a full overhaul of the systems.  This release brings some new features as well. Persistent wear has been implemented so users can pick up their aircraft exactly how they left it. As with the previous release, the aircraft comes with several avionics packages so the user can choose their level of equipment. A complete feature list can be found below:  ‍ Systems ‍ Cockpit ‍ This addition will also come with realistic normal and emergency checklists and an improved sound set.   This addition can be purchased over at the Just Flight Store for $32.99 USD. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news.      ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsbarn</id>
    <title>Black Square Releases Baron Steam Gauge Overhaul for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsbarn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641cc629ffba87c39395bd1e_steam-gauge-overhaul-analog-baron_7_ss_l_230215155954.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="305677"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Black Square has released another product in its line of aircraft overhauls. Similar to their previous releases, Black Square has created a study-level remake of the Beechcraft Baron, an aircraft that is provided with the simulator. As with the previous release, this aircraft includes a completely rebuilt interior and a full overhaul of the systems.  This release carries over features users of the other steam gauge products will be familiar with, such as animated circuit breakers and persistent wear. As with the previous release, the aircraft comes with several avionics packages so the user can choose their level of equipment. A complete feature list can be found below:  ‍ Systems ‍ Cockpit ‍ This addition will also include realistic normal and emergency checklists with over 500 checklist items and an improved sound set.   This addition can be purchased at the Just Flight Store for $32.99 USD. A bundle is also available which includes both the analog baron and bonanza. You must be a user of either the Deluxe or Premium Deluxe edition to use. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news.</summary>
    <published>2023-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inichi</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Chios Island National Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inichi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641da9ebb4ae9324c4ab1fd6_chios1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="457668"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of Chios Island National Airport (LGHI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 16th busiest airport in Greece with a yearly average of 240,000 passengers. It serves Chios, the fifth-largest Greek island.  Owned by the government, Chios Airport started its operations in mid-1969 with an Olympic Airways flight from Athens. It underwent several upgrades, including a new passenger terminal in the 1980s. According to Greek Travel Pages, the airport recently received 9.6 million euros in funding from the National Strategic Reference Framework to upgrade the infrastructure and facilities, expanding the terminal to comport higher traffic figures. Deputy Minister Giorgios Karagiannis has mentioned it’s part of a broader plan to modernize the airports in the country.  With a single, 1,511-meter-long runway, it mostly gets regional traffic from either Olympic Air or Sky Express’ ATR fleet, but it can fit up to an Airbus A320/ Boeing 738. The airlines mentioned above are the only ones currently serving the airport, with frequent flights to Athens, Thessaloniki, Lemnos, Mytilene, Rhodes, and Samos.   The scenery features hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation with custom ground decals, signposts, vegetation, parking barriers, and more, accurate real-world decals and advertisements, accurately placed lighting, surrounding objects including shops and boats, and hand-placed ground service equipment properly scattered around.   It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $8.58, requiring at least 1.84 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/chupro</id>
    <title>Chudoba Design Announces "Project People" for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2023-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/chupro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/641db020bb63c4b35f014517_pp4.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1346999"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Yesterday, Chudoba Design made an announcement post on their Facebook page regarding their release of Gothenburg for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12 and a new project, temporarily named "Project People," bringing Inverse Kinematics animated 3D people into X-Plane.  The project will involve renting a motion capture studio for two weeks in April to capture a wide range of movements that can be used to create models of idle people, passengers, ramp agents, and more. These models will be imported into X-Plane as an extensive library, and the best part is that it will be free for users and freeware scenery creators. Payware scenery creators will only need to pay a small fee per airport that uses the library.   They have also mentioned the possibility of a potential MSFS conversion in the future "if everything goes well" while also reinforcing it's their biggest project to date.  ‍ While the focus is currently on "Project People," Chudoba Design plans to bring more sceneries to X-Plane and convert some of their existing sceneries to MSFS. LBBG, HETB, and HEMM will be brought to MSFS, and they also plan to recreate some objects in LROP and completely recreate groundpoly in LKPR. With all these exciting developments, users can look forward to an even more immersive simulation experience with Chudoba Design.  There is no information on a potential release date, but the developer recommends keeping an eye on their Discord for further details.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
