<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-10-08T18:32:06.436109+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerovj</id>
    <title>Aerobask Release ViperJet For XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerovj" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6334ab59349254af721e331f_viperjet3.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="144016"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular X-Plane aircraft developers Aerobask, best known for their Phenom 300 and upcoming Falcon 8X have just released an all-new aircraft! The ViperJet. The ViperJet is a home-built Jet aircraft which first flew toward the end of 1999. It then made its public debut at AirVenture in the year 2000. The base kit retails for around $200,000 but most complete aircraft end up being finished closer to the $350,000 range. Figures from April 2020 show that there are currently 7 ViperJet aircraft registered in the USA.  Thanks to Aerobask, you can now have your very own ViperJet!  The aircraft features include:  To read a complete feature list or pick up your own ViperJet, visit the X-plane.org store where you can get it for $34.95</summary>
    <published>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrnah</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Releases New A320 Hotfix</title>
    <updated>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrnah" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6335d703e818b60e18eabac2_fnx1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="588509"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has just released a new hotfix to their recent A320 update, addressing issues with the rudders and landing behavior (it was prone to bouncing even with smooth touchdowns, introduced with the first hotfix that addressed the drag coefficient of the flaps). The update is available on their website for registered customers. ‍ ‍ A320 v1.0.3.134 [SYSTEM]  - Adjusted custom low speed friction model to be slightly more fluid  - Fixed incorrect air/ground mix factor causing irrecoverable nose down elevator after a bounced landing  - Removed alpha-buffer pseudo-prot, causing issues with flare authority in certain conditions [FM]  - Adjusted spoiler efficacy  - Improved suspension geometry and setup to reduce bouncing, absorbing more energy on touchdown and subsequently sitting lower on the ground  - Added lift dumping to spoilers so the aircraft is more stable after touchdown in a crosswind  - Improved aircraft's crosswind and weathervaning characteristics  - Adjusted lateral tyre friction to prevent weight on wheels sideslip and/or unintended ice skating ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/c510mu</id>
    <title>Cockspur C510 Mustang Released </title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/c510mu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63373766a015491a7a531238_C510_Promo_1-600x312.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="167576"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSFS aircraft developers Cockspur have released their all-new C510 Mustang for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This release may come as a surprise to some in the community who have not been following development too closely, as initially it was due to release a little further down the road.  The C510 is a very light business jet developed and built by the Cessna aircraft company. The mustang is approved for single pilot operations and seats 4 passengers in the standard configuration. It is also used by various operators throughout the world as an air-ambulance which has been recreated by the Cockspur team! The aircraft offers the following features;  -3 different variants; Standard, High Sierra, and air ambulance -Multiple liveries -Different static elements depending on variant -Accurate flight model -Accurate systems modelling -Built from scratch for MSFS -Interactive Cabin -Visible passengers -Custom engine sounds -Extensive documentation -Developed with help from real Mustang Pilots -G1000 NXi integration The Cockspur C510 can be purchased from the Cockspur website for Euro 24.99 ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfscn</id>
    <title>MSFS World Update XI Canada Is Now Available</title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfscn" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63373970708fb006caf3d578_MSFS_WU11_Canada_NoSnipe_Logo_NoText.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="931127"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSFS have released their all-new world update XI which focuses on Canada. One of the most stunning countries in the world, Canada is renowned for its incredible wildlife, lake districts, mountain ranges and of course Tim Hortons coffee! The new update from the team behind MSFS brings more focus and detail to Canada than ever seen before in a flight sim.  Asobo revealed: "In creating World Update XI: Canada, the Microsoft Flight Simulator team processed troves of its latest geospatial data, including digital elevation models, satellite imagery, and aerial photography. Complementing the data, models and imagery, the update highlights 12 urban regions enhanced with the latest photogrammetry data and features 87 hand-crafted points of interest" Just some of the new cities which have received an overhaul in this latest update are:  The update also brings 5 brand new handcrafted airports to MSFS, these are:  ‍ Best of all, this new world update is completely  free! to read a full changelog view the MSFS website. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/urbcms</id>
    <title>UK2000 Releases Belfast City for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/urbcms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63374a011c29c2396cf6850d_egac1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="451303"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 has recently released their rendition of George Best Belfast City Airport (EGAC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second airport serving the city of Belfast, located right in the heart of it and with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. Unlike Belfast Aldergrove, most of their routes are within the United Kingdom, with one international leg to Amsterdam with KLM, with seasonal charters to Barcelona and Bologna to begin in 2023, operated by EasyJet. The scenery uses PBR materials, including realistic ground markings, modeled interiors for both tower and pier, animated jetways, custom vegetation, and optimized for high performance. The feature list follows down below: The product is available on UK2000’s webpage for £14.99 or Flightsim.to for $14.99 and requires at least 121 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asdrka</id>
    <title>Aviation-Sim-Design Releases Kyritz Airfield for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asdrka" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63374b591167780c714abe9e_edbk.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="437983"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviation-Sim-Design has just released their rendition of Kyritz Airfield (EDBK)for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a commercial airfield in a district near Berlin and close to the Baltic Sea. With two runways of one kilometer each (asphalt and grass), it’s the ideal environment for general aviation airplanes and gliders. With a modern lighting infrastructure, nocturnal flight operations are allowed, making it a jack-of-all-trades for small aircraft. The feature list follows down below: The product can be purchased on flightsim.to for $10.49 and requires at least 1.26 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msrsam</id>
    <title>MK Studios Releases Shannon Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msrsam" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63387c0c0ebc1cf35e918f33_shannon1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="353094"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MK Studios has just released their rendition of Shannon Airport (EINN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Ireland, with plenty of aviation history on its back (first transatlantic proving flight, first duty-free airport shop, Europe’s first United States border preclearance facility, the list goes on). Back in the 1960s, it was a busy refueling stop for international carriers crossing the Atlantic. Nowadays, it averages around 1.7 million passengers every year (pre-pandemic). It’s a focus city for Ryanair, with over 16 routes. The scenery features an updated ground layout, realistic night lighting, satellite coverage around the airport and a detailed mesh. It can be purchased for $12.78 on Orbx Direct and requires at least 2.13 GB of free disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arpsif</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Palm Springs International for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arpsif" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63389b24b57d0c747a0a83bd_psp.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="329468"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos has just released their rendition of Palm Springs International Airport (KPSP) for X-Plane, a popular tourist destination with a yearly average of 2.5 million passengers. Located in the famous Coachella Valley, it provides a challenging and visually impressive arrival, with no ILS to help out in case of bad visibility. It is an important transit airport, served by many airlines with multiple route options. The scenery features PBR materials, high-resolution textures, custom ground clutter, and weathering, performance-friendly optimization, enhanced orthophoto imagery, hand-placed vegetation, and full compatibility with both X-Plane 11 and 12. It can be purchased on Axonos’ Gumroad Store for $19.95 and requires at least 3.69 GB of free disk space to install. They have also made an MSFS version that retails for $18.88.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inibla</id>
    <title>iniBuilds KLAX Los Angeles release date announced!</title>
    <updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inibla" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633a335815b41b5e27e87365_26_952fa232-ddec-4761-af9f-d0fe7fa9806c.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="500557"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IniBuilds is excited to announce their anticipated LAX scenery scheduled for release tomorrow! Los Angeles known for its impressive travel numbers has finally been brought alive with iniBuilds' version of SoCal's mega airport. This release includes handmade ground textures and dynamic lighting including the iconic entryway sign from KLAX. Other details include modeled terminal concourses, logos, unique art details, and more! Feature list is detailed below. ‍ ‍ You can grab your copy tomorrow at iniBuilds's store. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msrpia</id>
    <title>M’M Simulations Releases Pristina International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msrpia" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633a6e88dd6b0e7b1ef7c64a_pristina1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="273940"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. M’M Simulations has just released their rendition of Phristina International Airport Adem Jashari (BKPR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Currently the only port of entry to Kosovo (via air), with a yearly average of 2 million passengers, served by multiple European airlines such as Austrian Airlines, Eurowings, Swiss, and Wizz Air. Originally built as a military air base, it used to contain the second largest military underground hangar complex in Yugoslavia.  The scenery features an accurately modeled terminal (with an interior), custom night lighting, parking positions that match real-life data, PBR materials, and a real-world-based terraforming profile. The airport is available on flightsim.to for $17.49 or on SimMarket for €17.84 and requires at least 4.51 GB of free hard disk space to install.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpgaha</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Announces Hot Air Balloon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpgaha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633a76576bae883c21e27d7b_balloon.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="454327"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has just announced their newest add-on project, a Hot Air Balloon for Microsoft Flight Simulator, releasing this Friday (October 7th) for $15.00, exclusively on their website. Known for developing helicopters, such as the H135 mod with an impressive 534000 downloads and their payware H145, this is their first venture into the ballooning universe. The HPG Hot Air Balloon comes with a huge feature list, as seen down below: ‍ Highly Detailed 3D Model, Textures and Animations - Professionally modeled with incredible interior and exterior details - 17 liveries included, all at 4K resolution and with PBR textures inside and out - Fully animated cockpit and animations for inflation, deflation, stall and collapse - Animated 3D humans including a hot air balloon operator and 2 passengers - Designed and optimized for VR with great FPS performance, working VR Cockpit Zoom and proper visual scaling throughout the model ‍ Avionics &amp; Systems - Steam gauges showing barometric altitude, vertical speed and envelope thermometer - Available AI pilot that can control the hot air balloon based off terrain or altitude - EFB tablet included with maps and additional apps available - Balloonist Maps App: shows GPS speed and track - Little NavMap App: connect to LNM, the free open source flight planner, navigation tool, moving map, airport search and airport information system - Nearby Radio Stations: listen to radio stations local to the area you're currently flying in ‍ Hot Air Balloon Flight Model - Fully integrated internal hot air balloon flight model and envelope simulation - Power Plant: 2x 12 million BTU burners with realistic visual and sound effects ‍ Immersive Sound Pack - Realistic burner and environmental sounds   Bonus Features - Launch fireworks with realistic visual and audio smoke and explosion effects - Create other nearby AI flown HPG Hot Air Balloons on demand - HPG Hot Air Balloon can be set to follow a MSFS flight plan or current wind conditions Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/oapaxm</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Pacific Aerospace 750 XSTOL for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/oapaxm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633bd4810705fb4286bfdab7_orbx1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="205104"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has just announced the development and imminent release of their newest project, a Pacific Aerospace 750 XSTOL for Microsoft Flight Simulator, coming in four variations: skydiving, agricultural, cargo, and passenger. You can read more about them and their unique features on their forum announcement. Manufactured in New Zealand, the versatile aircraft carries up to 9 passengers or 17 parachutists (skydiving variant), powered by a Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6 Turboprop engine that produces 750hp, making it plenty powerful and allowing it to take off and land in less than 244 meters!  As far as systems and avionics are concerned, the real-life counterpart and add-on are single-pilot IFR capable, with two COM and NAV radios, EHSI, CDI, and GPS, along with simulated circuit breakers and an accurate fuel system. They have also released a roadmap for the project where they state a post-release addition of a custom PT6 sound pack, failures, more liveries, landing challenges, bush trips, and more.  The airplane will be available on OrbxDirect “within the coming days” for $24.95, and on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace at a later date. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ife346</id>
    <title>IndiaFoxtEcho Visual Simulations releases M-346 for Microsoft Flight Simulator.</title>
    <updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ife346" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633c6167bbba790b88584aad_302726521_6020609041285840_6318830664896955025_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="755770"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IndiaFoxtEcho Visual Simulations has released their M-346 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Leonardo M-346 is a twin-engine fighter commonly used for training in armed forces, with primary users Israeli Air Force, Italian Airforce, and the Polish Airforce, to name a few. The M-346 was also a contender to replace the T-38 in the US Airforce, being succeeded by the Boeing T-7. India Fox Echo recreated procedures based on the actual M-346 flight manuals, with a focus also on the HUD, MFD, and UFCP. Modeling and texturing details are faithful to the actual aircraft, with ten liveries included.  ‍ ‍ IndiaFoxtecho will improve and add more features to the M-346 as time progresses. Currently available for PC with an XBox version coming soon. The M-346 is available on OrbixDirect and SimMarket. Check out the well-produced trailer by the Italian Virtual Airforce here!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/apaefm</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews A330’s EFB for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/apaefm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633dee8c23c51ff5b6d65c70_as3.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="84857"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a short video, Mathijs Kok from Aerosoft has previewed some of the functionalities of their brand new Electronic Flight Bag (EFB) for the upcoming A330 for Microsoft Flight Simulator. It covers relevant aspects such as Simbrief integration, NavDataPro/Navigraph compatibility, flight planning tools, live map, pushback, etc. There is no information about release date or pricing just yet, but you can follow the development updates on Aerosoft’s forum thread on the A330’s progress.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/hpgrha</id>
    <title>Hype Performance Group Releases Hot Air Balloon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/hpgrha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/633fa905abe2687a20674e52_bal1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="261776"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Hype Performance Group has released their Hot Air Balloon for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Usually known for developing helicopters such as the H135 freeware and the payware H145, they decided to try ballooning next. With a custom flight model, it’s - according to HPG - the first professionally developed hot air balloon for MSFS. The feature list follows down below: The add-on is available on HPG’s website for $15.00. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inivlb</id>
    <title>iniBuilds releases its free Venice Beach Pack for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inivlb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/634189cd5b23083a3a3c648a_VBC.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="583795"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. ‍ iniBuilds released its Venice Beach Pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator today, featuring the well-known attractions Venice offers. iniBuilds recently released its KLAX scenery, making an ideal bundle for scenery covering the Southern California Area. The pack covers the Boardwalk while adding the expected lifeguard shacks, vehicles, and a fictional beach airstrip. Scenery focusing on non-airport environments could soon reshape flight sim scenery. iniScenes is on to something with this package. The KLAX Venice Beach Pack is Free for Microsoft Flight Simulator; on the iniBuilds store.</summary>
    <published>2022-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
