<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-01-27T18:23:17.837949+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/basmem</id>
    <title>BMWorld and AmSim Release Memphis International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/basmem" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c8e01effea5d8108520c10_mem1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2357667"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. BEAUTIFUL MODEL of the WORLD and AmSim have teamed up once again to build and release a rendition of Memphis International Airport (KMEM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the primary international airport serving Memphis, covering 1,600 hectares of land, sporting four runways, and averaging 4 million passengers a year as of recent.   Mainly a cargo airport, known as the FedEx Superhub, it processes a significant number of packages per year, featuring many nonstop destinations all across the globe, along with a network of domestic routes all over the continental United States. For 16 years (between 1993 and 2009), MEM used to be the busiest cargo airport in the World, overtaken by Hong Kong Intl. in 2010 but remained the busiest cargo airport in the country and the entire western hemisphere until 2020, when the COVID-19 eCommerce boom made it take the first place once again, although rather briefly.   Passenger-wise, it averages 80 flights a day, with Delta Airlines being the market share leader with 21.33% (828,000) of the total number of passengers between 2021 and 2022. American Airlines is second, with 20.36% (790,000), and Southwest is third, with 18.47% (717,000). As far as destinations are concerned, Atlanta is the busiest, with 422,000 passengers, followed by Dallas-Fort Worth and Charlotte, with 257,000 and 190,000, respectively.   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with a fully modeled terminal interior, animated jetways, high-resolution custom ground textures, surrounding buildings fully modeled, parallax windows, airline codes assigned to each parking, and FSLTL compatibility.   It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $22.73, requiring at least 2.53 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxlau</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Launceston Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxlau" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63c9d5f38c8a89332bff2688_launce1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="626040"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Launceston Airport (YMLT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second-busiest airport in Tasmania after Hobart, with a yearly average of 1,500,000 passengers (pre-pandemic).  Qantas Group is the biggest operator in the airport, with their subsidiary (JetStar) offering up to six daily flights to and from Melbourne, two daily flights to and from Sydney, and one daily flight to Brisbane. Virgin Australia offers a similar selection with five daily flights to and from Melbourne, one to Sydney, and seasonal flights on select days to Brisbane. Airlines of Tasmania and Sharp Airlines offer a variety of short legs to nearby destinations. Its origins date back to the early 1930s, when it was established as a small grass runway for regional flights, then called The Western Junction Aerodrome. It was officially opened as a government aerodrome in 1931 when over 20,000 people watched Colonel Brinsmead - then controller of civil aviation - “cut the inaugural ribbon.” From 1932 and beyond, small aircraft would fly from Launceston to Flinders Island.  During WW2, it was used by the Royal Australian Air Force as a flight school, preparing pilots for combat. It was the only RAAF air base in  Tasmania. Two of the hangars are still around to this day.  In the early 60s, plans for a Major redevelopment were approved, which included a runway extension, pavement strengthening, and a new terminal building. In 1982, the runway was once again extended to allow for the operation of Boeing 767s. The current privatization came in 1998, with joint ownership between the Launceston City Council and Australia Pacific Airports Corporation. The post-9/11 crisis and the rise of low-cost airlines made the airport grow in passenger traffic, reaching one million passengers for the first time in 2007.  Such exponential growth demanded another expansion, which doubled the size of the terminal and reached completion in November 2009, costing 20 million Australian dollars.  Developed by Ken Hall, an indie, who happens to be from the region and had exclusive access to the airport, taking hundreds of reference pictures to help with the accuracy and even allow for extra realism on the texturing side of things. It features a faithful recreation of the airport as it currently stands, with PBR texturing, static aircraft, detailed hangars, and terminal building. It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $17.03, requiring at least 2.65 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orppsw</id>
    <title>ORBX and PilotPlus Release Swansea Airport for MSFS </title>
    <updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orppsw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cafddf53c71e39f5c8cc22_63be885504258-400x225.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="29143"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ORBX and PilotPlus have teamed up to release a highly detailed and accurate Swansea airport scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This new scenery package is set to give pilots an immersive and realistic flying experience as they navigate the airport and surrounding areas. With state-of-the-art technology and a wealth of information about the real-world airport, Pilots can expect an unparalleled level of realism and attention to detail. The scenery package boasts the following features:  You can purchase this stunning new scenery on the ORBX store for £10.68 today! </summary>
    <published>2023-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdb7m</id>
    <title>PMDG Releases Boeing 737-700 on MSFS' Marketplace</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdb7m" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cb996e473b13dd70d97940_zach1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1081091"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG’s Boeing 737-700 is now available on Microsoft Flight Simulator's marketplace, only on PC at this time and priced at $69.99 (pricing may vary per region).  ‍ The marketplace version is almost identical to the PMDG Store counterpart, featuring three different variations: passenger, BBJ, and cargo, all with accurately represented systems, a high-fidelity flight model, PBR textures, a realistic flight deck, and different cabins matching the chosen variation, along with the ability to pick between winglets or split scimitars. The only difference between both is that the Marketplace version does not come with the Operations Center, which is obtainable from their official downloads section. Updates might also take longer, as the files need to be approved by Microsoft before being pushed to the marketplace. The Boeing 737-700 is a single-aisle, twin-engine jetliner that is part of the 737 aircraft family. It was introduced by Boeing in 1997 as a shorter and more fuel-efficient version of the 737-800, typically seating between 110 and 149 passengers (depending on the configuration), and offering up to 2,950nm of range. Commonly used by airlines for short to medium-haul flights, it's known for its reliability and cost-effectiveness. ‍ Images are courtesy of ZachJaneway. There’s no information regarding the arrival of the -600 and -800 models to the marketplace yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/baw172</id>
    <title>Boris Audio Works Releases Cessna 172 Sound Set for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/baw172" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cba00350b9e2b761ab35e8_boris172.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1087078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Boris Audio Works has recently released their Cessna 172 Sound Set for Microsoft Flight Simulator, built on hours of real-life interior and exterior recordings made with industry-grade equipment. It is their second payware sound set for MSFS, released nearly two months after the first one.   Compatible with both the G1000 and steam gauge variants (and the WBSim 172 modification), featuring different specific sounds for both, such as battery and gyro noise on the steam gauges, which is silent on the G1000, as per real life. The sound set also includes dynamic engine sounds, wind and aerodynamic drag, dynamic touchdown and ground roll, multi-stage stall horn, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:  -Dynamic engine sounds -Wind and aerodynamic drag -Buttons, switches, knobs, and levers -Fuel pump -Batteries, gyros, and avionics fans* -Dynamic touchdowns and ground rolls* -Stall horn with several stages changing intensity depending on AOA -And more! ‍  It’s available on the Threshold Store for $15.00 and SimMarket for roughly $16.24, requiring at least 37 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mldias</id>
    <title>MLD Scenery Releases Iasi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mldias" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cc6a2b15b51488c4e41ee1_iasi1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3268316"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MLD Scenery has recently released their rendition of Iasi International Airport (LRIA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fourth-busiest airport in Romania with a yearly average of 1.3 million passengers (pre-pandemic).  As one of the oldest accredited airports in Romania, its history dates back to almost 100 years ago (1926), when it first became a commercial airport with scheduled flights, operated by CFRNA (Compagnie Franco-Roumaine de Navigation Aérienne). Almost 30 years later, it got a new runway, a modern lighting system, and a passenger terminal followed in 1969, with another upgrade in 2001 to separate domestic and international flights.  A brand new terminal (T2) was built in 2012, increasing its passenger capacity and specially designated for Schengen and domestic flights. A long-term, multi-stage upgrade program started the year after, including a new runway (finished in 2014), a new terminal building (inaugurated in 2015), and an apron extension (completed in 2021).  In early 2022, the managers signed a €66 million contract with an Austrian construction company to design and build a new terminal (T4) and extend the parking lot, increasing the airport’s capacity to 3.3 million passengers yearly. The estimated completion date is sometime in December 2023.  The scenery features a high-fidelity rendition of the airport, with an updated layout (as of 2022), custom ground polygons, custom approach and taxi lights, custom night lighting, parallax windows, and photorealistic textures on the airport buildings. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.16, requiring at least 1.62 GB of free disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsdtgs</id>
    <title>FSDreamTeam Updates GSX Pro for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsdtgs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63cc77b9b0c560cfb0f3392e_gsxpro.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="51362"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FSDreamTeam has recently updated GSX Pro for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding support for remote deicing, new menu colors, and several QoL improvements.  GSX Pro improves and expands the ground services with realistic pushback, catering, refueling, baggage loading, and marshaling, introducing unique features such as visible animated passengers, cargo loading, follow me cars, towbar pushback, de-icing, underground refueling, walk-in gates, VDGS docking systems, and more.   The newest update adds support for remote deicing, allowing the user to call for deicing on remote pads like in real life. FSDT claims it’s just the first step of the update, with the upcoming one featuring editing of custom deicing areas.   The deicing fluid simulation was also improved, with different colors per fluid type (one is yellow, two is clear, three is orange, and four is green) and varying saturation depending on concentration.   GSX’s in-game menu was modified, featuring a new color scheme that better matches the sim’s default color palette, and new icons to help differentiate between runway starts and custom deicing areas.  The update also added an option to ignore departure time when using SimBrief, internal support for the Aerosoft TwinOtter and PMDG DC-6, new safedock types, exclusion patterns to prevent jetways not being recognized correctly on some third-party airports using jetway links as simobjects, and more. The complete changelog follows down below:  ‍ It’s available on FSDreamTeam’s website for $29.99, requiring at least 8 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lun767</id>
    <title>Lunar Simulations Announces Freeware 767 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lun767" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d115cc7306cee1fcfa2819_767-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2394108"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Lunar Simulations has recently announced the development of a freeware Boeing 767 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, set to feature integration with the Salty Simulations mod for proper autopilot behavior, a fully custom primary flight display, an EFB, cockpit animations, and more.   According to the developer (on the announcement post), the development started in October 2021 (1 year and three months ago), with its current progress at a state where they can finally show some of it in the form of screenshots. The feature list includes realistic flight dynamics, a high-quality 3D cockpit and exterior, realistic systems and avionics, accurate performance data, high-resolution textures, and custom sounds and effects (marked as coming soon).   The Boeing 767 is a mid-size, wide-body twin-aisle airliner that first entered service in 1982, designed as a technology bridge between the narrow-body 757 and the wide-body 747/777, seating from 181 to 375 passengers and with a range of 3,850nm to 6,385nm depending on the variant. It has been a popular choice for years due to its fuel efficiency and operational flexibility, suiting domestic (North America) and long-haul operations. Over 1000 767s have been built in total as of 2021.  There’s no information regarding the release date yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/v1sbar</id>
    <title>V1 Studio Releases Barra do Garças Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/v1sbar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d240b0dd107ea7e6b5bac4_bar1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="201025"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. V1 Studio has recently released their rendition of Barra do Garças Airport (SBBW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the northeasternmost part of the state of Mato Grosso in Brazil.   Built in the 1960s, its purpose was to serve as a regional hub for the transportation of agricultural products and other goods. It was not until the 2000s that it underwent significant renovations and expansions, including the construction of a new terminal and a runway upgrade. Now an important regional airport, it is served by Azul Conecta with frequent flights to Cuiaba (Mato Grosso) and Goiânia (Goiás).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with hand-made ground textures, accurately modeled and positioned dynamic lights, custom-made vegetation, high-detail models of the airport buildings, and a true-to-life landside recreation with custom decals, signposts, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket and on the GearDown Simulations Store for roughly $8.16, requiring at least 788 MB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jfltfc</id>
    <title>Just Flight Releases FS Traffic for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jfltfc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d2b6d64c1519733ee93783_traffic1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1074765"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has recently released FS Traffic for Microsoft Flight Simulator, their brand-new AI traffic plugin that injects traffic based on real-world data with matching models, liveries, and accurate scheduling.   FS Traffic features a fleet of native aircraft models with performance in mind, sporting high-definition textures, night lighting, custom animations, custom visual effects, compatibility with airport jetways and ground units, realistic sounds by Turbine Sounds Studios, and compatibility with online networks such as VATSIM, along with tens of thousands of real-life commercial flight plans from different periods, with data sourced from the same supplier used by real-world websites and applications.   Data coverage includes the summer of 2022, with 2021 and 2019 to follow as free updates in the future. The time and the day of the week you choose within the simulator will dictate the density, as it is in real life.  Users can customize their flight plans with Traffic Control Centre, a tool where you can create new flight plans, add liveries, and add new third-party aircraft (as AI). Traffic density can be controlled on the fly with the in-game menu, with the possibility to regenerate it or get rid of it altogether.   The developers claim there is no performance impact compared to the default offline traffic because models are said to be optimized, taking full advantage of the sim’s visuals without tanking the framerate.   It’s available on Just Flight’s Store for $39.99, requiring at least 8.6 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aerosl</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Previews Oslo Gardermoen for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aerosl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d2d403bd20dd67a94dbab7_engm1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3048832"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft has recently previewed the progress on the Oslo Gardermoen (ENGM) rendition for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the busiest airport in Norway with 30 million passengers yearly.   Developed by Jo Erlend, the upcoming OSL is his third Major scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator (he is also the creator of Aerosoft’s Köln-Bonn and Brussels). There’s no feature list yet, but the previewed images show custom jetways, custom ground service equipment, terminal interiors, a piano (perhaps the first piano ever in the simulator?), and a VDGS system.   Oslo Gardermoen is the main airport serving Oslo, located approximately 47 kilometers northeast of the city center. Opened in 1998 as a replacement for the outdated Fornebu Airport, which had been operating since 1939. It was built to modernize and expand Norway’s airport infrastructure and improve accessibility to the capital city, quickly becoming the Main hub for domestic and international travel in the Country.   There is no information regarding the price or release date yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2a250</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations’ Comanche 250 for MSFS Enters Beta Testing</title>
    <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2a250" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d2daee83e88a379f1b44bc_a2a-1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="420712"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations made a forum post announcing their upcoming Piper Comanche 250 for Microsoft Flight Simulator has entered beta testing, with some new features still in the works.   There’s not a lot of information regarding the features, but they have added a quote from a beta tester who claims to love the texturing, sounds, animations, and the EFB. On their original cockpit screenshots thread, A2A stated it’s going to be the best airplane they have ever made in every aspect (physically, visually, and aurally).   The Comanche 250 is a light single-engine, four-seat aircraft produced by Piper Aircraft, first introduced in 1961 as an upgrade to the earlier Comanche 180 model, featuring a more powerful engine and improved performance. Powered by a 250hp Lycoming IO-540-K1A5 six-cylinder engine, it can cruise at 200 mph with a range of up to 800 miles. Known for its sleek design and advanced aerodynamics, it provides a smooth and stable flight experience. It was in production until 1972, formerly quite popular among private pilots, flight schools, and air taxi companies.  The release date and pricing are still unknown, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmdmmr</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmdmmr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d2f96da53b7389cdebae86_mmr1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1355311"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently released an update (v3.00.0060) to their 737 Lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding MMRs (multi-mode radios), minor fixes, and changes to the ground handling behavior.   In the update announcement post, Robert Randazzo states the update is mostly “foundational” with most of it being stripped out of the changelog due to it being internal and focusing on “preparing the ground” for future equipment additions such as the upcoming EFB.  The highlights include the addition of Multi-Mode Radios and the tweaks to the ground handling qualities of the airplane, switching from PMDG’s own internal algorithms to Asobo’s, claimed to be better than before and with the promise of further tweaks to bring a realistic Boeing steering experience. The complete changelog follows down below:  0012223: [Pedestal - Radios/Comms/Navs]introduction of MMRs (GLS functionality pending) (abashkatov) 0012251: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Black texture on all VC's (vscimone) 0012210: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Captain Footrest adjustment (vscimone) 0012253: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Texture clipping on NAV 2 panel (vscimone) 0012228: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Comm 2 strange texture (abashkatov) 0012173: [Virtual Cockpit - Functionality/Click-Spots] F/O PREV PAGE button not animating (vscimone) 0012211: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Right Air outlet needs adjustment (vscimone) 0012198: [External Model - Geometry] Light bleeding through front cabin walls (jbrown) 0012199: [External Model - Geometry] Hole in front of passenger cabin (jbrown) 0012150: [FMS - Performance Pages] Consistent use of custom payload ZFW value (emvaos) 0012190: [General - Ground Operations] Stairs 1L Arrive Even if JTWY INH (hvanrensburg) 0012175: [FMS - Setup/Options Pages] EFIS/MAP Options still greyed out (hvanrensburg) 0012180: [External Model - Liveries] Texture Alignment Between Fuse2 - Fuse3 Left Side (jbrown) 0012176: [Virtual Cockpit - Geometry/Textures] Black texture on top of glareshield (vscimone) 0012226: [Virtual Cockpit - Functionality/Click-Spots] Switches with PMDG Mouse option (hvanrensburg)​ ‍ The 737-900 variant is out of the testing phase, undergoing work on the last-minute details for the impending release.   The Universal Flight Tablet is still being worked on, with a WASM/communication issue depending on input from Asobo to find out whether it’s on their end or a platform problem.  The upcoming DC-6 update is waiting on a platform update before it can be released, and the 777 is still being worked on but with nothing to show for the time being.  The 737 lineup is available on the PMDG Shop for $34.99 (737-600) and $69.99 (737-700 and 737-800, individually).  Pictures are courtesy of Pineapple_Wizard. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbhel</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Helipads LA Police for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbhel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d3ac5bb7fdb4be0e3b9899_lapd1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="814224"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released a set of LAPD helipads in downtown Los Angeles for Microsoft Flight Simulator, part of their Police Activities Expansion Pack aimed at city-building simulation professionals.   The pack features a highly detailed model of the LAPD Heliport, the LAPD headquarters, the LA County Jail, and many Sheriff’s department helipads scattered around the LA basin area. It’s said to offer a unique and realistic look into the daily operations of the police forces in a Major urban area.  The Los Angeles Police Department heliport is a helicopter landing facility in Los Angeles, established in the 1970s as a way for the LAPD to have quick access to the city’s airspace for various policing needs, such as the pursuit of suspects and surveillance. The heliport is also used for training and administrative purposes. Over the years, the LAPD has acquired a fleet of helicopters for use at the heliport,  including the Bell 206 JetRanger, the Airbus H125, and the Airbus AS350. The heliport has become an important part of the LAPD’s policing efforts and is considered one of the busiest law enforcement heliports in the United States.  The new Los Angeles Police Department headquarters is a state-of-the-art facility located in downtown Los Angeles, California. The building was conceived to be environmentally friendly and sustainable, featuring energy-efficient systems and materials. The new headquarters will be a 12-story building with approximately 602,000 square feet, comporting around 1,200 employees, including offices, training rooms, a fitness center, a secure parking structure, and a rooftop terrace. It replaces the old Parker Center, demolished in 2018.  The Los Angeles County Jail is a complex of several facilities located in LA. It’s the largest jail system in the United States, with an average daily population of around 18,000 inmates. It's operated by the Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department and is responsible for the incarceration of individuals who have been arrested or awaiting trial. The jail facilities range from maximum to minimum security and include the Men’s Central Jail, the Twin Towers Correctional Facility, and the Inmate Reception Center. The jail system has been the subject of criticism in the past for issues such as overcrowding, inadequate medical care, and mistreatment of inmates. In recent years, the Department has implemented several reforms addressing these issues, including reducing the jail population, improving conditions for inmates, and increasing transparency and accountability.  It’s available on Orbx Direct for roughly $10.18, requiring at least 1.71 GB of free disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/wbsjpl</id>
    <title>WBSim and JPLogistics Release Cessna 152 v2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/wbsjpl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d3d0f13c4fc129a1106973_152-1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="948161"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WBSim and JPLogistics have recently updated their freeware Cessna 152 to version two, adding external eye candy, engine wear, plug fouling, custom instruments, and more.   The 2.0 update adds an engine cowling and pitot tube cover, wheel chocks (except for the tail dragger variant), and engine realism improvements that include general engine wear, oil usage, overheating, plug fouling, correct pitot icing, and static port blockage. Instrument-wise, they have added a custom KAP140 and KR87 ADF, the option to have a PMS 750, an old ADF and transponder, a newer Garmin transponder, a KN64 DME (still work in progress), and an EGT gauge. The complete changelog/feature list follows down below: ‍ ## V2.0.0 - WBSim Initial Release     - All previous model and texture issues are now resolved (THANK YOU Wombii)     - Functioning External eye candy! (THANK YOU Wombii)         - Engine cowling cover         - Pitot tube cover         - Wheel chocks (missing from tail dragger for now)     - Engine related realism and failures added including         - general engine wear         - oil usage         - overheating         - plug fouling         - correct pitot icing, both port and drain hole         - static port blockage     - Various selectable instruments         - Custom KAP140         - Custom KR87 ADF         - PMS 750 option *         - "old" ADF *         - "old" transponder *         - "newer" Garmin transponder         - KN64 DME (kinda - WIP) *         - EGT gauge     - Flight model from base 152     - Engine tweaks to align speeds and fuel with POH values     - Corrected OAT gauge     - Independent TACH and HOBBS times     - Working breakers that may trip from time to time     - Electrical overhaul (WIP, more to come) ‍     * usage of the 750 will force a few options due to equipment and space issues...         - NO transponder choice, it's built in         - NO DME         - NO ADF choice, KR87 ONLY         - It is how it is...  The Cessna 152 is a two-seat, fixed tricycle gear, general aviation airplane that was first produced in 1977 by Cessna Aircraft Company. The aircraft has a maximum speed of 124 mph and a range of about 480 miles. It’s known for its ease of handling and its ability to operate from small, grassy strips. It has proven to be a reliable and durable airplane, with many still in service today. Despite its age, it remains popular among flight schools and private pilots.  It’s available on Flightsim.to for free, requiring at least 472.37 MB of free disk space to install. Shout out to themsmyshoes on our Discord for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdscaa</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Previews Campo dos Amarais Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdscaa" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63d3d85d2f64d3db09fb342d_campo.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3280059"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations has recently previewed the progress on their rendition of Campo dos Amarais - Prefeito Francisco Amaral State Airport (SDAM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving Campinas, the fourteenth most populous city in Brazil.  Despite not having scheduled flights throughout the year, the traffic figures sit at nearly 40 thousand passengers a year, all of that being general aviation, divided between executive jets, air taxis, and student pilots. With a total of 25 hangars and compatibility with nocturnal operations, it’s the ideal business alternative to Viracopos, the main airport in the region. It’s operated by Rede Voa, a private Brazilian airports consortium responsible for sixteen airports scattered around the country. They won the concession to Campo dos Amarais and four airports in the São Paulo state back in March 2017, when the previous owner, DAESP (the Airways Department of São Paulo State), had to give up on most of their airports due to financial problems.  Developed in close contact with the operator (Rede Voa), the scenery will feature an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with an 85% accurate mesh, custom ground textures, custom vegetation, and more.  There’s no information regarding the release date or pricing, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
