<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-05-21T18:24:03.204376+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2wpb</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases North Palm Beach Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2wpb"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66407f115972d4e91e7d4a11_beach1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of North Palm Beach County General Airport (F45) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a general aviation airport serving West Palm Beach, in Florida, with a yearly average of 100,000 aircraft operations. Opened in 1994, it’s the county’s newest airport. It sits right next to the town of Apix, a former rocket testing facility created as part of Project Suntan during the Space Race. Covering an area of 741 hectares, with a huge part of it dedicated to environmental preserves, it has two asphalt runways and a single turf runway. Both asphalt runways are the exact same length (1,311 meters) but have different widths (30 and 23 meters, respectively). The turf one is slightly shorter, at 1,121 meters. The traffic consists mainly of general aviation activities (93%), with the remaining 7% corresponding to air taxi operations. There are 264 aircraft based at the airport in total. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, custom night lighting, PBR materials, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $10.77, requiring at least 22.22 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/axybcg</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Gold Coast Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/axybcg"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6640963972d7a8203075fdc3_663bec1616443.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos have released their rendition of Gold Coast Airport (YBCG) for X-Plane 12, serving Gold Coast and Queensland, with a yearly average of 5,7 million passengers. ‍ Created in 1936, it was originally named Coolangatta (Aboriginal word for "Place of Good View"), consisted of three grass runways and served as an emergency airport for airmail aircraft flying between Brisbane and Sydney. With the first regular passenger service starting after WWII, it received service from Ansett Australia, Trans Australian Airlines and Butler Air Transport with DC-3s and DC-4s. In 1958, runways and taxiways got paved, allowing the usage of jet planes such as DC-9, and some bigger prop planes like L-188 Electra. Despite the name change in 1989, Gold Coast Airport still retains its original ICAO and IATA codes: YBCG/OOL.  The latest terminal expansion was completed in 2022 and includes more than 19 new parking stands, out of which 4 are equipped with jetbridges. Today, Gold Coast Airport serves 10 airlines flying to 26 different destinations in 3 countries, as well as two more seasonal destinations.  The Axonos YBCG features a highly accurate representation of YBCG with a new apron and taxiway, 3D grass, custom HDR night lighting, PBR and HD textures, color-corrected orthophotos and animated marshalls. ‍ This scenery is available for purchase at the OrbxDirect for roughly $19.89 and requires at least 2.32GB of free disk space. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfsyam</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Yamagata Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfsyam"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66409d15f59e34317076fd59_yama1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Yamagata Airport (RJSC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Yamagata in Japan and has a yearly average of 223,000 passengers. ‍ It was opened by the Imperial Japanese Navy in World War 2 and briefly used by the United States military after the war. Later, it was utilized by the Japanese Self-Defense Force as a training facility.  It was turned to civilian control in mid-1964 as a third-class regional airport. Eight years later, the runway was extended to 1,500 meters, leading to a reclassification to Class II in 1979. A new - and final - extension happened in 1981, followed by the construction of a new terminal building in 1984. International charter services started in 1981, taking full advantage of the newly expanded runway. Destinations included Finland, Hungary, New Zealand, and even Mexico. The airport's traffic peak was in 1991, followed by a rapid decline in 1992 due to the inauguration of the Yamagata Shinkansen. While the airport saw almost 500,000 passengers in 1991, the figures were down to 50,000 in 2002.  Fuji Dream Airlines (Nagoya, Sapporo), J-Air (Osaka), and Japan Airlines (Tokyo) currently serve it.  ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, custom ground-poly, performance-friendly optimization, and more. ‍ It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.86, requiring at least 29.20 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xtragu</id>
    <title>X-Trident Releases AW-109 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xtragu"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6642fa918a03b5c1706d472d_agusta1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Trident recently released its rendition of the AgustaWestland AW109 for X-Plane 11 and 12. This multi-purpose helicopter is used in a variety of roles, both military and civil. Its development began in the late 1960s, with the first prototype making its maiden flight in 1971. The official FAA certification in 1975 followed, and it was officially introduced in 1976.  Originally designed and manufactured by Agusta as A109, it was the first all-Italian helicopter to be mass-produced. An eventual merger of Agusta and Westland Helicopters from Britain led to a rebranding as AW109. Powered by two Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PW206C engines, the AW109 can cruise at 285 km/h and has a maximum range of 932 km.  The add-on features an accurate rendition of the popular helicopter, with a high-quality 3D model, fully animated cockpit elements, a fully digital instrument panel, a functional circuit breaker panel, a custom FADEC with fully automated engine start sequence, realistic performance across all envelopes (tested by real-life pilots), and more. The complete feature list follows below: ‍3D Model Instruments and controls Autopilot Flight model Liveries Documents Support for both XP12 and XP11 ‍ The AW109 is available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $45.00, requiring at least 593 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xwikri</id>
    <title>XWind Studios Releases Kristiansund Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xwikri"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6643bc3d01bd7a8f67a8b6a0_kri1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. XWind Studios recently released their rendition of Kristiansund Airport (ENKB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Kristiansund in Norway and has a yearly average of 314,000 passengers. The airport was inaugurated in mid-1970 after almost two years of construction, costing the government 31 million NOK. There was a competition to serve the new airport from the start: Both Braathens SAFE and Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) wanted the lucrative route to Oslo Airport, Fornebu. Both were granted the route on a temporary basis.  The construction and eventual inauguration of Molde airport in 1972—which kicked in right after Kristiansund Kvernberget's inauguration—led to a massive drop in traffic figures, given that it single-handedly cut half the region's catchment area. For comparison, Kristiansund averaged 88,246 passengers a year during its second year of operation, and it took another fourteen years to match that figure again after Molde Airport's inauguration. It underwent a massive overhaul in 2010, funded by Avinor, including a runway expansion, a larger car parking lot, and the construction of a larger terminal.  It's currently served by Braathens Regional Airlines, Scandinavian Airlines, and Widerøe.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, detailed landside recreation, custom elevation for the entire island, custom night lighting, an up-to-date airport layout, a custom GSX profile, and more. ‍ It's available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $13.74, requiring at least 1.90 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lrx121</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Releases X-Plane 12.1.0’s First Public Beta </title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lrx121"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6643d498922cd349104b90c0_xpl1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research recently released the first public beta of X-Plane 12's long-awaited 12.1.0 update. This update introduces improved anti-aliasing, new particle effects, lighting improvements, and more. With a strong focus on visual quality improvements, X-Plane 12.1.0's first public beta brings a glimpse into the heavy strides made into improving the anti-aliasing system, depth of field, shadows, lighting, particle effects, water, and autogen. Below is a list of the key takeaways from the visual improvements at hand:  Anti-aliasing (AA): Improved quality with better scene handling and coverage for alpha-tested surfaces (those with transparency). Depth of Field: More control with a setting for Real Camera Shake (RCAS) and a notification when textures are reduced due to memory limitations. Shadows: Smoother shadows overall, cloud shadows on water, and faster rendering times. Lightning: This version features more realistic visuals with subtle color adjustments, distance variations, and bolt thickness changes. Sound effects have also been improved for a more immersive experience. Particle Effects: The new system allows for particles on ground contact, easier editing with copy/paste, and datarefs for better control. Pre-built effects include jet engine afterburners (JATO), water bombing, ground scrapes, and rotor wash from helicopters. Aircraft configuration files (ACFs) let you disable these effects if desired. Water: Fixed water clarity issues, with color and transparency depending on location. Cloud shadows are now visible on water surfaces. Compatibility note: existing X-Plane 11 water scenery packs may not work perfectly due to differences in water rendering and might require updates from the creators. Autogen: Enhanced visuals for high-rise buildings in European cities and improved parking aircraft placement at airports, prioritizing larger planes for bigger spots. The update also enhances the G1000 navigation system, including an accurate startup splash screen, a NAV page, a stormscope, datalink weather support, Terrain, a WPT page, an AUX page, and new datarefs.  It also includes two additions to the supported flap systems, allowing the accurate simulation of manual flap controls such as the one in the Piper PA-28, with precise and gradual adjustments, and the dial-a-flap system, which is present in some McDonnell-Douglas aircraft. The complete feature list and changelog can be found here, along with further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/davdub</id>
    <title>Davor Puljevic Releases Dubrovnik Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/davdub"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664655f565e14e530705cb9e_davor1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Davor Puljevic recently released their rendition of Dubrovnik Airport (LDDU) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves Dubrovnik-Neretva County and has a yearly average of 2.4 million passengers. The airport opened in 1962 and quickly became Yugoslavia’s busiest. By 1987, it had already served nearly a million passengers.  In the 2000s, a new passenger terminal was built to replace the original from 1962, costing the administration 70 million euros. It’s the most modern terminal in the country so far.  It’s a hub for Croatia Airlines and many other European carriers, including Air France, British Airways, easyJet, Eurowings, Finnair, Iberia, KLM, Lufthansa, Transavia, Volotea, Vueling, and Wizz Air, serve it on a seasonal basis. ‍‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom photo imagery, custom jetways, custom ground service equipment, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $21.65, requiring at least 443.95 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rot109</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-11 v1.09 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rot109"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66465ae49662f5f3767b306c_rotateupdate.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate has recently issued a new update to their MD-11 for X-Plane 12, adding Apple Silicon architecture support, pop-up displays, FMS improvements, and more. For pilots of all experience levels, the update offers improved functionalities, including pop-up windows for easier screen display management and additional options on the STAR page and FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator) for more precise flight planning and monitoring. The update also addresses a variety of user-reported issues. Improved VOR interception accuracy and tuned landing roll brakes ensure a more realistic and controlled flying experience. The update tackles numerous bugs related to flight controls, displays, navigation systems, and aircraft behavior. For virtual pilots seeking a more immersive experience, the update boasts improvements to LCDs' LED lighting and a reduction in dirt texture on the windshield, providing a clearer view of the virtual skies. ‍ The developers have also addressed compatibility issues with popular add-ons like A Pilot's Life, ensuring a smoother experience for users who have customized their flight simulator environment. ‍ The complete changelog with all the changes follows below: ‍ Please refer to their website for further information.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfs15</id>
    <title>Microsoft Posts Development Update with New Sim Update 15 Release Date</title>
    <updated>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfs15"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/663f5c512009038b7a042874_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently shared a new development update including an updated development roadmap and further information about the latest news from the team. The updated roadmap has provided a new scheduled release date for the delayed Sim Update 15. The new release date is now set for May 23rd. Additionally, the Microsoft team has released a small update for all simmers, which includes updated navdata, AIRAC cycle 2405. This provides simmers with newer and more up-to-date navdata. We'll keep you informed as soon as Sim Update 15 is released or if we have any more news about it. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ogbs12</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases TrueEarth Great Britain South for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ogbs12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6648fa68e2bffafda06f8c79_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Orbx has recently released the second TrueEarth Great Britain region for X-Plane 12. Following the release of Great Britain North, the next region to come out was Great Britain South. The only one left to be released is Great Britain Central. This TrueEarth package covers a total of 42,000 square miles (107,349 km²) and includes a wide range of features. TrueEarth Great Britain South covers Southern England and Wales, and it's designed with intricate details and includes numerous Points of Interest. Everything from Buckingham Palace to Cardiff City Stadium has been created to make it as realistic and visually accurate as possible. TrueEarth Great Britain South offers a variety of features, such as 42,000 square miles of aerial imagery, custom autogen, 3D trees, VFR landmarks, POIs, custom mesh, accurate road and rail networks, and more. The add-on is available on Orbx for approximately $37.70 and requires a total of 127 GB of storage space. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p777ma</id>
    <title>New PMDG 777 for MSFS Manual Previews Further Features</title>
    <updated>2024-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p777ma"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664a5024074eab7bbd14f340_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A member of the PMDG forum has discovered an internal link on PMDG's website leading to a user manual for their upcoming Boeing 777-300ER for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This manual reveals many features that had not been previously mentioned and provides answers to questions from the community that were left unanswered or only vaguely addressed by the company's CEO, Robert Randazzo. The new website not only includes the manual but also showcases a variety of liveries available for the plane. Furthermore, it unveils several previously undisclosed features, providing users with a comprehensive look at what the plane has to offer. Furthermore, the manual also provides insight into some of the included features. Here is a list of some of the most interesting features: After a user shared the new website, most of the responses and the original message were deleted from the forum. Following this, Mathijs at PMDG published the following: "Kudos to the person who used a domain scanner to find the manual, but this is indeed unplanned, so let's not make it a topic here." In the end, it looks like the manual was not supposed to be released, but when it was, we did get quite a good look at the new plane. If you want to check out the manual, it was available while we were writing this article, but is no longer there and rather humorously they redirected the URL to a Rick Roll. We will keep you informed as more information becomes available about the upcoming PMDG 777. Make sure to stay tuned to Threshold for the most recent flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftsy12</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Sydney Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftsy12"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664b1619ce19b15c0760cea7_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlyTampa has recently released its version of Sydney Kingsford Smith Airport (YSSY) for X-Plane 12. The airport serves the Australian city of Sydney and is situated approximately 5 miles (8 kilometres) from the city. As the biggest and busiest airport in Australia, it welcomes around 42 million passengers annually. In 1919, Nigel Love leased and established an airfield on grassy paddocks in the suburb of Mascot. The first flight from the airfield was with Love in 1919, and the official opening took place in 1920. After the lease ended in 1923, the Commonwealth Government acquired the airfield, just before the first regular flights began in 1924. The first gravel runway was built in 1933, and by 1949, the number of runways had tripled. Construction for a new terminal started in 1966 and was officially opened in 1970. Over the years, the airport has undergone several upgrades and constructions. Today, the airport serves numerous cities worldwide and is a hub for Qantas and Virgin Australia, as well as many other airlines, with a yearly total of over 300,000 aircraft movements. The newly released version of Sydney Airport includes many features such as a fully custom rendition of Sydney Kingsford Smith Airport, custom mesh, custom night lighting, SAM and LST integration, Ortho4XP patch, and much more. The newly released add-on is now available on Orbx for approximately $32.50. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mxipvk</id>
    <title>MXI Design Releases Preveza Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mxipvk"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664c98df90484b4f72ebc8d0_340412_M1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MXI Design has released their rendition of Preveza Aktion Airport (LGPZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the city of Preveza and Lefkada Island, with an average of 773,000 passenger operations per year. Opened in 1968, Preveza Airport is a popular airport during the summer season, with charter flights arriving from all over Europe, but it is also used by NATO and the Hellenic Air Force. In 2015, 14 airports in Greece, including Aktion Airport, were privatised by Fraport AG. Aktion Airport was presented with an investment plan to modernise the terminal and improve customer service. Along with the terminal renovation and extension, reorganisation of the apron and refurbishment of airside pavement were also planned. Outside of the summer season, Preveza Airport only receives domestic flights from Zakynthos, Corfu and Sitia. During the summer, more than 28 air carriers perform charter flights from Preveza to numerous cities in Europe, mostly in Germany, the UK and Sweden. MXI Design’s LGPZ features accurately modelled terminal and airport buildings, up-to-date ground markings, terminal interior, PBR textures, and custom static planes. Preveza Aktion Airport is available for purchase on SimMarket, for approximately 10.83$, requiring at least 1.52GB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned for more flight sim news to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/c3dsfa</id>
    <title>CAT3DUAL Releases Sfax Thyna Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/c3dsfa"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664c9ba136bd356fb26802e4_340377_DTTX-01.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CAT3DUAL has released their rendition of Sfax-Thyna Airport (DTTX) for MSFS. The airport serves the city of Sfax in Tunisia and has a yearly average of 200.000 passengers. It is located 6 kilometres outside the city of Sfax. During WWII, the airport was used by the USAF during the North African campaign and was known as Sfax Airfield. Two bombardment groups used this airfield - the 12th and 340th Bombardment Group, both using the B-25 Mitchell. After the war, Sfax Airport received many extensions and improvements, with the most important one being the construction of the new terminal in 1988 and the extension of the runway. In the following years, a cargo terminal was added, along with a warehouse, taxiways and the airport apron reconstruction. The latest expansion was finished in 2007, when a new terminal, consisting of three buildings, and a new control tower were built. Today, Sfax-Thyna Airport serves 6 airlines to 7 destinations, and many charter flights from Germany and UK during the summer season. CAT3DUAL’s rendition of DTTX features custom buildings on the airfield, main apron including an eastern expansion, accurate airfield way finders: taxiway signs and markings, airfield lighting placement and colours per Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP), custom perimeter wall and more. This scenery can be purchased on SimMarket for approximately 8.68$ and requires at least 135MB of free disk space. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ftegnj</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Releases Humberside Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ftegnj"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664c9e11e0e434082ff8c68b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. FlyTampa has released their rendition of Humberside Airport (EGNJ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Serving Lincolnshire, Kingston upon Hull and the East Riding of Yorkshire, this airport welcomes around 90.000 passengers per year. Opened in 1941 as an RAF air base, RAF Kirmington housed the 166th RAF Squadron that operated Avro Lancasters. After 1945, the airport was abandoned for 30 years, until the local council decided to activate the airfield again. After the local area was renamed, the airport was renamed to Humberside Airport. Due to the proximity of other airports, Humberside faces competition from East Midlands and Leeds Bradford Airport. This is because competitive airports have a wider range of passenger flights. The airport serves only two airlines with scheduled passenger flights, KLM to Amsterdam and Eastern Airways to Aberdeen, while during the summer season, TUI has charter flights to Palma de Mallorca, and BH Air to Burgas. FlyTampa’s version of Humberside Airport features Hi-res modelling and PBR textures, a modelled terminal interior with animated passengers, a GSX profile, and LOD performance modelling. This scenery can be purchased on FlyTampa’s website for 12.99$. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jetgen</id>
    <title>Jetstream Designs Announces Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jetgen"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/664ce3761ae36b5b1651cb09_lsgg1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Jetstream Designs has recently announced the development of Geneva Airport (LSGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This international Airport serves Grand Genève (Geneva’s metropolitan area) and has a yearly average of 14 million passengers. ‍ It was first established as an airfield in Cointrin, near Geneva (which explains the airport still being informally known as Cointrin Airport), in October 1919. It wasn’t until the late 1920s that the airport would get appropriately structured, with concrete hangars instead of makeshift wooden sheds.  ‍ The first concrete runway was built in 1937, with a total length of 405 meters.  ‍ The airport was heavily expanded during World War 2, as the Swiss authorities banned any departures for safety reasons. The runway was extended to 1200 meters near the end of the war, and provisions were made to ensure further expansion capabilities in the future. The first passenger terminal was built in 1946, costing 2.3 Swiss Francs to the authorities, along with a runway expansion to 2000 meters.  The runway was expanded for the last time in 1960, with jet traffic in mind, taking it from 2000 meters to 3900 meters. This is an unusually long runway for an airport of that size, and a territorial exchange had to be made between Switzerland and France to ensure that there would be enough room for it.  ‍ In the late 1980s, a new passenger terminal was built, with 12 jet bridges and two ground-floor gates. It ultimately replaced the old one from 1946, which now only opens during winter charter season.  ‍ It’s a hub for Swiss International Air Lines and an operating base for EasyJet Switzerland. Aegean Airlines, Aer Lingus, Air Canada, Air China, Air France, British Airways, Brussels Airlines, Delta Air Lines, easyJet, Emirates, Eurowings, Finnair, ITA, Jet2.com, KLM, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Scandinavian Airlines, TAP Air Portugal, Transavia, TUI Airways, United Airlines, Vueling, and Wizz Air also serve it. While a feature list has not been provided, the many screenshots shared on their social media platforms reveal some of it: custom ground textures, custom jetways, terminal interiors, and custom runway textures. Jetstream also proudly announces that Marcus Nyberg, a scenery developer from Orbx, has joined them to help with Geneva and future projects. There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
