<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-12-20T18:22:15.270397+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ddrbfi</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Designs Releases Boeing Field for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ddrbfi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580b34856ca39e17f82840e_KBFI_MSFS_13.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="377404"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Drzewiecki Designs has recently released his latest scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator, being KBFI Boeing Field in Seattle. This is Drzewiecki’s third Seattle-area scenery, following the release of Paine Field and Renton. All three of these airports serve as sites for production or delivery of Boeing’s lines of aircraft.  Boeing Field, officially known as King County International Airport, is situated five miles south of downtown Seattle. It served as Seattle’s main passenger gateway, until the larger Seattle-Tacoma Airport opened in 1944. It was crucial in the production of many early 737 series of aircraft in the 1960’s, due to the fact that Boeing’s other narrowbody production facility at Renton didn’t have enough capacity. Today, it mainly serves as a cargo airport, and is the site of the Boeing Delivery Center, where new 737’s are delivered after going through final preparation. The Drzewiecki Designs rendition of the airport has many features, including: As of the time of writing, you can get this airport on the Aerosoft store, but that will expand to other vendors shortly. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/arjacx</id>
    <title>Axonos Releases Jackson Hole Airport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/arjacx" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580bf79a03380541094b6b1_656e6ac492899.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2980147"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Axonos have just recently released their rendition of the famous high-altitude airport, Jackson Hole, for X-Plane 12. Situated in the rocky mountains, Jackson Hole Airport is a popular destination for those looking to explore the Rockies! Jackson Hole Airport was originally created in the 1930’s, and it was chosen for its advantageous location within Teton County. The airport was declared a National Monument in 1943, and eventually merged with the Grand Teton National Park in 1950. Jackson Hole is the only commercial airport in the United States to be part of a National Park. The runway was extended to its current length of 6300 feet in 1959. The original Frontier Airlines was the first airline to serve Jackson Hole, with flights to Salt Lake City, Denver, and Billings using Douglas DC-3’s and eventually Boeing 737-200’s. The terminal was completely rebuilt between 2009 and 2014.  Today, the airport is the busiest airport in Wyoming, seeing over 450,000 passengers per year. It has nonstop service to 15 destinations during peak seasonal times by 8 different airlines, and has year-round service by Alaska Airlines, American Airlines, United Airlines, and Delta Air Lines. It is the main destination for many ski resorts surrounding the airport. Axonos’ rendition of the airport includes many features, such as: You can add this airport to your virtual world for $22.99 from their store. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/cjrrms</id>
    <title>CJ Simulations Releases Rafale for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/cjrrms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580c1d1cb114fa2cbe8f941_410880261_884190530376367_9027274731770291189_n.jpg.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1924057"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. CJ Simulations, known for their renditions of fighter aircraft, have just released their rendition of the CJS Rafale for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Developed in partnership with CodeNameJack and DC Designs, it is another rendition of a very popular European fighter, following their release of the Eurofighter Typhoon last year. The Rafale is a French multi-role fighter, built by Dassault Aviation. It was developed out of the need of a new jet fighter for the French Air Force and Navy. The initial variant of the Rafale, the Rafale A, first flew in 1986, but after many changes and delays, the production version of the Rafale, the Rafale C, was introduced in 2001. Today, the Rafale is primarily used by the French Air Force and Navy, as well as the Egyptian Air Force and the Indian Air Force. ‍ The CJS rendition of the Rafale includes features such as high quality 3D interior and exterior modeling, various simulations of Rafale systems, and much more! You can get the CJ Simulations Rafale on the Microsoft Flight Simulator Marketplace for $35 USD. ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aabsms</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Announces Breezer Sport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aabsms" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6580d3b844dfd2023f4e8866__0019_Breezer-Sport-4.jpg.078b2911e50f730b24ee90d8f3f1b9ad.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="68785"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. German developer Aerosoft has announced that they are developing the Breezer Sport, and is their latest foray into the aircraft market for Microsoft Flight Simulator. Aerosoft, known for their simulations of airliners, such as the CRJ series, and their upcoming Airbus A330 project for MSFS, moves into the GA market with this announcement. The Breezer Sport is produced by the German aircraft manufacturer with the same name, Breezer Aircraft. The Breezer Sport is a light-sport, single engine aircraft that was developed in the late 90’s. The first flight was in 1999, and entered into production in 2001. A few years later in 2005, the Breezer Sport earned a light-sport rating by the FAA, and entered into the US market. It is powered by a Rotax 915 iS/iSC engine, and can hold up to two people, and is unique in its class for its aluminum construction.  A full feature set has not been announced yet, but Aerosoft has said that the aircraft will feature an authentic interior and cockpit layout, according to documents from Breezer themselves, as well as an animated glass canopy, glass cockpit with AS3 Touch, and a simplified implementation of the original RSFlight EMU. Aerosoft also has announced that the Breezer Sport will come with an animated kneeboard with original checklists, and a tablet. Aerosoft has not announced a release date or price, but Threshold will keep you informed whenever they do, so stay tuned for this and for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmt7eb</id>
    <title>PMDG 777 for MSFS Enters Beta Testing Phase</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmt7eb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65810afd41ff70b683b4e3c8_PMDG_777_cabin.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="921140"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. In a recent development update on their forums, PMDG’s CEO, Robert Randazzo announced that their upcoming Boeing 777 for Microsoft Flight Simulator has entered the hands of beta testers.This marks another milestone in the process of release of the highly anticipated aircraft for the simulator.This news comes after the release of their first preview image a few weeks ago, which set the community aflame with speculation on details about the aircraft. Randazzo says that we shouldn’t expect much yet, but more previews will be coming.  ‍ Also in this development update are updates on progress about the Marketplace, and updates to the Universal Flight Tablet Concerning the Marketplace, for PC, Randazzo tells us that the new updates will be coming, and it is only a matter of time before Microsoft approves the update and pushes it to the public. On the Xbox side of things, Randazzo says that they “continue to work on the testing and trouble-shooting tools that we need in order to collect sufficient data to demonstrate to the platform developer that the communications layer for C++/WASM airplanes is partially or fully inoperative on the Xbox platform.” He continues on to tell us that “We are working to find a way to disable the broken tablet functionality when running on Xbox so that we can at least keep Xbox users up-to-date with any other improvements and non-tablet changes that we make.” There also is a new update to the PMDG Universal Flight Tablet, which Mr. Randazzo says will be the final one for 2023. The full changelog follows below: 12817: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Navigraph map-type choice (IFR low/high/etc.) should be persistent (rmurdoch) 12610: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Save users pref of aircraft symbol in settings (rmurdoch) 12832: [EFB - Performance and Computational] New menu data for 777 (cbpowell) 12635: [EFB - General] Day/Night should default to most applicable and allow over selection please (rmurdoch) 12831: [EFB - General] Make signal bar reflect currency of airplane pings (rmurdoch) 12569: [EFB - General] Utilize MSFS built-in airport data for OPT (rmurdoch) ‍ Be sure to stay tuned to Threshold for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/csep</id>
    <title>Cockspur Previews Embraer Phenom</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/csep" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/658186f80a6d95c71de41267_411482272_346823951428489_1348043931857465735_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="656188"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Cockspur, known for their Cessna C162 and C510 Mustang, have previewed their upcoming Embraer Phenom 100. Originally announced earlier in December, there hasn’t been much information about the upcoming release. The Embraer Phenom 100 is a very light business jet that made its first flight in 2007. The powerplant of the Phenom 100 (EMB-500) is two Pratt and Whitney PW600 turbofan engines providing almost 4,000 lbf of thrust combined. Requiring only one pilot the Phenom 100 has room for up to 5 passengers depending on the configuration. With a service ceiling of 41,000 ft and a cruise speed of 400 knots, the Phenom 100 has a maximum range of 1,178 nmi. In the post on their Facebook page, Cockspur has provided several screenshots of the exterior of the plane. While there haven’t been any previews of the interior so far it looks as though Cockspur have provided excellent exterior modelling and impressive texturing. There’s currently no indication of when we could see a release of the aircraft or at what price point. For all of your flight simulation news updates be sure to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gksfar</id>
    <title>GKS announces development of the F-111E Aardvark</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gksfar" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6581ce19756d1c4e755d44d2_HOG.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="88654"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Golden Key Studio has unveiled their latest project, the development of the F-111 for MSFS, following their previous release of the MiG-21Bis Fishbed. The announcement was made via the flight simulator forums today. The Aardvark, an aircraft of the 1960s, was manufactured by General Dynamics and stands as a supersonic-capable medium-range multirole aircraft. It served various roles, excelling as an attack aircraft, bomber, reconnaissance, and electronic warfare platform. Primarily operated by the US Air Force and the Royal Australian Air Force, this aircraft witnessed over 500 units produced across six distinct variants. GKS has dedicated its efforts to the F-111E variant, powered by Pratt and Whitney's TF-30 engines that enable the F-111 to achieve speeds of up to Mach 2.5. Streamlining its high-speed capabilities is a swing-wing design reminiscent of the F-14 Tomcat. GKS has offered a sneak peek into the intricate details of the cockpit, ensuring a well-detailed version of its unique side-by-side seating cockpit. Judging by the screenshots shared by GKS, the exterior model appears to be nearing completion and or completed. While GKS has provided sparse details regarding pricing and release dates, we can anticipate additional information in the near future. Stay tuned to Threshold for updates on this exciting addition to the MSFS lineup.</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ispa3m</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares New Previews, Release Window of A300 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ispa3m" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6581f7dfadd0cb1d41e34fee_image.png.c1be82351e3ecdad9385849f62b31ea8_1_90-2.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2761604"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds have just released a development update, as well as a trailer and new preview images of their upcoming Airbus A300-600R for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The development update includes lots of information covering the highly-anticipated airliner, including a full list of features that we can expect on release. iniBuilds have also announced that release of the A300 will come before the end of this year, and they signaled that release could be just days away. Getting right to the feature list, iniBuilds have provided quite an extensive list in this development update, so below is an abbreviated list with some of the most important information: iniBuilds also shared an updated timeline on future updates for the A300, starting with a hotfix, as well as submitting an optimized Xbox version in the Marketplace in January. This is followed by the addition of the Pratt and Whitney engine variant and full ACARS/CPDLC functionality for free, which they expect to release in Q1 2024. After this will be a paid expansion that adds the EPIC avionics package seen on many updated A300F variants, particularly with UPS. For the full details on this exciting new development for iniBuild’s most recent airliner, you can go to the forum post here. ‍ While iniBuilds have not mentioned a firm release date, Threshold will keep you informed whenever they do, so stay tuned for this and for more high quality flight simulation news and reviews on the latest in flight simulation!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/acotpe</id>
    <title>Aco Design Studio Releases Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/acotpe" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65820873779bdb0d3c572a27_taipei2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1321781"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aco Design Studio has recently released their rendition of Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport (RCTP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Northern Taiwan with a yearly average of 48.7 million passengers.  It opened in 1979 as Chiang Kai-shek International Airport, replacing Songshan Airport as Taipei’s main airport due to overcrowding and limited expansion possibilities.   At first, it only had a single passenger terminal, but a second one was inaugurated in mid-2000, with only half of its gates in operating order. It only became fully functional in 2005.   A third terminal is currently under construction, increasing the passenger handling capabilities to 86 million passengers a year in total (45 million for that terminal alone). It will take 640,000 square meters of land and cost around 2.3 billion USD.  It’s a hub for China Airlines, EVA Air, Mandarin Airlines, Starlux Airlines, Tigerair Taiwan, and UNI Air. The visitors’ list includes AirAsia, Air Macau, Air New Zealand, Asiana Airlines, Cathay Pacific, Cebu Pacific, China Eastern, China Southern, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, Japan Airlines, Jeju Air, KLM, Korean Air, Malaysia Airlines, Peach, Philippine Airlines, Singapore Airlines, Turkish Airlines, United Airlines, and Vietnam Airlines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a high-detail terminal and interior, custom ground textures, custom night lighting, static ground vehicles, and a custom GSX profile.   It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $24.01, requiring at least 1.14 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfcuv</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases City Update V</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfcuv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65820d3883b577c78dbc2d7e_cuv.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="504666"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator has recently released a new update with a curated selection of renowned European cities, developed in conjunction with Bing Maps and Vexcel. City Update V: European Cities 1 includes five urban regions throughout Europe: The Hague (Netherlands), Brussels (Belgium), Košice (Slovakia), Zagreb (Croatia), and Cádiz (Spain), developed with the latest geographic information and triangulated irregular network surface modeling.  The update is free to all owners of Microsoft Flight Simulator on all platforms. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msfces</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator Releases Cessna T207A Stationair</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msfces" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65821348c28a5038b6c0724c_station.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="375273"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft Flight Simulator has recently released the new iteration of their Famous Flyer lineup: the Cessna T207A Stationair, a legendary light civil utility model with over 600 airframes built over 15 years of production (1969-1984). The Cessna 207 is the eight-seat variant of the Cessna 205/206, which was essentially a Cessna 210 with fixed landing gear and changes to the crew and passenger door arrangement. With a slightly longer fuselage (114 cm) and a nose section extension, it could fit more seats and more luggage, transforming it into the ideal flying wagon. Its real-world usage case varies from air taxi applications to skydiving, aerial photography, and private use. The airplane is powered by a Continental TSIO-520-M, producing up to 310 horsepower, a range of 671 miles, a cruise speed of 185 miles per hour, and a service ceiling of 26,000 ft ASL. The add-on features three variations: cargo, standard, and skydiving, with 20 liveries in total.  It’s available on the Marketplace for $14.99.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/avifre</id>
    <title>Aviotek Software’s Frankfurt International Airport for MSFS Releasing for Free in 2024</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/avifre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6582186983be7bde6b7f6cdf_aviotek1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="377643"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aviotek Software has published a development update where they thank the community for providing feedback, testing, and reference images and offer a rendition of Frankfurt International Airport (EDDF) as a “thank you” gift to be released in the near future.   They have been working on optimizing the user experience, increasing the level of detail, improving texturing, models, and some of it was shared with the community, which are the pics that illustrate this article.   Aviotek asks the community to “bear with them for another month” while they add the final touches (jetways, etc.) before an eventual release. They also invite people to apply to beta-test the scenery before its release (testing is set to begin in January 2024).   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/737087</id>
    <title>PMDG Updates 737 Lineup for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/737087" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65822614fd49bb24eeafab0b_1250410_20231218213033_1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1529635"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Update 3.00.0087 is now available for PMDG.com customers, bringing a list of fixes to their Ultimate Flight Tablet for Microsoft Flight Simulator.  PMDG’s last product update for this year is mostly minor, aiming to “squash a few items that we felt were disruptive,” according to Randazzo’s own words. The next update will be available in a few weeks, focusing on adding more functionality and features, as previously promised. The changelog follows below:   12817: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Navigraph map-type choice (IFR low/high/etc.) should be persistent (rmurdoch) 12610: [EFB - Navigraph Charting Functions] Save users pref of aircraft symbol in settings (rmurdoch) 12832: [EFB - Performance and Computational] New menu data for 777 (cbpowell) 12635: [EFB - General] Day/Night should default to most applicable and allow over selection please (rmurdoch) 12831: [EFB - General] Make signal bar reflect currency of airplane pings (rmurdoch) 12569: [EFB - General] Utilize MSFS built-in airport data for OPT (rmurdoch)  PMDG had mentioned in their last development update that the update would be submitted to the marketplace as soon as it was made available for PMDG.com customers. Still, its intake process might take longer than usual because of the end-of-the-year holidays.  PMDG’s aircraft lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator is available on their website, with prices ranging from $34.99 to $64.99. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ppbs</id>
    <title>PixelPlanes and Aerosoft Release Breezer Sport</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ppbs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6582ad4c0e257519f9956a22_05.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="265165"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PixelPlanes and Aerosoft have released their newest project, the two-seat ultralight Breezer Sport. The release comes just days after the initial product announcement.  The Breezer Sport as mentioned above is a 2-seater ultralight aircraft and features a full aluminum construction with a Rotax 915 iS/iSC power plant. The German-manufactured Breezer has a cruising speed of 145 knots and a maximum range of 755 nm. The aircraft also features a retractable landing gear. ‍ Pixel Planes and Aerosoft's rendition of the Breezer Sport features an authentic interior and cockpit, modeled after the original specifications from Breezer Aircraft. The aircraft features several animations and ground objects, this includes the opening/closing of the canopy as well as a removable safety pin and pitot cover. The cockpit features a full glass panel with integrated AS3 touch systems and a simplified RSFlight EMU for displaying engine information. The Breezer Sport can be purchased from the Aerosoft website for $22 USD.  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for all your flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/justfl</id>
    <title>Just Flight publishes end of year update</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/justfl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65831c8acc65189f9829ca6b_A330%20DETAIL2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="908363"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Just Flight has taken to their website and Facebook to provide a comprehensive update on all projects expected for release next year. The news bulletin covers all projects, indicating that Just Flight has almost every corner of the aviation market covered for the coming year. From general aviation to heavy airliners, it is evident that next year will be a busy one for Just Flight. The team has outlined a list of aircraft in production, all slated for release in the upcoming year. Starting with the highly-anticipated release of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, Just Flight vows to commit to ensuring product compatibility and development for Asobo's upcoming simulator. Airliner projects were thoroughly covered with updates and new previews, such as the A300B4 Professional, which was revealed at FS Expo last year. The team is diligently working on finishing the extensive texturing of the flight deck and exterior model, paying attention to every imaginable detail, including a reworked modeling of the nose section of the aircraft. System coding has made significant progress, with the completion of the electrical, air bleed, air conditioning, pressurization, APU, and fuel systems. These systems, like their real-life counterparts, will respond to environmental factors. Progress is ongoing, with the team aiming to provide every detail, down to individual weathered texturing for screw heads. Updates don't stop with the A300, as the RJ Professional is next in line to be released. Just Flight reports significant progress in coding and systems completion, highlighting new systems matching differences between the older 146 and the more modern RJ. Visually, the RJ will feature a high-density 3+3 layout with a full range of animations and sounds. A preview of the cabin is provided below.  The F70/100 Professional is also making progress, with a current focus on reworked texturing from new reference photographs, ensuring an unprecedented level of detail. Various details, such as certain switches and knobs, have been remodeled. The progress continues with animations, lighting, and systems integration.  Finally, an update to the 146 Professional is expected early next year, including the UNS-1 FMS and a reworked detailed cabin from the RJ Professional. This update is currently under beta testing, with more information expected closer to release. Furthermore, the Blue Bird Simulations' 757 is still scheduled for next year, with Just Flight stating that the team is "also incredibly busy" working on the "flying pencil." Just Flight covered general aviation projects, starting with the Piston and Turbine Duke by Black Square, nearing completion. Thandra Designs will collaborate with Just Flight to update their X-Plane 11 fleet to X-Plane 12 standards, utilizing all available features of the simulator. The Duchess, being the first on XP12 list, will feature 8k textures and modern texturing effects inside out. Animations will also be reworked, with reactive animations responding to G-forces and air resistance. Additionally, Just Flight’s new EFB will make it to the X-Plane 12 model, providing controls over airframe features. This update aims to breathe new life into the X-Plane version of the Duchess. Not all projects are progressing as well as hoped, with the Tomahawk project facing setbacks. Just Flight stated that the Tomahawk project stalled but is now at the center of their attention, bringing it in line for their next GA aircraft release for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The in-house team is working on upgrading the interior and exterior modeling and texturing, as well as systems. Expect fully functional avionics stacks, including the GMA340, SL20, SL40, the GX28 transponder, as well as GPS options. On the military side, Just Flight’s Tornado GR1 for MSFS is also making progress. The "Tonka" is being worked on by the same team that brought us the incredibly detailed Avro Vulcan. The same level of detail and passion is being applied to the Tornado. The team has remodeled many parts of the aircraft to bring higher detail and accuracy, with texturing receiving highly detailed 8k treatment as well. Coding is next on the team's list. The Tornado team will be tasked with transferring the Hi-Fi code from the Prepar3D Tornado to MSFS. During the transfer, new features and improvements will be added to bring as much operational accuracy to the real aircraft as possible. Also, Expect 24 paint schemes to be released with the Tornado. Just Flight is wrapping up and preparing for a busy 2024 for the flight sim community, with releases covering all spans of aviation. They express gratitude to the community for its support throughout 2023 and wish everyone a "Very Merry Christmas and health and happiness in the New Year." To see the full update page see follow this link. As usual stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news and updates! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/omduin</id>
    <title>IniBuilds has just releases the Skydive Dubai Skylinepackage for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/omduin" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/65832780830573b451c6c96f_skyline.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="56871"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. IniBuilds has just released the OMDU Skydive Dubai &amp; Landmarks package for MSFS, marking day three of their Winter Wonderland Event and winter sales. This package covers the Skydive Dubai airport and prominent landmarks across Dubai's skyline with high-resolution detailing. Notable features encompass 23 Marina Tower, Address Beach Resort, Atlantis the Palm, the Burj Khalifa, and more. Additionally, custom ground vehicles and sea vessels have are also included. The primary aim of this package is to provide users with an immersive experience of flying as a skydive drop pilot within the Dubai area. Key features of the package include the intricately modeled OMDU Dubai Skydive Airport by Fykky, a fully modeled JBR Beach area, and a range of iniBuilds assets such as the Yacht, Jet Ski, vehicles, and iconic police cars. The inclusion of brand-new lighting technology further enhances the visuals of prominent structures like the Coca-Cola Arena, Five Hotel, Ain Dubai Observation Wheel, Blue Water Island, AI Habtoor City, Burj AI Arab, Burj Khalifa, and more. The buildings included in the package are, 23 Marina Tower, Address Beach Resort, Address Boulevard, Address Sky View, Atlantis The Palm, Atlantis The Royal, Cayan Tower, D1 Tower at Jaddaf Waterfront, Dubai Frame, Dubai Mall, Elite Residence, Index Tower, Jumeirah Emirates Towers, Marina 101, Marina Gate, Museum of the Future, Ocean Heights, One Za'abeel Tower, Princess Tower, and The Palm Tower. The iniBuilds OMDU Skydive Dubai &amp; Landmarks package is available for FREE download via the iniBuilds store. Stay tuned to Threshold for more news on iniBuilds' Winter Wonderland Event!</summary>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
