<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-07-25T18:20:58.642942+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/peddev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes MSFS Development Update </title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/peddev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b4279b4c1fbeea9727d61b_pmdg1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1880921"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. PMDG has recently published the second development update of this month, with information on future 737 updates, console liveries, new marketplace arrivals, UFT, 777, and more.  Randazzo begins with information on the 737 Lineup updates for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which have been sent to the beta team, including changes to prepare the aircraft for the Universal Flight Tablet.   The Xbox liveries for the 737 are going through marketplace intake and should be made available soon. They are still exploring manners to minimize user costs for liveries.  They have also begun pushing the 737-600 and 737-900 to the Marketplace along with their liveries, with their prediction pointing to an end of July release.  The Universal Flight Tablet is being moved into its final leg of testing. It has been tested on a single airframe so far (the 737-700) to minimize developmental hassles. No previews are available yet.  The 777 has progressed significantly since FSExpo, with PMDG looking into previewing it soon.   They finish with a quick note on the DC-6, which should be getting an update in August.  Their product lineup for MSFS is available on their website and in the Marketplace, although only partially. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a2acom</id>
    <title>A2A Simulations Releases Accu-Sim Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a2acom" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b6746774c1b65fbb19f3d3_comanche1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="240459"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A2A Simulations has recently released their first airplane for Microsoft Flight Simulator: the Accu-Sim Comanche, based on a real Piper Comanche 250 they have owned and operated for a decade. The first of the Comanches, the PA-24, had its prototype built in 1956, sporting a semi-monocoque construction with retractable landing gear and powered by a 180 hp Lycoming engine. Production started a year later and continued until 1972, ended by a flood that compromised the entire production line beyond recovery. The Comanche 250, the one A2A simulates, came two years after the 180hp variant, with a 250 hp engine (hence the 250). Early models had manually operated flaps and up to 230L of fuel. At the same time, future units (post-1961) could carry up to 340L total on auxiliary tanks, and electrically actuated flaps were made standard in 1962.  A2A’s rendition is their first AccuSim 2.0 product, which is a culmination of years of experience with aircraft simulation, featuring a brand new aerodynamics system that accurately models how an airplane flies through the air. The aircraft features the aforementioned aerodynamics system, accurate engine performance based on their own Comanche 250, realistic handling characteristics and trim behavior, a physics-based per-cylinder simulation of the engine, dynamic ground physics, an advanced turbulence system, airframe vibration physics, authentic fuel simulation, a custom oil system with dynamic viscosity, advanced engine starter simulation, a physics-driven sound environment, a detailed JPI EDM 830 engine monitor, custom-coded Narco avionics, further integration options for third-party GPSs, and much more. The complete feature list follows down below: It’s available at the A2A Simulations Store for $49.99.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rfspes</id>
    <title>Rfscenerybuilding Releases Abruzzo Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rfspes" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b69deadd74108f59130ab7_pesc1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3164741"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Rfscenerybuilding has recently released their rendition of Abruzzo Airport (LIBP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Pescara, Italy, with a yearly average of 700,000 passengers.  It was built in 1917 by the Regio Esercito (Royal Italian Army), initially with their fleet of two Farman 14s. A year later, it hosted the 302° Squadron and their Ansaldo SVA Biplanes, among the best fighter bombers of the time.  After World War I, it was renamed Pasquale Liberi after a local aviator. Then, in 1927 it was expanded to 50 hectares and modernized.  With the advent of commercial aviation in the 1930s, Abruzzo was served by Società Area Mediterranea (SAM) with a tri-weekly service from Pescara to Rome Urbe Airport with a single stop.  World War 2 stopped commercial aviation in Pescara, which only resumed two years after the war with Transadriatica and their Douglas DC-3s. Avio Linee Italiane soon joined with a route between Milan to Brindisi, with stops in Pescara, Foggia, and Bari. ‍ Most commercial operations were suspended in 1979 after a revision of the minimum landing requirements by the ANPAC, a national association of civil aviation pilots. Pescara did not have the required ILS instruments, which made airlines like Itavia shy away from operating at the airport.   Things only improved in the early 1980s, after the arrival of Aermediterranea, a little airline controlled by Alitalia, and eventually Aero Transporti Italiani in 1984, also controlled by Alitalia.   The current terminal was opened in 1996, and the old building was reutilized for logistical and technical support. That terminal underwent multiple improvements between 2008 and 2018, including its expansion, modernization, and renovation, costing 33 million euros.  It’s currently served by ITA Airways (Milano Linate), Luxair (Luxembourg), Ryanair (Bergamo, Bucharest–Otopeni, Catania, Charleroi, London–Stansted, Turin), and Wizz Air (Tirana).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom ground service equipment, custom night lighting, realistic windows, an up-to-date ground layout, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $16.28, requiring at least 72.82 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simper</id>
    <title>Simulación Extrema Releases Presidente Perón International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simper" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b6d9658d7f99ba614b6264_peron1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2261705"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Simulación Extrema has recently released their rendition of Presidente Perón International Airport (SAZN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the cities of Neuquén, Cipolletti, Plottier, Centenario, and General Roca, in Argentina, with a yearly average of 800,000 passengers.  The airport was built in 1936 as Aero Club Neuquén, with a single gravel runway. Its paving and modernization only happened in 1951, when Argentina planned to pioneer air transport in Latin America.   Eight years later, the surrounding terrain was expropriated so they could build an International Airport with a longer runway, a proper passenger terminal, and proper general infrastructure.  The airport was renovated in 2013 and expanded in 2019, with the construction of a domestic and international pre-boarding area, with 1500 square meters for the first one and 630 for the latter. They have also built a new security area, two commercial lots with 80 square meters each, bathrooms totaling up to 140 square meters, and 18 check-in gates.  Aerolíneas Argentinas, Flybondi, JetSmart Argentina, American Jet, LADE, and Latam Argentina currently serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom jetways, custom ground textures, 4K PBR textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.60, requiring at least 957.13 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gds14b</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Announces 14-bis for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gds14b" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b83fb291aa874b929a8135_14bis2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="171603"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations, in partnership with RPSimulations and a popular aviation channel from Brazil (Aviões &amp; Músicas), has recently announced the development of a 14-bis for Microsoft Flight Simulator, first flown in 1906 and known (although not worldwide) as the world’s first airplane.  Inspired by Gabriel Voisin’s glider, Santos Dumont’s 14-bis was made of a Hargrave-cell and powered by a 50 horsepower fuel-injected V8 engine, making it able to fly for a few hundred meters at a time at an impressive (by the early 1900s standards) 40 km/h. It won the second prize in November 1096 at the Chateau de Bagatelle after flying for 220 meters, earning Santos Dumont a monument at the place, which is still up to this day. There’s no information about features, pricing, or a release date, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shapen</id>
    <title>SHADESCENE Releases Penang International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shapen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b84b81f8dd6ff40ba6521f_pen1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1145312"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SHADESCENE has recently released their rendition of Penang International Airport (WMKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 7.23 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1935 as Bayan Lepas International Airport when Penang was still a British colony.  It was heavily expanded in the 1970s, with a new terminal and a longer runway to accommodate the Boeing 747.   The administration has recently announced a 4-phase expansion plan, which started in 2020 and should reach completion by 2024, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It’s currently served by AirAsia, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Citilink, Firefly, Firefly, Indonesia AirAsia, Jetstar Asia, Lion Air, Malaysia Airlines, MYAirline, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, Starlux Airlines, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Smile.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a custom-modeled terminal, custom terraforming, custom jetways, high-resolution textures, custom objects, a terminal interior, custom night lighting, custom ground markings, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.49, requiring at least 370.23 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mfspen</id>
    <title>MFSG Releases Penang International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mfspen" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b84d8eb22bd91c913d0f6e_penang1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="704153"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MFSG has recently released their rendition of Penang International Airport (WMKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third busiest airport in Malaysia with a yearly average of 7.23 million passengers.  The airport was built in 1935 as Bayan Lepas International Airport when Penang was still a British colony.  It was heavily expanded in the 1970s, with a new terminal and a longer runway to accommodate the Boeing 747.   The administration has recently announced a 4-phase expansion plan, which started in 2020 and should reach completion by 2024, doubling its passenger handling capabilities.  It’s currently served by AirAsia, Batik Air, Batik Air Malaysia, Cathay Pacific, China Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Citilink, Firefly, Firefly, Indonesia AirAsia, Jetstar Asia, Lion Air, Malaysia Airlines, MYAirline, Scoot, Singapore Airlines, Starlux Airlines, Thai AirAsia, and Thai Smile.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an updated ground layout (2023), custom ground textures, custom jetways, and AI traffic compatibility.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $15.19, requiring at least 38.97 MB of free hard disk space to install. Owners of the FS2004/FSX/P3D version get the scenery free of charge. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sxaarr</id>
    <title>SXAirportDesign Releases Antonio Rivera Rodríguez Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sxaarr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b85a367e7bab97314d77b0_rivera1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3248140"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SXAirportDesign has recently released their rendition of Antonio Rivera Rodríguez Airport (TJVQ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the island of Vieques in Puerto Rico with a yearly average of 100,000 passengers.  It was built by the United States Navy in the mid-20th century as a small airstrip to support their military operations, only becoming a proper passenger airport after the army ceased training operations on the island in 2001.   It was renamed Antonio Rivera Rodriguez Airport in 2004 after a prominent Puerto Rican politician and former Mayor of Vieques.   There were plans to extend the runway in 2005 so smaller jets could fly into the airport, but it didn’t work out. The current length (1,311 meters) only comports small regional aircraft.  Air Sunshine, Cape Air, M&amp;N Aviation, Silver Airways, and Vieques Air Link serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, high-resolution aerial imagery, custom PBR ground polygons, custom night lighting, and custom 3D vegetation.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $11.25, requiring at least 257.67 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gdssdm</id>
    <title>GearDown Simulations Releases 14-bis for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gdssdm" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64b9aee76558999ded1a81ab_14bis.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="30986"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. GearDown Simulations, in partnership with RPSimulations and a popular aviation channel from Brazil (Aviões &amp; Músicas), has recently released a 14-bis for Microsoft Flight Simulator, first flown in 1906 and known (although not worldwide) as the world’s first airplane.  Inspired by Gabriel Voisin’s glider, Santos Dumont’s 14-bis was made of a Hargrave-cell and powered by a 50 horsepower fuel-injected V8 engine, making it able to fly for a few hundred meters at a time at an impressive (by the early 1900s standards) 40 km/h.  It won the second prize in November 1906 at the Chateau de Bagatelle after flying for 220 meters, earning Santos Dumont a monument at the place, which is still up to this day.  The add-on accurately simulates the aircraft’s performance and flight dynamics based on its original documents.   It’s available on the GearDown Simulations Store for roughly $2.51 (limited-time offer). Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/asf330</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Releases A330 Project's Website</title>
    <updated>2023-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/asf330" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bab87e06f5355d8ded615d_as1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="903327"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aerosoft released the A330 Project's website following their statement post Mathijs Kok's resignation a week ago. The new portal will update customers on the development progress, screenshots, upcoming features, and frequently asked questions.  Along with the brand new website, they have also published an update on the project's current status, covering their extensive effort in rebuilding the 3D model for Microsoft Flight Simulator and rewriting some of the systems.  Furthermore, they have mentioned it can now fly from A to B safely, with most systems working decently but with odd behavior still happening during testing because the flight management system and the autopilot were coded from scratch. Aerosoft has made a list with a few examples:   They are currently working on the soundscape, cockpit usability, and documentation.  There's yet to be any information on the release date or pricing, but Threshold will keep you informed!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pyrgne</id>
    <title>Pyreegue Dev Co. Releases East Midlands Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pyrgne" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bc65ad815d64a96071b3ae_ema1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="222970"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Pyreegue Dev Co. has recently released their rendition of East Midlands Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator (EGNX), serving the entire East Midlands region with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  The airport started as RAF Castle Donington in 1943, sporting three concrete runways and two hangars, and it hosted the 28 Operational Training Unit and the 108 Operational Training Unit during the short WW2 stint. It was closed and decommissioned three years later, in 1946.  Then, in 1964, a group of local government agencies bought the former airfield, investing heavily in transforming it into a commercial airport. It was then renamed East Midlands Airport and got ready for passenger traffic in early 1965.  The airport saw heavy upgrade work in the early 2000s when the traffic figures increased significantly. It included an extension of the passenger terminal, new car parks, and a new pier.  It’s an important cargo hub for DHL and UPS, which collaborate significantly to its second position in cargo traffic in the UK.  Airline-wise, it’s mostly an LCC airport, with the likes of Jet2.com (Alicante, Antalya, Faro, Fuerteventura, Funchal, Gran Canaria, Lanzarote, Málaga, Tenerife–South), TUI (Alicante, Hurghada, Lanzarote, Málaga, Sharm El Sheikh, Tenerife–South), and Ryanair (Alicante, Barcelona, Belfast–International, Bergamo, Berlin, Budapest, Cork, Dublin, Faro, Fuerteventura, Gran Canaria, Knock, Kraków, Lanzarote, Limoges, Málaga, Malta, Riga, Rome–Ciampino, Rzeszów, Tenerife–South, Wrocław).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with LiDAR elevation data, up-to-date satellite imagery, custom ground polygons with accurate weathering, an up-to-date airport layout, ATC/AI traffic integration, animated Skylink buses, dynamic gate doors (GSX is required), a custom GSX profile, a custom terminal interior, landside buildings, and more.  It’s available on Contrail for roughly $22, requiring at least 3.56 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/samjej</id>
    <title>SamScene Releases Jeju International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/samjej" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bda78afb12cff56096a3b8_jeju1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1423378"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SamScene has recently released their rendition of Jeju International Airport (RKPC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in South Korea with a yearly average of 31 million passengers.  The airport was built as a military airfield in 1946 and only converted to civilian use in 1963. The first international flight to Osaka, Japan, only happened a year later.  In the early 90s, due to the constantly rising passenger volume, the government decided to build a much larger terminal, reaching completion in 1997. It has been one of the busiest airports in the country ever since.  Jeju International Airport is a major hub for Korean Air and Asiana Airlines, and it also serves many other airlines, including Air China, China Eastern Airlines, China Southern Airlines, Delta Air Lines, EVA Air, Japan Airlines, Singapore Airlines, and Thai Airways.  The airport is currently operating at its capacity, so they are constructing a new one near the city of Seogwipo, expected to reach completion by 2025.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with a detailed terminal interior, custom night lighting, a detailed city center, iconic points of interest, custom ground markings, custom jetways, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $14.45, requiring at least 1.33 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/winyop</id>
    <title>WingSim Releases El Alcaraván Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/winyop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bdabb6299243be7de1f2c8_yop1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1077617"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. WingSim has recently released their rendition of El Alcaraván Airport (SKYP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Yopal, Colombia.  It was built in the 1960s to serve the oil industry in the state, with Aerotaxi Casanare S/A handling most of the passenger traffic.   In the late 90s, petrol companies worldwide gathered together to improve the airport’s conditions so it could accommodate larger aircraft. The president landed with a Boeing 707 to inaugurate the improvements in late 1996.  Ten years later, the Camera de Comercio de Casanare (their Chamber of Commerce) asked the Ministry of Transport to make it an international airport, which was only granted many years later. Despite being classified as an international airport and having an immigration facility, it has no international flights.  It’s currently served by Avianca, EasyFly, Latam Colombia, and Satena, with flights to Bogotá and Bucaramanga.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, custom night lighting, a terminal interior, hangars, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.35, requiring at least 2.59 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mskmum</id>
    <title>MSK Productions Releases Mumbai Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mskmum" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bdb07af02f056f360a427e_mumbai1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="2248887"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. MSK Productions has recently released their rendition of Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport (VABB) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Mumbai Metropolitan Region with a yearly average of 43 million passengers.  The airport started as a Royal Air Force airfield in the 1930s, housing multiple RAF squadrons during WW2, and was eventually handed over to the government to be converted into a civilian airport once the conflict had ceased.  The first expansion started in the 50s, with further work planned in the 60s but only executed in the late 70s, causing a lot of drama back then. Time magazine said the terminal was a “black hole” of sorts, and then a terminal building fire killed three passengers in 1979. It was overcrowded and unsafe.  The new terminal reached completion in 1980, costing 110 million rupees and temporarily solving the overcrowding. It was then modernized in the early 2000s, bringing it up to international standards.  It is currently the second busiest airport in India, after Indira Gandhi International Airport in New Delhi. Several airlines serve it, including Air India, IndiGo, Jet Airways, and SpiceJet.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR textures, custom buildings, dynamic lighting, animated jetways, terminal 1 and 2 interiors, custom terraforming, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $22.23, requiring at least 380.25 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/simda2</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Releases DA20-C1 Eclipse for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/simda2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bdb3e173a9fad5ca6cb797_da1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="119963"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. SimSolutions has recently released their DA20-C1 Eclipse for X-Plane 12, a two-seat, single-engine airplane manufactured by Diamond.  The Eclipse is the “fancy” variant of the DA20 Katana, a light aircraft introduced by Diamond in 1993, ideal for flight schools and private pilots on a budget. On the other hand, the fancy Eclipse only came to be in 1999, featuring rear windows, better visibility, and a complete set of equipment.  It’s powered by a 125 hp Continental IO-240-B, cruising at up to 138 knots with a range of 629 nautical miles with a 30-minute reserve.  The add-on features an accurate rendition of the aircraft, with high-resolution textures, user-friendly systems, and more. The complete feature list follows down below:   Features Liveries  It’s available on the X-Plane.Org Store for $24.99, requiring at least 476 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lr1212</id>
    <title>Laminar Research Updates X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lr1212" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64bfe8ede88eaaf5cf5ad8a4_Screenshot-2022-11-15-at-11.44.40.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2193773"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Laminar Research has released an early public beta for X-Plane 12.06. Users can expect a long list of bug fixes including fixes for users experiencing CTD crashes when landing at non towered airports and fixes to the Vulkan graphics API. The update also comes with a short list of known bugs including abnormal cloud shapes while using real world weather; Laminar has stated they aim to fix this in version 12.06b2.  Some of the more noticable bug fixes in the new beta include: The new beta comes just 12 weeks after the last update which focused mainly on fixes for the Laminar Research A330. </summary>
    <published>2023-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
