<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2026-02-01T18:46:18.523451+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zdpkea</id>
    <title>Zero Dollar Payware Releases Helo Kearny Heliport for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zdpkea"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697425bcb983c51332c748be_kearny1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Zero Dollar Payware has recently released their rendition of Helo Keany Heliport (65NJ) for X-Plane 12, one of the largest North American heliports with almost 30 helipads. The largest vertical-lift facility on the entire East Coast is a premier FBO that bridges the gap between New Jersey’s logistics hubs and Manhattan’s skyscraper-laden skyline.  Located only two minutes away (flying time, of course) from Manhattan, it’s an ideal staging ground for corporate shuttles, news crews, and tourism operators who need immediate access to the city without the operational hurdles - and costs - of landing directly in Manhattan’s public heliports.  ZDP’s rendition recreates the area with very high fidelity, including all 29 helipads, 5 fuel pads, and a transit pad. Furthermore, it also includes a few static helicopters provided by Jetset.  It’s available for free on Threshold, requiring at least 21.41 MB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a340previews2</id>
    <title>Aerosoft Shares New A340-600 Previews for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a340previews2"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69742ad8ed924cbcaa95f257_forty1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Aerosoft has shared new previews of their upcoming A340-600 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, showcasing the texture work around the flight deck and a couple of external shots. Developed in conjunction with Toliss, Aerosoft’s A340-600 promises a high-fidelity rendition of the intriguing four-engine beast launched by Airbus in 1993, with a deep systems simulation, an accurate 3D model, and realistic physics.  From the next development update onwards, the developers will start hiding hints in some pictures, and five copies will be given away among everyone who finds them all (one per post). There’s still no pricing or release date information, but Threshold will keep you informed! If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidfw</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases First Trailer for MSFS 2024 Dallas Fort Worth</title>
    <updated>2026-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidfw"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/69769f4ac5b4443003fe3798_KDFWForumBannerScenery.png.8d6a8bfd18d00be4df924a39ebf3a277.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just released the first official trailer for its upcoming Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. iniBuilds is recreating one of the world’s busiest aviation hubs, capturing the immense scale of Dallas Fort Worth with its five terminals, complex taxiway network, elevated bridges, and surrounding infrastructure. Built natively for MSFS 2024, the scenery makes use of the latest SDK features, with a strong emphasis on performance, despite the airport’s sheer size. The newly released trailer highlights many of the airport’s defining elements, including the fully modelled and animated Skylink Air Train system, extensive apron areas, and detailed terminal architecture.  iniBuilds has confirmed a comprehensive feature set, including over 180 custom models, bespoke ground textures, up-to-date airport layout data, detailed dynamic lighting, HD jetways, accurate taxi signage, and an official GSX profile. Level of Detail optimisation has been applied across to ensure smooth performance, even during peak traffic scenarios. Scenery Features: While no release date or pricing has been announced, iniBuilds says Dallas Fort Worth is “coming soon,” with content creators and streamers expected to receive early access ahead of launch.  We’ll keep you updated. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbcol</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Coleman A. Young International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbcol"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6976e331cde507f64957bd1f_coleman1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Coleman A. Young International Airport (KDET) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Detroit, Michigan, with a yearly average of 32,850 passengers. It opened as Detroit City Airport Terminal in 1927, designed by architect Perry A. Fellows and built by W. E. Wood Co., after five years of searching for an adequate location and carrying on the necessary construction work.  Two years later, the administration built the first hangar, and it quickly rose into Detroit’s main airport at the time. It was Detroit’s main airport until 1947, when Wayne County Metropolitan Airport took over the majority of the flights. That happened in large part because Detroit City Airport couldn’t be expanded further due to a cemetery in the vicinity, which local residents did not agree to demolishing. Traffic kept on dying over the years, with airline service completely ending in 2000 and the airport’s focus shifting over to pilot training and handling private/corporate flights.  The FAA has recently approved a plan to improve the airport’s infrastructure - the first in 30 years - which should theoretically unlock more than 100 million USD in federal funds over the next decade, allowing the administration to work on a new control tower, improved taxiways, and a regulation-compliant safety zone. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-crafted custom assets, custom ground textures, PBR texturing, fully modeled interiors, custom night lighting, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $13.83, requiring at least 2.77 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/prirecnew</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Releases Recife International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/prirecnew"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697837c7ac820c8c5d187e4b_recife1.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Paulo Ricardo has recently released their rendition of Recife/Guararapes—Gilberto Freyre International Airport (SBRF) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Recife, Pernambuco, Brazil, with an average of 9 million passengers per year. It was built during World War 2 to replace an airfield at the same location. In the years following the conflict, it became a strategic technical and refueling stop on routes from South America to Europe. A new passenger terminal was inaugurated in 1958, and its two runways were extended at the time to accommodate larger aircraft. In the late 1970s, an agreement was reached with Infraero (a state-owned airport operator) to further develop the airport, leading to renovations in 1982 and expansion work in the 1990s. A new passenger terminal, including a shopping mall and a concourse, was built in 2004, increasing its passenger handling capacity from 1.5 million a year to 9 million. In late 2009, the government invested 8 million BRL into upgrading the terminal for the 2014 World Cup, adding eight more jetways and modernizing the infrastructure. It’s a hub for Azul Linhas Aéreas and is served by Gol Linhas Aéreas, LATAM Brasil, TAP Air Portugal, and Voepass Linhas Aéreas. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, a highly detailed passenger terminal with a partially modeled interior, city landmarks, an up-to-date ground layout, and much more. ​ It’s available in the Marketplace (2020 and 2024) for $11.99. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kissar24</id>
    <title>Kiss Simulation Releases Sarajevo International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kissar24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6979965e7fe095501abb745a_sara1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Kiss Simulation has recently released their updated rendition of Sarajevo International Airport (LQSA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, serving the city of Sarajevo in Bosnia and Herzegovina, and averaging 1.3 million passengers a year. It was built in 1966 and opened for traffic three years later, although domestically. International operations began a year later, with Frankfurt as its first international destination.  The first renovation happened nearly 20 years later for the 1984 Winter Olympics, with a new terminal building, a runway extension, and navigational system improvements. The terminal was expanded in 2017, with a new 10,000-square-meter building capable of handling up to 2 million passengers a year. Its mountainous terrain and unpredictable weather have led to multiple financial losses over the years, most notably in December 2015, when over 40% of flights were canceled. The only way they could fix it would be by moving the threshold an additional 200 meters, which would shorten the runway, which is not ideal given that it’s already relatively short at 2,600 meters.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, including the new terminal extension, a custom runway profile, a real-world ILS profile, custom-made ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, runway weathering, and more. It’s available on SimMarket for $15.50, requiring at least 1.75 GB of free hard disk space. Owners of the 2020 version are entitled to a free upgrade. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mcucal</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update 13: California for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mcucal"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697a6de6510e591e618372b9_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Out of the blue, Microsoft has released its latest city update for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024. City Update 13 significantly enhances various cities across California. This update includes improvements in 18 different urban areas, such as San Francisco, Los Angeles, San Diego, and others. The 18 different areas have been accurately recreated using TIN (triangulated irregular network) surface texturing. The updated regions allow users to explore what the Golden State has to offer. It's important to note that Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 users must manually update both World Update II and World Update X from the in-Sim Content Manager for City Update 13 to function properly. This requirement does not apply to users of Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The new city update is now available for free in the in-Sim Marketplace. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ff77xp</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Updates 777 for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ff77xp"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697a88c173625a40a6c70465_MedalTVXPlane1120260111124133509.png"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has released another update to their 777 series for X-Plane 12, bringing version 2.3.12 to the addon. This update follows the numerous and regular updates that FlightFactor has done on their 777 since its first release. The update does not bring any new features to the aircraft, but does fix multiple bugs. ‍ In this update, Flightfactor has updated the manual, fixed the storm light switch, fixed deicing issues, and much more. The full changelog can be viewed below. Changelog:  ‍ ‍ The FlightFactor 777v2 can be purchased on the X-Plane.org store for 89 USD. There are also various other expansions that can be purchased for the aircraft, including the engine expansion, the freighter upgrade, or a pack combining all three. ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hnhv</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Tweed New Haven for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hnhv"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697c364f7c991ab77fe43e51_nh1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Tweed-New Haven Regional Airport (KHVN) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving New Haven and the New York Metropolitan Area, with an average of 1.1 million passengers per year. The airport opened for traffic in late 1931 as New Haven Municipal Airport. Li-Con Airways Incorporated and American Airlines were the first to commercially serve the then brand-new airport in 1933 and 1934, respectively. While Li-Con’s service lasted only a year, American Airlines’ route between Boston, New Haven, and New York lasted nearly three decades. Allegheny Airlines and Allegheny Commuter took over after American Airlines ended regularly scheduled service, operating BAC One-Eleven jets until the mid-1970s.  In the late 1970s, New Haven Airways kicked off their scheduled flights, becoming New Haven’s hometown airline - NewAir -, operating flights to New York (JFK and La Guardia), Philadelphia, Baltimore/Washington Intl, and Washington National with their fleet of de Havilland Canada DHC-6 Twin Otter, Embraer EMB-110 Bandeirante, and Short 360s. NewAir’s operations were relatively short-lived, with operations ending in 1985. After the mid-1980s, regularly scheduled service started declining massively, with airlines starting and quickly ending operations in New Haven. It wasn’t until the 2010s that New Haven would see renewed activity. In late 2024, the airport received $ 4 million to build a new passenger terminal, aiming to replace the previous one, built nearly a century ago, with modern facilities, almost 8,000 square meters of area, and greatly improving the airport’s passenger handling capabilities. There are also plans to expand the runway. Avelo Airlines and Breeze Airways are the only two airlines currently serving the airport. The scenery promises an accurate rendition of the airport, with an up-to-date ground layout, custom terminal and airport buildings, high-resolution PBR ground textures, a detailed apron, realistic night lighting, and performance-friendly optimization. It’s available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $9.64, requiring at least 3.36 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hbir</id>
    <title>Fly 2 High Releases Birmingham-Shuttlesworth International Airport for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hbir"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697c5f09366f000c65b90a87_bir1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Fly 2 High has recently released their rendition of Birmingham-Shuttlesworth International Airport (KBHM) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, serving Birmingham, Alabama, with an average of 3.2 million passengers per year, making it the largest and busiest airport in the state. The airport opened in early 1931 with a single east-west runway and a two-story passenger terminal. The airport was leased to the United States Army Air Forces for $1 a year during World War 2 to support national defense, becoming Birmingham Army Airfield. The period under the US Army’s helm brought several improvements, such as new paved taxiways, a new control tower, and the construction of an aircraft modification center. Despite Birmingham being considered a potential air transportation hub for the American South, an aviation fuel tax imposed by the city made it financially unfeasible for many operators, leading Atlanta to become the preferred choice instead. ​ The airport played an important role during the Bay of Pigs invasion in 1961, with pilots and crew from the Alabama National Air Guard selected to train Cuban exile fliers in Nicaragua to fly the Douglas B-26 Invader.  ​ A second passenger terminal was built in 1962 to accommodate the ever-growing passenger figures, along with a new control tower.  ​ Then, a new semi-circular terminal was completed in 1973 with 15 aircraft gates and a large parking deck.  ​ Between 1970 and 1992, a slow demolition process began to completely demolish the original passenger terminal built in 1931. The 1990s brought multiple runway expansions to accommodate larger aircraft. ​ In 2011, the administration approved a new three-phase terminal modernization project, demolishing the old terminal from 1962, the semi-circular terminal from 1973, and constructing new facilities with 19 gates, doubling the airport’s footprint. It’s served by American Airlines, American Eagle, Delta Air Lines, Delta Connection, Southwest Airlines, United Airlines, and United Express. The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, an up-to-date ground layout, custom jetways, accurate taxiways, custom PBR texturing, performance-friendly optimization, custom night lighting, and much more. ​ It’s available on OrbxDirect (2020 version here) for roughly $16.10, requiring at least 3.04 GB of free hard disk space. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orblandperth</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Landmarks Perth City Pack for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orblandperth"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697c67bc7818f1668870592b_per1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Orbx has recently released a landmark pack for Perth (Australia), designed to complement their new Perth International Airport (YPPH) airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The comprehensive pack aims to bring Perth to life with its vibrant skyline, adding hand-crafted custom models to further improve the experience when flying in and out of Perth International. There are over 40 custom-modeled buildings around the city, along with improvements to vegetation, better object placement (buildings, bridges, static boats, vessels, and cranes), custom night lighting around Elizabeth Quay, an airstrip at Langley Park for landings in the city centre, and much more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.56, requiring at least 2.55 GB of free hard disk space to install. There’s also a bundle with the landmarks pack and Perth airport, offering a 10% discount.  If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inidfwnew</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Shares New Previews of Upcoming Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inidfwnew"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697c6b5a04d151fa56087d5c_dfw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently shared a couple of new screenshots of their upcoming Dallas/Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) scenery for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, set to release soon.  DFW is the third-busiest airport in the world, with an average of 82 million passengers per year. As expected from such figures, the airport’s size is quite substantial, and not many developers have tried to tackle it in the past.  iniBuilds claims to have captured every corner of the airport, bringing an incredible hub experience to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The scenery promises an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom high-definition jetways, a high-resolution ground poly, performance-friendly optimization, over 180 hand-crafted models, custom ground service equipment, and much more. There’s no pricing or release date yet, but iniBuilds says it’s “coming soon”. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/kdfwre</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Dallas Fort Worth International Airport for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/kdfwre"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697d24a797a8a9478ab897a3_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has just released its version of Dallas Fort Worth International Airport (KDFW) for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. This airport serves the Dallas–Fort Worth–Arlington metropolitan area and was the world’s fourth-busiest airport by passenger traffic last year, welcoming an impressive 85.6 million passengers. The airport began commercial operations in 1974 under the name Dallas/Fort Worth Regional Airport. It was renamed Dallas/Fort Worth International in 1985. Initially, the airport had just four terminals, but it has since expanded to five, with plans for a sixth terminal underway. With seven runways, the airport accommodates nearly 90 million passengers each year. It serves a variety of airlines and is a hub for American Airlines, Ameriflight, Southern Airways Express, and UPS Airlines, while also serving as a base of operations for Frontier Airlines and Spirit Airlines. These airlines, along with many others, offer destinations worldwide. iniBuilds has included a comprehensive set of features in the scenery package. It features highly detailed models of all airport buildings, objects, and surrounding areas, as well as a full HD ground polygon. The airport layout is up-to-date, and it includes high-definition jetways and dynamic airport lighting. Additionally, the package contains a fully modelled and animated Skylink Air Train system, among a variety of other features. The newly released Dallas Fort Worth International Airport is now available from iniBuilds for $27.57. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned on Threshold! ‍ If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon!</summary>
    <published>2026-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inia340109</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A340 Airliner for MSFS 2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inia340109"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697d8c6a45b2779e35785123_a340lol.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A340 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, focusing on system stability, operational accuracy, and visual refinements across multiple liveries and models. ​ Update v1.0.9 includes fixes to FMGS, navigation systems, CPDLC/ACARS, and flight planning logic, along with mitigations for performance calculation, waypoint handling, auto-flight, and indications. Furthermore, it also refines visuals across multiple liveries and models, restores a few missing callouts, and improves their timing and behaviour. The complete changelog follows below: V1.0.9SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED SayIntentions - After receiving a handover, the DCDU no longer shows the active ATC UnitFIXED SayIntentions - Unable to request ATIS via CPDLC / ATC MenuFIXED Missed approach was shown in green in the MCDUFIXED Direct To issueFIXED FPLN A, DTO clips TO wpt NM textFIXED ACARS flight log page 2 bugsFIXED ACARS post flight report message not triggering COMPANY MSG in EWDFIXED FADEC not powering off as expectedFIXED ND FIX range rings not drawing centered on selected fixFIXED Beyond ATC integration not working as expected (CPDLC / METAR / ATIS)FIXED No DISCON to IAF when selecting STAR without VIAFIXED WIND request missing RETURN promptFIXED Engine 1 controls reverse indication for all four enginesFIXED Unable to enter 0°C temperature into PERF REQ pageFIXED DEPART REQ fields not auto-populating after INIT requestFIXED SID not listed in alphabetical orderFIXED Entering navaid on NDB R field blanks the page after briefly showing identifierFIXED Issues with Along Track WaypointsFIXED Issues with datalink system implementationFIXED Not possible to enter a custom ETP1 waypoint on the FIX INFO pageFIXED Heading bug disappearing on mini-compass rose in PFD while not in managed HDG modeFIXED DEGE3W INTCPT KLO R252 not shownFIXED Manually adding a constraint above FL100 automatically adds 250 knotsFIXED 10,000 ft speed limit waypoint inserted too earlyFIXED Format and calculation issues on INIT B and FUEL PRED pagesFIXED Company message FMC message not showing on FO side FMSFIXED APU door closes even without any electrical power FIXED Incorrect HDG maintained when on TRUEFIXED Course pointer incorrect in ND when on FIXED Unable to enter pilot waypoint on FIX INFO page FIXED Reference thrust indication switching to climb thrust immediately after liftoffFIXED Company Message memo remaining on after all messages viewedFIXED DDRMI compass card not showing TRUE heading when selected FIXED MCDU datalink status page issues ART 🎨FIXED Aerolíneas Argentinas missing engine decalsFIXED HiFly 9H-TQM missing under-wing registrationFIXED TAP CS-TOC missing under-wing registrationFIXED Fuel jettison valve black color lostFIXED Lufthansa livery updateFIXED GPU cable clipping through connection cableFIXED VIP livery Iran EP-IGA right winglet decal clipping / incorrect angleFIXED Light bleeding through couch backrestFIXED HiFly TQZ small line below right-hand stabilizer SOUNDS🔊 FIXED Printer paper sound split in two FIXED Flap sound delayed on first extension FIXED EVAC HORN OFF not silencing cockpit horn FIXED Missing RA callouts (90 / 80 / 70 / 5) FIXED Flap sounds delayed when moving from Flaps 0 to Flaps 1 FIXED Hundred Above and Minimum callouts tonal mismatchFIXED ISIS STD QNH button playing double-click sound FIXED No Smoking sign missing tone FIXED Cockpit door open / close sound only playing when inside cockpit ‍ It’s available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $61.92, requiring at least 7.02 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a350121</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Updates A350 Airliner for MSFS 2020/2024</title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a350121"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/68042934f3c420d62ca6c3da_china2.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. iniBuilds has recently issued an update to their A350 Airliner for Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and 2024, refining systems and usability, delivering multiple bug fixes, and improving overall consistency across all phases of flight. Update v1.2.1 focuses on greatly improving the FMGS, navigation, VNAV, and auto-flight behavior, whilst also addressing a variety of bugs affecting the general flight experience. It also brings improvements to thrust logic, true north handling, etc. The complete changelog follows below: V1.2.1SYSTEMS ⚙️FIXED Cannot enter AIRINC fixesFIXED Cannot click DIR TO box to input textFIXED PERF DES Page – PRED TO time value always incorrectFIXED Issue with cancel button clickspot on OISFIXED No rudder deflection shown on F/CTRL page on groundFIXED Predicted wind/speed ECAM with all WXR settings selectedFIXED Landing report not displayingFIXED FO MFD cursor not aligned with mouseFIXED True north reference missingFIXED Non-standard GP angles shown incorrectly on NAV RAD pageFIXED A/THR not disconnecting via instinctive pushbuttonFIXED Direct To clearing out flight plan in edge casesFIXED Issue converting speed to Mach when switching AP speed modeFIXED QNH value flashing on power-on with no MCDU dataFIXED Engine oil quantity indicationFIXED OPT and REC MAX FL decreasing after step climbFIXED Default transition altitude incorrectFIXED VNAV and PFD indication issues on RNP approachesFIXED Rudder indicator showing pedal position instead of actual rudderFIXED Terrain texture flickering on VSDFIXED Disengaging ATHR during climb gives incorrect thrust modeFIXED Floating bracket and ETP logic brokenFIXED NEW DEST in SEC FPLN not starting from selected pointFIXED AWY/WPT mismatch in secondary flight plansFIXED POSITION/MONITOR page BRG/DIST logic issuesFIXED Unable to create hold around custom waypoint in secondary planFIXED FD OFF HDG/TRK bug disappearing from NDFIXED Keyboard input issue when entering NEXT WPTFIXED DIR TO lat/long not working on NDFIXED DTO field remembering previous entry if not executedFIXED Entering FROM P.POS DIR TO not showing waypoint on next pageFIXED Cannot enter first SID from dropdown listFIXED Odd vertical deviation dashed path shownFIXED ND range indications displacedFIXED RTE SUMMARY database logic issueADDED Cancel or reset button on ATC COM D-ATIS page ART 🎨FIXED Improve cabin lightingFIXED GPU models clipping with GSX heavy pushback trucksFIXED Co-pilot model missing by defaultFIXED Pilot models missing from external cameraFIXED Spoiler animation slowing excessively near end of travelFIXED Beacon light spalsh refinedFIXED Missing ADF antennasFIXED Brake smoke effect triggering too soonFIXED Strobe effects missing physical double-flash EFB📱FIXED Autocovers option not workingFIXED ACARS pending update stuck and METAR symbol issuesFIXED Keyboard input issues affecting EFB entriesADDED EFB option to adjust cabin lighting SOUND 🔊FIXED RA callouts delayed near touchdownFIXED Certain RA callouts missingFIXED Minimum and Hundred Above callout tone mismatchFIXED APU and engine fire test volume too low with ANR enabledFIXED Engine 2 throttle lever missing soundsFIXED Split printer sounds in FS24 ‍ It’s available in the iniBuilds Store for roughly $82.57, requiring at least 13.62 GB of free hard disk space to install. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcraep20</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Announces Airport Enhancement Package 2.0 for X-Plane </title>
    <updated>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcraep20"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/697d958615d4f4125fbdc969_klax-mid-after.jpg"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Codr has recently announced a substantial update to their Airport Enhancement Package add-on for X-Plane, bringing procedurally generated life to over 36,000 airports around the globe. While the original AEP focused on replacing key assets (ground textures, common buildings, and service vehicles), AEP 2.0 aims to add to airports, not just replace assets around them. After months of development and tinkering, the developer has managed to create a program that reads and understands the global airports, procedurally generating overlays that greatly enhance the experience with tire skids on taxi routes, runways, and service roads, additional clutter at gates and near buildings, grunge, oil leaks, rust, and random ramp clutter, yielding a more lifelike experience around every airport in the simulator. While the procedural generation is the new star of the show, it doesn’t mean AEP no longer replaces assets, with over a thousand custom assets in total, including new pavement textures, service vehicles, new cars, all of the legacy hangars (and new ones), and various clutter objects. There are a couple of things that are still being worked on before release, such as more baggage cart variants, old long metal hangars, cargo area clutter, stability testing for a new feature yet to be announced, and beta testing. They also use this opportunity to seek people willing to help stress-test the new product and aid in shaping the final release through their contact page or Discord.  Furthermore, the developer has also mentioned that it will be a free upgrade for AEP 1.0 owners. If you enjoy our content and want to support Threshold, consider joining us on Patreon! ‍</summary>
    <published>2026-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
