<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-05-09T18:22:20.297449+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/parvcp</id>
    <title>Paulo Ricardo Releases Viracopos International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/parvcp" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644e6d81dab9f6b9078318b4_vcp1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="3479893"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Paulo Ricardo has recently released his rendition of Viracopos International Airport (SBKP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Campinas, Sao Paulo state, in Brazil. It's the fourth busiest airport in the country, with a yearly average of 11,845,500 passengers. The airport originated from a small airfield built in 1932 during the Constitutionalist Revolution in Sao Paulo. Then, in the 1950s, it started as a cargo airport, which is still one of its main roles today.   In the 1960s, it was Sao Paulo's international airport because Guarulhos did not exist yet, and Congonhas (SBSP) didn't have a long enough runway to accommodate international jet planes. The distance (100km) quickly became an issue, as people would fly to Rio de Janeiro - Galeão instead and then take a connecting flight to Congonhas. As a curiosity, it even showed up in the Guinness Book during that time as the furthest airport from the city it claimed to serve. It was Sao Paulo's international airport for nearly 25 years until Guarulhos International Airport (SBGR) was constructed. Losing the "crown" didn't mean it would be forgotten and left to rot, with Infraero investing millions in improving the airport's infrastructure for passengers and cargo. It was divided into three steps, the first completed in 2004, with the construction of new passenger lounges and a new cargo terminal. The second step, in 2005, expanded the passenger terminal and built a control tower. The third phase, which consists of constructing a second runway, still has yet to happen. ‍ It's a popular alternate airport to Rio de Janeiro-Galeão and both Congonhas and Guarulhos in Sao Paulo because it hardly closes due to adverse weather conditions.  Viracopos is the second busiest cargo airport in the country, with 77,000 square meters of cargo terminals, 1,700 square meters for animal cargo, and 1,480 cubic meters of refrigerated space.  ‍ The airport is the hub for Azul Brazilian Airlines, covering a huge domestic network and a couple of international routes. GOL Transportes Aéreos, one of the biggest South American LCCs, offers five domestic routes from VCP. On the cargo side, it hosts Azul Cargo and LATAM Cargo.  The scenery features a highly accurate rendition of the airport and the surrounding city (Campinas), with a fully modeled passenger terminal and its interior, custom ground markings, landside buildings, custom ground clutter, custom night lighting, a realistic depiction of the internal layout with all of the shops as per real life, multiple POIs, and more. It's available on the MSFS Marketplace for roughly $15.99, requiring at least 4.70 GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/bsscl650</id>
    <title>BSS Releases Soundpack for Hotstart Challenger 650</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/bsscl650" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644eb541ab76f87c4fb323fb_669001806_X-Plane2022-01-0900-15-55.jpg.49608ee2d0f29fb7bfba48f67f23d175.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="807434"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Blue Sky Star Simulations, better known as BSS, have released a sound pack for the popular Hotstart Challenger CL650. BSS is known for creating additional sound packs for many freeware and payware aircraft, these soundpacks revamp all sounds associated with the aircraft.   ‍ The Hotstart Challenger CL650 was released in early 2022 and has become a popular business jet addon. The Addon models the Bombardier Challenger CL650, a large cabin business jet based on the Canadair CRJ family aircraft. This jet can carry up to 19 passengers on trips up 4,000NM. The Hotstart CL650 was able to model this aircraft with “study-level” accuracy.  ‍ The BSS soundpack revamps many areas of the addon with new engine and wind sounds, a full feature list is as follows:  ‍ Existing Hotstart CL650 customers can purchase the sound pack from the X-Plane.org Store for $19.99. To purchase a copy of the Hotstart CL650, you can visit the X-Aviation.com store.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pmddev</id>
    <title>PMDG Publishes New Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pmddev" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6306a7ff9e1844bf69c05102_PMDG_NG3_screenshots9__68685.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="173754"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Robert Randazzo, PMDG’s founder, has recently published a development update on their forum regarding future updates for the 737 lineup and its potential Xbox release, the Universal Flight Tablet, the 777, and more.   Robert begins with information on an upcoming update for the 737 lineup. He claims they are refactoring some of the click-controls and animation logic to better conform with the new SDK standards, which differ from what it used to be back in 2020 when the aircraft was still under development. They managed to preserve all functionality on PC while also functioning identically on Xbox. They have also been refining AFDS roll control logic, improving magenta line computations, and continuing with the preparations to make the navdata system compatible with the new Navigraph database format.  With some of the aforementioned improvements, a new update is coming soon for the 737s. It will be available in the PMDG Operations Center for people who bought it directly via their website and a week later on the Marketplace (they state it’s hard to predict how long that will take, so it’s just an assumption).  PMDG claims to be “happy” with the 737 on Xbox, although holding off on releasing it just yet because they have not gained clarity on the timeline for the associated livery packages available in the Marketplace for use by Xbox customers. They are using the DC-6 as a gauge for how long it takes, and it appears to move through the process substantially slower than the aircraft itself. They intend to fully understand the timeline before releasing the aircraft. On that livery package note, they state that even though the original plan was to make it free of charge, the Marketplace has a minimum pricing of $4.99 per item, which will be the cost of each livery package, through no fault of their own.  The Universal Flight Tablet is said to be robust and ready for wide-scale testing after the developers had to fight an issue involving C++/WASM and their capabilities of sending/receiving data from the sim to the outside world. They don’t have a release timeline yet, but they say Navigraph/SimBrief users will be pleased with the UFT once it’s out.  The DC-6, on the other hand, also underwent heavy work to ensure proper compatibility with the Xbox, including changes to the shape/function of some clickable surfaces to facilitate their use on consoles. The changes are currently being tested; they claim it should be out late next week. PC users will also get the update, but it’s said to be “transparent,” given it targets Xbox folk.  They finish with information on the 777, saying “work is progressing nicely” and that the “pieces are coming together in a polished form.” Although they do not plan to show any in-development shots yet, they have claimed it’s “yielding some absolutely spectacular results” and that their development process has matured significantly since 2020. They promise that the wait and their silence will be paid off with great joy.  The 737 Lineup and the DC-6 are available on the PMDG Shop and in the MSFS Marketplace (partially).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/carfle</id>
    <title>Carenado Updates Part of MSFS Fleet</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/carfle" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/644ecc7203a3d77f3160ae0b_carenado1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="348570"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Carenado has recently updated some of their aircraft (PC12, C337 Skymaster, C170B, PA34 Seneca V, and PA28R Arrow III) to version 2.0 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, bringing many improvements and bug fixes. The new update aims to bring the aircraft up to the latest standard with improved integration of the custom Garmins (WT, TDS, and PMS), engine sounds, overall flight dynamics, a redesign of the electrical system, VR compatibility improvements, improved engine startup and heat effects, and minor bug fixes. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ ‍ The update is now available on the MSFS Marketplace, free of charge. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orblc2</id>
    <title>Orbx Teases London City Airport V2 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orblc2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6450f5bcb024aa0b4cfa0f8c_lon1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1542527"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently teased an upcoming update to their now nearly three-year-old rendition of London City Airport (EGLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in London with a yearly average of 5 million passengers. The original LCY came out back when the simulator was brand new, and developers were still getting acquainted with the SDK, making it quite outdated by contemporary standards, especially considering the real-life layout also saw changes in that meantime. Version two considers the airport expansion, with its parallel taxiway, new parking stands, and the remote digital control tower. ‍ They claim to have entirely rebuilt the airport, with an extensive rework of every detail, new textures, additional enhancements, and a custom ground poly.   ‍ The airport is said to integrate perfectly with their Landmarks London product, ensuring a highly immersive approach.  They claim it should be available soon on OrbxDirect, and previous owners will be able to get their hands on it for a small upgrade fee.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hbli</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Bellingham International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hbli" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6451290a2e7c1f23c6674ae2_bli1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1203983"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Bellingham International Airport (KBLI) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the third largest commercial airport in Washington with a yearly average of 316,693 passengers as of 2022.  The airport’s history dates back to October 1936, when the construction work began under the supervision of the WPA (Works Progress Administration), which had previously funded the purchase of the airport’s 200 acres of land from Charles F. Larrabee. Initially, there were plans for three runways, but only one was built, with 1,100 meters of length and 46 meters of width.   The US Army Corps of Engineers took over the entire project in 1940, expanding the airport to three full runways and building a basic infrastructure to operate as an airport. It was opened to the public a year later and then seized by the US Army not long after, following the Pearl Harbor attacks.   During World War 2, Bellingham International was utilized by the Fourth Air Force to provide an aerial defense to the Pacific Coast and later on for ferrying aircraft to Alaska for its subsequent transfer to the Soviet Union.  Post-war, the facility was closed and handed back to Whatcom County, slowly redeveloped as a civilian airport with a terminal designed by F. Stanley Piper. High costs led Whatcom County to sell it to the Port of Bellingham in 1957 for 1 dollar. The new owners were not fond of the high expenses either, only resurfacing one of the runways (16/34), which is still the sole runway in operation.  In 2010, the runway was resurfaced to accommodate Allegiant Air’s Boeing 757s on their nonstop service to Hawaii.   The terminal saw upgrades in 1980 with a two-phase project and a 38 million-dollar expansion in the early 2010s, increasing the number of gates and the general terminal area from 27,500 square feet to 104,000 square feet.   Bellingham is served by four airlines: Alaska Airlines (Seattle-Tacoma), Allegiant Air (Las Vegas, Los Angeles, Oakland, Palm Springs, Phoenix/Mesa, San Diego), San Juan Airlines (Eastsound, Friday Harbor, Lopez, Point Roberts), and Southwest Airlines (Las Vegas, Oakland).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of BLI, with an updated ground layout, custom ground markings, a terminal interior, and more.  It’s available on FlightSim.to for roughly $10.99, requiring at least 470.91 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/onfkir</id>
    <title>Onfinal Studio Releases Kirkenes Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/onfkir" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645256faee3ddd05c04659c6_kirk1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="939972"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Onfinal Studio has recently released their rendition of Kirkenes Airport (ENKR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 35th busiest airport in Scandinavia with a yearly average of 247,107 passengers.  Built as a military air station in WW2 and briefly operated as a civilian airport right after the war until its abandonment in 1948, it wasn't until 1963 that it would be reopened with a new terminal and an extended runway, where SAS and Finnair reigned supreme for nearly the entire decade until Wideroe and Norving followed suit.  In 1990, the airport underwent a major renovation and expansion, which included constructing a new terminal building, an extended runway, and modernized facilities for passengers and aircraft. The airport continued to grow and develop throughout the 1990s and 2000s, with additional upgrades and expansions to keep pace with the increasing demand for air travel in the region.  Kirkenes Airport has a single terminal building that houses all of the airport's facilities, including check-in counters, baggage handling, security, and boarding gates. The terminal is relatively small but modern and well-equipped with amenities such as a restaurant, a café, a duty-free shop, and a souvenir store.  It’s served by Norwegian Air Shuttle (Oslo, Tromso), Scandinavian Airlines (Oslo), and Widerøe (Alta, Båtsfjord, Berlevåg, Hammerfest, Honningsvåg, Mehamn, Sørkjosen, Tromsø, Vadsø, Vardø).   The scenery features a high-detail rendition of the airport, with accurate 3D models of all buildings, custom-made objects placed around the area, PBR textures, and night lighting. It also features the current runway dimensions. Furthermore, the terrain around the airport was corrected to more accurately resemble the real counterpart.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $13.15, requiring at least 355.71 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/uk2lci</id>
    <title>UK2000 Scenery Releases London City Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/uk2lci" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6453e2a6398751495f2ec5a5_landun1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1247371"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. UK2000 Scenery has recently released their rendition of London City Airport (EGLC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the fifth busiest airport in London with a yearly average of 5 million passengers.  Inaugurated in 1987, after years of bureaucratic slowdowns and with construction work only starting a year before, it originally had 1080 meters of runway and a glide path angle of 7.5 degrees, severely limiting the aircraft options that could fly into the airport. It took only a short time until they needed to extend the runway to accommodate more aircraft.  The extension came a few years later, in 1992, increasing it to a total of 1,508 meters, and reducing the glide path angle to 5.5 degrees, making it "compatible" with more aircraft, thus, attracting more airlines to operate at the airport.  The airport is mainly served by British Airways, with many intra-European destinations such as Amsterdam, Barcelona, and Zürich. The visitors' list includes ITA Airways, KLM, Loganair, LOT Polish Airlines, Lufthansa, Luxair, and Swiss International Air Lines.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport as it currently stands, with detailed buildings, realistic ground markings, high-resolution ground imagery, night lighting, highly detailed airport vehicles, performance-friendly optimization, custom vegetation, PBR materials, static aircraft, and optional trains.  It's available on SimMarket and UK2000 Store for roughly $15.45, requiring at least 53.17 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/navcha</id>
    <title>Navigraph Updates SimBrief with Charts Integration</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/navcha" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6453e8611180cdeb8b3e374c_navi1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="151885"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Navigraph has recently added a brand new feature to their SimBrief flight planner: Navigraph Charts are now available within their flight planner with four different map layers.   Navigraph Ultimate users can toggle their charts within SimBrief, with four options: High IFR, Low IFR, VFR, and World Map. To do so, click on the Navigraph icon in the top right corner of the map (displayed on New/Edit Flight and View Flight Plan page), and then a dropdown list will appear with the aforementioned options.   Users without the Ultimate subscription will only get the default style map. The Ultimate plan is available on Navigraph’s website for $9.92/mo or $89.98/yr.   Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rotm80</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-80 Pro for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rotm80" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6453f1ceec32760b1d3f19d9_rotate1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="110433"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate recently released their rendition of the McDonnell Douglas MD-80 for X-Plane 12 under a beta program.  The MD-80 Pro for X-Plane 12 aims to deliver a precise flight model and fine-tuned engine performance, developed with advice and counseling from real MD-80 pilots.  The features include a custom flight management system with SIDs and STARs, custom LNAV and VNAV, take-off and approach speed management, custom navigation display, complete HOLD functionality with entry pattern calculation and present POS, a detailed simulation of systems with WX/TCAS, an accurate PW-JT8D-219 model with its intricacies, advanced electrical and hydraulics systems, and realistic visuals with PBR texturing, accurate animations, rain and ice windshield effects, VR compatibility, and custom sounds.  The MD-80 is a twin-engine, medium-range jet airliner designed and manufactured by McDonnell Douglas. It was first introduced in 1980 and quickly became a popular choice for airlines worldwide due to its fuel efficiency and reliability. It was a shortened version of the earlier DC-9 airliner, which had been in production since the 1960s. McDonnell Douglas updated the design of the DC-9, incorporating more modern technology, such as advanced avionics and more efficient engines, to create the MD-80.  Despite its popularity, its production eventually ended in 1999 when Boeing acquired McDonnell Douglas. However, many MD-80s are still in service today, particularly in countries with developing aviation industries.  It’s available on X-Plane.Org for $59.95. Owners of the X-Plane 11 version are entitled to a discounted upgrade ($24.95).  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/agsbur</id>
    <title>AG Sim Releases Burgas Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/agsbur" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64550a051ed2d0d98d301b13_burgas1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="727378"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. AG Sim has recently released their rendition of Burgas Airport (LBBG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the 2nd busiest airport in Bulgaria with a yearly average of 2,885,000 passengers. The first landing strip was built in 1912 by the Bulgarian Army during the Balkan War. This airfield was used for military purposes during World War I and II. After the war ended, it was also used for civilian purposes. ‍ In the 1960s, a new modern airport was built on the old airfield site, officially opened in 1970. The airport had a single runway and a small terminal building at the time. It served as an essential transportation hub for Bulgaria's Black Sea coast, and it played a significant role in the country's tourism industry. During the 1980s and 1990s, the airport underwent significant renovations and expansions, including the construction of a new terminal building, a second runway, and improved navigation and air traffic control systems. These upgrades allowed the airport to accommodate larger aircraft and more passengers, becoming a major gateway to the country for tourists from all over Europe. In the 2000s, the airport continued to expand and modernize. In 2013, a new terminal building was opened, increasing the airport's capacity to more than 2.7 million passengers annually.  The airport's traffic is primarily seasonal, with many airlines coming over to visit during the summer: Aer Lingus, airBaltic, BH Air, Bluebird Airways, Bulgaria Air, Buzz, Corendon Dutch Airlines, easyJet, Enter Air, European Air Charter, Eurowings, Freebird Airlines Europe, GetJet Airlines, Jet Time, Jet2.com, LOT Polish Airlines, Luxair, Norwegian Air Shuttle, Ryanair, SkyUp, SmartLynx Airlines, Smartwings, Sunclass Airlines, Sundair, TUI Airways, TUI fly Belgium, TUI fly Netherlands, TUI fly Nordic, Windrose Airlines, and Wizzair (the only one with a year-long route to London Luton). The scenery accurately represents the airport's terminal, runway, taxiways, and surroundings, with custom ground textures, PBR materials, dynamic apron objects, and realistic night lighting.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $15.49, requiring at least 1.60GB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/sdeflo</id>
    <title>S-Design Releases Florø Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/sdeflo" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645512a778f7b09cd6542422_flo1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3440809"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. S-Design has recently released their rendition of Florø Airport (ENFL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the town of Florø in Vestland, Norway. The yearly average sits at around 200,000 passengers as of 2014.  The airport opened in 1971 with three other regional airports in Norway. Back then, it was served by Wideroe with de Havilland Canada Twin Otters until 1994, when Coast Air took over. Danish Air Transport took over briefly between 2003 and 2012 when Wideroe made their glorious return.   Avinor, the airport owner, has plans to eventually expand the airport, which still uses its first terminal from 1971, considered small by today’s standards. They also consider a potential runway extension from 1,700m to 2,000 meters, allowing bigger aircraft to operate at the airport. The major implication, though, would be the cost: 200 million kroner, and the amount of work it would imply, as it would require lots of flattening and landfilling.   It is served by three airlines: Bristow Helicopters (Deepsea Stavanger, Gjøa, Snorre A and B, Visund), DAT (Oslo), and Widerøe (Bergen).   The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-definition hand-made ground textures, true-to-life landside recreation, 20cm aerial imagery, highly detailed models of all airport buildings, and 4K PBR texturing.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $12.17, requiring at least 621.32MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!     ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/netgue</id>
    <title>NetDesign Releases In Guezzam Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/netgue" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6456a359d537e89d2831bfc9_datg1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1697928"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. NetDesign has recently released their rendition of In Guezzam Airport (DATG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a regional civilian and military airport in Algeria, right on the border with Niger.   Guezzam Airport was built in the early 1970s, primarily as a military airport. However, it has also been developed to serve commercial air traffic in the years since. Today, the airport mainly serves domestic flights within Algeria but also has international connections to other African countries, such as Niger and Mali.  The airport has a single runway that measures 2,200 meters in length and is equipped with modern navigational aids. The passenger terminal building is relatively small but provides all the essential services travelers require, including check-in counters, baggage handling facilities, and a small selection of shops and restaurants.  Due to its location in the Sahara Desert, Guezzam Airport can experience extreme weather conditions, including sandstorms and high temperatures. As such, travelers need to check weather conditions and plan their trips accordingly.  In addition to its role as a transportation hub, Guezzam Airport is also strategically important for military purposes. The airport is located near Algeria's borders with Niger and Mali, which have experienced security challenges in recent years due to the presence of armed extremist groups.   The scenery aims to faithfully recreate the airport based on the few available photos and satellite imagery, with a basic terminal, control tower, and an Algerian military base. It features 4K PBR textures, a VOR approach with the official airport chart included, detailed sandy sidewalks, realistic night lighting, and performance-friendly optimization.  It's available on SimMarket for roughly $11.00, requiring at least 242.62 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnancy</id>
    <title>France VFR Releases Metz-Nancy-Lorraine Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnancy" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6456b0500ecf7b713408630a_nan1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="264175"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. France VFR has recently released their rendition of Metz-Nancy-Lorraine (LFJL) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the Lorraine region of France with a yearly average of 250,000 passengers. The airport opened in October 1991, replacing Nancy-Essey and Metz-Frescaty, sporting modern infrastructure and supporting the region’s economic growth and development. In 2006, the airport underwent upgrades, with the runway being lengthened to 3,050 meters, along with refurbishing work on the terminal, built in the 90s. It’s 7500 square meters large, with 14 check-in desks, two gates, and two luggage claim belts.  It’s served by Air Algerie (Algiers, Constantine, Oran), TUI fly Belgium (seasonally), and Twin Jet (Marseille, Toulouse).  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with high-resolution ground textures, photo-realistic 3D buildings, realistic night lighting, multiple charts provided, and custom vegetation. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $9.09, requiring at least 280.75 MB of free hard disk space to install.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mx6bos</id>
    <title>MisterX6 Updates Boston Logan International Airport for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mx6bos" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6459ce0b4e1a000ede9da7b1_bosx1-min.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1376413"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. MisterX6 has recently updated their rendition of General Edward Lawrence Logan International Airport (KBOS) for X-Plane 11 and 12, the busiest airport in the Northeastern United States outside the New York Metropolitan Area with a yearly average of 42 million passengers as of 2019.  Opened almost a hundred years ago in September 1923, it was mainly used by the Air National Guard of Massachusetts and the United States Army Air Corps. Scheduled passenger service started in 1927 with Colonial Air Transport, flying people between Boston and New York City.  The airport had its first expansion during the 1940s and 1950s when the rise in demand for air travel forced the operator to increase its area size through landfills in Boston Harbor. In that same decade, the terminals were expanded, with Terminals B and C being constructed in 1949, still in use in 2023.   Shortly after WW2, Boston became a transatlantic gateway. American Overseas Airlines offered a weekly Boston-Shannon-London service in the late 40s, Pan Am’s direct flight to Shannon and Santa Maria Island in the Azores, then to London and Lisbon. In the early 50s, BOAC started nonstop operations from Glasgow, and Air France made a multi-stop link from Paris-Orly to Boston. By 1957, there were 49 weekday departures on average.  In the 70s, with the advent of jet aircraft, the routes multiplied: Pan Am started a daily service to London Heathrow with the legendary 747-400, and the daily traffic average skyrocketed. Such a boom forced the airport to grow even further, with the newly built Terminal E (1974) becoming the second-largest international arrivals facility in the United States.   Nowadays, Boston Logan International Airport has four terminals with 102 gate positions in total and six runways.   It’s a hub for Cape Air and Delta Air Lines, the latter holding 19% of the market share, with JetBlue taking the lead at 30.08%, and American Airlines is third with 18.54%, followed by United (10.42%) and Southwest (4.65%). Washington, DC, is the busiest national destination with 769,000 passengers, followed by Chicago-O’Hare (717,000) and Orlando (678,000). The international top three comprises London Heathrow (664,886), Dublin (346,232), and Paris Charles de Gaulle (326,184).   The scenery features a detailed rendition of the airport, with animated airport vehicles and ship traffic, animated marshallers and jetways, custom ground textures for taxiways and runways, photoscenery for the airport and surrounding area, lots of Boston landmarks, and now compatible with X-Plane 12.  It’s free on X-Plane.org, requiring at least 495 MB of free hard disk space to install. Shout out to agonyair for the news scoop! Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jarcop</id>
    <title>JarDesign Teases CoPilot Addon for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jarcop" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/645a8e87642f0702c8abdedc_linda1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2315905"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. J. A. Romanov, JARDesign's owner/developer, has recently published a short video on his YouTube channel teasing his upcoming CoPilot Addon for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which aims to add a realistic First Officer model in the cabin that can execute multiple tasks. According to the developer, it consists of an animated copilot object and a WASM module, combining speech simulation, speech recognition, a systems engine based on visual avionics, and more.  The video demonstrates the copilot's behavior on multiple aircraft, executing different cabin flows, chatting with the developer, and following checklists. Due to its config file dependent nature, it should theoretically work with any aircraft as long as someone sets it up properly. They claim to be still working on it, with no information regarding pricing or availability yet.Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
