<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2024-09-30T18:30:05.491462+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/waw111</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Updates Warsaw Chopin Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/waw111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66eb8b46f1c4f6889f72fd6e_warsaw1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Drzewiecki Design has recently issued an update to their recently released rendition of Warsaw Chopin Airport (EPWA) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding an option to remove static aircraft, minor fixes, and more. The changelog follows below: The scenery is available on Contrail and OrbxDirect for roughly $25, requiring at least 5.66 GB of free hard disk space to install. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fs24tr</id>
    <title>Everything New About FS24: The Threshold Rundown</title>
    <updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fs24tr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ec7fff22729782e85cd48b_ezgif-2-c4a4590944.avif"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Microsoft and Asobo have recently announced a plethora of new details about the upcoming Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024, including opening pre-orders for the new sim. They are very confident about the new game, calling FS24 the “Most Ambitious Flight Sim Ever”. ‍One of the flagship features coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is the new career system. Microsoft says that their system “mimics the experience of how real-world pilots start their aviation careers”. In the new simulator, users will be able to pick an airport to start their training journey at, and meet a mentor. The training will start out with the basics of flight in a smaller aircraft, and then users will be able to go through a certification tree for different aircraft plus specialties for things like airliner flying, firefighting, search and rescue, and more.  Performance on those missions will give the user experience and credits, which can be saved to eventually buy aircraft and manage a fleet, which will be affected by how aircraft are flown. According to Microsoft, “every landing, every bump on the runway, is going to impact the warranty of your planes, affecting the cost to keep them maintained”.  ‍The full list of aircraft that will be included at release has also been revealed. Some notable additions include the Boeing 737 MAX8, Northrup Grumman A-10C II, Airbus A321LR, and the Airship Industries A600. Included in the Standard Edition are many of the default aircraft from MSFS 2020 upgraded for FS24, as well as 30 new aircraft, bringing the total to 70 aircraft. The Deluxe Edition adds another 10 aircraft, with 5 more new with FS24. Premium Deluxe gives users 15 more aircraft on top of the standard and deluxe versions bringing the total to 95, with 10 new with FS24, including aircraft such as the Boeing Dreamlifter, Saab 340, and Boeing C17 Globemaster III. (For a more in-depth breakdown on the categories that you can buy, check the “Pre-Orders” section below.) Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 is slated to include many new technological improvements. First and foremost, they are introducing a cloud-focused “thin client”. Much more data will be streamed over the internet including all Marketplace content, reducing overall installation size, which was a very common complaint about MSFS 2020. Microsoft claims that the base installation size will be around 30 gigabytes, which makes for more than a tenfold decrease from the previous simulator. Asobo Co-Founder and CEO Sebastian Wloch explains further that they have “integrated everything into the cloud, and it is all streamed and kept into a rolling cache on the hardware. You don’t have to install any new World Updates; they’re just streamed seamlessly.”  Another major addition is the Electronic Flight Bag built by the team at Working Title. It will be accessible from the aircraft as well as the main menu, giving users a more powerful tool for flight planning, integrated charts, and weight and balance management. Some other features include a revamped UI, first person mode, overhauled weather and seasons, “soft body” physics simulation, simulation of every glider port and all maritime traffic, new AI traffic, new photogrammetry, wake turbulence, and much more.  The Marketplace is also going to receive many significant changes in the new sim. One of the most requested features was to overhaul the rating system. The new system will include different ratings for different aspects of a product, such as visual fidelity, system depth, and more. All of those ratings are combined to an overall rating, but users are able to see both the aggregate score as well as the individual categories. Microsoft will also be introducing a rental period for products on the Marketplace. Users will be able to rent some products for a certain period of time for a fee, the price of which depends on how long the rental period is. If the user decides to purchase the product some time after purchasing the rental, the user will only have to pay the difference between the full product price and the rental fee. At the time of writing, Microsoft has not specified how long that period will be. This rental practice will be implemented into all Microsoft products on the Marketplace, but third-party developers will have to opt in to make this available for their products.  If a user owns any Marketplace content from MSFS 2020, it will be brought to FS24, with limited exceptions for addons that may not be compatible with FS24.  FS24 will also include gifting products and virtual currency to friends, provided that users know the recipient’s Xbox Gamertag.  Microsoft has opened up pre-orders for the new simulator today, with 4 editions being available for purchase. Like MSFS 2020 before it, Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will have the Standard, Deluxe, and Premium Deluxe editions, but Microsoft is introducing a new tier with FS24, the “Aviator Edition”. The Aviator Edition will come with everything included in the Premium Deluxe Edition, as well as all 30 of the Microsoft-published Marketplace aircraft released from 2021 to 2024. There is also a new limited physical “Collector’s Edition” for sale at the Aerosoft Store priced at $259.99 before tax and shipping, which will come with the Aviator Edition of FS24 plus other physical goodies exclusive to the Collector’s Edition, which we’ve listed in full below. Here’s a detailed breakdown on what each edition will include (all prices in USD):  At the time of writing, Microsoft has not specified what the list of handcrafted airports included in FS24 will be. You can pre-order FS24 at the Microsoft Store. All pre-orders will come with the De Havilland Canada CL-415 firefighting aircraft to fly in MSFS 2020. Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024 will have major impacts for the hobby, the extent of which is still yet to be seen. As new information comes out about the new entrant in the Microsoft Flight Simulator franchise, Threshold will keep you updated, so stay tuned for that and for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jdgare</id>
    <title>Jetstream Designs Releases Geneva Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jdgare"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66ed70857ba525ecf74fba1b_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Jetstream Designs has just released its highly anticipated version of Geneva Airport (LSGG) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The airport serves the Swiss city of Geneva and is the second busiest airport in Switzerland, after Zurich Airport. Annually, the airport welcomes around 16.5 million passengers. The airport opened in 1919 as a small airfield in the area of Cointrin, just outside of Geneva. It wasn't until 1937 that the airport got its first concrete runway. Throughout the Second World War, the airport received various expansions. The first terminal was ready for use in 1946. On multiple occasions, the runway has been further expanded. Today, the airport has two passenger terminals and one Business Aviation Terminal. It serves as a hub for Swiss International Air Lines and is an operating base for easyJet Switzerland. The airport also serves a variety of other airlines from all over the world, serving destinations such as New York, Beijing, Dubai, Oslo, Barcelona, and Palma de Mallorca. With around 173.000 aircraft movements yearly, the airport was able to cater to around 16.5 million passengers last year. The recently launched version of Geneva Airport is filled with features, including a highly detailed and accurate representation of the airport, fully functional VDGS, modeled interiors of all terminal buildings, dynamic airside traffic, custom GSX profile, stunning night lighting, and much more. The add-on requires 2.42 GB of storage space and is available on Contrail for approximately $21.23. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbxsulphr</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Sulphur Creek Ranch for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbxsulphr"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f00acf0de9aa1198cd807c_sulphur.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx has recently released their rendition of Sulphur Creek Ranch (ID74) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This private lodge has a rich history - from catering to Hollywood stars in the past to being regularly served by a DC-3 - it now focuses on hunting trips, horseback riding, and wholeheartedly embracing general aviation. The ranch’s project started in 1946 when Doctor Ben Morgan booked a guided trip through the Sawtooth Mountain Range in Idaho, where he mentioned missing the cowboy lifestyle from his childhood, which prompted Pearl Hornback, the guide, to mention a homestead that recently came up for sale, called “Parker Ranch.” They soon flew over the ranch, and Dr. Morgan didn’t hesitate to buy it before landing at it in person. He intended to transform it into a destination resort for the Hollywood elite, exposing them to a premium Wild West experience, with hunting and fishing trips at a premium. While that was the original intent, most of the visitors preferred to ride horses, mimicking what they’d seen - or acted - in movies. The infrastructure built to appeal to Hollywood folk involved the construction of nine modern (for the time) lodges with running water, electricity, electric stoves, and freezers. The hydroelectric system built on Blue Moon Creek made that possible. Sulphur Creek Ranch eventually expanded by purchasing another homestead beside it, becoming the “Lower Sulphur Creek.” A Johnson’s Flying Service Douglas DC-3 transported the materials required for its construction out of the nearby McCall Municipal Airport.  According to Orbx, the scenery features an accurate rendition of the ranch, with PBR textures, custom vegetation and terraforming, over 100 custom assets, multiple time-triggered occurrences, custom static aircraft, and fire barrels for evening operations. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.25, requiring at least 1.86 GB of free hard disk space to install. ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/320359</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 Family for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/320359"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f14fa969afcc22cfd797fa_a319_a321_3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Fenix Simulations recently released an update to its A320 family lineup for Microsoft Flight Simulator, which includes a small performance improvement, bug and texture fixes, and more. Version 2.2.0.359 fixes the compatibility with SayIntentions ACARS, a LVR ASYM ECAM message during an engine failure with the throttle levers on idle, flap rod animations, clickspot tweaks on the first officer’s side, and standby ADI vibrator volume, among other things. The complete changelog follows below: Avionics and Systems Art and Sound The developers have also stated they have run through 127 beta builds since the release of their A319/A321 expansion, averaging two builds a day.   The Fenix A320 base package and the A319/A321 expansion are available on their website for $106.49 (bundle).  ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flyt12</id>
    <title>FlyTampa Updates Toronto Pearson International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flyt12"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f3fd39884196601723983c_toronto1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. FlyTampa recently issued a long-awaited update to its Toronto Pearson International Airport (CYYZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The update addresses terrain issues, adds new buildings, and brings full compatibility with World Update 11: Canada. Update 1.2 brings substantial changes to the scenery, among their first products for the – then – new simulator. The complete changelog follows below: The scenery is available on OrbxDirect for roughly $20.03, requiring at least 2.30 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vfat30</id>
    <title>VFlyteair Simulations Releases Piper Twin Comanche for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vfat30"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f4046f8b60d3f790c73e98_twinkie3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. VFlyteair Simulations has recently released their rendition of the Piper Twin Comanche PA-30 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, their first product for the platform after many years of add-on development for X-Plane. The PA-30 Twin Comanche is a twin-engined (as the name suggests) monoplane designed and built by Piper Aircraft, Inc. It is, in a nutshell, a PA-24 with two engines, developed to compete with the Cessna 310 and the Beechcraft Baron. It ultimately replaced the PA-23, also known as the Piper Apache, their former two-engine airplane. The first prototype was converted from the single-engined Comanche (PA-24) by Ed Swearingen, who operated a facility that specialized in modifying production aircraft models. It was given two 160 hp Lycoming IO-320-B1A engines and flew out of San Antonio, Texas, for the first time in 1961. An official prototype was built a year later in Lock Haven, Pennsylvania (where their factory used to be at the time), and the FAA’s approval was given shortly after in 1963, with the first delivery following only a few months later. VFlyteair’s rendition replicates the analog version of the Twin Comanche, with an eventual update to bring glass panel options from their X-Plane 12 version under consideration for the future. The classic version sports a Century IIB autopilot and TDSSim GTN750Xi compatibility (a GTN750Xi and 650Xi stack) for improved situational awareness. According to VFlyteair, the in-sim rendition features an accurately modeled PA-30, using real-world aircraft blueprints and comprehensive photographic reference, with 4K texturing, PBR, detailed normal mapping, a 3D virtual cockpit, wear and tear on texturing, simulated electrical systems, and 26 different liveries from multiple countries. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $33.39, requiring at least 910.13 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rmd11p</id>
    <title>Rotate Releases MD-11 Passenger for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rmd11p"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f43294b290d2cb0c5988cf_Banner_Image.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Rotate has just released its highly anticipated passenger configuration of the McDonnell Douglas MD-11 for X-Plane 11 and X-Plane 12. The iconic three-engined passenger aircraft is now available for everyone to take to the virtual skies. The first MD-11 was delivered to Finnair in December of 1990, with the type entering service for the airline later that month. Although the MD-11 resembled the DC-10, it had significant differences. The MD-11 featured updated engines, a larger wingspan, a higher maximum takeoff weight, an elongated fuselage, a glass cockpit, and most importantly, an extended range. The introduction of a glass cockpit eliminated the need for a flight engineer. In total, 200 MD-11 aircraft were built, including passenger, combi, and freighter versions. Rotate's MD-11 Passenger model is an enhanced version of their previous freighter variant. The passenger variant includes a passenger cabin, specific elements in the cockpit, an air panel, synoptic display, evacuation panel, attendant communication panels, and a load manager designed specifically for the passenger variant. According to the developer, the MD-11 offers in-depth system simulation, realistic flight dynamics, and more. The newly released Rotate MD-11 Passenger is available at the X-Plane.Org Store for $83.95. If you own the Rotate MD-11 Freighter, the discounted price will be $34.95. ‍ For the latest flight simulation news, remember to stay tuned to Threshold!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inijob</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Johannesburg O.R. Tambo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inijob"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f5620a8a54a6c83b90abdb_jobu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iniBuilds has recently announced the development and imminent release of O.R. Tambo International (FAOR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Johannesburg and Pretoria in South Africa, with a yearly average of 17.8 million passengers. The airport’s history begins in 1943, when the South African government planned to build three international airports, one on the Witwatersrand and two smaller ones in Cape Town and Durban. Four possible sites around Johannesburg were picked, and only two made it through the final scrutiny: Kempton Park and the existing airport at Palmietfontein, Johannesburg’s main airport at the time. They decided on Kempton Park, preceding the expropriation around the area within the same year and kick-starting the construction work, which took roughly eight years and cost the government 8 million pounds.  The advent of jet aircraft led to expansion work in the following decades, which included improved airside facilities, extra parking areas, hotels, and more. In the early 1990s, the terminal was expanded, receiving thirteen passenger bridges and modernizing the preexisting infrastructure. By the mid-1990s, it had already overtaken Cairo as the busiest airport in Africa and was within the top five in the Africa-Middle East Region, only behind Dubai, Doha, and Abu Dhabi.  It’s a hub for AirLink, CemAir, FlySafair, LIFT, and South African Airways. Air China, Air France, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, KLM, LATAM Brasil, Lufthansa, Qantas, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Swiss, Turkish, United, and Virgin Airlines also serve it.  The scenery promises an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside, custom night lighting, custom jetways, an up-to-date layout, and more. There’s no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you updated! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dqas24</id>
    <title>Microsoft September Dev Q&amp;A: The Threshold Recap</title>
    <updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dqas24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f57bfb3572e461a8e6ef88_Fuji_MSFS_2024.jpg.avif"/>
    <summary>Sim: FS24. Following their recent preview event, Microsoft and Asobo have hosted another of their monthly developer live streams, this time focusing on the highly anticipated Microsoft Flight Simulator 2024. The lengthy hour and forty-eight-minute livestream covered various MSFS 2020 and FS24 topics and answered many of the community’s most burning questions about the upcoming sim, so we’ve compiled it all in one place! The live stream started with a section about Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020. Jorg Neumann, Head of Microsoft Flight Simulator, addressed criticisms of the newly released Boeing 707-320C by Aeroplane Heaven, stating: "The Aeroplane Heaven guys, they tried really hard," and acknowledging, "I know the INS is not what people want, but we will continue working on this and listen to the feedback." Additionally, Neumann announced the release date for AAU3 on October 1st and the release date of the highly-requested update for the ATR-42/72 series developed by Hans Hartmann, released on October 10th. We’ve divided this into sections, summarizing the answers for each question for ease of reading.  ‍ Q: Why is 64 GB the ‘ideal’ amount of RAM, and does more RAM help performance?‍ Sebastian Wloch, Asobo CEO and Co-Founder explains that 64 GB was chosen for users who want to “push every option to max detail” and do other things like recording or streaming, but the average user will only want 32 GB of RAM. He added later that FS24 will have an adaptive detail feature that automatically scales the sim's detail to hit a specific FPS target, but the user can disable it if they choose to.  ‍Q: On Xbox, can we expect the same performance and memory related stability issues in FS24 as in 2020? What optimizations have been made to make the new level of fidelity possible on Xbox consoles?‍ Wloch states that various improvements to the Xbox platform have allowed them to access 2.5 GB more RAM, which he says “really helps in terms of stability and performance”, in addition to the performance improvements baked into the new sim.  Executive Producer Martial Bossard adds that the new sim will no longer support DirectX 11 because FS24’s new rendering pipeline utilizes many of the new features of DirectX 12.  ‍Q: MSFS2024's reliance on online access for far more assets presumably means that a server outage is likely to affect far more users than the current server outages do. At present a lot of assets are stored on our systems whereas this will no longer be the case in MSFS2024, How feasible will it be to play offline in the future if at all?‍ Wloch starts by saying that most of the data was already being streamed in MSFS 2020, but they’ve added to that total, including Marketplace content. However, the user can decide if they want to stream or download content from the Marketplace. He continues to say that if the network is interrupted for up to a few minutes, users will not notice that much, but beyond that point, he states that “you need to be online at some point to fly”. Q: Will cloud and weather depiction be improved in MSFS 2024? Wloch mentioned many things in his answer, including the addition of cirrus clouds, redone lighting, weather systems like tornadoes, and translating the effects of the weather to the environment, such as trees, grass, and water. However, tornadoes will only be in missions because they do not have a reliable live data source for them. Q: Will there be a working weather radar? Bossard’s answer was very brief, saying that the feature is “still on the backlog”. Q: Will autogen buildings be getting a refresh in the new sim? Bossard says that work is still in progress on autogen buildings, but any change will come after the launch. Q: Will MSFS 2024 receive World Updates and City Updates? If so, will they also be released day-and-date for MSFS 2020?  Neumann gives a quick answer: “Check”. Wloch and Neumann mentioned a few other small features in this section, including adding a “historical world” for 24 hours, weather, and working windshield wipers. Q: Can I import all my settings/preferences/keybinds/etc. from Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 or will I need to set up all of that again? Bossard has some bad news: “Unfortunately, you would have to set [it] up again, because the way we are doing things is so different,...there is no way to translate one to the other”.  ‍Q: Will there be VR support in MSFS 2024? Will it be improved over the current implementation? Will it be available from Day 1?  Bossard confirms that VR will be supported from Day 1 and that they have made improvements to render thread performance. However, users can expect the same performance difference between 3D and VR as MSFS 2020. ‍Q: What you have made abundantly clear is that Al Aircraft traffic will be much better representing their real-life counterparts and that is really great. But I have questions to that point: Will we see an improved behavior from these Al vehicles (i.e. planes no longer driving through one another or ground vehicles not stopping when an airplane passes)?‍  Bossard says they “have tried to improve and to have better ground services”, but he acknowledges that “sometimes we have some weird things there”. He mentions the possibility of community improvement of ground services through the World Hub. Q: What improvements can we expect for the default ATC? Will you be utilizing Al similar to addons like SayIntentions and BeyondATC?  Neumann stated that “there are some” improvements to the default ATC system made by Asobo and WorkingTitle. He also mentions that the team looked at options like SayIntentions.ai but is not planning it for launch. Neumann does leave the door open for something akin to those products in the future, saying, “it’s good ideas that they [BeyondATC and SayIntentions] have”. Q: You said that if we crash our own plane in Career mode then it's lost. What happens if there's an internet outage or software crash in the middle of a mission? How does the sim handle such a situation? Will we lose a plane because of that?  Bossard clarified that the damage is “the result of the physic [sic]” and that they are “only handling that kind of situation when we are computing the forces and the effects of the crash”. Q: Do you have to go through all the trainings and check-rides to get to career missions or can you skip any part of it?‍ Bossard confirms that “you can skip it. Q: ﻿Can we use 3rd party planes / helicopters in career mode if the features they have are compatible with the mission tasks?  “Yes, but…under conditions”, says Bossard. He then explains that Marketplace aircraft have systems that check whether they have the right features to comply with specific missions. Q: Which items from the Feedback Snapshot and Development Roadmap will be implemented in MSFS 2020 and which items will be deferred to MSFS 2024  Neumann says that there is not a concrete list as of yet, but “there are goals to bring back certain features when possible to [MSFS] 2020”, but will separate the list “in the coming weeks”.  Q: Is it expected to let freeware developers join the Marketplace?  Neumann answered “probably, yes”, adding that “we just worked through some stuff with our…lawyers, so there will be some news here soon”. ‍Q: Will the SDK open up to allow more types of products to be developed i.e. Chaseplane for camera views, weather software like Active Sky, and tools such as AutoFPS?  Neumann explains that “this is not really an SDK question only”, and since they are 8 weeks out from releasing FS24, they would first have to make “everything tidy, and then we’ll talk about some of these things again”. Q: What about add-ons purchased from third-party stores (Orbx, simMarket, Aerosoft, PMDG, etc.)? Will they be transferable?  Neumann confirms that MSFS 2020 content can be copied “over to the community folder.” Notably, he did not provide a disclaimer about compatibility issues with some addons, but Microsoft and Asobo have repeatedly indicated this may be the case. Q: Can we buy Premium Deluxe planes separately in 2024? “Yes. I heard that loud and clear last time, and we did that,” Neumann says, acknowledging the community’s feedback.  ‍ Unlike in the past, where there was usually only one Q&amp;A session each month during the developer livestreams, Microsoft has announced that they will hold many more sessions covering specific topics during the ramp-up to the release. You can find the schedule below: This developer stream has revealed quite a lot about the upcoming simulator, but despite that, Microsoft and Asobo still have more to show. Throughout all these exciting new developments, Threshold will keep you up-to-date with the newest, so stay tuned for that and for more high-quality flight simulation news and reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/eje111</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Releases E-Jets Family Update 1.1.0 for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/eje111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f68dba429996de1751e939_eje1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. X-Crafts recently updated their E-Jets Family lineup to version 1.1.0 for X-Plane 11 and 12, adding FMS speed mode, ILS autotune, steep approach capabilities (E170 &amp; 190 only), and over 160 new features, enhancements, and fixes. The update automates many things that were manual in the past, decreasing the required workload to operate the airplanes while also increasing the immersion factor. The speed management, for example, is now fully automatic, thanks to the new FMS Speed feature. The automation also extends to the ILS approach system, with an autotune feature that automatically tunes the correct frequency and handles the transition from LNAV&amp;VNAV to LOC&amp;GS, mimicking the expected real-life behavior. The E170 and 190 will also feature steep approach capability, making it possible to fly it into London City Airport realistically. It is famous for its 5,5-degree glide slope angle and the limited range of aircraft that can fly there. The E175 and E195 lack the certification in real life, therefore not sporting the feature. The displays can now be popped up, moved, and resized for a clearer, more accessible view. Positioning settings are persistent and will carry over on subsequent simulator loads. There are over 160 improvements in total, which follow below in the complete changelog: FMS SPEED ILS AUTOTUNE STEEP APPROACH (Available on the E170 &amp; E190) BRAND NEW POP-UP SCREENS OTHER NEW FEATURES FMS COCKPIT AUTOPILOT AUTOTHROTTLE (X-PLANE 12 ONLY) TAKEOFF AP MODES ENHANCED TO REFLECT REAL SYSTEMS PFD MFD EICAS EFB THRUST RATING SYSTEM ENGINE PERFORMANCE VNAV FLIGHT MODEL (X-Plane 12 only) SYSTEMS ANTI-ICE SYSTEM VR HARDWARE 3D MODEL SOUNDS ‍ Refer to their blog post for further information on the update and its features. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pngpk3</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases PNG Highland Bush Strips Pack 3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pngpk3"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f6958c7e1df501c5651ef9_pap1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx has recently released their third pack of Papua New Guinea Highland Bush Strips, featuring seven new airstrips (Nomane, Kora, Guwasa, Meninga, Herowenaq, Gimi, and Simogu) and 50 new models.  Bush airstrips in Papua New Guinea are generally the only gateway to certain remote villages, meaning it’s vital to their existence and the only way to bring supplies in. The weather is often harsh, the runways are often short and hand-carved, and the challenge is unparalleled. The new pack supplements Packs 1 and 2 with seven new destinations, 50 new models, custom runway elevation profiles, custom autogen, and more. It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $13.09, requiring at least 2.68 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/infaor</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Releases Johannesburg O.R. Tambo International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/infaor"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f5620a8a54a6c83b90abdb_jobu1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. iniBuilds has recently released their rendition of O.R. Tambo International (FAOR) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving Johannesburg and Pretoria in South Africa, with a yearly average of 17.8 million passengers. The airport’s history begins in 1943, when the South African government planned to build three international airports, one on the Witwatersrand and two smaller ones in Cape Town and Durban. Four possible sites around Johannesburg were picked, and only two made it through the final scrutiny: Kempton Park and the existing airport at Palmietfontein, Johannesburg’s main airport at the time. They decided on Kempton Park, preceding the expropriation around the area within the same year and kick-starting the construction work, which took roughly eight years and cost the government 8 million pounds.  The advent of jet aircraft led to expansion work in the following decades, which included improved airside facilities, extra parking areas, hotels, and more. In the early 1990s, the terminal was expanded, receiving thirteen passenger bridges and modernizing the pre-existing infrastructure. By the mid-1990s, it had already overtaken Cairo as the busiest airport in Africa. It was within the top five in the Africa-Middle East Region, behind Dubai, Doha, and Abu Dhabi.  It’s a hub for AirLink, CemAir, FlySafair, LIFT, and South African Airways. Air China, Air France, British Airways, Cathay Pacific, Delta Air Lines, Emirates, KLM, LATAM Brasil, Lufthansa, Qantas, Qatar Airways, Singapore Airlines, Swiss, Turkish, United, and Virgin Airlines also serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom ground textures, true-to-life landside, custom night lighting, custom jetways, an up-to-date layout, and more. It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $20.05, requiring at least 7.44 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/flwc24</id>
    <title>Flysimware Releases Sierra C24R for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/flwc24"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f6f2ee85db9ae5dd3fec8f_sierra1.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Flysimware has recently released their rendition of the Beechcraft C24R Sierra for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a single-engined low-wing aircraft first launched in 1977, based on the Beechcraft Musketeer. Developed as the retractable gear version of the Beechcraft Musketeer family (comprising the Model 23, Model 19 Sport, and Model 23-24 Super), keeping the engine choice of the Musketeer 23-24 Super, which couldn’t be fully unleashed due to the fixed-gear configuration. Thus, the Musketeer Super R was created in 1970, also known as the A24R, which competed directly with the Piper Arrow. Two years later, it was renamed “Sierra.” It sits right in the middle of their lineup between the cheaper, fixed-gear Musketeers and the fancier Bonanzas, selling for a standard price of $24,950. In 1974, the Sierra received an engine upgrade, sporting the Lycoming IO-360-A1B6 and a new propeller design. Three years later, the model represented by this add-on came, the C24R, which featured the same engine as the 1974 B24R, albeit with an even larger propeller and a slight aerodynamic cleanup, making it six knots faster. Production continued until 1983 when the lines were closed due to an aviation economic downturn. 744 Sierras were built during those thirteen years. The add-on claims to feature realistic flight dynamics, 4K PBR textures, interactive environment sounds, a Boris Audio Works Wwise sound set, custom-coded gauges, multiple choices of avionics (GTX 345, GMA 340, GNS 530, GTN 750, GTN750Xi), windshield rain effects, exterior icing effects, different cockpit variations (Garmin G5, Garmin G3X, and the choice between PMS/TDS GTN750/750xi or the built-in GTN 530), and ten liveries to choose from. It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $35.14, requiring at least 4.39 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/jff111</id>
    <title>Just Flight Provides F70/100 Progress Update</title>
    <updated>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/jff111"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f6fc56c996a71817dda672_3_9dCB7XLOuF.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Just Flight have released another development update on their upcoming Fokker 70/100 Professional for Microsoft Flight Simulator on their website. This time, the update covered the external textures.  The Fokker F70 and F100 are narrow-body regional airliners produced by the Dutch aircraft manufacturer, Fokker. Developed from the earlier F28, the F70 and F100 offered larger cabins, updated avionics, and higher MTOWs. Equipped with two Rolls-Royce Tay Mk 650-15 engines, the F100 could cruise at Mach 0.77 for a range of 1,700nm. According to JustFlight, the external textures have undergone a complete rework, and have been upscaled to 8K. This allows for many rivets and screws to be visible. Alongside the improved textures, the fuselage skin has also received a lot of attention from the developers, as ripples on the fuselage caused by many pressurization cycles can now be seen. The decals on doors, emergency exits, static ports, as well as the landing gear bay, were also redrawn and upgraded.  The developers have hinted that their next progress update might cover the aircraft’s systems. Unfortunately, as of the posting of this article, no information about the support for the upcoming FS24, pricing, or the release date has been announced. As always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and high-quality reviews!</summary>
    <published>2024-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbgca</id>
    <title>Orbx Previews Landmarks Gold Coast for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbgca"/>
    <link href="https://cdn.prod.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/66f9aa0bd8e37252ab50a2e6_11957-7ae170849d12b7159d37c7ee3cff89e3.webp"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS20. Orbx have announced another product from the ‘Landmark’ line - Landmarks Gold Coast. Joining the likes of Cape Town, Dubai, Singapore, London, Paris and such, the Gold Coast will be the 16th city to get its rendition developed for FS20 by Orbx. Gold Coast is Queensland’s second-largest city with a population of over 640,00 and is known as one of Australia’s best tourist destinations, the Gold Coast is famous for its long sandy beaches, surfing, and vibrant nightlife. Orbx’s rendition of ‘Goldy’ features over 40 custom buildings, animated boats along the coast, animated roller coasters, and the Gold Coast University Hospital with a helipad. The full feature list is as follows: No information about the pricing or the release date has been released. However, as always, Threshold will keep you updated! ‍ Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight sim news and reviews! ‍</summary>
    <published>2024-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
