<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-06-14T18:28:13.432848+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdnapl</id>
    <title>RDPresets Debut Naples Airport in Latest Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdnapl" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629db7d8db3dbefc6a0d23c8_wing-tra-737_orig.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1701430"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Creators of Rotterdam-The Hague for Microsoft Flight Simulator, RDPresets have announced that Naples’ airport will be their next pursuit for the platform.  With this news the developer doubles the number of projects they’ve got on the go, as work on Marseille continues concurrently. “[Marseille] has hit some major bumps in the road, some items failed our Quality Assurance and are requiring some remodelling, this will take time and has set Marseille back two release slots, meaning as it stands two other airports will come before it." The developer explains that the delay is necessary to ensure quality. "But this does allow me to announce you our first new airport which is in Italian [sic], “Aeroporto di Napoli”." "We’re incredibly proud of how this product is currently being developed and it’s going at an incredible pace. We’re using a new texture method ensuring a higher texture resolution, but at the same time using less texture sets. "It took us some time to perfect this and arguably we’re still learning it, but we feel it is really good already and worthy enough to put it above our current Rotterdam airport quality." RDPresets want to go 'the extra mile' in ground detailing with Naples, saying that the final product will 'truly give you an idea of arriving or departing [at an airport with proper weathering]. They have not offered a release date as yet, but maintain that the first in-sim images of Naples will debut shortly. It was also revealed in the development update that the brand is working on a hub software for their products. The software will be called RDHome. See the source post for this article on the RDPresets website.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mvpcce</id>
    <title>Milviz Discusses Updates for PC-6 Porter and Cessna 310R</title>
    <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mvpcce" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629e70ea2b797332fd34fdff_286338871_5346744258703239_4442868559021534495_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="465253"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The tail-dragging turboprop PC-6 Porter from Milviz will shortly see an update according to developers, who are currently working on 'stage 2' of the Pilatus craft. The aircraft was first released for Microsoft Flight Simulator in September 2021 in a typical land-faring configuration. Milviz's stage 2 is set add floats and tundra tyres to the available set-ups. An option for an older steam gauge cockpit with 'multiple radio options' will also be available according to the developer. Speaking to the status of the update, the team had this to say -- "Development is ongoing, but we are a bit behind schedule. Hope to have some pics with the floats in the coming weeks." Stage 2 of Milviz's PC-6 Porter will see a price rise for new customers, but existing users will be able to upgrade for free. The developer says that your initial purchase will entitle you to any future updates for this products. In the same Facebook post, the team also made brief mention of their latest release, the Cessna 310R. The twin piston craft's service pack is "nearly finished!" See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/p42mex</id>
    <title>Parallel42 Announces New Airstrip; 'Scenes' to Sell Separately</title>
    <updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/p42mex" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629ef27127ce87013d8a92d5_0_bETJs4vXIrxSLDhT.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="289353"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Parallel42 continues their unique ‘scenes’ series with Mexican Mountain, a bush camping spot in Green River, Utah. The series is tailor-made for the group’s FreedomFox aircraft, which was released in December 2021. ‘Scenes’, small fictional airstrips dotted around Microsoft Flight Simulator’s backcountry, come free to customers of the FreedomFox and are stocked with plenty of room to park up on multiplayer adventures.  Edson Soriano, managing director at Parallel42 commented that the dioramas “continue bringing value to your time flying FF/F2.” The latest creation in the series, Mexican Mountain — which has been given the fictional ICAO ‘42MX’ — has been made in collaboration with several real-world pilots operating in the area. Green River makes for a dramatic backdrop for bush flying, with large elevation changes, ridges, cliffs and pinnacles but to name a few prominent features. “Mexican Mountain truly is…out there, the views are tremendous, &amp; you’ll have plenty of places to practice STOL landings nearby and you’re a short hop away from Moab.” Mexican Mountain will be available for free to owners of the FreedomFox Complete Package (incl. all Orbx customers) and will be available separately on the Microsoft Marketplace for $7.99 USD.  Starting with Mexican Mountain, previously released ‘scenes’ will also be migrated to the Marketplace so users without the FreedomFox Complete Package can use the strips too.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ownrel</id>
    <title>RWY26 Debuts in MSFS with Teaser &amp; Release of Owen Roberts Intl. Airport</title>
    <updated>2022-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ownrel" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/629ff2f20ddc54e420f6d68a_omg.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="528129"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A few hours ago, Runway 26 Simulations has officially made their debut on Microsoft Flight Simulator with the announcement of their first product on the platform, Owen Roberts International Airport (MWCR). Shortly after the news drop, the team got it released on SimMarket. The real airport is the main international gateway for the Cayman Islands. Consisting of a single 2,398 runway with a recently upgraded terminal, the airport is home to the nation’s flag carrier, Cayman Airways and sees over 1 million passengers traversing through the airport. The airport is a major facilitator to Cayman Islands’ reliance on imported goods, processing 1.5 million and a quarter of a million pounds of cargo and mail respectively. In a Facebook post briefly captioned “Behold... First scenery for MSFS2020…” The team also dropped a trailer on their YouTube channel, providing a quick walkthrough of the airport rendition. On the product page, there’s not much in the way of information, with the notable omission of a basic feature list. We do know that it comes at a rather light 175MB package. The developer is recognised for its scenery creations focused around Central America, and the push into MSFS with the West Carribean airport is something to be expected. If you’re up for some scenic flying, you could begin your journey by exploring George Town. The airport, priced at 15 Euros - is an accessible ask. Presumably, this will mark the beginning of more caribbean airports to come, particularly from Runway 26, stay tuned as we’ll keep you in the loop on future developments from the development team.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcf15u</id>
    <title>DC Designs Updates F-15 Eagle for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcf15u" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1c2c7136b9a0e4636524f_284544172_3265782867076023_2111639058208303226_n.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="416453"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Military aircraft developer DC Designs have released a new update for their F-15 Eagle product for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The McDonnell Douglas craft was first made available on the platform in January 2021. The update was quietly added to the Just Flight website today, with some of the main drawcards being a new fly-by-wire control system and re-done cockpit and instrument panels. Here’s the full changelog: DC Designs’ F-15 Eagle, which includes the C, D, E and I variants, is available for purchase through Just Flight’s online store. It retails at $40.99 USD.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/assfra</id>
    <title>Aviotek Showcase First Screenshots of Frankfurt (EDDF) for X-Plane</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/assfra" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1c7c791183b53a0b7ef48_287006497_1925031934362597_6289553976030141825_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="136348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Being both Germany’s busiest airport and Lufthansa’s primary hub, Flughafen Frankfurt is a large undertaking for any scenery developer, perhaps none less so than Aviotek Simulation Software, whom began on the airport in late 2020. Today, the group published the first in-simulator screenshots of EDDF, which will be coming to both X-Plane and Microsoft Flight Simulator. It appears to be the former that the developer tackles first, as the images, posted on Facebook, come from Laminar’s sim. X-Plane has traditionally been the home of Aviotek, who have previously released five products for the platform via X-Aviation. “Now it’s time to fill the ramp with our pretty vehicles and equipment,” reads the social media post. “There are still some improvements required, objects to be placed and bugs to fix, but the team is working day and night to deliver the best rendition possible for both the simulators, so you can really feel-there.” There is no release date or price that has been made available as yet. It is also not clear whether the Microsoft Flight Simulator rendition of Frankfurt will be available at the same time. You can find out more about Aviotek’s Frankfurt project in a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vskboi</id>
    <title>Verticalsim Announces Boise for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vskboi" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1ced70fb718609759fdbf_287024476_4807808412656800_2786903833022319994_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="161459"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Boise’s relatively small airfield makes headlines for the second time this week with another developer announcing they’re bringing Gowen Field to Microsoft Flight Simulator. This time, the creator is Verticalsim. The scenery-maker has previously covered KBOI in X-Plane and in-line with previous releases, is now working on bringing their extensive catalogue of products for Laminar’s sim over to Microsoft Flight Simulator. Verticalsim published the following feature list with the announcement: Though a release date has not been mentioned, users likely won’t have to wait long for Boise to launch as based on previous releases Verticalsim tends to have a very short turnaround. Threshold will keep you posted.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ausham</id>
    <title>AUscene Teases Hamilton Island Airport for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ausham" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a1d4302cfb6ba96ea3783d_284513968_514946167039563_5900949890880924501_n.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="218117"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Australian tourist destination Hamilton Island and its airport, YBHM, has received more attention today in the form of a new development update from AUscene. The airfield is one of two projects the developer currently has underway for Microsoft Flight Simulator. On release, Hamilton Island will move alongside the developer’s ‘Reefworld’ area scenery covering the Great Barrier Reef. The two will be offered as a bundle pack due to their proximity. Today’s development update focused on the terminal’s interior, which the developer initially debated whether to include at all. “After much consideration we decided to add the Terminal Interior and are excited to finally be able to share some previews with you all! Hamilton Island will be our most extensive product with plenty of details for you to discover at the Airport, Marina, Resort and Dent Island.” See the source post for this article on Facebook.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xcdsrr</id>
    <title>X-Codr Designs Releases Sedona Red Rocks for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xcdsrr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a40727f36d7d0ea90ba84a_Screen%20Shot%202022-06-10%20at%2011.08.20%20PM.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2179245"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier this week, X-Codr Designs released Sedona Red Rocks for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The scenery, which comes with detailed models/textures and custom orthoimagery, will provide users with an immersive flight in the stunning Sedona region of Arizona, allowing them to experience the area’s famous geological wonders. According to the developers, an array of different rock formations ranging from Cathedral Rock to Capitol Butte are hand modeled and textured after their real life counterparts in Sedona.  ‍ Additionally, NAIP orthoimagery has beenused to “cover up glaring shadows” while performance has been optimized to minimize the scenery’s impact on the users’ computers. Finally, Sedona Airport (default or X-Codr’s upcoming rendition) has been seamlessly blended into this product. For a complete list of features,, visit the developer’s website. Currently, the Sedona Red Rocks by X-Codr Designs can be purchased in the MSFS MarketPlace for $14.99 USD. For other Microsoft Flight Simulator news, check out another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/lmmelb</id>
    <title>Landmarks Melbourne by Orbx Now Available</title>
    <updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/lmmelb" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a523d5c1fdbb460479f0d5_629-da56ab81442ca2bd8215be740378f006.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1383373"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Home to the Australian Open, the Australian Grand Prix, and Orbx's Australian Headquarters, Melbourne is the group's latest destination in the Landmarks series and was made available yesterday. The product boasts another 200 points of interest over the simulator's default skyline from World Update 7 -- which Orbx also had a hand in creating. "Welcome to the cultural and sports capital of Australia and the hometown of Orbx!" reads the product description. "With about a third of its current five million residents born outside of Australia, Melbourne’s skyline mirrors its inhabitants’ diversity, from Gold Rush and Victorian architecture to ultra-modern skyscrapers." The feature list reads: Landmarks Melbourne is available for $17.89 AUD (US$12.62 | €11,99 | £10.24) from OrbxDirect. To see more images, check out a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fsrpro</id>
    <title>FSRealistic Pro Released</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fsrpro" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a52b4474c14f14cf317a77_unknown%20(1).png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3111061"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Effects management system FSRealistic 'Core' has now been available for seven months, having been initially released in November 2021. In the time since, rkApps have taken to improving upon the work seen in that product with the new FSRealistic Pro. The 'Pro' version builds upon the effects included in 'Core', with the developer proclaiming a "growing list of 28" different interactions. Speaking to Threshold, the developer explains the leap forward that the 'Pro' version has made:  "After a long period of time that Asobo didn't support camera movements, it has recently released a partial support and we have now finally managed to make a breakthrough with amazing real camera effects to create a more-than-ever realistic flight experience." "We are proud to be the first company to offer such level of realism and excited to offer you [the chance] to join the ride!" FSRealistic Pro is available for EUR 28.00 from simMarket here. Users of 'Core' are able to upgrade at a discounted price of EUR 5.60. Threshold is giving away two copies of FSRealistic Pro to readers of this article. To enter, simply write a comment below this article. The winners will be drawn in 24 hours.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a31fre</id>
    <title>iniBuilds Announces Microsoft Flight Simulator Partnership: A310 to be Free</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a31fre" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a63d7a1f699a875c0cbca1_image.png.b0f3905239211c26c17332f5436020b6.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="700074"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. iniBuilds' aircraft development branch have shared perhaps the most significant development update in their history this evening with news that a partnership has been struck between themselves and Microsoft Flight Simulator. Users will benefit from a free copy of the group's A310 aircraft for the platform, which outside of Microsoft Flight Simulator currently retails for £69.99 GBP. In a post on the iniBuilds forum, chief executive Ubaid Mussa explains what's to look forward to with the shortest Airbus wide-body: "The aircraft introduced a two-crew glass cockpit and is truly a versatile aircraft perfect for short-long haul operations (up to 10 hrs!). It existed in many variations and iterations; our aircraft on initial release will be the A310-304 powered by General Electric CF6-80 engines, passenger variant only." The iniBuilds team have reportedly re-modelled a number of 'significant areas' about the aircraft as well as having undergone a complete re-texturing since the last set of previews, which you can check out here. Additionally, a real A310 has been used in development of the audio environment. "Moving onto systems: we have completely re-written our code base for the Microsoft Flight Simulator version, enhancing and improving our A310 systems in all areas from the previous iteration of this product." "Significant parts of aircraft have greater levels of dynamic behaviour and reliance for example in our electrical system; each item within the aircraft has an impact on the power drawn from the generators, even individual fuel pumps, which will cause realistic electrical system demand changes. "The FMS (flight management system) which is an essential component for the navigation of the aircraft, has been completely re-written from the ground up allowing for more realistic operations on day-day flying, along with new features not previously seen on iniBuilds products. The FMS will allow for full lateral and vertical guidance modes including RNAV approaches and overlay NDB VOR approaches." The largest news of the announcement in fact comes right at the end: iniBuilds' A310 for Microsoft Flight Simulator will be available for free as part of the 40th Anniversary Update in November 2022. Mussa calls this a fantastic step for the industry in the ability to provide high quality aircraft simulations. See more at the announcement of the A310 for Microsoft Flight Simulator in a previous article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/msf40t</id>
    <title>Microsoft Flight Simulator 40th Anniversary: Helicopters, Gliders, DHC-2, DC-3 &amp; Many More New Aircraft</title>
    <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/msf40t" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a6467cb373dc45d0ec24ce_6.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3366894"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The 40th Anniversary of Microsoft's longest running franchise (that's right, Microsoft Flight Simulator) is fast approaching. Today, at the Xbox &amp; Bethesda Games Showcase, the team have showcased what is in store for an update coming in November. It will also mark the first time they've collaborated with an aircraft developer for a simulator update, with iniBuilds teasing that their A310 will come free with the 40th Anniversary edition in November. To the guts of the announcement: news today centres around a trailer released on the Xbox YouTube channel. It shows a number of new aircraft and indeed categories of aircraft coming soon. The team start vintage with the first chronologically appearing to be a Wright Flier II - this is followed in quick succession by the Spirit of St. Louis (which carried Charles Lindbergh on his non-stop transatlantic flight in 1927). A relic of Flight Simulators past, the Douglas DC-3 will also make its way to Microsoft Flight Simulator, appearing here in an Emerald Harbor Air livery. Similarly, the DHC-2 Beaver is also showcased. The Granville Gee Bee Z Super Sportster also makes an appearance, adding another aerobatic aircraft to the platforms current selection. Sliding into shot with aptly orchestral music, it was revealed that gliders will shortly be available for Microsoft Flight Simulator too. The model seems to be a Glaser-Dirks DG-808. Having left rotorheads waiting since the release of the simulator, the developer also showed off helicopters for the first time. A Bell Jetranger and a Cabri G2 look to be the default additions and the video also showcases a number of helipads in the sim. Finally, right at the end of the video and even after the credits, the developer teased the UNSC Pelican -- an aircraft from Microsoft's Halo franchise -- which will also be making an appearance in the update. Microsoft Flight Simulator's 40th Anniversary Update will be available in November to all users.  See the source video for this article here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ffxpde</id>
    <title>FlightFactor Shares X-Plane Development Update</title>
    <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ffxpde" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a72a0bb912a76ea62fecdc_278391652_516087066594252_1002473650932431623_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="101607"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. FlightFactor has taken to the X-Plane.org Forum today to share a 'comprehensive' development update covering two of their in-development aircraft as well as four other products which have already been released. The brand's leader Ramzzess says that the 'time is right' for a holistic overview of the group's projects given the short time until X-Plane 12 becomes available. No images were shared in this post, however, we've included screenshots from previous teasers which have been published over the past couple of months. Addressing the 777v2 and 787 first, Ramzzess says that "the models being built [are] more complicated than anything that we have developed before, to the point of insanity." The Flight Management System, EFB, maintenance, and sound systems all remain 'in progress' at various stages of completion.  A CPDLC system will be included with both aircraft, which at this stage is being integrated with some third party addons.  Failures will be completed on release, but at this stage FlightFactor believe that most things covered in real-world sim training are implemented. There are currently over 1000 individual failures, with 'more stuff' to be added after release.  Another unique aspect of these Boeing widebodies will be a multi-crew simulation. Ramzzess describes this as an 'enormous undertaking'. Interactions between the captain, first officer, cabin crew and ground staff will be covered, with more to be added post-release. The first officer will be able to assist in all standard procedures on release, similar to the likes of FS2Crew products for ESP-platforms.  FlightFactor list the following as being 'basically ready for release:' Turning attention to the A320, Ramzzess applauds the work of the Airbus team for the release of v1.3.0, which has improved FPS counts by a reported 20-50%. Before the end of the X-Plane 11 run, the team want to bring back the web browser, integrate a new weather radar and correct a number of small issues. With X-Plane 12, however, FlightFactor plan some more significant changes, these include: The final topic covered in the development update today are the group's other three models, the Boeing 757, 767 and Airbus A350.  These will be compatible with X-Plane 12 from the outset and will see extended support and updates through the end of version 12 or if a new version of the aircraft is rolled out -- there are no specific plans for this as yet. A 767-400 variant is also being worked on and will be added to the various 767 packages available right now.  "It is in all respects a continuation of that line. Not a standalone model," says Ramzzess. See the source post for this article on the X-Plane.org Forum.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aphdhc</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Partner with Microsoft for DC-3 &amp; Debut Standalone DHC-1 Chipmunk</title>
    <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aphdhc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a6472acf79f600ffd92934_3.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="880498"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. A second developer has now gone public on a deal struck with Microsoft for Flight Simulator's 40th Anniversary Update, this being Aeroplane Heaven and the aircraft in development the legendary DC-3. Similar to iniBuilds, the other developer signed on with Microsoft for the update, the developer has been under NDA on all news surrounding the project. Speaking on Facebook, the developer maintains that "the package will be the self-same one as we would release ourselves with other advantages yet to come." "The sounds have now been completed by the best in the business and a new flight model is also now complete, authored by another top FM coder." "As part of the Anniversary celebrations we will be bringing you all the liveries we have shown you, in a special add-on package absolutely free. We will now be able to bring you updates both here and with Microsoft, as the package progresses to release in November." Later in the day, the developer also showcased another aircraft which will shortly be added to their range: the DHC-1 Chipmunk. The deHavilland craft was teased in a single image posted on Facebook, proclaiming its 'very' soon arrival. The so-called 'poor man's Spitfire' does not appear to be part of the 40th Anniversary Update and thus will be a payware product. See both of these items on Aeroplane Heaven's Facebook page. Alternatively, check out the large number of aircraft coming to Microsoft Flight Simulator with the 40th Anniversary Update in a dedicated article here.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/drzewiecki-design-released-rzeszow-jasionka-airport-eprz-for-microsoft-flight-simulator</id>
    <title>Drzewiecki Design Released Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport (EPRZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/drzewiecki-design-released-rzeszow-jasionka-airport-eprz-for-microsoft-flight-simulator" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/62a7c836f0923513c0157793_297387_EPRZ_MSFS_11.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="1796359"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Earlier this week, scenery developer Drzewiecki Design released Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport (EPRZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The product, an accurate rendition of the southeastern Polish airport, features high quality textures/models and serves as the gateway for pilots looking to venture into eastern Europe. According to the developers, the airport is created based on the latest layout of its real life counterpart. The scenery features high definition PBR textures and mesh, as well as detailed models, custom night lighting, and terminal interiors. Additionally, the airport has been optimized for performance and is FPS-friendly without sacrificing any realism. Finally, the scenery also includes Rzeszów City landmarks scattered in the region around the airport in order to further increase the users’ immersion. For a full list of features, visit the developer’s website. Currently, the scenery can be purchased on simMarket for EUR 15 or USD 15.87. The developers recommend users to have at least 1.6GB of free space on their hard drives in order to successfully install the product. For information on other Drzewiecki Design products, checkout another Threshold article.</summary>
    <published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
