<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2022-09-16T18:31:21.272948+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12re</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 Released</title>
    <updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12re" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63162c1e2485a0822bcf4b73_Fb5r2HLXgAUS8Mf.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="76582"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The moment has arrived, and a new generation of flight simulator is upon us. Taking to Twitter just moments ago X-Plane announced that X-Plane 12 is now available. X-Plane 12 can be purchased from X-Plane.com for $59.99  Laminar Research has provided the following information;  New features:  This Early Access digital edition is ideal for people who: X-Plane 12 Early Access includes: Continue to keep your eyes on Threshold over the coming weeks for the latest updates and news surrounding aircraft, scenery and much more for this all-new simulator. ‍ ‍   ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/pcmsfs</id>
    <title>Project Coastline For MSFS Released</title>
    <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/pcmsfs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6318c38cffe8d6748154f34b_279722058_397582412376955_6692229729613934459_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="813814"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Project Coastline Italy and Malta have been released for Microsoft Flight Simulator. This version may be a work in progress but it is still a jaw-dropping scenery package and is now available for purchase. Containing 400km of the Italian coastline this VFR scenery is a pilot's dream. ‍ “Rocks, cliffs, boats, yachts, docks, harbours, marinas, palms, working lighthouses, moving harbour crane lifts, parasols, night lights, animals, and more have been added to improve the overall quality of the coast, which by default is flat and dull. Landmarks have been added to the world map so you can easily plan your trip.”   According to the developers the addon currently includes;  - The whole Tuscany region improved with rocks, marinas, harbors, boats etc. - The commercial harbours of Genova, La Spezia, Savona-Vado  (Liguria). - The commercial harbours of Cagliari, Olbia, Porto Torres (Sardegna) - The commercial harbours of Gioia Tauro, Reggio Calabria (Calabria) - The commercial harbour of Catania, faraglioni di Aci Trezza, - Palermo, Messina, Gela (Sicily) - The commercial harbour of Civitavecchia, Fiumicino, Olbia (Lazio) - The commercial harbour of Trieste (Friuli-Venezia-Giulia) Venezia (Veneto) - The commercial harbour of Bari, Taranto and Brindisi (Puglia) - The commercial harbour of Ravenna (Emilia-Romagna) - The commercial harbour of Naples and Salerno(Campania) - The commercial harbor of Ancona and Pescara (Marche) - Malta - Astronomical Observatories - Boats have been added to the whole Italian coast and lakes. - An optional freeware version of the Grosseto Military Airport LIRS (USAF planes are present just for eye candy). - All the rivers bridges and underwater objects of the 9 photogrammetric Italian cities have been cleaned up. Now all the bridges are visible and not covered in water. The cities are Milan, Verona, Venice, Bologna, Florence, Rome, Naples, Catania, Palermo, and Bari.   This is well and truly a must-have for VFR pilots who enjoy flying in the region and is available from both Flighsim.to and Simmarket for approximately €25.00  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/aero12</id>
    <title>Aerobask Announces Upcoming Release of ViperJet</title>
    <updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/aero12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631914afdfb6c651033ab6bf_1677803628_viperjet-2022-08-2409_51_00.jpg.8e2f5543f43b4ad8bb55c49cbd2f1f61.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="157684"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. This week, Aerobask announced information regarding the ViperJet for the newly released X-Plane 12 Public Beta. Originally released in 2015 for XP10, the ViperJet has been updated to keep up with the improving progress of Laminar’s X-Plane Flight Simulator. New improvements for XP12 include updated avionics, a flight model tailored for XP12, along with all the expected visuals such as 3D model textures. Aerobask rebuilt the entire aircraft to take advantage of the latest features the new sim has to offer. Detailed in this forum post are XP12 images of this sleek home-built jet showcasing the new XP12 effects added to the new model. We will keep you updated with more Aerobask news here on Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/inilax</id>
    <title>iniScene Announces LAX For MSFS</title>
    <updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/inilax" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631a70eb202ef72b5c1cc906_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2117777"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The iniBuilds team have announced the release of their upcoming scenery, Los Angeles' LAX Airport. Over 170 different airlines serve the Los Angeles International Airport, being one of the busiest airports in the world making it a must-have in your flight sim. It is well known that iniBuilds pay close attention to detail when it comes to making scenery, making this upcoming release is no exception! This version of LAX is based in early to mid-2022, easily familiar if you've flown into LAX recently. iniScene detailed a slew of features in the official forum post here. Features include handmade ground textures and dynamic airport lighting. You'll find familiar logos, decals, and ground vehicles on the ramps creating the busy congested feel of LAX. iniBulids have also modeled terminal concourses by hand, giving you more things to check out and explore between flights. Of course, the iconic LAX entryway sign is modeled with dynamic lighting!  Currently, KLAX is in beta testing so expect a release in the near future. iniScene has released a promo trailer detailing more features and details not listed in the announcement post. Check it out below It's worth a watch! Expect more information regarding the release here at THRESHOLD.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xpil12</id>
    <title>xPilot release XP12 Compatibility Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xpil12" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/5f3b23368a65f3d9a7c9a339_MainWindow.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="31476"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Popular plugin xPilot has been updated to beta version .35 which adds support for X-Plane 12 among some other changes. xPilot is a cross-platform pilot client for X-Plane 11 originally, and now X-Plane 12 that allows you to connect to the VATSIM Network so you can fly amongst aircraft and receive virtual air traffic control services in real-time. For a full changelog and the free download link, you can click here ‍ Threshold, bringing you the latest in flight sim news!  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xenv17</id>
    <title>xEnviro Release Progress Update On Version 1.17 and Beyond </title>
    <updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xenv17" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631cf39ddb8f385a8463607d_scale_2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="78835"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The team behind the popular X-Plane addon xEnviro have released an update on what's in store regarding the project's future development.  ‍In a forum post this evening, head of development Magnus has outlined future plans for the project along with reasons behind the perhaps seemingly slow development of version 1.17 ‍ It has been revealed that xEnviro will not be released during the Beta phase of X-Plane 12. Magnus provides us with the reasoning behind this;  “xEnviro will not be released in this Beta run. Laminar Research has closed off all access to the platform by not giving access to the 3D draw callback, depth buffer and so on. X-Plane 11 was already limiting us and thus demanded a lot on performance to work. Especially when Vulkan was released, and our dynamic seasons got abruptly cut off. “  Magnus goes on to further state; “However. We are in a dialogue with Austin on the matter, and I am optimistic that we will find a solution to our limited access so that we can release 1.18 in XP12. Regardless of when this access is given, we must finish 1.17 in XP11.” New features expected in version 1.17 of xEnviro include;  Magnus has disclosed that they are currently rebuilding the beta testing team and while he is not in a position to provide a time frame he provides us with in update in stating “We’re at the final stretch before the chicanes that lead to the finish line” We will keep you update on the development of xEnviro V1.17 as it progresses.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xworld</id>
    <title>X-WORLD Europe Released For X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xworld" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631e5ade0228d10a8e8f8a95_2.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="481665"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Highly popular scenery package X-World developed by SimHeaven has released its European scenery package for X-Plane 12! In a post on their website, SimHeaven have announced the free scenery package which is now available.  The post on their website states;  "X-World continues for X-Plane 12 the successful and high quality sceneries for X-Plane 11 like X-Europe, X-America and so on. Objects are not set by an autogen rule, they are set  following OSM data in addition with Microsoft building footprints, which leads to a more realistic look and feel." SimHeaven go on to further explain;  "X-WORLD is a series of scenery packages covering the whole world, each continental package is separate available: X-World_Africa, X-World_America, X-World_Antarctica, X-World_Asia, X-World_Australia-Oceania, X-World_Europe" The download for X-Europe can be found here. </summary>
    <published>2022-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fisf6f</id>
    <title>Flyingiron Simulation Releases its F6F Hellcat</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fisf6f" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631f1fa7aad167d92aefa828_f6f-32_900x.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="93348"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Flyingron Simulations released its long-anticipated F6F Hellcat, adding to its ever-growing war-bird hangar. In WWII, the Grumman Hellcat served primarily as a NAVY bird on aircraft carriers. It replaced the F4F Wildcat to take on the A6M Zero. The Hellcat later became one of the top performing combat aircraft of the war gaining over 5,000 kills by the end of World War II. Flyingiron has brought the Hellcats legacy to Microsoft Flight Simulator with meticulous attention to detail. Flyingiron has also gained recognition for its Spitfire and P-58 models developed for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The F6F-5 HELLCAT is for sale for the reasonable price of $45 AUD.  ‍ The model is well detailed and handcrafted, taking over six months to complete. A few notable features include attention to aircraft systems and thermodynamics, factors to be considered in terms of wear and tear, and power plant management. Expect a learning curve when flying the Hellcat, which will challenge your manual flying skills. The F6F will be an exciting aircraft to switch to if you are used to flying today's modern birds. Usability features include a virtual tablet with customization options, maintenance, live aircraft monitoring, and more.  For a complete list of features including the product manual, check out the Hellcat product page here on the Flyingiron Simulations site. ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/dcdesh</id>
    <title>DC Designs Announce Harrier Update and Surprise Fighter Project</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/dcdesh" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/631fbedc50514036f29d3eea_305975846_507159501412807_4030653392269115163_n.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="488607"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. DC Designs have posted a news update to their Facebook page detailing requested features from several customers. One such request from customers is if the Harrier could bow as it does in real-life air displays, as seen in this video. Here is the response. ‍  “I had not had the chance to test this until recently, and yesterday was able to give it a go. The answer was: yes you can! However, to balance the Harrier while performing the bow and not climb, drift, or descend is really difficult even in light winds. The aircraft’s engine thrust responds to N2, which means there is a lag between adding or removing power, and the thrust altering to climb or descend in the hover, which complicates things even further.” Check out more test footage of the Harrier here. The developer also dropped hints of a "Secret project” within the post. Just today the project was announced via Facebook as a partnership with a new developer “CJ Simulations". The pair are working together in bringing the Eurofighter Typhoon to FS2020.  This will be a well detailed model with a fully operational cockpit. The Typhoon will have a custom flight model simulating its unique delta canard system. You can expect many liveries and visual aerodynamic effects to be featured with this fighter as well. DC Designs also released a video displaying the Typhoon's maneuverability, aerodynamic effects, and modeling details! The Eurofighter is slated to be released in October for PC and XBox. We’re looking forward to these releases. DC Designs is known for their awesome fighter aircraft for FS2020, especially the F-14 Tomcat. We’ll keep you updated with more information here at Threshold! ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/thresholdjobs</id>
    <title>Threshold Is Hiring!</title>
    <updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/thresholdjobs" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6320f2169c2f79ad659e59cb_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="222171"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Are you an avid flight sim enthusiast looking to turn your hobby into more than just a hobby? Well, now you can! Threshold is delighted to announce the recruitment of new content creators, news writers and reviewers.  Working at Threshold holds so many advantages; such as earning some money on the side at a competitive scale by writing about your passion and at your leisure. You work when and how you like, with no minimums to meet, and no requirements for activity.  Threshold staff are paid by article, so the more you write the more you earn.  Let's dive a little deeper into what each role consists of, and to whom it’s tailored: News Writers: News writers are the backbone of Threshold, primarily the role consists of finding stories and news to write about in the flight sim world. This can range from Aircraft release announcements to new simulators being released and everything in between. News writers can earn money per article at a very competitive rate. Our main area of recruitment currently is for news writers, it is also an area friendly to both new and experienced individuals and great for skill development.  ‍ Reviewers:  Are you passionate about flight simulator addons? This is the right role for you. Reviewers perform in-depth tests of products for simulators such as MSFS and X-plane. There are many benefits to becoming a reviewer such as receiving test copies of some of the latest add-ons in the flight simulation world, working closely with many developers and building relationships helping to shape the way products develop further and earning money all the while!  ‍ Requirements: You don’t need to be above average in English but you should have a solid base to work from and be willing to learn and progress your writing over time. Please only apply if you are in a position to write relatively often. If you are able to take on all of the roles advertised then that is a huge bonus. Many of our writers write reviews but help out with news now and then. To apply email rob@thresholdx.net today and express your interest.  ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xjetyt</id>
    <title>X-Crafts Posts Demo of E-Jet Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xjetyt" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632108ad4487d2aba354ade2_ejets001.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="80107"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. The X-Crafts team has taken to their YouTube Channel and posted a full flight video in their rendition of the Embraer E-195 demonstrating the new FMS, new autopilot systems, and new displays. While most of the team has remained tight-lipped since the FSExpo Showcase, the team has brung steady work and the continuous development of their E-Jets Family.  The video starts off at LOWW and showcases the complete programming of the WIP FMC, and shows off the new EFB, with at a glance looks to include takeoff and landing perfs, checklists, ground service, and integrated Avitab, along with a weight and balance tab. Ending the video off, the demo ends with the programming once again of the FMC for landing at LYBE, and we watch as the aircraft comes to the gate and ends the flight. Note that this product is still very much a WIP. The team has stated that there will be a paid upgrade for XP12 for both the E175 and E195.  No ETA has been stated by the development team. Follow Threshold for more news!</summary>
    <published>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/tolair</id>
    <title>Toliss Release Airbus Fleet Update For XP12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/tolair" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6321cbba84352de43604d648_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1855944"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Developers Toliss have released an update for their X-Plane Airbus range bringing their popular A319 and A321 variants into XP12. The aircraft will be available to those who owned them in XP11 for $10.99 each via the X-Plane.org store The discount will be automatically applied to your account, Toliss have explained.  A variety of new features have been added to the A319 just some of them include; ‍ The A321 has also received a variety of updates and new features;  To read a full list of new features and changes to the A319 and A321 check out their store page here We will endeavour to keep you updated on Aircraft and Scenery that are brought into XP12 as the weeks go on.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/free-xp12-dataref-compatibility-checker-released</id>
    <title>Free XP12 dataref compatibility checker released</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/free-xp12-dataref-compatibility-checker-released" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6321e4fa65e57a9302a2988d_usage.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="253387"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Porting existing addons to XP12 has been somewhat turbulent for developers with complex addons. Fabrice Kauffmann published free software assisting developers with migrating addons from XP11 to X-Plane 12. According to a post at Helisimmer.com, the script scans OBJ, LUA, and SND files for obsolete datarefs. Addon developers will save time updating addons to XP12 using his free tool. Thanks to Fabrice Kauffmann; this will help the growth and improvement of X-Plane 12! The software is free for Windows 10/11 and available on GitHub!  Threshold, bringing you the latest in flight sim news! </summary>
    <published>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/versim</id>
    <title>Vertical Simulations Releases Free Update for KSYR for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/versim" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/63225537927e0a30ea9bc3d1_screencapture.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="381865"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Vertical Simulations has announced on his Discord that he has just released a free update for KSYR in X-Plane 12. Previous owners of the X-Plane 11 version will find the updated version under their ‘account page’ section on his website – https://verticalsims.com/ – Additionally, purchasers of the original scenery from SimMarket &amp; the Xplane.org store will also find the update available to them.  Also within the announcement, Vertical Simulations noted the following Changelog improvements found in the new update: ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/xp12d2</id>
    <title>X-Plane 12 Developement Update</title>
    <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/xp12d2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/6322c3784d1e217427e02bd4_Screen-Shot-2022-08-28-at-1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="3839634"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Earlier today, Ben Supnik took to the X-Plane Developer blog to post about the current state and findings with X-Plane 12 since its initial early access release just two weeks ago. In the post Mr. Supnik highlights the rationale behind releasing X-Plane 12 for early access when the simulator is far from being fully developed, as there are “...still over two hundred open bugs.” Mr. Supnik immediately stressed how important it is to Laminar Research that the “entire X-Plane community be involved in X-Plane 12’s growth,” and not be confined to a limited number of beta testers.  Major areas of improvement include clouds, in which Mr. Supnik explains that the development team is working on shaping and cloud quality, improving resolution, correcting artifacts, and improving overall performance. The developer goes on to point out that clouds are some of the most taxing graphics on any system and it’s a “give and take” relationship between performance and quality. Lighting is another focus of improvement for the developer as they want to correct and improve the auto-exposure and tone mapping within the sim.  For those X-Plane 12 users who are dissatisfied with the Boeing FMC in the highly anticipated Airbus A330 that shipped with the default aircraft upon initial release of X-Plane 12, you’ll be happy to know that the developer is working on a proper Airbus MCDU for the plane. This update is expected to ship during early access, but with no specific mention of a date at this time. Mr. Supnik lastly points out that a few new SDK and authoring features are “mostly completed” and will ship during early access as well. Mr. Supnik further hinted at allowing third party access to the in-sim weather system.  Additionally, the development team at Laminar will continue to optimize the sim’s GPU usage while beginning to optimize VRAM use (as they have not done so at this point). For users of X-Plane 12 who are having VRAM issues, Mr. Supnik suggests lowering the simulator's resolution. Lastly, Mr. Supnik mentioned that over the course of the past weekend, some of the development team met to do planning and roadmapping for the sim. He disclosed that beta 3 should be coming out “shortly” (with no specific date or bug the planned update will fix). Mr. Supnik also disclosed that X-Plane 12 has been submitted to Steam and is currently in review. He’s hopeful that X-Plane 12 will be available soon on the Steam platform for those interested in picking up the simulator there instead of through the developer’s site.  If you are interested in picking up X-Plane 12 now, you can do so by visiting the official website for X-Plane here. Threshold will keep you updated on any new developments.</summary>
    <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/gblfr2</id>
    <title>Global Forests v2 Released for X-Plane 12</title>
    <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/gblfr2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/632346180134bbee25dbffcf_19f241_849b3f55ced84a338f83fc94add3cb8e_mv2.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="92185"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. Geo Reality Design recently released v2 of its Global Forests addon for X-Plane 12, adding more immersion, replacing and, enhancing X-Plane's vegetation. Global Forest 2 covers three regions, Europe, North America, and Asia-Oceania. V2 complements Global forests V1 for seamless integration with Ortho4XP, terrain, and X-Plane 12’s seasons! Over 400 .for files utilized with various trees, vegetation, and density data. Based on real-world information using vegetation height/density from global map data to provide that living world feel, something bush pilots would greatly appreciate! Global Forests v2 is on the X-Plane.ORG store for $15.00. Check out this video on their YouTube page for additional footage!  ‍ ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
