<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://www.thresholdx.net/news</id>
  <title>Thresholdx blog</title>
  <updated>2023-08-26T18:19:03.323591+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://www.thresholdx.net/news" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/evroon/msfs-rss/main/feeds/threshold.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <logo>https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d3103abc01d83/5f2387c90e9e1dca5453fc23_web1.png</logo>
  <subtitle>News about flight simulators.</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbde3</id>
    <title>Orbx Announces Idaho’s Deadly 3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbde3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e284bf443afee27e4cd5ad_ded1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="561791"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently announced the development and imminent release of Idaho’s Deadly 3 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, a pack with three challenging airstrips and a bonus makeshift helicopter area with a STOL landing zone.  ‍ The “Deadly 3” are three challenging airstrips scattered around Idaho with tricky approaches, uphill slopes, birds, wildlife, and drones!   ‍ Dewey Moore, the first of the airstrips, is located on the north side of Big Creek, 19 miles west of the junction of Big Creek and the Middle Fork of the Salmon River, with a 700 ft long gravel runway at 4,494 feet above sea level. It’s recommended for highly experienced mountain pilots only (in real life). ‍ Simonds is a very difficult airstrip located on Monumental Creek, close to where it joins up with Big Creek. It’s often used for guided hunting trips and doesn’t have any infrastructure, meaning pilots should bring their own tie-downs and camping equipment. It has a 900 ft long gravel runway, and pilots are instructed to watch for traffic from the nearby Monumental Ranch private airstrip. ‍ Vines Airstrip is located on the south side of Big Creek Canyon, two miles west of Cabin Creek Airstrip, close to where Big Creek joins into the Middle Fork of the Salmon River. It’s a 1,100 ft gravel strip at 4,110 feet above sea level, and pilots are instructed to land on runway 27 and take off from runway 9. Real-life recommendations include instructions on short field operations, and pilots are generally advised to follow Big Creek to avoid trees on final approach and watch their airspeed very carefully as a 10 percent increase in approach speed means a 21% increase in landing distance.  ‍  The three strips are a short flight away from 85U Soldier Bar and McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL), both developed by Milo Taylor, the author of Idaho’s Deadly 3. His new creation features substantial terraforming work, custom animations, custom vegetation, and much more. The complete feature list for the package follows down below:  ‍ There is no pricing or release date information yet, but Threshold will keep you informed! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/zls152</id>
    <title>ZL Simulation Releases Cessna 152 Freeware for X-Plane 11 &amp; 12</title>
    <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/zls152" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e28c1e555ee9fc45747f4d_152.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1293898"/>
    <summary>Sim: X-Plane. ZL Simulation has recently released a freeware Cessna 152 for X-Plane 11 and 12, featuring a realistic flight model and physics, PBR textures, a 3D cockpit, and much more.  ‍ The Cessna 152 is one of the most popular trainer aircraft in the world, with over 7,500 built during its eight years of production (1977-1985). It was a modernization of the Cessna 150 design with an improved engine, greater useful load, noise level reduction, and better compatibility with 100LL fuel. They were powered by a Lycoming O-235-L2C engine producing 110 horsepower at 2,550 RPM, with a range of 416 nautical miles, a 14,700ft service ceiling, and 123 miles per hour of cruise speed. ‍ Production ended when Cessna decided to end production of all of their light aircraft, with a successor being developed in the form of the unsuccessful 162 Skycatcher (2007-2013). ‍ According to the developer, the project has been worked on for over three years, featuring a realistic flight model, PBR texturing, a 3D cockpit, custom FMOD sounds, ten liveries, a paintkit, performance-friendly optimization, windshield rain effects on X-Plane 12, a built-in Garmin GNS 430 GPS, and custom coded systems using XTLua. ‍ It’s free on X-Plane.Org, and the source code is open-sourced on GitHub.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/rdpsta</id>
    <title>RDPresets Releases Stuttgart Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/rdpsta" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e3b2140c83b990822b06c4_str1.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="208592"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. RDPresets has recently announced the development and imminent release of Stuttgart Airport (EDDS) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Stuttgart in Germany with a yearly average of 7 million passengers.  Built in 1939 to replace Böblingen Airport, it was taken over by the American forces right after the war. It was partially returned in 1948: runway and facilities were shared with the US Army during the Cold War. ‍ The original terminal was replaced in 2004 with four terminals capable of handling up to 12 million passengers annually. ‍ Eurowings and Turkish Airlines use Terminal 1; Terminal 2 is used by Lufthansa and Star Alliance partners; Terminal 3 is used by TUIfly and KLM, and Terminal 4 is a separate building for other airlines, set to be rebuilt and expanded in the future. ‍ It’s a hub for Condor, Eurowings, and TUI fly Deutschland, sporting a substantial list of destinations. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with animated jetways, custom models, PBR texturing, a custom interior with 3D passengers, more than a thousand clutter objects around the apron and surroundings, custom ground textures, performance-friendly optimization, accurate night lighting, custom taxiway signage, ground traffic, and more. ‍ It’s available on their website for roughly $22.87, requiring at least 1.02 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/shdlgw</id>
    <title>SHADESCENE Releases Langkawi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/shdlgw" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e3b62db27874f94dfe72e8_lkw1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1200571"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SHADESCENE has recently released their rendition of Langkawi International Airport (WMKL), serving Langkawi and Peris in Malaysia with a yearly average of 3 million passengers.  It was built by the Japanese Army in 1945 as an airfield, only becoming a passenger airport in the late 1980s after a huge effort by the government to develop Langkawi as a major tourist destination.  It saw its first upgrade in 1991, bringing it up to international standards in terms of infrastructure.  The airport was expanded in 2018 to accommodate up to 4 million passengers annually.   AirAsia (Johor Bahru, Kuala Lumpur–International, Penang, Singapore), Batik Air Malaysia (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Kuala Lumpur–International), Firefly (Kuala Lumpur–Subang, Penang), Malaysia Airlines (Kuala Lumpur–International), MYAirline  (Kuala Lumpur–International), and Scoot (Singapore) serve it.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom terraforming, custom scenery objects, moderate terminal interior details, custom night lighting, hand-crafted ground markings and textures, and more.  It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $13.03, requiring at least 242.91 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/orbv16</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Volanta 1.6 </title>
    <updated>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/orbv16" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e52518dcd13f98046a5555_volanta1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="1811562"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. Orbx has recently updated Volanta to version 1.6, bringing new features, improved functionality, bug fixes, and more.   ‍ It adds a new playback function, allowing users to “replay” their flight path, the ability to filter the flights shown on the map, design improvements on the map settings panel, aircraft icon changes, new languages (including Chinese and Romanian), and more. The full changelog follows down below: ‍ Additions ‍ ⦁ Added playback controls for past flights! Flights can now be "replayed" in Volanta at various speeds with an intuitive timeline-like navigation experience that marks key events such as landings. ⦁Added the ability to filter the flights shown on the map ⦁ New and improved map settings panel design ⦁ The map will highlight products that are nearby during a flight ⦁ Select between stable and experimental plugin release channels ⦁ Improved downloading of airport data ⦁ Closed airports are noted in tooltips and information cards ⦁ Airports now have local time and country information ⦁ The open/closed status of an airport is now considered when a destination is being automatically selected based on a landing ⦁ Product recommendations for the user's active flights' origin and destination have been added ⦁ Many new aircraft icons have been added ⦁ Language translations have now been included, such as Chinese (Traditional) and Romanian ‍ ‍ Fixes ‍   Volanta v1.6 has a lot of updates to provide the greatest user experience: ‍ ⦁ FSS controller labels have been fixed (no longer crashes into area controller labels) ⦁ Controller tooltips will function even when an approach ring is present in the same location ⦁ Enroute controllers now appear on the airport’s controllers page ⦁ An airline can now be eliminated from an aircraft ⦁ The flickering radius circles for approach controllers when hovering over them have been fixed ⦁ Tooltips no longer scroll with the app ⦁ Screenshots can now be seen on the map ⦁ Volanta Premium Subscribers can sync with Orbxdirect ⦁Users can select area controllers even when the labels are displayed in the same place as an approach controller radius ring ⦁Controller tooltips are no longer shown when the controller layer is not visible ⦁Fixed an issue causing enroute controllers to no longer appear in the list of VATSIM controllers on the airport card ‍ Volanta is available for free on their website. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fnx214</id>
    <title>Fenix Simulations Updates A320 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fnx214" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e52add077dfc7477e1369c_cover.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="489297"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fenix Simulations has recently released another update (v1.5.2.214) to their A320 for Microsoft Flight Simulator, tweaking the flight model with flare mode refinements, drag improvements, mitigating the nose down behavior on landing, and more. It’s the second update post-V2 Block 1 (the first mitigated the high CPU usage issues on some systems), aiming to improve the flight model with tweaks on how the aircraft behaves on flare, allegedly making it less prone to floating, along with corrections on the drag behavior with flaps 3, and also sorting out the nose smashing down instantly upon touchdown.  They have also worked on improving the avionics, making the VNAV more polished, and correcting how the aircraft interprets certain restrictions. The high CPU usage across their bootstrapper and the app is also one of the things Fenix has managed to mitigate on this update. Other changes include sound improvements, minor art fixes, and volume level adjustments. The complete changelog follows down below: ‍ ‍ The add-on is available on their website for roughly $63.64.  Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ssrda2</id>
    <title>SimSolutions Releases Diamond DA20-C1 Eclipse for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ssrda2" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e5313b1e6ad5bfe58d9196_da20.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="391112"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. SimSolutions has recently released their Diamond DA20-C1 Eclipse for Microsoft Flight Simulator, marking their debut on the platform with a high-detail rendition of the popular two-seater introduced in 1992.   The Eclipse is the improved version of the DA20 Katana, with rear windows, better visibility, and improved equipment aimed at private use.  ‍ It’s powered by a 125 hp Continental IO-240-B, cruising at up to 138 knots with a range of 629 nautical miles with a 30-minute reserve. ‍ The aircraft add-on features an accurate 3D model, 4K PBR textures, a GTX 327 transponder, a DAVTRON clock system, a checklist, a flight model based on real-world experience, and more.  ‍  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $19.77, requiring at least 992 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/fl2jej</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Jeju International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/fl2jej" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e59790b1ee2a82591ecbf4_jej1.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="729523"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Jeju International Airport (RKPC) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, the second busiest airport in South Korea with a yearly average of 31.3 million passengers.  Built as Jeju Airfield during the Japanese colonial period by the hands of enslaved Jeju locals, then taken over by the US Army after World War 2 and used by the Korean government as an extermination field during the uprising, where an estimated 700 Jeju citizens were shot to death (known in South Korea as the April 3 massacre, or Jeju uprising. The total death toll surpasses 30,000) and buried. Only 237 of the bodies were found during a full-scale excavation in 2007.  The airport was built in the late 1960s as part of a governmental effort to develop the island’s tourism. It was inaugurated in 1968 with a 1,200-meter runway and a modestly sized terminal, initially aimed at domestic operations. Expansion work was only conducted in the 80s and 90s, lengthening the runway and upgrading the terminal facilities to accommodate larger aircraft and more passenger traffic. ‍ The international status was granted in 2002 with the construction of an international terminal, kickstarting a massive growth in passenger traffic (from a 9 million/year average to almost 20 million within a decade). The numbers peaked in 2019 at 31 million passengers.  It’s a hub for Jeju Air and a focus city for Air Busan, Asiana Airlines, Eastar Jet, Jin Air, Korean Air, and T’way Air. Visitors include China Eastern, China Southern, HK Express, Scoot, Spring Airlines, and Tigerair Taiwan.  ‍  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, highly-detailed models, performance-friendly optimization, and an official GSX profile.  It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $21.88, requiring at least 8.21 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ugdf16</id>
    <title>The return of the beloved Falcon series!</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ugdf16" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e618643273e84c6e077ec5_falcon.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="278774"/>
    <summary>Sim: OTHER. The return of a classic, MicroProse announces, Falcon 5.0 after requiring the Falcon brand. Recently, MicroProse announced the successor to the Falcon series, Falcon 5.0. The Falcon series was one of the most sophisticated combat simulators of its time. Falcon 4.0 was released over 25 years ago and focused on a detailed, accurate simulation of the F-16 Falcon. Some rated it as close to 90% system accuracy. MicroProse was ahead of its time by coding the complexity of the "Vipers" flight systems, avionics, flight characteristics, and PvE AI combat. The simulator campaign is based on a South Korean/North Korean conflict with allied forces such as the United States providing military support and aiding South Korean defenses against invading North Korean aggression. You take on the role of a Viper Pilot under the United States Air Force. You are tasked with air-to-ground bombing runs, holding air space superiority, and more. ‍ Starting with training, learn the nitty-gritty of jet combat and F16-specific combat maneuvers amidst dogfight scenarios. Learn armed tactics, weapon behaviors, and characteristics through 30 training missions. I wouldn't skip over them! Ahead of its time was a pilot rating system based on detailed kill reports and kill quality. The player's kills and actions directly affect the path of the game as well. In addition, Falcon 4.0 supported online multiplayer PVP dogfights, incredible for its time. Falcon 4.0 claimed some of the best reviews of any combat flight simulator for its time. The simulator reaches back to 1987, with Falcon 4.0 Allied Force as the most recent iteration. June 2005.  Hopefully, MicroProse will give us that ringed flight ops manual. ‍  ‍ PC-Pilot Magazine's Derek Davis interviews David Laettie of MicroProse covering the push and goal to get Micropose back into Flight Simulation. The interview has exclusive screenshots of a new aircraft addition to the Viper's simulation. Derek Davis also inquired about other flight simulation projects during the interview. Access to the article and exclusive cockpit shots of both aircraft can be viewed on PC-Pilot with a subscription.  ‍ Falcon is still alive at the hands of Benchmark Sims Team akaBMS . BMS has worked to keep the title current with today's technology and modern software capabilities. MicroProse thanked the team for keeping the simulation alive through the years. It looks like an exciting acknowledgment and upcoming teamwork to bring the best out of Falcon 5! Benchmark Sims Team announced on Twitter that they have resolved the intellectual property subject with Falcon 4.0 and will continue development with minimal disruption. A highlighted version of the contractual agreement can be found on BMS's forum post.  ‍ ‍ Falcon 5.0 is expected to be on the markets before the holiday season.  ‍ Stay tuned and expect more from Threshold for more information covering this evolving project! ‍  ‍  ‍  ‍ ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/a300ini</id>
    <title>The Official IniBuilds summer event with A300 progress details.</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/a300ini" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e63f0d7679ac0d760c9893_image.png.f0a0792817c4133a8cd65d50db72e3ac.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="2540029"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. The Official IniBuilds summer event starts tomorrow! iniBuilds reminds you to have your iniManager up to date for downloads. Each day IniBuilds will feature discounts for 24 hours only on new products by iniBuilds or a production partner. Expect the debut of two new partners as well! Event dates are August 24 at 5 pm BST and new deals daily at 5 pm BST. The Grand finale product announcement is on August 28! ‍ IniBuilds sheds light on the build progress of the highly-anticipated A300-600 since its debut at FSExpo last June. Their forum post showcases high-res images of details like rivets, screws, and panel gaps, as well as the usage of high-resolution decal sheets. The photos highlight the distinctive work the team is doing. ‍ IniBuilds showcased the recreated animations of A300's cargo door, as well as the fully operational nose gear model. They also discussed the systems and flight model.    “In the last update we provided, we talking about some of the key features this product is going to include such as comprehensive systems simulation, realistic flight model, full ACARS, CPDLC simulation, and a whole lot more! “ ‍  IniBuilds used the latest simulation techniques within the flight model CFD simulations flowing over the wings tail ending by reinjection into the A300 fight model. Improved ground effect using CFD technology, accurate drag, and engine thrust simulations throughout the flight envelope. Lastly mentioned was the complete overhaul and rebuild of the autopilot systems. Key highlights are new operating flight directors providing smoother operations and a new auto land system with LOC and GS laws. LVL Change V/S will be much smoother in the Auto Pilot handling overhaul. Improved core system logic and a new LNAV system improve with processing more complex SIDs and STARs.  The pricing/release timeline shapes up like this.  “To those of you, who were concerned about the PW variant; I have some good news. We are going to introduce this into the package for FREE.  Stage 1: FREE Stage 2: FREE  Stage 3: PAID ‍ As always stay tuned to Threshold for more updates on the IniBuilds Summer event and A300 news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/mscciv</id>
    <title>Microsoft Releases City Update IV: Western Europe for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/mscciv" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e66e1206ef14ecb6def4a1_cityupdate.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="832365"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Microsoft has recently released a new city update for Microsoft Flight Simulator, adding five Western European cities (Annemasse, Geneva, Ghent, Luxembourg City, and Rotterdam) and one airport (Cologne-Bonn Airport).  ‍ Annemasse is a commune in the French Alps with 5 square kilometers of total area and 36,250 residents, making it the second most populous commune after Annecy. ‍ Geneva is Switzerland's second most populous city, with 201,818 inhabitants as of 2018. It's situated in the country's southwest, near the French border.  ‍ Ghent is a city in the Flemish region of Belgium (the Dutch-speaking part), the third largest in the country with 265,086 inhabitants, only behind Brussels and Antwerp.  ‍ Luxembourg City is the capital of Luxembourg, lying at the heart of Western Europe, with a population of 132,778 people. It has the highest per capita GDP in the world as of 2022. ‍ Rotterdam is the second largest city in the Netherlands, situated in the province of Zuid-Holland. The municipality has 664,311 inhabitants, but the metropolitan area is nearing 2.5 million. ‍ Cologne-Bonn Airport (EDDK) serves the city of Köln in Germany with a yearly average of 9 million passengers. It's the seventh-largest passenger airport in Germany. ‍  The update is available right now for free on PC and Xbox. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/vssvij</id>
    <title>Velocity Studios Releases Vijayawada Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/vssvij" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e674849294960b0d11df03_vij1.png" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="3148728"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Velocity Studios has recently released their rendition of Vijayawada Airport (VOBZ) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Vijayawada with a yearly average of 966,383 passengers. ‍ Built as an army base during World War 2, it was later converted into a civilian airport. Scheduled services were only introduced in 2003, with Air Deccan’s route to Hyderabad. Kingfish followed suit until 2011, when Air India, SpiceJet, and Jet Airways also introduced daily flights (canceled not soon after). ‍ A new terminal was built in 2017, allowing a yearly average of two million passengers. International status was granted a few months later, with the inaugural international flight a year later, an Indigo flight to Singapore Changi.  ‍ Air India, Air India Express, Alliance Air, and IndiGo currently serve the airport. ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with PBR materials, dynamic night lighting, custom ground markings, realistic navigation aids, and more. ‍ ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.59, temporarily discounted from its full price of $11.96. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/obxid3</id>
    <title>Orbx Releases Idaho’s Deadly 3 for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/obxid3" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e7049e4b2f6fb91ac11e5c_idaho.jpeg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="480078"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Orbx has recently released their newest scenery pack for Microsoft Flight Simulator, including three challenging airstrips in Idaho and a bonus makeshift helicopter area with a STOL landing zone.  The “Deadly 3” are three famous - and challenging - strips in Idaho, known for requiring a lot of technique to get the landings right. Dewey Moore, Simonds, and Vines Airstrip are as barebones as a landing strip can get, with no basic infrastructure, making it ideal for hardcore camping. ‍ Dewey Moore, the first of the airstrips, is located on the north side of Big Creek, 19 miles west of the junction of Big Creek and the Middle Fork of the Salmon River, with a 700 ft long gravel runway at 4,494 feet above sea level. It’s recommended for highly experienced mountain pilots only (in real life). ‍ Simonds is a very difficult airstrip located on Monumental Creek, close to where it joins up with Big Creek. It’s often used for guided hunting trips and has no infrastructure, meaning pilots should bring tie-downs and camping equipment. It has a 900 ft long gravel runway, and pilots are instructed to watch for traffic from the nearby Monumental Ranch private airstrip. ‍ Vines Airstrip is located on the south side of Big Creek Canyon, two miles west of Cabin Creek Airstrip, close to where Big Creek joins into the Middle Fork of the Salmon River. It’s a 1,100 ft gravel strip at 4,110 feet above sea level, and pilots are instructed to land on runway 27 and take off from runway 9. Real-life recommendations include instructions on short field operations, and pilots are generally advised to follow Big Creek to avoid trees on final approach and watch their airspeed very carefully as a 10 percent increase in approach speed means a 21% increase in landing distance.  ‍ The three strips are a short flight away from 85U Soldier Bar and McCall Municipal Airport (KMYL), both developed by Milo Taylor, the author of Idaho’s Deadly 3. His new creation features substantial terraforming work, custom animations, custom vegetation, and much more. The complete feature list for the package follows below:  ‍ ‍ It’s available on OrbxDirect for roughly $12.91, requiring at least 697.99 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍ ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/ahlanc</id>
    <title>Aeroplane Heaven Lancaster Development Update</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/ahlanc" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e7791e74375c96a60fc797_1.PNG" rel="enclosure" type="image/png" length="452383"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Aeroplane Heaven has made an announcement regarding the development of their upcoming Avro Lancaster for Microsoft Flight Simulator. The Lancaster project was originally announced back in 2022, it has been a main focus for the company since the release of their DC-3 for the Microsoft Flight Simulator 40th anniversary update.  ‍ ‍ ‍ The Avro Lancaster was a highly significant aircraft developed for the RAF during World War Two. It proudly served not only the Royal Air Force but also the Royal Australian Air Force and the Royal Canadian Air Force. The Lancaster was designed with a spacious bomb bay, allowing it to accommodate the largest bombs utilized by the RAF. It is most notable for its pivotal role in Operation Chastise, better known as the Dam Busters raid. In this operation, British flight crews skillfully dropped cylindrical-shaped bombs, ingeniously spinning them before release, to have the bombs skip across the water to effectively destroy the Möhne and Edersee dams. ‍ ‍ The development update, which was posted to Aeroplane Heaven's Facebook page, states that the modeling and textures are nearing completion, however, there's been no announcement regarding a release date other than that it's expected to be released in the second half of 2023. Aeroplane Heaven has stated they're also working on "some cool coding ideas to bring extra functionality" to the aircraft, though it hasn't been announced what these extra functionalities may include. Aeroplane Heaven has also hinted at the possibility of additional model variants (Mk I, Mk III, etc.) if "time allows". The developer has however confirmed that the aircraft will include custom flight crew models that feature period-correct uniforms and equipment.  ‍ ‍ Threshold is excited to bring you this and other updates for your favorite simulators! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/f2hccr</id>
    <title>Fly2High Releases Corpus Christi International Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/f2hccr" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e7dcd796fdf5a42c9bd7a7_corpus.webp" rel="enclosure" type="image/webp" length="393446"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. Fly2High has recently released their rendition of Corpus Christi International Airport (KCRP) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Corpus Christi, Texas, with a yearly average of 645,000 passengers.  The airport was built in 1960, replacing Cliff Maus Airport, which formerly served the city (since 1928). Cliff Maus couldn’t grow any further, restricted to its 400-acre area, rapidly becoming a problem as the demand for air travel increased. In October 1956, voters approved 3.2 million USD in funding to build a new 1,800-acre airport.   A new terminal was opened in 2002, with six gates, 15,300 square meters of built area, and a modern infrastructure to meet the new demands.   American Eagle, Southwest Airlines, Sun Country Airlines, and United Express currently serve the airport.  The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with hand-made ground textures, custom night lighting, highly detailed buildings, and performance-friendly optimization.  It’s available on the iniBuilds Store for roughly $9.53, requiring at least 2.31 GB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>/news/100itu</id>
    <title>OneHundred Simulations Releases Itumbiara Airport for MSFS</title>
    <updated>2023-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link href="/news/100itu" rel="alternate"/>
    <link href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5b27a494dc3d312fe5c01da8/64e92638daa1adf5f3dfcc5c_sbit.jpg" rel="enclosure" type="image/jpeg" length="663877"/>
    <summary>Sim: MSFS. OneHundred Simulations has recently released their rendition of Itumbiara Airport (SBIT) for Microsoft Flight Simulator, serving the city of Itumbiara, Goias, Brazil.  ‍ It’s mostly a general aviation airport, serving the local farmers and UHI (Usina Hidrelétrica de Itumbiara, a hydroelectric plant) personnel. The plant - depicted in the add-on - was built in 1974 and produces 2.082 mW, serving most of Goiás, Minas Gerais, and Mato Grosso do Sul.  ‍ With a 1,752-meter runway at 1651 ft above sea level, it can accommodate most general aviation aircraft and even medium-sized jets.  ‍ ‍ The scenery features an accurate rendition of the airport, with custom 3D models, custom ground markings, realistic ground layout, PBR texturing, and custom terraforming for the hydroelectric plant. ‍ It’s available on SimMarket for roughly $7.58, requiring at least 36.74 MB of free hard disk space to install. Stay tuned to Threshold for more flight simulation news! ‍</summary>
    <published>2023-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
